<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1190551" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-10-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1011</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Christine Ritz, Group Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch, Finance and Controlling</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Detlef Wittig, Executive Vice President, Group Sales and Marketing</participant>
      <participant id="4">Max Warburton</participant>
      <participant id="5">Christine Ritz</participant>
      <participant id="6">Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch</participant>
      <participant id="7">Christian Breitsprecher</participant>
      <participant id="8">Lothar Lubinetzki</participant>
      <participant id="9">Gregor Claussen</participant>
      <participant id="10">Detlef Wittig</participant>
      <participant id="11">Philippe Houchois</participant>
      <participant id="12">Thierry Huon</participant>
      <participant id="13">Michael Punzet</participant>
      <participant id="14">Adam Hull</participant>
      <participant id="15">Jochen Gehrke</participant>
      <participant id="16">Horst Schneider</participant>
      <participant id="17">Adam Jonas</participant>
      <participant id="18">Albrecht Denninghoff</participant>
      <participant id="19">Arndt Ellinghorst</participant>
      <participant id="20">Georges Dieng</participant>
      <participant id="21">Christiaan Hetzner</participant>
      <participant id="22">Kristina Spiller</participant>
      <participant id="23">Jan Schwartz</participant>
      <participant id="24">Edward Taylor</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen and welcome to today's Volkswagen AG Interim Report for the period January to September 2008 Conference Call. For your information this conference is being recorded. At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to your host today, Ms. Christine Ritz, Group Head of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Volkswagen conference call for the first nine months of 2008. I'm joined today by Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch, Member of the Board of Management, Volkswagen AG responsible for Finance and Controlling; and by Detlef Wittig, Executive Vice President, Volkswagen AG, responsible for Group Sales and Marketing.</p>
          <p>As usual, you can also follow the webcast and download the chart from our website volkswagenag.com/ir. Questions can be sent by e-mail or called in. Before we start, I would like to mention that after the speech of Mr. P&#xF6;tsch and Mr. Wittig, we will first respond to the questions of analysts and later answer those of journalists.</p>
          <p>I would now like to ask Mr. P&#xF6;tsch to give a few comments on the highlights of the first nine months of 2008 before Mr. Wittig goes into detail of the deliveries to customers. Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot ladies and gentlemen, also a warm welcome from my side to this conference call. I'm very pleased to be here today to discuss our performance in what has clearly developed into a difficult macro environment. You've heard a lot from our competitors as they reported third quarter results over the last week or so as to how the markets have slowed dramatically in the third quarter and into the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Our deliveries and sales have held up well but we cannot remain detached from the broader macro trend and our sales development is slowing. So while I can report to you today that we have sold more cars in the first nine months of 2008 and that our global market share continues to rise, I must add a note of caution that we too are feeling the pressure from declining overall demand.</p>
          <p>Into this maelstrom, we launched the new Golf in September, with fuel efficiency improved significantly or specifically up to 28%. A further improvement that is already high build quality and even better interior and a sharper design. We launched our best Golf ever but also a car that is cheaper for us to build. The new Golf will play an important role in both our sales and financial performance in 2009 and beyond as we face these challenging times.</p>
          <p>We were delighted to complete the transaction to increase our holding in Scania to 68.6% of the voting rights in July. Consequently, we have consolidated Scania as our ninth brand. I will explain the mechanics of the consolidation a little later in my presentation.</p>
          <p>The first nine months of 2008 including Scania from July 22, our operating profit increased significantly by 15% to &#x20AC;4.9 billion. Consolidated pre-tax profit also increased strongly by 11.2% to &#x20AC;5.3 billion, 0.5 billion above the comparable 2007 figure.</p>
          <p>Despite the challenges of higher raw material and energy costs, we have continued to reduce our product costs. For the first nine months, our CapEx ratio lies at 4.9%. Despite the concerns of the world economy, we continue to invest for the future in new models, in improved more fuel efficient Powertrain as well as investing in new facilities in Russia, in India and soon also in the United States of America.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we had a good start to the year with a more difficult third quarter and the fourth quarter will not be any easier. However, with the results looked so far, we have the confidence to reaffirm our targets for 2008.</p>
          <p>I will give you a few more details on our financial performance later. Now, I would like to hand over to Mr. Wittig, who will take you through our sales development. Mr. Wittig, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. P&#xF6;tsch. Good afternoon. Ladies and gentlemen, let us first have a look at the trend of the world car market this year. The developments of &#x2013; on the global financial market clearly impacted the world car market over the last two quarters of this year.</p>
          <p>On this chart here, you can see the development by quarter in comparison to the previous year. The first quarter showed still an increase of the world car market by 2.6% and then the second quarter already signaled a slight decrease of minus 0.1% and in the period July to September the markets fell rapidly by 6.9% worldwide compared with the third quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to add to this chart our performance, the Volkswagen Group deliveries, in contrast and you can see it with the blue columns on the chart now. In contrast to the total car market, our Group deliveries to customers developed significantly better. Given these circumstances, we clearly performed well. In quarter one, we increased our deliveries by 6.9% and in quarter two was also positive with a 4.8% increase and in the third quarter our deliveries were also slowing down but we still had a slight plus of 0.1%. So cumulative, our result was plus 3.9% versus the total market, down by minus 1.4%. And as a result of this performance, we are gaining market share worldwide.</p>
          <p>Looking at our performance in comparison to the total market on a regional base, you can see here where we outperformed the car market and I would like to start from left top with North America. And you can see there, while the North American market was down by 11% compared to 2007, our Volkswagen Group sales decreased by only 3.3%.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, the market, the total market showed a reduction of minus 5% while we, our Volkswagen Group deliveries were only 2.4% below the level of 2007. In the other regions of Eastern Europe, of South America and Asia-Pacific, for instance, so they are the famous BRIC markets: Brazil, Russia, India and China, these total markets grew strongly as you can see on the chart. However, the Volkswagen Group deliveries performed even more successful, above the level of the market growth. So as I mentioned before, we gained market share in all major areas in the world, thus taking now the number three position behind Toyota and General Motors on the world chart.</p>
          <p>With the next chart, I would like to turn to the sales volume by market areas and here this time we have split up Europe into Western Europe and Eastern Europe and we've split up South America and South Africa into the two different regions because of totally different performance showing. I would like to start with the Volkswagen column. The left column here you can see there that from January to September 2008, we increased our deliveries to customers by 3.9% to about 4.8 million vehicles, which is a new sales record for the Group.</p>
          <p>The next column shows Western Europe. In Western Europe, our deliveries declined slightly, year-on-year due to a very weak market in Italy and also in Spain and in the U.K. In contrast, our deliveries to customers in Germany were up, reaching a record market share of 33%.</p>
          <p>In Eastern Europe, however, we saw an increase in deliveries of 19.6% and therein our sales figures of &#x2013; in Russia and in Ukraine and in Europe. In Russia we were able to increase our deliveries to customers by 68% while in Ukraine it was up by 51%.</p>
          <p>The next area is North America. You'll see a decrease of our deliveries by 3.3% as compared with last year. Deliveries in the U.S. were almost flat. However, therein the Volkswagen brand showed a slight increase of 0.2%. Mexico is part of our North American region, saw a decline of minus 9.7% due to the strong supply of used vehicles coming in from the U.S. South America, the positive trend continued with a plus of 17.5% and that was mostly driven by Brazil. Brazil was up by 20%.</p>
          <p>Deliveries in Asia-Pacific improved by 12.7% and that is in particular thanks to China's strong growth of 13%. In India, we saw a growth rate of 70%. That was mostly driven by &#x160;koda there. In South Africa, we saw a decline of 28%. The total market was down by a similar rate.</p>
          <p>The next chart shows our performance of our individual brands of the Group. We start with the Volkswagen Passenger Cars. Volkswagen Passenger Cars increased their sales to customers by an overall of 3.1% up to 2.8 million now and that was driven by the strong growth in Central Europe, in Eastern Europe, in China and in Brazil.</p>
          <p>Audi sales were up 2.9% up to a total volume of 762,000 cars and that was supported in particular by the strong demand for the new A4 and the A5 range. &#x160;koda continued its very positive trend with a further strong plus of 14.8% to now 531,000 units. Highlights for &#x160;koda were the market entry in China and the 90% increase in Russia.</p>
          <p>Seat, however, suffered a decline of 10.2% but considering that the Spanish market was down by 22%, so the double of what Seat suffered and the Spanish market was down by 40% in September only, we think that the Seat performance was reasonably good, especially now driven by the new Ibiza that was just launched in the market.</p>
          <p>Bentley was down by 20.4% from January to September this year and that is certainly due to the focus market of Bentley, the North American market, the U.S. market suffering from the credit squeeze.</p>
          <p>Our Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles continued their excellent development in 2008 with deliveries to customers increasing by 8.5% up to 387,000 units now. All model lines contributed to this success in all major regions. Scania for the first time is included here and this is included with sales starting from July with 13,000 units.</p>
          <p>Now a few highlights on some of our models. The picture here shows our new Golf. We can proudly say that the new Golf had excellent reactions from journalists and of our dealers &#x2013; from our dealers since the first showing in Iceland at our press presentation there. It was accepted as the affordable car, which combines dynamic design with the best quality and functionality in its segment. Positive effects as far as new models on the Volkswagen side are concerned, also came in from the launch of the new Golf in Brazil, the Sagitar in China, and certainly still the Tiguan.</p>
          <p>And I would like to make a remark here. At this point of our presentation a remark on our product range not only, the Volkswagen product range, but also the Group product range, the other brands. We do have actually a product portfolio of about 170 models and this product portfolio is relatively young with an average age of three years. So from that point of view with this young product portfolio, it is certainly one of the competitive advantages that we actually have. That is the situation in 2008. Looking ahead in 2009, we will launch another 30 new models and model improved versions. And I think the drive that we get from our product range will continue not only this year but will go into next year as well.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, in addition to that, we offer over 90 model versions with CO2 emissions below 140 grams per kilometer. And of these 90 model versions, there are nearly 20 models having a emission level below 120 gram per kilometer. And I think that no other competitor can offer such a wide range of CO2 efficient cars. In summary, our product portfolio gives us good reasons to be well prepared for the future.</p>
          <p>Turning to Audi, Audi reported the best January to September period in its history. This success is certainly also the result of the enlargement of the product portfolio. And this year very much saw, since its market introduction end of last year, the A4 Sedan and now since April the A4 Station Wagon, both enjoyed a great success meeting our Audi customers' expectations.</p>
          <p>&#x160;koda, the &#x160;koda brand continued its good performance in the January to September period, setting a new sales record. The new &#x160;koda Superb, which you can see here on the picture, introduced in June this year contributed to this new sales record. And with a widening market base of &#x160;koda and the start of production of the Fabia in China this month, &#x160;koda will certainly be able to continue its success story.</p>
          <p>Seat, Seat delivered from January to September 288,000 cars to customers. On this chart here you can see the new Ibiza, the design masterpiece with sporty design, high quality and precision, which fits very well to the brand's 'auto emoci&#xF3;n' theme and the order entries of the new Ibiza are meeting our high expectations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Wittig. Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, can you take us through the financials please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course, I can. And let's get started with sales revenue. Sales revenue, which as you know, excludes our Chinese joint ventures which we report as equity in the financial result, increased by &#x20AC;4.4 billion to 85.4 billion, boosted in part by the consolidation of Scania from July 22. Volume growth generated deposits &#x20AC;3.2 billion, pricing added a further 0.8 billion before mix and currency, that's mainly the US dollar and British pound, reduced the overall growth. Volkswagen Financial Services added a further &#x20AC;0.7 billion.</p>
          <p>Turning now to operating profits, which improved by 15% to &#x20AC;4.9 billion, I would like to take a little bit of your time to explain how we have consolidated Scania. Scania reported their third quarter results last Friday. With the result of &#x20AC;1.1 billion, Scania's operating result for the first nine months was up 24%. For the third quarter, Scania reported an operating result of &#x20AC;289 million as their excellent performance was maintained in a tough environment. As I mentioned earlier, we have consolidated Scania from July 22. The proportional result for third quarter, combining vehicles and services and the financial services area of Scania consolidated within the Volkswagen Group, is &#x20AC;227 million.</p>
          <p>We have then applied purchase price accounting according to the IFRS rules, which as I've mentioned before, impact in particular, the earlier periods of consolidation. This is shown in our chart analysis by business line, as you will see in a moment, within the "Other" category. The impact of applying PPA, when combined with a truncated quarter sales, as we consolidated only from the 22nd of July, means that the result for this quarter, the third quarter, relating to Scania is a net double-digit negative in the overall group reporting operating result. As we move forward, I am confident that we will report a positive impact from our consolidation of Scania for the second half.</p>
          <p>Now price, mix and volume contributed a positive &#x20AC;0.8 billion and we had a negative impact after hedging of 0.6 billion from currencies. That's mainly the US dollar, the British pound, as well as the Czech koruna. Despite the headwinds of further increases in commodity prices, our continued efforts to improve the costs of our vehicles resulted in a saving of &#x20AC;0.7 billion in product costs. Fixed costs and depreciation remained broadly stable with a negative of just 0.2 billion. Volkswagen Financial Services continued to weather the storm in the financial market and, despite tighter conditions, the operating result also remained stable.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to cash flow. In the automotive division, cash flow from operating activities was &#x20AC;7.7 billion, down 3.7 billion on 2007. This is due in particular to an increase in working capital driven by higher stocks. This increase was mainly a deliberate action to ensure that the changeover of the Golf as well as other models, I got to say volume models, over the summer period was as smooth as possible. The slowdown in the market also made a contribution to higher stocks as did the inclusion of Scania for the first time with an impact of 1.7 billion.</p>
          <p>With our new models successfully launched, we are reducing our stock levels and I am confident that we will return to a more normal level by the end of the first quarter at the latest. Cash flow from investing activities stood at &#x20AC;7.8 billion. Excluding our investment in Scania shares in 2008 and in MAN shares in 2007, among others, investments rose by a net 1.6 billion reflecting our investments in new product as well as more efficient Powertrain and new productions facilities.</p>
          <p>Following our normal seasonality pattern, our CapEx ratio stood at 4.9% and is expected to be around 6% by year-end. Without the investment in Scania, our net cash flow is positive. Automotive net liquidity ended the period at &#x20AC;11.8 billion reflecting the Scania share purchase and remained at a high level.</p>
          <p>A quick comment on liquidity and access to the financial market. Refinancing markets were particularly unstable in the third quarter of 2008, the situation that is continuing and impacting all areas of the automotive value chain, including the suppliers and dealers. However, we firmly believe that we can access sufficient liquidity for our financial services arm as the Volkswagen Group benefits from its solid liquidity position and its conservative refinancing policy.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a look now at the financial performance of the different brands. The positive sales development combining with further improvements in our cost efficiency led to a positive development in the operating result of the Volkswagen Passenger Car brands, Audi and Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles. &#x160;koda's earnings dropped by 13.5% to 455 million contrasting with the improvement in revenues which grew by 10.5%. The impact of the strong Czech koruna is proving to be a significant break on performance. The dramatic drop in the Spanish market &#x2013; market was down 22% in the first nine months, is impacting all our brands, none more so than Seat. With sales down 5%, Seat has slipped to a result of a negative &#x20AC;30 million.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, Scania is included here for the first time. To repeat, the numbers shown correspond to the period July 22 to the 3rd of September and include Scania's financial services too; although the FS part is subsequently split out and added to the existing FS activities of the Volkswagen Group at the end of the analysis.</p>
          <p>The preliminary PPA adjustment is included within the "Other" line so that the brand result remains focused on the operating performance. And finally, our Chinese business has continued its excellent progress, both in sales and in earnings, recording a proportional operating profit of 250 million. That's up almost &#x20AC;100 billion on the prior year.</p>
          <p>Now this leads us to our 2008 outlook, which I'm sure remains familiar to you, as it has remained stable since it was first announced at the Annual Results Conference last March. We had an excellent start to the year with strong sales in the first half. In Q3, deliveries to customers were flat as the banking crisis started to bite. With highly volatile markets reflecting consumer uncertainty, Q4 is difficult to predict. However, we remain confident that the tailwind from our good start to the year, together with the support of our new models, will bring us to our full year target.</p>
          <p>That is to say that, thanks to higher sales revenue resulting from the expected increase in unit sales, together with our efficiency and productivity improvement, our operating profit for 2008 will come in above the previous year's figure. The inclusion of Scania from July 22 will increase our reported deliveries and sales further. The consolidation in the full second half, and thereby also in the full year figures, will have a slightly positive earnings impact from the inclusion of our ninth brand.</p>
          <p>With regard to the financial result, as we now consolidate Scania fully, an impact from the removal of the equity consolidation in the third quarter can be already seen. The fourth quarter will suffer a similar loss of benefit to say. However, with volatile market and the impact from derivatives, that's mainly related to commodities and other entries, the financial result remains difficult to predict. The investment in the additional shares in Scania has impacted our net cash flow and liquidity which, we predict, would otherwise show a positive tendency for the year.</p>
          <p>I know you would like me to give some comment on 2009. We have traditionally reserved this for our Annual Press Conference in March but let me give you at least some of our thoughts today. We anticipate that the weak trends we have seen in the third quarter will extend into the fourth quarter and on into 2009. In summary, we believe that the 2009 global car markets will be below 2008.</p>
          <p>Volkswagen will perform better than the market in 2008 and has gained market share and we expect a similar trend in 2009. However, let me be quite clear, considering the uncertainty of the global economy, both now and looking forward, the ongoing difficulties in the financial markets and to try to focus what this means for the automotive sector. One thing is for sure, 2009 will be a very tough year. We will do everything possible, everything necessary to face this in production of the Volkswagen way and we have a lot of new cars in the pipeline such that our model range in 2009 will be the youngest product portfolio ever.</p>
          <p>To sum up, we have often said that the path towards 2018 would not be straight. This is not the time now to panic or for rash, short-term decisions. We continue to work long and hard to make our company stronger. We stand ready for the challenge.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, thank you very much. We will now move to the Q&amp;A session, starting first with the questions of analysts. Can we take the first question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We will take our first question from Mr. Max Warburton from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, yeah, good afternoon everybody. Dr. P&#xF6;tsch I've just, I've got two questions please. The first one is financial. The second is, I guess, more legal and strategic really. The first one, just on gross liquidity in the automotive business, you give the details of this calculation on page 23 of the release, and you show that automotive has 8.3 billion of securities and loans. Could you just help us understand how much of that is securities and how much is loans and who the loans are made to? And related to that, could you just give us your thoughts on potential financing challenges at LeasePlan? I work on the assumption that in that number there's a loan to LeasePlan but could you just talk through your comfort with LeasePlan's financial situation?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is, could you help us understand how a domination agreement in theory would work at Volkswagen? Porsche states that they would seek it if they took their shareholding above 75% of the ordinaries. Could you help us understand how the VW law, as it currently stands, works? Is it possible to get a domination agreement or seek a domination agreement at Volkswagen while the VW law still stands? I think that would be very helpful for all of us. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. So Max has two questions: the first question is about our gross liquidity, if we can give some more information about loans and securities and if we can explain the situation at LeasePlan. Then the second question is about the domination agreement, if such a domination agreement with Porsche would be possible. Thank you, Max.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To the first question on gross liquidity, to see what we pulled in terms of securities and loans, securities stand for 7.1 billion in the stated 8.3 billion for security and loans, which leaves 1.2 for the loan side and that's part of our complete line of roughly &#x20AC;15 billion, which is only used by roughly that amount.</p>
          <p>Then on LeasePlan, to continue on with that; first of all, let me say that it's an excellent company. It's performing extremely well. The business model is fine. It's very clear that LeasePlan, as other frequent issuers, currently are somewhat limited in terms of access to the debt capital markets. But we don't believe that this situation is going to carry on for long and that's why the top priority currently is to provide facilities as necessary to protect that situation. As soon as the markets are back, very clearly LeasePlan, on the basis of its very solid foundation, will continue to finance its business on a standalone basis.</p>
          <p>Then the other question on the domination agreement. I thought it's very clearly positioned in the public &#x2013; as long as the Volkswagen law stays in place, stating that 80% would be necessary or in other words, the blocking minority is stated with 20% and as long &#x2013; of course, purely hypothetically talking &#x2013; Lower Saxony does not dispose of their shareholdings, it would not be possible to enter into a domination agreement without, of course, the support &#x2013; let me put it that way, again to stay on the hypothetical side &#x2013; of Lower Saxony.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, could I just ask a quick follow-up question on that? If that &#x2013; and thanks for the very clear answer. If Porsche, as potentially a 74% shareholder, wanted to access VW's cash via some other form, is it your understanding as a Board member of this company that again it would need to be put to a vote with Lower Saxony to be any way of Porsche getting a distribution of that cash, e.g. a dividend payment to all shareholders would have to be approved and could be vetoed by Lower Saxony, is that the case please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again I thought also that should be very clear and at that point if there is no domination agreement in place it would, of course, need the support by the Supervisory Board of Volkswagen to use any of the cash or any other advantages of Volkswagen. So that is, of course, very difficult if not to say impossible to imagine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then let's have the next question please. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Christian Breitsprecher from Oppenheim. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, it's Christian Breitsprecher from Oppenheim. Firstly, a question on your outlook for 2009. I mean, do I understand your outlook correctly that profits are not probably going to drop at Volkswagen in 2009? And secondly, on LeasePlan, your co-investors in LeasePlan have a put option to basically sell their share of the company to you. Firstly, could you tell us at which price they can do that and secondly, are there any talks or do you see any risk that they might do that in the near future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Christian Breitsprecher has two questions for us. One is if we can give some more information about our outlook for 2009. And the second question is about LeasePlan, if we have any put options or at what price and if we give here an update. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To the first question, as far as the situation 2009 is concerned I only can repeat what I already have said. We will be more specific at our Annual Press Conference in March. And again, as it appears from today's point of view, the situation will most likely be the one that the total market will be below the market we've seen in 2008, and we are confident that in a similar way as 2008 we will be able to beat the total market performance.</p>
          <p>To the second question. As far as LeasePlan is concerned, yes, the co-investors very &#x2013; I would say normally in the situation as the one we are in, do hold put options but we cannot comment on this point on what their thoughts on whether they would ever consider to execute them and at which point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you say anything about the price at which they can put it to you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, unfortunately I cannot comment on the price. That's part of our secrecy commitment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can we have the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, indeed. Our next question comes from Lothar Lubinetzki from MainFirst. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, it's Lothar from MainFirst. Just some questions, one is of course the PPA &#x2013; could you tell us whether the cash flow statement and the depreciation you showed there, whether the PPA is included; and I take you don't want to quantify the PPA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, thank you. Lothar Lubinetzki has one question for us. It refers to the PPA and if we can give some more information, if we can quantify the PPA and if we can give some details about our cash flow statement with regard to the PPA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, the effect coming out of the purchase price accounting is included in the cash flow statements. Of course, only the first step which relates to the effect booked in the third quarter, and the amount is in the neighborhood of 300 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So now let's take the next question, please. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Gregor Claussen from Commerzbank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have two questions if this is okay. The first one is that there were recently statements from other carmakers regarding the Brazilian market, that they expect roughly 15% decline in Q4 year-on-year. Do you share this view or do you have any other expectations and do you have any assumptions for growth in Brazil for the next year? And my second question is regarding the Volkswagen law again and the blocking minority of Lower Saxony. As far as I know, there will be a hearing in front of the District Court, Hanover on the 6th of November, but sooner or later this will end up in front of the European Court of Justice. Would you agree with me if I say that this can take a very, very long time, even longer than 2009? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Mr. Claussen has two questions for us. One is about Brazil, which development do we expect in Brazil in the fourth quarter and if we can give an outlook for 2009. The second question is again about the VW law and what do we expect, how long does that probably take the whole legal dispute? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to refer to the first question; we have seen a slowing down of the growth rate in the Brazilian market. We have not seen that the Brazilian market went below last year's level, so just to look at the numbers here. While in the first two quarters or in the first half year, the Brazilian market was up by some 25% above last year, it slowed down in the third quarter with still a growth rate of 18%. And we expect maybe a further slowing down but still a growth rate in the market, which will lead to a total market this year in Brazil which will still be ahead, by 20% ahead of last year. Taking into consideration the slowing down of the Brazilian market, the forecast certainly for next year is &#x2013; again, it's difficult, it's crystal ball, but we can expect that the total market will be maybe at the same level of this year, maybe slightly below but that is crystal ball talk, but again we have seen still growth rates this year in Brazil, yes, slowing down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To the second questions referring to the Volkswagen law again, let me say this again very clearly &#x2013; I do not want to speculate on which positions the parties involved might take or might not take. So the only comment I can give at this point is that it's not to be ruled out that the whole thing might end up again at a European Court and these processes, of course, take their time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we take the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, indeed. Our next question comes from Philippe Houchois from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. First question is I'd like to know, can you tell us what has caused a positive swing in the net other operating items in your P&amp;L? It's always a line that we have difficulty understanding. So can you explain what was the swing and if we can assume that would continue in Q4? And the other question I have was regarding some disclosure you made in your annual report regarding some credit lines that have been given to you, 12.5 billion and you used 10 billion. There was a comment about those lines could be unilaterally canceled by the banks that granted them in case of is a change of control. Could you confirm that is still valid or if anything has changed regarding either the ability of banks to cancel those lines or the amount of those credit lines that you disclosed at the '07 account? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Philippe would like to have some more information about our other operating income. If you can give some more details here about the positive swing? And the second question is with regard to our credit lines if there is a change of control clause included? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To the first question on other operating income, the main effect there is coming from our currency hedges. And while, of course, as far as revenue is concerned, we have the full effect coming out of currency fluctuations, we see the positive impact of our currency hedges in our other operating result. And secondly, yes, of course, in a significant part of our credit line there is a change of control clause included. That's due to the steps Porsche has taken. We are currently negotiating with our banks in regard to that clause, but let me remind you that this is a pure backup facility. It's not drawn at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Let's take the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Indeed. Our next question comes from Thierry Huon from Exane BNP Paribas. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I've got a question about your cash flow statement. Could you explain us why the depreciation went down during the three quarters? And I've got another questions about your production schedule for Q4. Do you intend to reduce your production during this quarter, of course, except the Golf which has just started?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much. Thierry has two questions for us today. So the first question relates to the cash flow statement and why the depreciation went down in the third quarter. The second question is about our production schedule for the fourth quarter of 2008, if we have any plans to reduce our production. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To the first question I could state ironically, first of all, unfortunately it's not possible to write off something a couple of times. And if you refer to, for example, the balance sheet at the end of 2007 compared with 2006, you will see that our fixed assets actually moved downwards and that's clearly the effect coming from our significant investment discipline in the years 2005, 6 and 7, just to refer to the most important period. So, again as the basis is low it results in a reduction of depreciation.</p>
          <p>And as far as the second question is concerned, the production schedule, it's very clear that Volkswagen is, by the fact that we held up reasonably well in more difficult circumstances, that we also adapt month by month our future production plans to what is needed in the markets as far as the development of demand. And therefore, of course, we have numerous measures in our pockets which we can use if the situation is improving but there is no final decision taken so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's clear, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Michael Punzet from DZ Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Michael Punzet, DZ Bank. I have one question regarding your tax rate. Could you please explain what happened in you third quarter and what we could assume for the full year '08? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Mr. Punzet has a question about our tax rate in the third quarter and if we could give an outlook for the full year 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the main impact, first of all, on the tax rate is, of course, the new tax regime in Germany. That has a significant effect and that's why the tax rate for the full year will be at and around 30%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Adam Hull from Execution Limited. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon everyone. I had three questions, if I may. Firstly, in your outlook statement you've used the term 'further improvements in your liquidity position.' I just wanted to be clear are you just referring to, sorry, referring to the end of 2008? Is this relative to the 11.8 billion in Q3 or the 13.9 at the end of '07? And then second, just to be clear on Audi, the 9% margin in Q3. Were there any specific one-off items on provisions or any other accounting elements there, because the Audi report is rather thin on the Q3?</p>
          <p>And then finally on CapEx, you talk about the 6% guidance but you've also historically given us some absolute numbers. I think you talked about 20.9 billion of investments in '08 out to 2010. So, just to be clear, should we be using rather more the 6% or the 20.9 and which is more important and what kind of projects might you be looking to delay? I think you've mentioned that in the past. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Adam. Adam has three questions for us. One &#x2013; the first question is about our outlook for 2008, if we can give some more information about what we expect with regard to liquidity. The second question is about Audi and if we can give some more details about the margin development and if we did any provisions. And the last question is relating to our CapEx ratio, what does that mean in absolute numbers? What do we do or do we delay some projects this year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the first question, our statement is referring to the development from 2007 towards the end of 2008. And we made it very clear that we are referring to an improvement before the purchase price for Scania is considered. So, otherwise this would not be a real apples and apples comparison. Secondly, there are no significant provisions or one-offs in the Audi segment for the third quarter.</p>
          <p>And on the CapEx side, it's always good to refer to the 6% level for the simple reason that the other number you were mentioning is covering a number of years. It is pretty much in line, by the way, with slightly more than 6%, so it's not too far away from our target number. And in this respect I've got to say that if we're able to improve against the 6% level, it's not related to the point that we would have postponed anything. It's clear that our people in the purchasing departments do a fantastic job in renegotiating investments whenever we have to take significant decisions on this. Of course, there are little changes in terms of the timetable also but the major part is that, on the basis of our longer-term plans, we've pulled in numbers which are the best guess or best estimates we have but this is not to say that we are to spend all of that money. So, it's &#x2013; the best thing is to refer to the 6%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just thinking, if I could just follow up, are there any sort of conditions, if things stay very difficult, would you consider delaying even sort of CapEx programs in emerging markets? I thought you'd &#x2013; there were some release that suggested that you were considering &#x2013; we're talking really I guess about 2010 plans?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we made it very clear that in a similar way as we adapt as far as our production schedule is concerned to keep our capital lockup on a reasonable basis, we also are trying to identify and reevaluate on which investments are absolutely necessary. In that respect, it's clear in the most actual situation that capacity-related investments are, in a few cases, to be reduced, postponed, or whatsoever, and certainly there could also be some structural investments which are not directly related to our key products where we could take a different decision as we have taken in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Jochen Gehrke from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Basically I have two questions. Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, could you clarify on Scania, once again on the consolidation effects, what net of purchase price that you paid was the impact on your net liquidity? And secondly, on the same thing here on working capital? And my second question relates to your share price. Unarguably most people would say your share prices are at a very elevated level. You've been briefly the biggest company of the world today -- this week. You have authorized capital. What makes you think that you're not raising, trying to capture this potential for this potentially short period of time and use authorized capital to raise equity? Your major shareholder has created a situation in which share supply is apparently very tight. Couldn't this help you, in the long run, to also achieve some of your strategic goals with takeovers such as MAN and also some of your competitors, which are trading at very low shares? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Jochen Gehrke has two questions for us. He would like to know if we can give some more information about the impact of Scania on net liquidity, on working capital and what we paid for Scania. And the second question is about the development of our share price, actually if we can imagine or if we are considering to use the authorized capital to raise equity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let's get started with Scania, first of all. And as we said, there is a number stated, first of all, to talk about operative profit for the third quarter, and there is an effect coming out of the purchase price accounting. The net effect is a double-digit number. In other words, without Scania, purely talking about the third quarter, our operating profit would have been better, but I also said that throughout the year if you look at the full &#x2013; half year period, this is going to change and this going to turn into a slight double-digit profit number.</p>
          <p>Now the purchase price of the last portion of Scania shares was around &#x20AC;2.8 billion and it's clear that the respective goodwill of that part and the former part was put into the purchase price allocation and that results, of course, in depreciations which as I also pointed out are clearly relatively heavier at the beginning of the depreciation period. That's all I can say at this point.</p>
          <p>To the other question as far as share price development is concerned you know that I will not comment on the share price development. And thank you for the hint but I can say that there are no plans to create additional equity at Volkswagen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Let's have the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Horst Schneider from HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Horst Schneider from HSBC, good afternoon. I have got three questions, if I may. Firstly, it's about potential impact of tax exemptions here in Germany. We heard that for the first time this morning in the German press that maybe the German government will put subsidies in place here for cars having Euro 4, Euro 5 or Euro 6 compliant cars on the street. So, I would be interested in your view on that. Will that lead to any major buying resistance in Q4 2008 in Germany? What will be the potential demand effect maybe in 2009? And then maybe, yeah, to which extent you might be affected from that and how many percent of your fleet is already running, for example, on Euro 5 and Euro 6?</p>
          <p>Then the second question I have is on &#x160;koda. Would be interested to get your opinion if the situation at &#x160;koda will also continue like that in the fourth quarter as we have seen it in the third quarter? So would be interested if you see a major &#x2013; if you see maybe a volume upturn and if that lead also to a margin recovery? And then the third question that I have is on &#x2013; is how many Volkswagen ordinary shares are held by employees and management at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. We have three questions now from Horst Schneider. The first question is about the proposal of the German government with regard to a new tax system. And the second question is about the performance of &#x160;koda in the fourth quarter, if we can give here some more information. And the last question is about the ordinary shares held by employees and management of Volkswagen. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I will respond to the first question, the plans of the German government to change the taxation system. We can only welcome that the German government discusses this and we would even more welcome that there is a speedy decision on that because the uncertainty contributed certainly also to the uncertainty in the German car market, which was flat over the last 2-3 years. And we can expect that there will then return some certainty as far as our customers are concerned in favor of the CO2-related taxation. We know that we do have this tax regime introduced in 15 different European countries by now and it helped to sort of support stability of demand, yes, while at the same time it also introduced a downsizing of the demand going for smaller cars.</p>
          <p>And that relates, that takes me to the second part of the question, which part of the fleet of our Volkswagen and the Group's brands fleet is meeting Euro 5 standards? The simple answer is all of our cars meet the Euro 5 standards. So, from that point of view and also from our product portfolio, going for smaller cars, and having, as I mentioned before, 90 models that meet the 140 CO2 gram level, we can only welcome any move of any government, and especially here in Germany, going for CO2-related tax and in favor of fuel consumption cars that are going towards the 140, 120 CO2 level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then I can continue on with the question on &#x160;koda. First of all, you state that in operative meanings &#x160;koda is an excellent company, high level of productivity. The big problem we have is the currency development of the Czech koruna and while the &#x2013; one of the key reasons obviously is a question over policy which is driving the exchange rate in levels which are, in our view, not substantiated, is creating a significant issue on the whole automotive value-added chain. There are, in the meantime, a number of suppliers running into trouble and for &#x160;koda it means not only that the cost position is losing competitiveness. It also means that, of course, that competitors delivering and shipping cost from other areas do have some competitive advantages. And that's why it's very difficult to predict in which direction this is going to go. We saw a slight correction of the currency but one thing is very clear. Once we end up with a more reasonable Czech koruna, &#x160;koda will be back to former profit levels. On the next question, the number of shares held by Volkswagen employees, we've got to say there are no statistics available. We don't know how many shares are held by our employees.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, an add-on question, just relating to the tax exemptions in Germany. Let us know about the buying resistance in, eventually in Q4 2008?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, as there is no decision actually we don't see any impact on Q4. It could happen that with an early decision that there may be some sort of delays in buying cars this year but that's only Q4 and more or less Q4 in our case is booked out. So we would not see any effect on our volume development this year but we would see a positive development, a positive impact on our sales next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am really sorry but due to the limited period of time I would like to ask you to raise one question only. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Adam Jonas from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good evening. A couple of questions or just one question, sorry, on residual values. Many of your competitors have had to make some adjustments as the used car market has come under pressure. Presumably you're not completely immune to this. Yet you have not yet taken a charge. Can you explain to us then where you do recognize falling residuals or have you just provisioned enough and it's not a problem at all, you feel no need to do it or just generally tell us kind of how you stand on that metric, please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you very much, Adam for that one question only. So it's about our residual value and which development we see here. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, we got to say that we also recognize some pressure on residuals. While we feel, compared with other players, somewhat better protected against this because we have &#x2013; the majority of our cars which are in the market are, for example, very fuel efficient cars, which in a few areas had led to the point that our residuals were developing much more stable compared with other car segments. Nevertheless, there was the necessity to step-up our provisions somewhat but as we are executing, since many years, a very conservative policy, it's been in relative terms digestible. And as I've explained a couple of times here also &#x2013; as we revise our provisions each month with most recent statistics coming in from third-party institutions, we feel we are absolutely prepared and protected there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Albrecht Denninghoff from BHF. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. I would like to come back to these Scania consolidation issues. Is it correct if I want to calculate the comparable net liquidity or net debt situation that I take the Group numbers out of the cash flow statement and I subtract the industrial equipment equivalent sales figures from the Scania reporting and translate this to euro? Or is there any other allocation or valuation effect? Yes, that would be the main question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Albrecht Denninghoff, I guess we can explain that question afterwards. It's quite easy. We will support you &#x2013; we will provide you with the Q3 report of Scania and I guess we don't have to discuss that right now here. Thank you. Let's have the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Arndt Ellinghorst from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks a lot and good afternoon everybody. Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, thanks a lot for clarifying the situation on domination and cash transfer. I think that was very helpful for all of us. And just a follow-up on the Volkswagen Law, as far as I understand it, talk about the Volkswagen Law and the Volkswagen Articles of Association. And may be could you share your thoughts on how this could technically be removed in case the European Court of Justice says it's illegal? And then just a yes or no question really, did Volkswagen sell any put options on Volkswagen shares? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we have one question again about the VW Law and the Articles of Association, if we can give here some more information even, we discussed that already.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it should be clear that as far as the blocking minority is concerned, there are similar barriers built on, first of all, by the Volkswagen Law and then also by the Articles of Association. I would not like to move too much into the technicalities because it would create the understanding that we are heavily working on anything there. And, in fact, this is not at all the case, because I think we have a clear cut situation, first of all, and until we are getting out- a different situation with regards to Volkswagen Laws, it doesn't really make sense to deal with any other issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we take the.....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, sorry, just on the put options. Did Volkswagen sell any put options on Volkswagen ordinary shares?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we did not sell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So now finally, we take the last question of analysts please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Georges Dieng from Natixis Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, good afternoon to everyone. I have a question following up the issue of market trends for 2009 and how you could react to the downturn. I was wondering if you could elaborate on the flexibility tools that you have and how you could withstand a market drop without having maybe to cut workforce quite sharply, if you could maybe expand a little bit on that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, thank you. Georges would like to have some more information about the market development in 2009 and if we see a downturn, which kind of flexibility tools do we have. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think the question was fundamentally related to our measures which we could potentially take and, in fact, there are a number of measures which potentially could be applied. First of all, I should say that still in a number of areas in our plants we're working overtime. We're also working special shifts and that consequently leads to the point as our time accounts as we would say are completely full. First thing would be that we would start potentially to use up time accounts, of course, after reducing anyway working overtime. Then we have a number of temporary workers where we have a decent degree of flexibility. So this is to say that there is a substantial flexibility available, which could be used and maybe I should say also that our priority is, of course, to identify the kind of measures which do not deteriorate in any extent our way to improve productivity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much. Now let's hear what the journalists would like to know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have our first question from the media from Christiaan Hetzner from Reuters News Agency. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Thank you very much. Just two questions really quickly. First of all, I'd like to just get a comment about whether management expressly supports or does not support a Porsche domination agreement? Secondly, you had talked about the outlook for 2009. Fiat had been a little bit more specific about what they sort of see coming. Could you give us perhaps also along their lines a worst case scenario about where you see things developing in 2009, both for the global markets as well as for VW? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Christiaan has two questions for us, if the Board of Management supports the intention of Porsche with regard to a domination agreement and if we can give some more information about 2009. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So to the first question regarding the domination agreement, this is clearly not something on the agenda of the Board of Management because it clearly relates to the sphere of shareholders. The second question, with regard to 2009, we don't feel at this point in time at least, that it's making a lot of sense to talk about worst case or best case scenarios. We have still a pretty strong order book. That's what we are working through. And as we, a couple of times mentioned, here it's very clear that it's appropriate to prepare a set of measures to deal with situations, which could be more difficult than the most recent situation, of course. But it's very clear that we have a decent amount of flexibility in this company with the measures I was already mentioning and that's the policy. And we will have, of course, after the one and the other milestone coming up, we have to identify the most &#x2013; then the actual situation and take the respective decisions. Again, clearly the framework conditions are worse than a few months ago but we don't feel it's the right time to panic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could just ask a follow-up question. I would imagine that it would be useful to talk to Lower Saxony about whether or not they support a domination agreement? I mean &#x2013; I take it you're not pressing Lower Saxony to support, to also vote in favor or something like that. In other words, at the moment the Board is not doing anything to help Porsche's cause for such an agreement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can only repeat what I already said. The Management Board is of the opinion that this is clearly an issue in the sphere of the shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Please take the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Kristina Spiller from Financial Times. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I'd like to know regarding Seat, do you plan or do Volkswagen plan any additional measures to protect Seat for the downturn, do you expect more costs cut, for instance? And how do you think on the whole will the company develop in the future? And the second question would be regarding markets like Latin America, Asia and Eastern Europe. I like to know what are you going to do if &#x2013; what happens &#x2013; we've seen already the markets are not growing that strong as they have done in the past. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, we had some problems to understand you correctly. So, I guess the first question was about Seat, if we take other measures due to the downturn of the Spanish market. And the second question was I guess about different &#x2013; the development of different markets in '09. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First question on Seat and I already made a statement in my first comment. It's very clear that Seat is heavily affected by the market development in Spain. And while we can say that the average for the first nine months was a negative 22%, in fact, a few of the last months the market dropped by up to 40%. So, in that sense it's, I think, very obvious that there must be a substantial effect on sales. So that's one thing.</p>
          <p>The other thing is that we started introducing new cars with the Seat Ibiza and we are very pleased to learn that the car is received extremely well by all the markets. Of course, the performance in other markets than Spain is substantially better as the market in Spain currently is not following any normal pattern of any market. So, this is only to say that we are consequently executing the strategy which we rolled out for the Seat about two years ago and we will continue on with this.</p>
          <p>As far as the production volume is concerned, it's very clear that we had to adapt to the market situation, but for Seat the same holds true as for other places. We've invested incredible amounts into a talented workforce. Excellent people there and that's why we are defending the existence of our workforces as much as possible. And for the moment, we feel that there is a good chance that we can continue on with this.</p>
          <p>In that sense it's very clear, not only related to volume development, it's necessary that in situations like the one at Seat, we have to adapt other plans also as far as investments are concerned. And, of course, we have to make measures to improve also the cost situation. But this is not an exceptional position Seat is in, it's certainly something which holds true for other areas also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as far as the second question is concerned, the outlook or performance of &#x2013; I think you referred to the emerging markets. Yes, we have seen the emerging markets with high growth rates and I've mentioned earlier Brazil and we have also seen that there is a slowing down of the growth rates, but still all these markets, the emerging markets, will see at the end of this year, cumulatively rather high growth rates. Now with the downturn it is, again, difficult to forecast what's going to happen next year, but even if it's &#x2013; sort of slows further down the level that these emerging markets have achieved by now as far as sales volume is concerned and look at, for instance, the Russian market, where the Russian market ends up this year at 2.8 or 2.9 million cars and the sales rate has slowed down in third and fourth quarter as well, still the Russian market will stay at 2.8, 2.9 million next year. We may have had higher expectations, but we have never seen the Russian market at a level of 2.8, 2.9 million. And we will continue exploiting this market and other markets as well with even higher market shares based on either the start of production in these markets next year or based on the, as mentioned before, on the very young product portfolio that we do have. So, we do see a further chance for us when it comes to market positions while even if the emerging markets are sort of coming to a standstill, it's a standstill at high level, at high volumes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Jan Schwartz from Reuters. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Only one question please. Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, you said that and it just &#x2013; I think it was in the beginning of your speech that your &#x2013; there's no final decision yet taken on a possible production cut. So you're considering on this issue but what about Christmas holidays, are you discussing to extend holidays during this time, and when you are &#x2013; if you are, then for which time please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's &#x2013; when you are referring to the holiday period around Christmas, yeah, first of all, I should say that it's a very traditional approach to close down the plants during the real Christmas holidays, that that's very normal. And, of course, under the given circumstances, we are evaluating on whether it's recommendable to add on the one and the other day to these holidays. Again, there is no final decision taken. We still have a certain window to take that decision and the number of days might be between two and four days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. So we have time for the last question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our last question comes from Edward Taylor from Wall Street Journal. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, I have a quick question. On September 29, Porsche submitted a mandatory offer for Audi shares and Volkswagen said that it would not accept this bid. Could you give us some color as to why, given that Porsche has said they don't want to carve Audi out of <mark type="inaudible" /> Volkswagen decided not to accept this bid, and could there be any conditions for a change in this view?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, honestly speaking, we thought that what we are doing is just on what more or less everybody should expect because Volkswagen for a reason we believe thinks that Audi is the very much core of the Volkswagen Group and I don't have to say that we are linked in many areas. I think both Audi is depending on Volkswagen with a number of platforms. Volkswagen is taking advantage of some high-tech engines of Audi to just give a few examples. And from that end, it simply was never an item on the agenda to dispose of our Audi shares. And that's why we entered into an agreement with Porsche where we committed not to sell our shares and Porsche committed to give us a call option, so we can, if any shares end up with Porsche, we can call them and have everything, as far as Audi is concerned, in Volkswagen's pocket. It's a completely consensual situation between Porsche and everybody at Volkswagen that this is the right way to go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I would like to come to an end. Thank you very much for taking part in our conference call. Good bye from here in Wolfsburg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That will conclude today's conference call. Thank you for your participation ladies and gentlemen. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>