<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1172450" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1011</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch, Member of the Board of Management, Finance and Controlling</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Detlef Wittig, Executive Vice President, Group Sales and Marketing</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Christine Ritz, Group Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jochen Gehrke</participant>
      <participant id="5">Christine Ritz</participant>
      <participant id="6">Detlef Wittig</participant>
      <participant id="7">Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch</participant>
      <participant id="8">Albrecht Denninghoff</participant>
      <participant id="9">John Lawson</participant>
      <participant id="10">Christian Breitsprecher</participant>
      <participant id="11">Adam Jonas</participant>
      <participant id="12">Frank Biller</participant>
      <participant id="13">John Buckland</participant>
      <participant id="14">Christoph Rauwald</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Volkswagen Conference Call for the first six Months of 2008. I'm joined today by Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch, Member of the Board of Management, Volkswagen AG responsible for Finance and Controlling; and by Detlef Wittig, Executive Vice President, Volkswagen AG, responsible for Group Sales and Marketing.</p>
          <p>As usual, you can also follow the webcast and download the chart from our website www.volkswagenag.com/ir. Questions can be sent by e-mail or called in. Before we start, I would like to mention that our after the speech of Mr. P&#xF6;tsch and Mr. Wittig, we will first respond to the questions of analysts and later answer those of journalists.</p>
          <p>I would now like to ask Mr. P&#xF6;tsch to give a few comments on the highlights of the first half of 2008 before Mr. Wittig goes into detail of the deliveries to customer. Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot ladies and gentlemen, also a warm welcome from my side to this conference call. I'm very pleased to be here today to discuss our continued good performance. As I last spoke to you in April, global economic trends have certainly become more of a concern. I am therefore particularly delighted to announce that not only have our sales outperformed market, but we were able translate these into a strong improvement our operating result.</p>
          <p>Our operating profit increased significantly by 21.8%, &#x20AC;3.4 billion in the first half of 2008. Consolidated pre-tax profit also increased strongly by 25.5%, to &#x20AC;3.8 billion. Despite the challenges of higher raw material and energy costs, we have continued reduce our product cost. First half, our CapEx ratio lies at 4.3%, continued to invest in our new models, Powertrain as well as new facilities in Russia and India, our CapEx will rise up to 6% this year.</p>
          <p>Good sales performance and profit delivered thus far in 2008 and our expectations for the second half has given us confidence, reaffirm our goal of improved sales and profitability 2008.</p>
          <p>I will give you a few more details on our financial performance later on. Let me now hand over to Wittig who will give you an overview our positive sales development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and welcome also from my side ladies and gentlemen. On the first chart I can show you left column the Volkswagen Group sales results which is as far as deliveries to customers are concerned, new sales record for us with an increased rate of 5.8% against last year were now up 3.26 million vehicles. Likewise during the same period the world car market increased by only 1%, so that simply results in gaining market share on our side.</p>
          <p>Now looking at the individual brands of the Group from left to right. First, the Volkswagen Passenger Cars also a new record, sales record. Equally &#x2013; equal to the performance of the total Group, an increased rate of 5.8% up to 1.9 million cars. And this growth from the Volkswagen brand cycle is certainly driven by our results in China, in Russia, Brazil and also a positive development in the German market.</p>
          <p>Audi Sales were up by 1.4% up to 516,000 cars, the best first half year in Audi's history. That was certainly driven by the new A4 and the new A5.</p>
          <p>&#x160;koda continued it's very positive trend with a further, further strong plus of 17.9%, up till now 367,000 units and highlights as far as this quarter performance is concerned certainly the market entry in China. And an 80% increase in Russia, up to 24,000 units in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>SEAT, however suffered a decline of 7.5%. But taking into account the very difficult Spanish market that was down by 17% in the first half year and also the Italian market, and the Audi Ibiza in the run-up phase, this is from our point of view still a reasonably good performance. We will see more then from SEAT in the second half.</p>
          <p>Bentley was down 16.5% and that compares with the first half year of 2007, where we saw high demand therefore the launch of the Bentley GT. We expect also a more balanced demand then for Bentley.</p>
          <p>Our Commercial Vehicles continued had a excellent development in the first half year with deliveries to customers increasing by 12.9%, up to 264,000 units, all model lines there contributed to the success also in all areas in the world.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the deliveries to customers by area, by market area. This chart shows the two columns to your right, steep increase rates for the South American market 12.4% and Asia-Pacific 20.00 -- 21.5%. So those areas were driving our sales volume.</p>
          <p>Europe now starting from left, in Europe our deliveries increased to 1.96 million units, up to 1.7%, but we had to separate a little bit the European areas into Western Europe and Central and Eastern Europe. As far as Western Europe is concerned, we saw a decline &#x2013; a slight decline of our sales by minus of 1.2% because of the very weak total markets in Italy and Spain. And in contrast, we had a good sales performance in Germany and the UK.</p>
          <p>Germany in our domestic market we reached a record market share of 32.7%. The contrast program shown in Central and Eastern Europe where we saw an increase of deliveries by 18.7% and this is certainly driven by the two markets, Russia where we increased our sales by 63% and Ukraine.</p>
          <p>Then into North America, though we had a decrease of 3.8% as compared with last year's period, therein is the United States where we almost flattened our sales volume which is a different trend comparing version in the United States with the Volkswagen brand however showing a remarkable &#x2013; a slight increase of close to one where we saw a decline because of market situation there.</p>
          <p>Now turning North America, positive trend here is driven by Brazil and Argentina. Brazil was up &#x2013; our sales in Brazil were up by 22% and in Argentina <mark type="audio gap" />. However, hidden in these figures is South Africa where we saw a decline &#x2013; a drastic fall of the total market by some 20% of our sales <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Very favorable situation Asia-Pacific, we saw our sales practically going up by another 21% and this is due to strong growth that we enjoyed and still enjoy in China with 23% and also in India where we started now first steps Volkswagen in the market after Skoda &#x2013; growth rate there of 70% <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Now would like to show you a comparison of the development of the world car market, the total world market by area and comparing it with our sales performance in these respective area. You can see up there North America, where we saw as car market, the total market declining in the first half year by minus 8.5%. Although we did much better, yes, we saw a decline of our sales by minus 3.8%, but in relation to the total market then that shows that we are gaining strength and that we are gaining market share.</p>
          <p>Western Europe, the total market also went down by 2.6%. We did better, yes, we saw a minus 1% and at the same time the market share increased for the Group &#x2013; for our Group in Western Europe.</p>
          <p>Then turning toward the more dynamic markets, the famous BRIC markets, Eastern Europe and Russia in there. The car market very dynamic total market went up by 30%, we went up by 35% in Russia as I mentioned or even by 63%.</p>
          <p>South America also dynamic, a very dynamic the car market there, plus 16% for the car market but plus 18% for us. And there in is Brazil with 22% increase of sales. So we are gaining market share in South America. Asia-Pacific, that includes China, India and Japan, certainly the market went up by 10.5%. So it's not that dynamic anymore but still growing. We had the chance of gaining 21% more than last year, so we make &#x2013; we increase our penetration in the Asia-Pacific area.</p>
          <p>So we gain market share, our world market share actually as we can count it went up close to 10% -- 9.9%. So we are gaining -- we are getting closer to our --</p>
          <p>Turning to a few highlights on new models for our various brands. First of all, Volkswagen Scirocco shown here, had an excellent reaction from journalists and dealers since the first showing at the Geneva Motor Show. The Scirocco was accepted as the affordable dream car combines exciting expressive design and pure enjoyment of drive. And we will launch the car this year local in the markets here in Europe, end of August.</p>
          <p>The positive volume effects for the Volkswagen brands resulted also from the <mark type="inaudible" /> North America and in China, and the Sagitar, Bora base.</p>
          <p>Tiguan &#x2013; again mentioning the Tiguan with almost 50,000 deliveries first half year for the very good performance. We are looking forward now to introducing the Passat CC in June and the Golf &#x2013; and the new Golf generation end of October.</p>
          <p>Now turning to Audi. As mentioned before, Audi reported the best first half year in its history. Success is certainly the result of the renovation of the model lineup and the enlargement of the product portfolio. And the Audi A4 Avant shown here picture, has enjoyed great success. Matching our customer's requirements, Audi design oriented stationary. The A4 sedan introduced at the end of last year already performed very strongly with sales going up 30%.</p>
          <p>Equally successful was the A4, A5 Coup&#xE9; of which we have delivered almost 27 <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>&#x160;koda, the &#x160;koda brand continued the success during the first half year and I've mentioned the 17.9% increase rate already, the picture here shows the new Superb. The Superb was introduced last month on the European markets and was certainly a contributor to the ongoing success of the brand, the picture here shows the intelligent Twindoor concept for the rear hatch allowing easy access to the huge trunk compartment.</p>
          <p>China has started production of the Fabia in the second half of last year, pushed the deliveries for the first half year 2008 up to 33,000 cars and that was major push also for the sales volume of the &#x160;koda worldwide. And then we will start in the second half year in October, second model for &#x160;koda.</p>
          <p>Now SEAT. As mentioned before, we had a minus of 7.5% but that is really due to the very weak home markets Spain and also the weak total market in Italy and the run-out of the Audi Ibiza. This chart here shows the new Ibiza. The new Ibiza went on sale in May and we will compliment the range to the Coupe 3.0 version in July. We'll see the new design here what we call the aero design, sporty and innovative car, full of character, high precession and quality and we expect turnaround certainly for the Ibiza, for SEAT, and to start a new chapter in quality and in profitability for the brand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Wittig. Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, can you take us through the financials please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes of course I can. And let's get started with the sales revenues. Sales revenue which as you know excludes our Chinese joint ventures which we report within the equity results, in financial results increased by 3% or 1.6 &#x2013; rose to &#x20AC;56.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Volume growth generated a positive 2.2 billion. Pricing added a further 0.5. While mix currency, that's mainly the U.S. dollar and British pound reduced overall growth. Financial services added a further &#x20AC;0.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Now let me now turn to operating profit. Price, mix and volume contributed a positive &#x20AC;0.5 billion. We had a negative impact after hedging of &#x20AC;0.4 billion from currencies and it's mainly the U.S. dollar and British pound.</p>
          <p>Despite the headwinds of further increases in quality prices, our continued efforts move to cost of our vehicles resulted in the saving of &#x20AC;0.5 billion in product costs. Fixed cost <mark type="inaudible" />(16;37) made stable while lower depreciation moves by capital efficiency of the last year's offset higher cost related expansion revenue of <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Financial services continues to weather the storm in financial markets and despite higher funding cost remains slightly ahead of last year's first half earnings.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to cash flow. In the automotive division cash flow from operating activities was &#x20AC;5.1 billion. Cash flow from investing activities stood at 2.8 billion, excluding our investment in MIM, 2007 among others, investments rose by 653 million reflecting our investment in power train products and new facilities.</p>
          <p>As we commented in first quarter, earlier years we have taken significant steps to achieve the sustainable improvement in our working capital. Whilst we continue to maintain a firm hand on purse strings, such an improvement cannot be repeated each year.</p>
          <p>In addition, our success in increasing sales also leads to higher inventory as we insure our network has sufficient supply. Following our normal seasonality pattern, our CapEx ratio at 4.3% is expected to climb towards 6%..</p>
          <p>Cash flow from operating activities exceeds our investments by &#x20AC;2.3 billion, contributing to further increase automotive debt liquidity which ended the period at &#x20AC;15.1 billion, 1.6 billion over our 2007 year-end ratio.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a look at financial performance of the different brands. Positive sales development binding with further improvements in our cost efficiency, led to strong improvement in the operating result of Volkswagen Passenger Car brand, Audi and Volkswagen Commercial Vehicle. &#x160;koda's earnings increased by 7%, 381 million underperforming to growth of 11.7% sales due to the impact of the strong Czech crown. With new EBITDA, shared renewal of its product portfolio is emerging, however faced with dramatic drop in the Spanish market, faces the stiff near term challenge. Ability to remain in the black, recording 2 million for the first half is testament to the hard work of the entire sales team.</p>
          <p>Finally, our Chinese business has continued its excellent progress both in sales and in earnings, recording a proportional operating profit of &#x20AC;184 million, more than double the performance of the first half 2007.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we noted a number of you on the call today are concerned about the outlook for the global economy and to auto sector. I believe the Volkswagen Group is well positioned for the current economic climate. Both Mr. Wittig and myself will now take a few moments of your time to outline the challenges we see and strategies as adopted that will ensure we can conquer them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well when I look at the external challenges and the chart with the first three challenges here, global demand slowing, engine consumer priorities and ignition regulations. Certainly clear for all of us that the global economy is slowing down from the strong growth last couple of --</p>
          <p>But I would like to underline, we still see growth across our global sales in 2008 and beyond. But as I mentioned earlier with a regard to our sales performance so far in 2008, we cannot see a clear split between the so-called developed markets and the emerging market. If you sort of add up the volume increase of the first half year, that certainly comes from the emerging markets and not from the developed market where we are going into.</p>
          <p>Secondly, the surge in the oil price, its volatility may lead new car buyers to consider more economical smaller cars and or smaller engine. We can clearly see this strength not only in the U.S. market but also in Europe. And there is concern for the environment. Yes, leading on the other hand to a wide range in Europe of 15 different national taxation regimes analyzing CO2 emissions and this diverse push to emission regulations in Europe is certainly a further burden impacting customer choices.</p>
          <p>If uncertainty as to what the different national takes will look like is perhaps the most <mark type="inaudible" /> occupation. There are not only challenges but there are also opportunities and as far as emissions are concerned in consumption, fuel consumption is concerned; we certainly worked early on these challenges with solutions and maybe too early ahead of their time. The aluminum Audi A2, and the 3.0-liter Lupo. I guess we have confidence in developing.</p>
          <p>Our modern diesel engines today, technologically leading TSI gas engines in our current BlueMotion range of cars for the Volkswagen brand and similar ranges, equal ranges for all our brands have built on this. We offer customers a range of class leading fuel efficient engines without compromising comfort. Combined with our DSG gearbox, we offer excellent <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>I have already mentioned the BRIC market. Our push into the markets of India and Russia, for instance, our sales are growing at an exceptionally fast pace, ahead of the opening of our new factories in <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Our leading positions in China and in Brazil will be a market leader, allows us to profitably tap the enormous growth taken.</p>
          <p>Also we transfer the lessons learned from our success to the newer markets will allow us to consolidate our <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>I would also like to underline the contribution of our financial services. Financing, the second question when buying a new car. I am delighted that we have such an excellent company supporting our business, fantastic range of product.</p>
          <p>So summarizing challenges and opportunities, yes I'm of course concerned with the global economic trends passing their shadow on a number of car markets in the world but I believe we have the right products, we have the right technology, we are all -- we are well supported by our financial services colleagues. Now our brands are trusted as high quality innovative brands by our customers <mark type="inaudible" />. We are sure we can ride out the storm and we will continue to delight ever more customer &#x2013; our products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So allow me now to focus on some of the other challenges. You are all familiar with the strong euro and the unprecedented weakness of the U.S. dollar not only is this a concern for our U.S. business but for all our U.S. dollar denominated <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Newspapers are full of stories surrounding the price of steel and oil based commodities and rising interest rates, very turbulent market I think not only on the customer side but clearly impact the cost of funds for our industrial and financial service activities. So how we position?</p>
          <p>We have announced our plans to open a factory in the U.S. in 2011, this will complement our assembly and powertrain activities Mexico, buying with exports to other markets will substantially depress, balance our U.S. dollar exposure. Short-term, we have substantial hedging in place will provide good protection and will help smooth exchange rate impact.</p>
          <p>Hedging on commodities will provide some help, too. Our colleagues in purchasing our working spread outs together with our engineers to reduce our costs yet further from the &#x20AC;0.5 billion I announced earlier. Our new initiative for the tool kit developed from Audi at the future of their tool box for transversal engines for Volkswagen other brands will provide further constant leap our cost saving effort.</p>
          <p>Only the scale we gain will lead further double-digit percentage saving in the cost as well as engine investment in the engineering area. Although we cannot rule out some impact from inflation affected to commodities we use to build our cars, I am convinced we still have a huge potential further cost savings.</p>
          <p>Couple of these activities to Volkswagen weigh our initiatives mainly in the manufacturing arena delivering savings up 10% in productivity per annum. This will continue funding for our financial services activities is of course more expensive than before but we have been able to minimize the impact wide range of funding tools. And as I have often said, our strong cash balance underlies the strength of our automotive balance sheet, giving us the means finance growth internally while still keeping some back for a rainy day.</p>
          <p>As Mr. Wittig commented, buying with our potential to delight even more customers with our products, but costs, investments, remain firmly under control with hard work we can look forward to the future with confidence.</p>
          <p>And this leads us to our 2008 outlook. First half was a good result. Our strategy has proved to be the right one or to current environment. Customers continue to buy our cars at an increasing rate directed by the exciting design of our cars, our efficient powertrains and our excellent quality. Reaffirming what I said to you on the Q1 conference call, thanks to higher sales revenue coming from the expected increase in unit sales, together with our efficiency and productivity improvements, our operating profit for 2008 will be listed above the previous year's figure.</p>
          <p>Continue to expect a positive net cash flow and a further improvement in the automotive division's liquidity position. As noted this point that this is before taking into account the effects of our acquisition of further shares in Scania. We raised our share in voting rights to 68.6% on the 22nd of July which was yesterday when the key anti-trust approvals were granted.</p>
          <p>This enables us to consolidate the Scania as our 9th successful brand. After consideration of the effect of purchase price allocation, we expect Scania to make some slightly positive earnings contribution Volkswagen Group in the second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, thank you very much. We will now move to the Q&amp;A session starting with the first questions of analysts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our first question will come from Jochen Gehrke from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have three questions actually for me. First of all Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, I think we all noted in the first half a very sharp decline in depreciation in the industrial business, I wonder whether you could comment on that is this the trend that we should expect for the full year hence in the level of reduction in H1 just multiplied by two. Or is there any different seasonality in that?</p>
          <p>Secondly, Mr. Wittig, regarding China yesterday, AutoLive was more cautious with regards to this market for the fourth quarter, is this also something that you expect to happen in terms of remarkable slowdown in growth at least in the Chinese market for the rest of the year?</p>
          <p>And thirdly, Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, most recently you commented on raw materials and steel, citing that Volkswagen has three to five -year contract so seeing no problem, I wonder whether you could give us an update, have you seen any renewed attempt by steel makers to break these contracts and what's your take on that with regards to raw material price inflation on P&amp;L VW? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you very much. Jochen Gehrke has three questions for us. For the first question is about depreciation and if you can give some more information and an outlook for 2008.</p>
          <p>The next question is for Mr. Wittig with regards to China which -- what development we expect for the full year, do we expect any slowdown? And the third question is about raw materials, if we can give some more information about the impact of steel, if he can give you some more information. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I will start answering the second question where China is concerned. Well, we have seen the Chinese market expanding this year by 14% but that's a mixture already off the first quarter. The first quarter the market went up by 20%, in the second quarter slowed down with an increase rate of only 9%. So we do see already a slowing down, certainly influenced by the earthquake and the floods but also the starting -- seeing an impact of the credit squeeze measures of the government. So we will see a further sort of a softening of the market in the second half year. But we still expect that the Chinese market will be somehow 10 to 12% above last year in total this year. So through the growth but softening of the growth, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm continuing on the question of depreciation. Very clearly speaking if you look at the balance sheet, it's very obvious that on the basis of very disciplined investment policy in the past. We are now enjoying a reasonable number in terms of depreciation, in line with our forecast that we see the CapEx sales ratio coming up step-by-step that is going to change but clearly not to any significant way this year.</p>
          <p>The second question on raw material contracts. I must have missed the quote that I ever said we would have no problem at all. The fact situation is that we are reasonably projected short-term. And that specifically given for 2008, but it's some dates clearly and after some time, we will also be hit by what's currently taking place in raw material markets and that's why clearly we also have to prepare for a situation when all the effects which are currently registered on the spot markets will have their effect on our bottom-line. How we can handle this that's clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So can we have the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now move to Albrecht Denninghoff from BHF Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. First, two housekeeping questions regarding the shipment products and the production schedule, could you tell us how much were your production figures for China? And this also increased quite exponentially or did you have already a slowing production rate in China? That would be effect the first question.</p>
          <p>And second question as your reduction was considerably stronger in the second quarter as your shipments. Could you tell us what the effect from the P&amp;L is? Could you confirm that it's not significantly higher than &#x20AC;150 on the improved fixed costs results effect from the higher production than the shipment network? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. Albrecht Denninghoff had two questions for us. The first question is about shipments and production figures for China. And the second one is again about strong development of production in the second quarter and if you can give some further information about the effects on our P&amp;L? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe a little bit principal comment at this point, you will recognize when you look at the yearend numbers of 2007 that our stock situation was not as we would put it ideal. We were missing a number of cars in terms of the overall volume on stock and also of course, we are missing a number of specific models. So what we were trying to do in the first half was to compensate this to a certain part. Unfortunately, we still have to say in a number of areas we are not satisfied with what we were able to achieve for the simple reason that we were selling with a higher frequency than what we predicted some months ago. So some adjustments have to be taken still. Though we could say, we think with these exceptions in mind, we are prepared for the second half of the year but there is no significant impact to the P&amp;L by the fact that production was high -- was running higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from <mark type="inaudible" /> from HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from HSBC, good afternoon. Three questions if I may. Firstly, I have seen your other operating profits in the automotive divisions; it's up by &#x20AC;319 million in the second quarter year-on-year. That asset was still flat in Q1 2008 year-on-year. So I ask myself what is the reason behind that, may you give some explanation on that.</p>
          <p>Then second question that I have is on SEAT. If you also said SEAT turned negative again in the second quarter. I know you have ambitious plans regarding model launches at SEAT this year and also next year. But please can you give some update what you expect from SEAT if Spanish car market remains at peak and new models really lead SEAT into sustainable profitable situation.</p>
          <p>And then third question is on Scania, I know that you consolidated Scania, may be you can give us some information what you expect in terms of PPA depreciation here going forward. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. <mark type="inaudible" /> has two -- three questions for us.  The first question is about the other operating profit, if you can give some further update for the Automotive division? And then the second question is about SEAT, if you can give some information which development do we expect for SEAT now that the Spanish market is quite weak. And the third question is about the consolidation of Scania, if you can give some more details on that, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well to the first question in terms of other operating income, the main driver behind the positive development there is the effect coming out of our cash flow hedges in terms of currency. And while we show the fair valuation of the total volume of our contract in our equity position without affecting the P&amp;L, once we release the basic business then of course we also release the respective forwards.</p>
          <p>And in the second quarter, we were reasonably successful there. Of course there is no side of the coin which is that the exchange rates to somewhat were going well specifically as far as the British pound and the dollar were concerned. And that's creating a significant positive impact, that's why although the exchange rate effect in our swing factor analysis from the operating profit last year to this year was -- is shown with 400 million negative. It's clear that if the real exchange rates would have been effective, that number would have been dramatically higher. So we were fortunately heavily protected against this. That's the main effect on other operating profit.</p>
          <p>A word on SEAT, yes of course SEAT had a bit of a difficult second quarter for the simple reason first of all that as we were able to show the Spanish market dropped quite significantly, and significant part of the SEAT business of course is taking place in Spain. The second point is very clearly that we are just in the middle of changing from the former Ibiza model to the new Ibiza model.</p>
          <p>The good thing there is that we got very positive comments from the press and the first customers about the cars that makes us very positive as far as the future is concerned. Nevertheless, it takes some time until we ramp up production into cars fully available. And that's why the second quarter is shown not in a sufficient way. Over the full year we are still positive that SEAT will realize a positive operating result above the year 2000 ever.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, can I raise an add-on question here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just finish on that please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then to as far as Scania is concerned, it's a little bit premature to talk about single effects coming out of purchase price accounting, that's why we thoughtfully choose the formula to save to give you a little bit an orientation on what you could potentially factor in your models is that taking the performance of Scania for the second half and potential effects coming out of purchase price accounting, most probably we'll end up with a only slightly positive result.</p>
          <p>Now you had another question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's particularly regarding SEAT. I agree with you certainly regarding 2008 because EBITDA is also positioned in the second which is probably growing in light of the &#x2013; light of crude prices but when I look into the SEAT pipeline for 2009, I see that you are planning to launch here maybe then a D segment car or rather automated cars which are rather high fuel consuming, and so I get some doubts if they could really be a success in the market, given the higher oil prices and given the fact that the Spanish car market is in such a weak situation and is that &#x2013; I like to ask myself what is happening with SEAT and really in the long term so beyond 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now a quick answer to that that. There's no reason to put any question mark to the SEAT strategy for the simple reason that yes you are right, we will introduce also bigger car next year but it's very clear as the focus markets for this car are more in -- specifically also the southern part of Europe, it goes without saying that the car will be powered by very fuel efficient engines and that's why that's not a contradiction to the most recent trends in the market and of course it's not creating any question mark to the SEAT strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we take the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from John Lawson from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much and good afternoon all. First question referring back to the earlier answer on raw materials, I wonder has Volkswagen created any explicit goal of recovering raw material costs from the customers with price rises? Basically, what do you think of that as a strategy?</p>
          <p>Second question, we don't seem to hear much anticipation of the new Golf in terms of enhancing your returns. If we go back a little bit in history, this was seen as a major step forward. I wonder whether there were any specific hopes on the cost or revenue side that you can share with us for this model as it comes in the final quarter of the year.</p>
          <p>And then finally for Mr. Wittig, I suppose, if we put together all of the BlueMotion and echo ranges that you're selling to the market today, could you give us an idea of what proportion of sales they're currently representing? Could you tell us how fast you might hope to build those up or do you suppose that in time BlueMotion will simply become your mainstream product? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. John Lawson has three questions for us. First question is about the impact of raw materials on our earnings and if we consider any price increases for our car? The second question is about the Golf, if you can give some more information on cost and revenue side for this year? And the third quarter is about echo ranges which we offer to our customers and what proportion of the total sales they have and if that will be our &#x2013; in the future our mainstream product? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, regarding your question as to potential price hikes. First of all, when we listen to the market and listen to our competitors we see a number of announcements that also our competitors are scared because of the price hikes on raw materials and also they are confronted some of them with a higher Euros in the foreign business. So from that point of view the industry doesn't seem to be able to compensate all the raw material price hikes and the challenges from exchange rates to rationalization programs only. So there is a trend in the market that we may have to pass on some of these cost increases to the customer.</p>
          <p>We are reviewing the situation as well, we need to know more specifics as to what finally will be the cost increase that is hitting us, but yes; we will also certainly not be able to compensate all of these price increases. So we have actually discussing whether we should pass on some of these price hikes to our customers and the question being, it is we are acting in a very competitive market actually. So we have to watch our competition as well. But as I can see and feel it from the temperature in the market, there seem to be some price hikes in the second half of this year going to the market to our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I can continue with your question regarding new Golf. First of all to be honest I think the current car deserves a positive remark because without any doubt it turned out to be extremely competitive and stable in the volume it produced and since quite a while we have improved the returns, of course, still a level or to a level which is not completely satisfying. But I think that the car which really that turned out to be by far the most successful one in the segment deserves some positive remark.</p>
          <p>So let me have a few comments on the new Golf of course, as we were all saying, we need to change a couple of things on the cost side, that's all done and in spite of the cost increases coming from the commodity side and also out of other areas, the car shows a significant improved cost basis. That should not mean that we would offer the car for a lower price than the existing car that would be a wrong interpretation and that means taking everything together the return of the new car right from the beginning will be significantly better.</p>
          <p>And of course, looking at the volume of the new Golf, it is one of the pillars for the continuation of the positive performance of Volkswagen without any doubt, and it's clearly one of the reasons why we are in a position to say well, primary conditions clearly did not turn to the positive in the last couple of months but we still stick to our commitments for this year and also for further years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well as far as the question of BlueMotion range is concerned, I can tell you that as far as the Volkswagen range is concerned we are selling in Europe as something like 7, 8% of the total volume as BlueMotion models very successful in there certainly Golf and all of BlueMotion models.</p>
          <p>This is true also for our other brands, the Audi with the E8 models and &#x160;koda with the GreenLine, and SEAT with the Ecomotive. So in total we have sold in Europe something like 70-80,000 cars in the first half year based on these echo models but that's not the whole story because we have to take into consideration the shift into the smaller fuel efficient TSI engines and also into some of our smaller and very efficient diesel engines and that altogether is a much higher number then.</p>
          <p>That answers also the question whether some time we will see the BlueMotion models as the 100% of our Volkswagen, that's certainly not the case because we will work into our cars. We will design into our cars all the elements of the blue model versions today and there may be then a BlueMotion version number two someday when we have worked it through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Christian Breitsprecher from Oppenheimer. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good afternoon, it's Christian Breitsprecher from Oppenheimer. I have three questions. Firstly on growth in the second half, can you give us maybe some idea what you think about the top-line momentum whether it's going to slow versus the first half particularly in light of the switchover at the Golf or whether you expect a momentum similar to what we've seen in the first half of the business here, maybe you can give us some numbers there?</p>
          <p>Secondly, just to check whether I understand it correctly on the CapEx ratio, in the first half we've had a CapEx ratio of about 4.3%, for the full year you are saying around six, does that mean that in the second half we might as well see a CapEx ratio above 6%?</p>
          <p>And then thirdly on hedging positions, can you give us an update how far you are hedged for 2009 in the major currencies and when you have put these hedges in place?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Christian Breitsprecher has three questions for us. So the first question is about growth. What do we expect for the second half of this year? The second question is about overall CapEx ratio, which CapEx ratio do we expect in the second half of this year, will that be above 6%? And the third question is if you can give some more information about our &#x2013; about the levels of our hedging activities for this year, next year and when we put that in place? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the first question is concerned, we will have to differentiate between the trend and the total economy and the total car markets. As mentioned before, yes we do see a slowdown of the growth rate not a slowdown in total but a slowdown, a softening of the growth rate as far as the total markets are concerned. That's one factor. Then there is our own performance.</p>
          <p>We have sold close to 6% more cars in the first half year. And we have announced that there will be new product coming especially in the second half of the year. And even in the third quarter like on the Volkswagen side the Passat CC hasn't hit the market yet. The Scirocco hasn't hit the market yet. And the new Golf is to be launched in the second half year. As far as sales is concerned, the new Ibiza -- it's actually just been introduced in the market so we perform in the second half year and so forth and so forth. So from that point of view, we do expect an even higher growth rate for Volkswagen &#x2013; for the Volkswagen Group in the second half year than in the first half year and that can only be influenced by this softening of the total markets.</p>
          <p>So in summary, we are quite confident that you will be able to at least continue the growth rate of the first half year which should be even better because of the new product arriving in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I continue on with the CapEx ratio. And as we look at 4.3 of the first half, we always said it's going to be up to 6% for the full year, which is really &#x2013; say it is 6% but I think it's highly probable that we will spend more CapEx in the second half which should bring CapEx to sales ratio up whether we are coming any way close to 6% is something which is difficult to say because I will have to explain that I think. We are talking about marginally pretty thick items and then the big question is will we sign on the final agreement with the supplier of the equipment still this year or is it going to be passed out over to next year, it's something which is not completely in our hands. But CapEx is clearly going to go up in the second half.</p>
          <p>As far as hedging is concerned, for 2008 and 2009, we are hedged in the key currencies because that way that's the dollar and the British Pound to a pretty large extent and our currency basket over all of the currency shows somewhat more than two-thirds. So we are reasonably covered for what potentially could happen on the exchange rates side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Frank Biller from LBBW. Please go ahead. Frank, your microphone is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So maybe we should take the next question, we cannot hear anything here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Adam Jonas from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Thanks and good afternoon. Adam Jonas from Morgan Stanley, just one question really. On page four I believe of your release, in the upper right hand corner, there's a statement about the conversion period for the eighth tranche of the stock option plan begins in July of 2008 and could lead to the creation of three million new shares if all options are converted. On that statement, can you give us a couple of details because using the current share price at least today, three million new shares equates to about &#x20AC;618 million. Can you give us an idea, does that sentence mean that these are vestable right now that you can exercise these options and get stock delivered immediately. Confirm that.</p>
          <p>Can you also confirm if you can the exercise price of this eighth tranche? So we have an idea of how in the money that 618 nominal value is. How many people this is related to? Details like this. How much of that number is senior management including the management board?</p>
          <p>And finally and I'm sorry to ask this question but it's just the reality that we're learning about what is -- can be done in Germany. And I'm not suggesting that you would do this but to the best of your knowledge under German law. Could you use swaps or any other similar contract for difference to monetize those options or those shares at least, without having to report it to the regulator? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Adam. You have a question or some questions about our option program. If you can give some more information about the eight tranche and how many people did exercise this and if you can really end at which price. If you can give some more information. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A little bit afraid I will not be able to answer all the questions. But I think probably what is important to understand is that first of all, it's part of a program which the company has been executing for many years. And of course each year a certain tranche of the program is up to becoming released and quite normally there is quite a timeframe until the holders of the options can take decision on whether they want to have it released now or later on.</p>
          <p>And the other thing is also the company is, if you want to put it that way, only the executor but not the decision maker, it's completely up to the single individual to take a decision so the single individual will take a decision on whether he or she feels that now is the right time or whether it might be better to wait somewhat.</p>
          <p>There is a defined date for each tranche where a certain tranche ends which means after that date; we would automatically trigger the option which would be turned then either into shares, physical shares or the respective amount of money. Of course to be paid out after tax.</p>
          <p>It is a pretty big number of people, which are holders of these options and in any idea that the company again could play any games with that is just completely impossible on the basis of this scheme which I was trying to explain. Is the program in or out of the money? Significant part of the whole program are in the money for the simple reason that looking at the share price development of the past years, it would be difficult to see that it would be out of the money and that means there is a high probability that at least significant parts of the program will get executed once the due date which is the first timeline for each of the tranches are reached.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for offering that -- the information, the extra details, we appreciate it. Can you then just finally of the three million of the eighth tranche, do you have at hand how many shares from the prior tranches are presumably in the money and held by Volkswagen employees at this point? Meaning is the three million the extent of it or are we talking about --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're right. It's held by employees of Volkswagen not by the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Totally understand that. I guess the idea is how much of that -- of the eighth tranche is what is fully out there and in the hands of Volkswagen individuals. The 650 million just for one tranche I mean that's a larger number to begin with but it could be or are we talking about billions here? Billions of Euros?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I &#x2013; we hear you. We only are not 100% certain whether we understand your question correctly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was just wondering if you can tell us basically how many shares of Volkswagen to your knowledge or that you can disclose to us, are owned by Volkswagen employees and management at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But the problem there is if you are asking for all of the employees, we simply have to say we don't know because there is no obligation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then of management?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as management is concerned, you can look in the reports as far as the Board of Management is concerned, it's of course public knowledge.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Frank Biller from LBBW has our next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Can you hear me now? I had some technical problems, sorry about this. Actually I have three questions; the questions are long-term U.S. dollar exposure. Now you are creating a new factory in the U.S., production 2011. Maybe you can elaborate on your net exposure in the running fiscal year. Is it a $7 billion U.S. dollar amount and goes down or what's your long-term expectation here, is it going to zero or two or three billion.</p>
          <p>The Chinese profitability is the next thing here. What's your assumption in the long run, is it a margin of three or four percent of which is this in the second quarter? And the next thing, do you have expectation -- what about your penetration rate assumptions and how does this concern your earnings line? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much. Frank Biller has three questions. The first question is about our net exposure in U.S. dollar. If you can give an outlook there? The second question is about our -- the profitability of our Chinese business? And if you can give information about the penetration rate. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you please repeat -- on what you mean with the penetration rate or <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I can clear this up. Your expectation in diesel versus gasoline. The diesels now has a premium against gasoline. The prices sharp increase in diesel prices and I know you have a greater, larger expense to diesel around cars. And here, what's your assumption in the mid-term or long-term, is the diesel penetration rate going down worldwide or is it still stable and how does this concern your profitability line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, So I can get started answering the question on the U.S. dollar exposure, you might know because we commented few times in that. Currently the net exposure is between six and seven billion U.S. dollars and of course with the decision we've taken to build a factory in the U.S. and not only that but to significantly increase the added value in the dollar arena, we think we've got a good chance to reduce this most probably even in total terms but of course much more significantly in relative terms as we want to grow volume in the U.S. not only by locally produced cars but also by imported cars.</p>
          <p>Second point, Chinese profitability, it's visible that we succeeded with our Olympic program to bring the profitability significantly up and I think it can be expected that we are able to improve this situation further on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But as far as the diesel development is concerned, first of all, I would like to point that the European development in Europe, the total distribution between gasoline engines and diesel engines is actually 55% roughly 55% in the European total market growth for the diesel engines, 45% for gasoline engines.</p>
          <p>The highest point that we saw in the penetration of diesel engines was end of last year in Europe at 57, 58% so it went down to 53%. There is a similar trend in Germany as well. We hit the highest point in Germany with a 50-50 share roughly end of last year and is actually 45% for the diesel engines.  As a -- but how will it affect us?  Well there's one very simple answer. Yes, we are sort of the leading manufacturer as far as diesel engines are concerned. So there might be an effect on us in a slowing down diesel market.</p>
          <p>But on the other hand, what we do see actually is that on the gasoline engine side with our TSI engines, we have a huge demand, a pent up demand which we cannot satisfy actually. So with the new development of these TSI engines, the turbo charged smaller gasoline engines, we are well prepared for future trends and from that point of view we don't see any negative impact on our balance sheet. We do see a challenge and to transfer us to taking over also the leadership as far as the gasoline market, the low consumption engine is concerned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you. I'm sorry but due to the limited period of time, I would like to ask you to raise one question only. Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from John Buckland from MF Global.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, can you hear us? I guess we have some &#x2013; we have a technical problem. We cannot hear John. So please take the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" /> (01;14:51).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> (01;14:54). Good afternoon. One follow up question to your comment on Scania, you mentioned that you expected less than positive earnings contribution after purchase price allocation depreciation. If that's on the EBIT line or on the net, net base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So a -- thank you. <mark type="inaudible" /> (01;15:18) has one question about the Scania consolidation, where do we see the effect on the EBIT line or on the net base? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer is on the EBIT line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Can I follow-up question on this issue because this would mean on a next level after minorities that you have l0ss contributions from Scania, am I right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's not right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine. Let's take the next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" /> from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right thanks a lot, it's Andt Allingcoft Credit Suisse. I have one and half questions if I may. Mr. Wittig, on Brazil, we heard Peugeot this morning talking about slight slowdown at least in the growth rates in <mark type="inaudible" /> and with you being the market leader. Could you share your thoughts on the Brazilian market and how potentially the increase in inflation and increase in interest rates could affect car demands especially in Brazil?</p>
          <p>And then for Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, this is a follow-up question on the currency issue that was raised before, could you share with us when roughly you on average hedged your currency exposure for 2008 and when on average you hedged it for 2009? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. So Andt Allingcoft (01;17:05) has two question for us. So the first question is about the Brazilian market, what do we expect there for the full year. And the second question is again about our hedging policy if you can give some more details on that when we roughly hedged our exposure. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well as far as the Brazilian market is concerned first of all we do see and enjoy a very strong growth rate in the total market. And we see a rather successful run out of the old goal version and they've just presented the new goal to the public in Brazil. With this dynamic development of the total market and of our sales there, we are fully exploiting the capacity of our plants. So in the second quarter, we were even missing market share because we were not able to produce sufficient volume of cars. We've done some restructuring, reorganization in the plants. And now with a new goal going in the second half year in the Brazilian market, we will see a -- I think a very interesting growth &#x2013; specific growth for Volkswagen in Brazil. So from that point of view, we don't see and we don't expect any negative impacts from this side of the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the question -- the half question on the currency side is the tricky one <mark type="inaudible" /> as you know because if I would talk about the timing when we entered into the hedges, I could even straight away talk about the underlying rates that what we not want to release, so I hope for your understanding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I understand that. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>John Buckland from MF Global will ask our next question. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Thank you. I missed the other one cause I was listening oh the web actually. The question is you talked about earlier about you have to prepare yourself for the headwinds that are going to come perhaps when the hedging runs out. I just wondered if you could just elaborate what you &#x2013; what the degree of headwinds you were thinking about because clearly you are getting a huge amount of protection at the moment, that's both foreign exchange interest rates and obviously raw materials as well. Perhaps you can just sort of quantify possible when these &#x2013; when you expect these headwinds to really hit you and what level of preparation you need?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. John Buckland is asking for the headwinds if you can quantify that our headwinds and when we will see a certain impact and how do we prepare?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So just in a rough sketch when you were asking in terms of headwinds in principal terms to sum that up, it's currency, raw materials, it's structural changes in the markets due to the CO2 issue, taxes and the like and just know not to talk too long I mean we showed some principle of issues on our page 15. If you sum that up then over the number of years taking all the hedges out before any counter measures, we are clearly talking a four-digit number, million, which would potential hit the company.</p>
          <p>Now that's why it is extremely important that we succeeded in buying enough time to prepare for that and when we take decisions as to build cars in America and that's of course one very important approach to counter measure these effects as we've done in past years and that's why it's reasonably easy for us to continue on with all these programs we've done in past.</p>
          <p>As we on a very disciplined basis build more and more of our cars on certain platforms and modular toolkits. As we improve productivity, which in essence means we can build more cars with the same number of people. In essence it means that we have managed a significant change to the company which puts it in -- it is already in a reasonably robust situation and that's why we are confident taking all the measures together that we will successfully be able to not only counter measure but to continue on our way of profitable growth for the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you in scale I mean in fact you are being protected now from all your hedging et cetera. Do you need another program to summarize the forward motion program to get ready for this -- the hit when it comes, is that degree of headwind we're thinking about or is it the fact that they &#x2013; we haven't &#x2013; in the past you talked about having to pay back half the full motion cost savings to the market. Is it the fact you haven't actually had to do that, that's the reason, is that another way of looking at it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the right way to look at it is that for a number of years we have executed very tough programs in the company which &#x2013; and I think we're all very clear on this. Where not any situations where something after a certain period went away, we succeeded to change the culture of the company and that's why there is no real basis to initiate another program because as a matter of fact if you look at the main ingredients of the programs we've done, it's still the key issues people are working on.</p>
          <p>The whole organization is moving to improve productivity, will show two-digit improvement each year, we are committed to that, to the public. We will build cars for lower costs, still extremely attractive car &#x2013; cars which will hit the market. I could talk very long on that but if you just remember the key issues we've touched on with former programs, it's not that these programs will be ended. We are still working the same issues certainly more professional than ever before because we've done it since quite a while and we're still heavily motivated to continue on with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just quickly, why is it never Northeast of Scania, I don't understand that? You mean you not own 100%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, what was your question we didn't get it, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On Scania you said there was no, I think the answer to the previous question, was there wouldn't be a minority challenge against the P&amp;L. I just wondered why there wouldn't be given you are not own going to be &#x2013; you are going to consolidate but not will be owning 100%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. I think obviously, you got the question wrong and also the answer. At least I understood the question as on how the effect coming out of the consolidation of Scania would affect the P&amp;L. And my answer was it will only have a minor effect on the bottom line for the simple reason that we not only have to look at the profitability of Scania which is an outstanding one as we all know, but of course we have to see on where we allocate part of the goodwill to which assts to significant amount it will be inventory and order backlog which will turn quite quickly and that will create a counter balancing negative effect in the second half of 2008.</p>
          <p>And so taking everything together it means that there will only be a slightly positive effect coming out of Scania in the second half of 2008 not very clearly we'll have a significantly positive effect next year then, but I did not talk about any change of the minority situation in terms of shareholdings in Scania.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ok, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Now <mark type="inaudible" /> coming from a journalist please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Christian Hefner from Reuters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, can you hear me? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, yes I was just wondering if you could sort of explain something to me as far as headwinds you had mentioned after you've had this strong first half, why haven't you not been able to issue at least a more concrete guidance in terms of what you expect for sales and for operating profit since at the moment it would seem to imply a rather dreadful second half. And as far as your comments earlier about cost cutting and restructuring were concerned when will we stop seeing these huge profit gains from your cost savings program?</p>
          <p>And then lastly just concerning the comment from <mark type="inaudible" /> (01;28:37) last week about Conti and Schaeffler, I was trying to get an idea about what &#x2013; where you saw the benefit for Volkswagen in terms of a Continental or Schaeffler combined group? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Christian Hefner (01;28:55)has three questions for us. The first one if we can give some more information or more details, more concrete outlook for 2008 with regards to sales and overriding profit. And then you have a question about the issue of Continental, a possible takeover of Schaeffler  and then we have a question &#x2013; third question about the cost cutting and restructuring measures. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all and maybe I approached questions that's not in -- from the tail end. It was a question with regards to Continental Schaeffler. We commented that we do view the approach of Schaeffler in principal terms positive and the primary condition that we're not entering into a long battle which at least would potentially carry the risk of deteriorating the operating business. Now why are we taking this position? Because we are &#x2013; if our information is correct, that's the biggest customers both have Schaeffler and also Continental.</p>
          <p>And we are currently -- which is nothing new but just a continuation of our policy in past years. We are supporting a few pretty strategic projects and we would be of course be not at all pleased if any of these projects would be lacking support by any of the management teams. That's why we of course extremely interested to as quick as possible see the straightened out a clear, positive situation. Because would be extremely happy of course we continue on with these projects.</p>
          <p>Now in terms of the improvement of the business performance in Volkswagen, I thought we had some good questions and hopefully some acceptable answers to that. For us, the impression is important that we never stopped improving our underlying performance, it's just we were continuing on with that. And we still do, knowing that some part of that is only doable by new products. But I think we've demonstrated looking back some time as we are able to produce very significant improvements each quarter, each half year, each full year  and there is no reason to believe that we would not be able to continue on with that.</p>
          <p>That brings me to the first question that's our outlook and honestly speaking there's recapping over the last few weeks where the number of companies had to revise their outlooks. I think looking at the great number of uncertainties all around. I think we're absolutely fine in just saying that we will improve against last year and we're committed to do this again next year. I think that's a significant commitment in itself and there's no reason to be any more specific on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. I just one follow up question about Continental is concerned just when you had said -- when you were talking about Continental you did not approve the breakup of the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. We didn't get your question and unfortunately we are --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just as far as the breakup of the company is concerned, you would not support a break up of Continental I would take it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we were very clear that we would do anything negative which would potentially create a risk of disrupting the company or key structures and processes of the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm really sorry. But we have to come to an end so we take the very last question from journalist. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Christoph Rauwald from Dow Jones. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon everyone. First quick question to Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, could you give us an indication on how Volkswagen of America has done financially in the first half of 2008. And when do you expect the unit to reach breakeven on a full year basis. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay we have the last question from Christoph Rauwald. It refers to our business in the U.S., when do we reach breakeven?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think having refused to comments -- was giving to us and having that in mind knowing how difficult the market trend is, I really have to say and I'm pretty well known in being very much holding back comments which are overly positive. I really have to say the team in America did a great job, fantastic job. Because we are able to keep our volume up. We were continuing to improve the bottom line. We were &#x2013; what's at least of a similar importance, we were continuing to improve fuel performance, customer satisfaction, quality, we're moving up the ranks in JD Power. So that's exactly what we need to do and to continue on with to prepare for the point in time that we have product available which are produced in the market. And that's why I think the team there did a great job in the first half.</p>
          <p>We are moving in the right direction of profit wise. In order to make sure that there is no misunderstanding, we still have to say very clearly on a group level if we take into consideration the losses on the manufacturer's side, it can only be if we talk about operating profit, a negative number. But in the given framework conditions, the unit in America has done a great job and is absolutely moving right direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But there is no specific timeframe for the breakeven outside, get that one --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for taking part in our conference call. Enjoy the afternoon, enjoy your holiday. Goodbye from here from Volkswagen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>