<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1511595" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1011</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Group Investor Relations">Christine Ritz</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Member-Management Board">Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Member-Management Board &amp; Head-Sales &amp; Marketing">Christian Klingler</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Broker)">Jochen Gehrke</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Michael J. Tyndall</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (UK)">Stephen M. Reitman</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Trinkaus &amp; Burkhardt KGaA (Broker)">Horst Schneider</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Stuart P. Pearson</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Commerzbank AG (Broker)">Daniel Schwarz</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Fraser E. Hill</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="B. Metzler seel. Sohn &amp; Co. KGaA (Broker)">J&#xFC;rgen Pieper</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Redburn Partners LLP">Charles A. Winston</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="DZ Bank AG (Securities)">Michael Punzet</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Landesbank Baden-W&#xFC;rttemberg (Broker)">Frank Biller</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Morningstar Research">Richard J. Hilgert</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA">Rabih Freiha</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd. Germany">Christian Breitsprecher</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Bankhaus Lampe KG (Broker)">Christian Ludwig</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="The Financial Times Ltd">Chris Bryant</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="Bloomberg LP">Christian Wuestner</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to Volkswagen's January to September 2012 Results Conference Call. For your information, today's conference is being recorded. At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Christine Ritz, Head of Group Investor Relations. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Volkswagen's conference call on the results for the period January through September 2012 based on the ad-hoc and the interim report we published this morning. Joining me on today's conference call are Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch, member of the Board of Management Volkswagen AG responsible for Finance and Controlling; and a member of the Board of Management Volkswagen AG responsible for Group Sales and Marketing, Christian Klingler.</p>
          <p>The webcast can be viewed via our website at www.volkswagenag.com/ir where you will also find the charts available to download. Questions can be sent by e-mail or called in. After the presentation, we will take questions first from analysts and then from journalists.</p>
          <p>Let me now pass you over to Mr. P&#xF6;tsch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you and a warm welcome from my side to those of you joining this call today. Our results announced this morning clearly demonstrate the strength of the Volkswagen Group. In tough market conditions, we have reported a solid performance in line with our expectations as we continue to build the foundations for our future.</p>
          <p>In the first nine months of 2012, the Volkswagen Group delivered 6.9 million vehicles to customers across our car and truck divisions, an increase of over 11% reflecting the strength of our brands, our globalization strategy as well as the inclusion of MAN and since August Porsche too.</p>
          <p>The volume increase including the consolidation of MAN and Porsche drove sales revenue up to &#x20AC;144.2 billion. Operating profit came in at &#x20AC;8.8 billion as expected and was at the level achieved for the same period in 2011. This is a respectable achievement considering the heavy PPA charge.</p>
          <p>Profit before tax increased significantly to &#x20AC;23 billion for the first nine months benefiting in particular from a higher financial result. This was driven by strong earnings and our equity-accounted investments, particularly in China as well as from the measurement of the put/call rights related to Porsche and even more so from the re-measurement at the contribution date of the stake we already held.</p>
          <p>At &#x20AC;9.2 billion, Automotive net liquidity remained solid after nine months as we continued to invest in our future with key new models such as the Audi A3 and Golf as well as reflecting the full integration of Porsche and Ducati and the increase in our stake in MAN earlier this year.</p>
          <p>Let me now pass you over to Mr. Klingler to take you through our sales performance during the first nine months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, a warm welcome to the conference call from me also. This chart shows half yearly graph plus the third quarter of 2012 for the world car market and group deliveries to customers in comparison to the same period last year. Market growth is observed in most regions around the world, especially in Asia, but also in the Americas. The exception is Western Europe where the eurozone debt crisis has led to heavy contractions in markets such as Italy, France, Portugal and Greece. While markets such as this &#x2013; the U.K. still reports some growth and elevated level of market risk exists across the whole region.</p>
          <p>Negative developments stemming from Europe are affecting consumer confidence around the world and in particular in economies which exports to the region. Following a decent growth in the first half of this year, global car markets started to decelerate visibly in the third quarter. We continue to closely monitor increasing levels of risks around the globe.</p>
          <p>Now, looking at the car market performance in direct comparison to the Volkswagen Group in the first three quarters of 2012 on a regional basis, as you can see, the Volkswagen Group has outperformed the market in every region. Despite difficult conditions in Western Europe, we slightly increased our global market share, the Western European market declined by almost 8% while the Volkswagen Group recorded a decline of less than 3%. As already mentioned, major markets in the region suffered significant reductions amid a weak economic background. In particular, the Portuguese and Greek market contracted by about 40% against the first three quarters of 2011 and Italy and France are down by 21% and 14% respectively.</p>
          <p>While the current European crisis remains unresolved, we see considerable further risk to car market volumes. Strong market headwinds continue, such as record high unemployment in Southern Europe plus weak consumer sentiments across the region. Austerity measures like the recent Spanish VAT increase further constrained these markets. The situation has placed the whole automotive industry under considerable pressure.</p>
          <p>Competition has identified significantly, which places particular strain on manufacturers, which focus on smaller vehicles in Southern Europe. The potential impact to the car market and our business from further shocks to the financial system or sovereign balance sheets would be substantial. While still unlikely, a eurozone collapse scenario would heavily impact the entire global economy. We therefore continue to closely monitor the development in each market.</p>
          <p>Now, we will take a look at the performance of the individual brands of the group. In the first three quarters of 2012, nearly all of our volume brands achieved an increase in terms of deliveries and for the group totally deliveries to customers exceeded last year's level by 11.1%.</p>
          <p>Volkswagen passenger car deliveries were up by an impressive 10.6% to more than 4.2 million cars, driven by a robust sales record and strong demand in China, the U.S., Russia and Brazil.</p>
          <p>Audi deliveries rose by 12.8% compared to last year to over 1 million cars being very successful in China, the U.S., Germany and Russia. &#x160;KODA expanded deliveries up to 707 &#x2013; sorry, 717,000 cars mainly due to the strong demand in Russia, China and India. Fiat still suffered from the weak Western European markets. Porsche is fully consolidated from 1st of August, 2012. Bentley has managed to expand deliveries with strong demand in the U.S. and China. And Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles increased deliveries by 4.9% with strong demand in Russia, Australia and Germany.</p>
          <p>Now, we take a look at the situation of the individual heavy commercial vehicle brands of the Volkswagen Group. The global truck market declined more than 8%. Worsening economic conditions in the major markets, particularly in Europe and South America had a negative impact on truck demand and led to an intensification of the competitive environment.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, the truck market shrunk by 7%; while in Central and Eastern Europe, the truck market grew by plus 38%. The slowdown in most parts of Europe were partly offset by the significant drop in the major market Russia and a few other countries outside of Europe.</p>
          <p>The Brazilian truck market, that's the major market in South America, contracted by minus 20%.</p>
          <p>With the main focus on Europe and South America, Scania and MAN faced headwinds in these declining markets with a decrease of truck and bus deliveries in the first three quarters of 2012 of 20.5% for Scania and 11.9% for MAN.</p>
          <p>In Europe where OEMs were selling trucks from stock with heavy discounts, Scania could avoid similar actions as they had already reduced production in 2011. The sales of Scania in Brazil were in line with the heavy duty sub-segment development especially as Scania moved to Euro 5 engines while others still had Euro 3 trucks in stock.</p>
          <p>For MAN, the decline is largely related to Brazil, again due to the change in emissions standards from Euro 3 to Euro 5 from the start of 2012. In Q3, the market is on the same level as the previous quarter. Underlining sales in power, engineering where we are represented by MAN grew by 7% and reached &#x20AC;3.1 billion.</p>
          <p>Now, let us take a look at a few highlights on some of our new models, which will provide a good base for our sales performance in the coming months. The new Volkswagen Golf had its world's premier in Berlin in September and will be introduced on the market next month. In a sensitive world demanding lower consumption and the lower CO2, the new Volkswagen Golf demonstrates how the best gets even better. It represents the car, the embodiment of contemporary mobility.</p>
          <p>The Audi A3 3 Door delights customers with its progressive innovations combined with unique sophistication and satisfies the various needs of the markets. The Audi A3 3 Door was shown at the Geneva Motor Show in March and hit the road this August.</p>
          <p>The &#x160;KODA Rapid is a new class of &#x160;KODA, a spacious family car, which combines generous space with simply clever solutions. The &#x160;KODA Rapid was shown at the Paris Motor Show in September and introduced on the markets this month.</p>
          <p>The SEAT Leon 5 Door is the most beautiful way of driving a functional car. It sets new standards in design, quality and driving experience, also shown at the Paris Motor Show last month. The new SEAT Leon 5 Door will be introduced on the markets next month.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Klingler. Now let's return to Mr. P&#xF6;tsch for some more details on the key elements of our financial performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's start at a high level and focus on the contributions made by our two divisions, including the performance from our equity-accounted investments. For the period January through September 2012, the Automotive Division comprising of Passenger Car and motorcycle, Commercial Vehicle and Power Engineering interest reported an increase in sales revenue of 25% to &#x20AC;130 billion. The increase in unit sales as well as the first time consolidation of MAN and Porsche were key contributory factors.</p>
          <p>Operating profit of &#x20AC;7.7 billion was fractionally below the &#x20AC;8 billion reported for the same period in 2011. And here, one has to take note of the significant PPA charge of &#x20AC;1.4 billion primarily relating to MAN and Porsche, which weighed on the operating results. Just to hint at how significant this PPA charge is, the operating profit margin would have been almost a full 1% higher at 6.9% rather than the reported 6% if the MAN and Porsche PPA component is excluded.</p>
          <p>And, of course, we also had the burden of the significant costs relating to the introduction of new models based on the MQB architecture, specifically the new Audi A3 and Golf which will pay off in the years to come.</p>
          <p>Profit before tax for the Automotive Divisions climbed 40% to &#x20AC;21.8 billion. Here the financial results played a major role. The equity-accounted results increased to &#x20AC;13 billion, a core contributor here was our Chinese joint ventures which reported a pro rata operating profit of &#x20AC;2.8 billion.</p>
          <p>Our indirect interest in Porsche also made a contribution for the period from January to July. Following full consolidation, the performance of Porsche since August 1 is now included in the operating result. However, the most significant factor was the re-measurement of the value of our existing 49.9% stake in Porsche prior to full consolidation, which increased by &#x20AC;10.4 billion.</p>
          <p>The other financial result, among other things, includes the valuation effect of our put and call rights related to Porsche prior to consolidation. The valuation increased significantly in 2011 and by a further &#x20AC;1.9 billion in 2012.</p>
          <p>Our Financial Services Division, which includes the Financial Services activities of Porsche AG, from August 1 as well as the Financial Services activities of Porsche Holding Salzburg, MAN and Scania increased its operating results by 17.2% to &#x20AC;1.1 billion. Profit before tax for the entire group at &#x20AC;23 billion was up almost 40% for the first nine months of the year.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to the operating results performance in more detail. The positive performance in volume, price and mix versus the corresponding period in 2011 came in at &#x20AC;0.6 billion. The effect from higher volume was partially offset by a less favorable country mix and challenging market conditions. Combined with a continuing positive development in the exchange rate of &#x20AC;0.9 billion and lower product costs of &#x20AC;1.2 billion this was almost fully offset by the rise in fixed costs and startup costs of &#x20AC;2.5 billion. This rise in costs related to the introduction of the new Audi A3 and Golf on the new MQB architecture alongside the associated renewal of production facilities which peaked in the third quarter and weighed heavily on the quarter's results.</p>
          <p>PPA played a role in the Trucks, Buses and Power Engineering business area. Combined with weak market conditions, this led to a negative swing of &#x20AC;0.6 billion, although within this, the Power Engineering activities reported a positive result.</p>
          <p>The Financial Services Division, including the Financial Services activities of MAN, Porsche, Porsche Holding Salzburg and of course Scania, lifted earnings by around &#x20AC;0.2 billion. In total, the operating result at &#x20AC;8.8 billion was just around &#x20AC;140 million below the level for the first nine months of 2011, a clear sign of the strength of our group in that we are able to report such solid earnings even while our core models are being changed, high PPA charges are being booked and while tough market conditions in Western Europe prevail.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to the financial performance of our main brands. In the first nine months, the Volkswagen Passenger Car brand carried the bulk of the MQB cost burden, I already mentioned. Consequently, while unit sales and revenue increased, the earnings declined slightly to &#x20AC;2.9 billion. Audi increased its earnings by 6% to &#x20AC;4.2 billion. &#x160;KODA and SEAT recorded results broadly in line with last year, as Bentley's turnaround continued. Porsche included just for two months in the operating results, reported close to &#x20AC;400 million before PPA charges offset most of the result.</p>
          <p>Our Commercial Vehicle interest reported mixed results with the market conditions in Europe and South America clearly impacting our heavy truck interest, while light commercials are recording just a slightly lower operating profit. The sharp increase in the others line reflect in particular the increased PPA charge, I have mentioned, as well as the elimination of inter-company profits, which increased following the full consolidation of Porsche.</p>
          <p>Turning now to cash flow in the Automotive Division; operating cash flow reduced slightly from &#x20AC;12.4 billion to &#x20AC;11.9 billion. Stock levels increased by &#x20AC;0.8 billion year-to-date. Also, this was a reduction of &#x20AC;1 billion from the half-year stage. This formed part of an overall &#x20AC;2.8 billion improvement in working capital in the quarter. Investing cash flow increased from &#x20AC;8.6 billion to &#x20AC;11.3 billion. Excluding equity investments, cash flow in investing activities rose to &#x20AC;7.4 billion from &#x20AC;5.3 billion reflecting upfront investments in our factories in particular with regard to MQB and the renewal of our product portfolio.</p>
          <p>Consequently the CapEx ratio for the first nine months climbed to 4.6% &#x2013; for the full year, in line with our usual seasonality patterns, this is likely to rise to above our long-term guidance of 6% reflecting the ongoing commissioning of investments in our factories to support new products.</p>
          <p>Now staying with the Automotive Division, net liquidity at the end of September was &#x20AC;9.2 billion. This reflects in particular the investments I just mentioned. And of course with respect to the third quarter one must also account for the consideration of &#x20AC;4.5 billion and the inclusion of the negative liquidity at Porsche AG as part of the deal to construct the Integrated Automotive Group with Porsche. Combined the effect on Automotive liquidity from the integration is around &#x20AC;7 billion.</p>
          <p>The acquisition of Ducati generated a cash outflow of just under &#x20AC;1 billion. We continue to drive in the direction of a higher net liquidity to be in tandem with the revenue growth, providing the confidence to continue our strategies despite any short-term capital market interruptions which might occur.</p>
          <p>And so to conclude my presentation today, let me now turn to our outlook statement which you can read in full in our interim report. As we stated when reporting our performance at the half year stage, market conditions continue to be challenging. While we expect growth in the global car market in 2012, the pace will probably continue to slacken in the remaining months of the year, with the Western European market decline expected to accelerate towards the end of the year.</p>
          <p>The pace of growth in the markets for Trucks and Buses is expected to slow in 2012. The global market could fall below the 2012 level. Sales revenue is expected to exceed the level of 2011. This is due in part to the consolidation of MAN and since August, Porsche too.</p>
          <p>PPA will largely offset Porsche's contribution to the operating profit this year. With regards to MAN after PPA, no positive earnings contribution is expected. In summary, we aim to match the level of the 2011 operating result.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this year Volkswagen Group has taken significant strides towards our 2018 goals as we build on our three strong pillars of, firstly, Passenger Cars including motorcycles; secondly, our Commercial Vehicles and Power Engineering business; and thirdly, Financial Services. We have worked long and hard to ensure that we remain at the pinnacle of our industry while at the same time driving efficiency through our engineering and production activities, and MQB is just one of the clear results.</p>
          <p>As the first Golfs are delivered to customers in the coming weeks, we consider ourselves well prepared to confront the global challenges of our industry. While there is no doubt still much to do, our results show that we are on the right track. And while tough times will linger, especially here in Europe, more customers than ever are turning to the Volkswagen Group, and we can be confident of our success in the years to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mr. P&#xF6;tsch. As we move now into the Q&amp;A section of our call, can I please ask you to limit yourselves to just two questions to allow everybody a chance within the time available. So, let's start now with the questions of analysts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We take our first question today from Jochen Gehrke of Deutsche Bank Frankfurt. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. Two questions, if I may. First of all, on your cost and profit walk, in the third quarter we had the fixed cost and startup cost impact of &#x20AC;1.1 billion, sizably above what was there in the first quarter. Can you just help us understand the dynamics in the coming quarters? Is this the peak now with the rollout of MQB? Is it going to plateau and then come down? Or how should we really look at cost ramp-ups in the coming quarters?</p>
          <p>And secondly, I wonder if you could comment on what's been happening in the market most recently? One of your competitors is getting bailed out by the government, at least in part, with a government guarantee awarded to the bank. What's the take on Volkswagen to the European market environment? Do you think this is compliant with European regulation? And are you not afraid that on the back of that pricing has way more legs to go down? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Jochen, for your two questions. So the first question refers to our fixed costs and the <mark type="ph" /> effects (24:54) and the impact in the third quarter, you would like to have a guidance which fixed costs we do expect in the coming quarters? Was Q3 a peak? Or how should we think of the development in the future? And the second question refers to the competition in Europe, and if we can comment on the European market, the environment, what do we expect there? Even also with regard to pricing conditions. So I would suggest we start with the question on the European market, and Mr. Klingler will be happy to answer this question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So if we talk about the European market, it is unfortunately clear that the European debt crisis is affecting direct our customers. So there's a big difference between the North and the South. In the South, the crisis is stronger, and the people are suffering more. So as a consequence, we see of course that the markets are declining. So for example, we have already mentioned, Spain has a strong decline. We have another like in Italy where we have a strong decline, or Portugal. But we see as well in other countries that the phenomenon is taking pace that total market in Europe is going down. This has of course an impact on our competition as well on our own side. So we are saying since more than a year that we are thinking that we need to observe very closely the development in Europe, and we continue to do that.</p>
          <p>We believe that the pressure on pricing will continue. We see that in several markets on different levels. We are, as we have not changed our strategy, always in a situation where we have a logic just to follow when it's needed, but we try to avoid clear price aggressive actions. And we see of course that some of our competitors do have the need to make &#x2013; turn their plans, and as a consequence some, I would say so, surprising actions could occur.</p>
          <p>We do not believe that the pressure on pricing will be reduced over the next months to come, and we believe that the situation in Europe over the next years will stay on quite a low market level.</p>
          <p>This is essentially due to the economical situation, where first, this situation needs to be improved, and second, of course, the confidence of the customers need to come back so that we can have a clear cross-perspective of the markets. However, we are gaining market shares, and we have a reasonably strong performance in Europe. This would be my answer for the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I can continue with the question on the fixed cost side. Let me first of all say that it should be very clear that the significant part of the cost increase throughout the year relates to the growth development of the group on the path we've taken so far. So it's very clear with the continuation of the ramp-ups we experience in India, in Russia, in America and a few other places, we are adding on fixed costs. But it's also clear that there is an equivalent, which you can find in looking at sales revenue for example.</p>
          <p>Now very clearly there is a specific element, which is the introduction of the MQB Modular Toolkit, firstly started at Audi with the A3, then continued at Volkswagen with the Golf, and we are still in the middle of this process. Now what I can say at this point is no surprises, so we are just executing very much along the plans which were established before.</p>
          <p>And then looking into the future, it's clear that there is kind of a peak in the third quarter, but we should have the expectation that clearly in the fourth quarter and also the first two quarters next year, we'll see significant effects on that side. As of course we will see the MQB Modular Toolkit be merged into the product portfolio, not only at Audi and Volkswagen, but also at SEAT and the &#x160;KODA. So that's why we clearly have to continue to digest a portion of our fixed costs in that time period.</p>
          <p>We should not forget that one of the fundamental reasons of the introduction of the Modular Toolkit is, besides the introduction of fascinating new models, is a significant step in terms of productivity and efficiency. And that's why we will increasingly then, throughout the next years, see the advantage coming in also into the P&amp;L.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Let's ask the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Michael Tyndall of Barclays. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. It's Michael Tyndall from Barclays. Two questions if I may. I guess the first one is just in relation to inventories, quite impressed with your cash generation in Q3 particularly given that the Golf 7 is still pre-launch. So I wonder if you could talk about where you finished the quarter in inventories? And maybe perhaps within that talk about whether or not growth this year has been ahead of what you were expecting in terms of volume growth?</p>
          <p>And then I guess the second question just relates to pricing overall, and looking at your EBIT walk-down, I guess the inference I can draw given that volumes were up in Q3 is that pricing and mix was negative. I'm wondering if you could perhaps tell me whether or not pricing itself alone was negative in Q3? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Michael. So we have two questions. The first refers to our inventory level and the cash generation in Q3, and you would like some more information where we finished the quarter? And what do we expect then for the rest of the year or for our future there? And the second question refers to our EBIT walk-down to the <mark type="ph" /> color of (32:45) pricing and mix, if we can give you some more details? Was both negative &#x2013; or you are asking us was pricing and mix negative or can we be here a little bit more specific? Mr. P&#xF6;tsch will start with those questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the inventory side, I think I can very easily remind you on comments we made in our last conference call, both Mr. Klingler and myself, where we tried to introduce to you that for a number of reasons we had to overstock the company a bit, which is a quite usual procedure taken just to prepare for model changeovers, specifically if related to such very significant volume models like the Audi A3 and the Golf model. That was the situation at about the middle of the year, and as we were clearly saying at that point in time, we then also, with some adaptions of the production sequence, we managed to move pretty close to what we would call ideal stock levels, which is broadly true looking at the global situation.</p>
          <p>In the meantime and on that level the intention is that we would continue on with that ratio towards the yearend. If ever possible, we are trying to manage stock levels to be somewhat below the ideal level, just to be prepared for a situation which cannot completely be ruled out, that we would see a pretty weak month early next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Mr. Klingler will give the answer with regard to pricing and mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the pricing side or on the mix side, it is true that there is an effect on the mix side, which is first a question of the country mix, then a question of the model mix, which is in the numbers and which can be clearly identified. Is there in the third quarter more pressure on the pricing side? The answer is yes. There is more pressure there. Still on a decent level, but the pressure is there, and we believe, as we just mentioned before, that the pressure will continue. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Let's have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We move on now to Stephen Reitman of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon. Could you comment on the level of Golf orders you're currently seeing for the Golf 7? And also comment as well on how you see the situation in Brazil developing? If you think the incentive or temporary boosts are going to end in October or the end of the year? And what implications that has for 2013? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Stephen, for your two questions. I do assume Mr. Klingler is happy to answer those questions. The first one refers to the Golf order, if we can give a number for the order book for the new Golf? And if we can describe the situation in Brazil, the current situation, and also with regard to the remaining quarter? And maybe also we can give an outlook for 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So if you allow I will start with the Golf 7. We have a very good direction on the markets concerning the Golf. We are seeing that we are winning up to now all tests in the magazines, and that not only by small but by very strong differences. We have an order book which is clearly above 15,000 orders, which is above our expectation. And I think up to now we are very, very happy how the development of the Golf is proceeding.</p>
          <p>The entry into the market is starting next month. So I hope, and I'm fully convinced of this, that afterwards we can report how positive the Golf is coming into reality in the different markets where we launch the car.</p>
          <p>So if we now go to Brazil, it is true that the incentive on the IPI will be reduced. So the question is when? Unfortunately I cannot tell you when it will be exactly, because there are at least two scenarios. One is clearly the scenario that it ends at the end of the month. We don't know whether the government would apply a continuation. If there were a continuation, which would be announced several days before the month end, we believe it would be up to the end of the year.</p>
          <p>So clearly for next year in any case we have the phenomenon as we have in all of these markets where some incentives are stimulating the demand, that there would be a counter action in terms of a lower market level, but in general we don't see very high risks there, because we have an existing demand.</p>
          <p>Brazil itself is a market which has economically reduced its positive path, and a lot depends as well on the level of interest rates. So we shall see as well how the interest rates will go further on as well as the exchange rate next year. So we are &#x2013; we believe that the Brazilian market will stay on a, let's say, decent level, normal level without a too big negative impact coming from these incentives in terms of reduction of the IPI.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let's have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We take the next question from Horst Schneider of HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. It's Horst here from HSBC. My questions are, first question is related to the currency gains. You have booked in the first nine months &#x20AC;900 million positive currency gain. Given the fact that euro has strengthened, should we expect rate of currency gains to come back in Q4? And, could you maybe also really shed some light on 2013 that if the currency, so it means the euros against the dollar stays at 1.30, will you have again a positive currency effect? And, maybe you can also give us some indication which amount we could expect? And, the second question basically relates to China. We are seeing here now at the moment a massive slowdown of sales of Japanese carmakers. Are you already seeing a positive impact? And, should we expect more or less strong acceleration of sales in China in the fourth quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much. So, we have two questions from Horst. One question refers to China and I'm sure Mr. Klingler will be happy to answer that, if the slowdown of the Japanese carmakers have any impact &#x2013; has any impact on our sales development, also for the last quarter and for the current &#x2013; for the following months? And, the second question refers to currency gain. So, Horst is &#x2013; wants to know if &#x2013; what do we expect for the last quarter this year. Do we still see there a positive development? And, can we give maybe also more information with regard to next year? Do we still expect then a positive currency effect? And, Horst is curious if we can give &#x2013; can quantify that as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, maybe I can get started and talk about the currency situation. As you rightly said, it was a positive gain of some &#x20AC;900 million in the first nine months of 2012. And, it's realistic to assume that we'll have another positive effect in the fourth quarter, whether that's fully proportionate or not doesn't make a major difference I would say, but we'll add something on to this. For 2013 it's a bit more difficult and we should not build our hypothesis only on the dollar rate as that's a little bit more complex situation; that's why in conservative thinking one should assume that there is no significant negative effect in 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, if you want me to ask about China, I'm happy to answer to this. It is true that the Volkswagen Group has a positive momentum in China this year in the first nine months so even before the situation of tension between Japan and China has occurred. Is there an impact on the market? Yes, there is some impact on the market. Therefore, the Japanese competitors have announced reduced production, sometimes &#x2013; if I remember well, about 50% of the normal rates. Do we have some positive effects? Yes, we do have some positive effects. How long will it take and how will it come up to the end of the year? This is a little bit difficult to answer, being honest. A lot depends as well how the relations will go further on that. So, in general, we believe that our performance in China will continue to be positive and continue to have a positive vision up to the end of the year. I think that is probably the most appropriate answer to your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you see on the back of that also already a price improvement sequentially?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The pricing situation in China for Volkswagen was in general, let's say, pretty okay before. And, to see up to now already pricing effect, it's frankly to say too early to discuss it because the sentiment is just four weeks old. So, we cannot really answer to this because we have the one effect that, of course, some of the Japanese competitors are trying to make the deal and, therefore, the increased incentives. Then you have another effect that, of course, due to the stock which will be reduced there could be a positive effect in the incentives. So, up to now, frankly to say it's too early to answer to this question precisely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We take the next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We take our next question now from Stuart Pearson of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. So, two questions; firstly, just relating more to the Audi side of the business, just noting the first year-on-year decline in a while. I was wondering if you could talk about what's happening with corporate demands in Germany in particular but in Europe as a whole, just noticed the last few months, and maybe it's just seasonality, but there seems to be some decline there in corporate sales of premium. So, I wonder if you could just elaborate what you're seeing from your corporate customers. And, then the second question, just a fairly quick one on the dividend; just given the strong cash generation that we have seen, how quickly do you think we can expect to see a move up to the 30% payout ratio? Is that possible as soon as for fiscal 2012 or is that something we should model as a more gradual ramp towards, say, 2014 or 2015? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, thank you, Stuart. The &#x2013; your line was quite bad, so hopefully we did understand everything correctly. If not, please let us know. So, the first question refers to the demand situation in Germany. Also corporate and private sales, how is fleet sales developing? And, the second question refers to our dividend and the payout ratio, if and when we can expect a higher payout ratio for our shareholders. So the first question, if I got it right, Stuart, I would ask Mr. Klingler to answer this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that was right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. So, if you talk about the question about the corporate demand, I think in Germany the normal ratio is about 60% to 40%, 60% coming from the commercial side and 40% from the private side. So, this has been as well confirmed in 2012. So that is more or less the same ratio. Is there a small softening over the last few weeks? Maybe there is something but we cannot really report more than that. In Europe, the tendency is that the ratio is more logic to a 50-50 split. This is in general as well held in this year even if it's more favorable for the fleet sales which is about 52% more or less January to August. So, we cannot report here that there is a stronger decline of corporate demand than on the private demand. But, nevertheless, we should not forget that the market is going down. So, as a consequence, of course, the corporate demand is going down as well. We are very sensible on this. We are here in a very good position. The Volkswagen concern is here very good in all aspects. And, we believe that the situation will be more or less on the same level, but there is some risk of softening. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the dividend side, I cannot say substantially more than what I've said so far, which is that medium term we aim for an adjusted payout ratio on a sustainable level of around 30%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's have the next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We move on now to Daniel Schwarz of Commerzbank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you. I have two questions. First is, in total, you still feel comfortable with your indication that Q3 was a trough and that you expect to pick up in Q4. Is that right? And, maybe could you give an indication for the contribution of Porsche's Capital Financial Services to your Financial Services business? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Daniel. So, your two questions for us; the first question refers to the development of the third quarter and the fourth quarter, if we can give guidance that the fourth quarter will be &#x2013; that in the fourth quarter the CapEx will rise and if we can give some more....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not the CapEx but EBIT.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sorry. And, then also you would like to know if the fourth quarter will be better than the third quarter with regard to our EBIT achievement. Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And, the second question refers to the Porsche business and if we can give some more information about the FS business of Porsche, how was the contribution of that unit to our FS division?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, on the first question, let me first of all say because the word trough has bit of negative sentiment, I would say let me really make sure here at this point it is just what we were expecting, and we are completely in accordance with our plan. It was clearly foreseeable that by doing the big model changeovers there are very significant ramp-up costs, and also effect &#x2013; first effects coming in by the new equipment. So, to cut a long story short, we feel very comfortable with where we ended up with in the third quarter, which essentially means that we will improve in the fourth quarter just to meet our guidance, to match the 2011 operating profit. Then on the Porsche Financial Services side, maybe two quick statements. First of all, this will be a slightly &#x2013; this is already a slightly positive contribution to the overall situation, but of course, for 2012 we need to say on that side similar to the whole Porsche situation that what we gain in terms of additional EBIT potential will be absorbed by the depreciation on PPA coming in, more or less at least. So that's why the situation is somewhat similar looking at the full piece.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We take the next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Fraser Hill of Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. It's Fraser Hill from Bank of America. Just one question on Audi in China and the premium end. We've heard a lot from some of your competitors recently about the market, and clearly inventories were somewhat higher for the premium space in China in the middle of the year, seems to have come under a little bit more control of late with perhaps dealer discounts narrowing. Could you provide us with your perspective on that dynamic, both for the industry as a whole and also for Audi? Have you seen discounts in the middle of the year, perhaps as substantial as we've heard from some of your peers? And, indeed, have you seen the market tightening more recently, which also seems to have been a theme? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Fraser. You are interested in Audi in China. So, if we can give some more information how the situation is in China for Audi, also with regards to the overall market conditions, rising incentive levels. So, what do we expect here for Audi? Mr. Klingler will answer that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, it is true that the premium market in China has had a more complicated time in the first nine months, 2012 than in 2011. So, there was more pressure in the market, as well some inventory issues but the inventory issues are essentially concentrated in the market on the imported cars. So, maybe just explain a little bit how it works. You have there the local production. Audi is very strong there of course. And, then you have the imported cars, like for example the Audi A8 or like for example the Audi Q7 as you might have from other competitors as well, respectively. So, I would say so there have been some actions done by one another competitor, which was essentially positive to the incentives in general but that's more concentrated again on the imported cars than on the local produced cars. We had the introduction of new models, like the Audi A6, very successful. And, we feel that after the more intensive situation, which had its peak probably some kind of June, that the situation is now getting to a more, let's say, normalized even though it's not normalized yet, it's more normalized situation. So Audi has, of course, tried to get as far away as possible from this development but, of course, due to competition isn't always possible. And, we think that the situation over the next month would probably go into, as I mentioned before, a normalized situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Can we have the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We move on now to <mark type="ph" /> Austin Earl from Marshall Wace (54:56). Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. I just had two questions. One is on the MQB and the ramp-up costs. I just wondered if it's possible to separate the two charges or maybe just confirm that Q3 was the peak in terms of those. And, then secondly, I just wanted to understand regarding MAN; it looks as if after a very poor Q2 that MAN has now had a better Q3, but I'm not sure if I can interpret their accounts through your accounts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Austin. We have two questions. The first question refers to MQB and ramp-up costs, if we can give here some more details, and especially you are interested if the Q3 was the peak related to MQB charges? And, the third &#x2013; the second question refers to MAN, due to the different accounting standards MAN and Volkswagen is using there, if we can compare Q3 and Q2 and give there some more information on the performance of MAN.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, first of all on the MQB side; again, as we said before, there were significant ramp-up costs which had to be digested. It's a significant part, a very significant three-digit amount which is incorporated in our swing factor analysis on the fixed cost side of our EBIT position, comparing 2011 and 2012. As I said before, we assume from this point that this could have been the peak in Q3, but we clearly have also to bear in mind that by the continuation of the introduction of the MQB platform if we look at the group level introduction into additional brands and models that still the next month and quarters will carry a decent proportion of ramp-up and introduction costs.</p>
          <p>Second question on MAN; there you find quarterly result on the EBIT line before any PPA charge of &#x20AC;161 million. I should say at this point that still this year the displayed numbers for EBIT are not 100% comparable between Volkswagen, MAN. But that would be a slight improvement against the second quarter. Still, let me put it that way, there is room for improvement. And, to shed a little bit more light on this, let me repeat what I said for the full year. It will be such that, in spite of a significant positive contribution, if seen together with the PPA charge, the resulting amount will be negative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's have the next question, please. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now move on to J&#xFC;rgen Pieper of Metzler. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. I have two questions. The first one is another one on pricing, maybe just a little more description. Is it right to say that pricing is principally negative in all regions, maybe with the exception of China? Or, is it really predominantly Europe? And, second one on Porsche; we had &#x2013; in the two months, we had a 19% EBIT margin if you just take the EBIT, of course, before PPA. Is it prudent enough to expect &#x2013; taking into account that August, September are normally not the strongest months for Porsche and taking into account certain volume increase next year and maybe a bigger proportion of the 911, is it prudent enough to expect roughly 20% EBIT margin for Porsche next year? Or, is it &#x2013; would it be too optimistic and not conservative enough? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, J&#xFC;rgen. So, you have two questions for us. The first question is for Mr. Klingler in regard to pricing, if we can give some more information if we see in all regions negative pricing development, exception &#x2013; with the exception of China? And, the second question refers to the EBIT margin of Porsche AG, if we can give here guidance for next year and J&#xFC;rgen is suggesting a margin of 20%, EBIT margin, in 2013 and would like to know if that is too optimistic. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, if we talk about pricing, it is clear that the pressure in Europe is probably the stronger one if you compare to the other regions. The situation in other markets have not changed strongly in the last quarter than in the quarters before. So that means, for example, in the U.S. &#x2013; or North America we have more or less the same pricing situation that we had six months ago. This is as well true for Russia. There is some pressure on pricing in South America, which is of course essentially due to this stimulation package and reducing the IPI. We see as well in China a continuation of the normal pricing pressure as it was in last month. So, it has not increased strongly and here talk about the CKD business so the normal business we &#x2013; not normal, the business done through our own plants in China. So, I would guess that the pricing pressure in Europe is as I said before the stronger one and we expect that it will continue. We cannot say that this is a worldwide phenomenon to the same level. So, we still have clear differentiations depending on the regions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then on the Porsche side, first of all just to confirm this, I think Porsche is turning up again 2012 with an excellent performance. You might be aware that we have a minimum target of profitability established at Porsche, which is 15%, and I think there is no reason to believe that we would not be able to meet this target. How far this can go is, I think, also heavily depending on how the economy develops any further on the one hand. And, then just a little reminder here, we should not forget also Porsche started significant CapEx spending for the simple reason that at the end of next year there is a very important product launch which will extend the product portfolio at Porsche. So, if it was possible, clearly I'm sure the colleagues at Porsche will do the best they can. So far, I think it's better to keep feet on the ground.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's have the next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We move on now to Charles Winston of Redburn Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, good afternoon. My two, just in terms of the product cost side of the EBIT walk-down; there was a &#x20AC;300-million gain this quarter compared to &#x20AC;600 million, I think, in the second quarter. I was just wondering if you could perhaps update your thoughts for the full year for that line item and perhaps give us some tentative thoughts as to what you might see in 2013. And, then just in terms of the cash tax, there was a pretty significant cash tax charge in the quarter; I think it was about &#x20AC;1.8 billion or thereabouts. I was just wondering if you could flesh out thoughts there. Was that a bit of an abnormal item and is it likely to step back? Or, is that a new run rate in terms of cash tax paid? Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Charles. So, you have two questions for Mr. P&#xF6;tsch. The first question refers to our product cost savings and if we can give a forecast for the full year 2012 and also an outlook for next year. And, the second question refers to the cash tax charges; there was a significant outflow in this period and if we can give you some more guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, first of all on the product cost side &#x2013; and I give a lot of compliments to my colleagues, specifically on the purchasing side and also the engineers trying to squeeze some costs out of our products that they managed again a very significant contribution to our P&amp;L also in the third quarter and I think there is good reason to believe that we might be able to somewhat, let's say, continue on with that performance for the remainder of the year. Whether we'd be able to produce as much savings in 2013 might be a little bit aggressive; you know that we normally target on, let's say, up to &#x20AC;1 billion to be achieved in a 12-month period and that's clearly also a target set for 2013.</p>
          <p>On the tax side; first of all, I should give a basic comment which is quite normally high tax payments are mainly driven if profits run high, and then quite normally you have, in a sequence of sometimes two years, three years or sometimes also only four years, you have tax audits which then after a while end in a tax payment covering a number of years. And that kind of thing happened in the third quarter so there is cash-out for settlement of several tax issues relating to past years in the magnitude of around &#x20AC;1.3 billion included. And, then there is another charge which relates to the Porsche transaction, which is cash-out in the third quarter but will be recovered in roughly six months down the road.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let's have the next question, and it would be great if you can concentrate on one question only because we are running out of time. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We take our next question from Michael Punzet of DZ BANK. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Michael Punzet, DZ BANK. Good afternoon. Maybe &#x2013; okay, one question. Maybe you can explain a bit what's happened at Scania because we saw a drop in sales and especially in the margin. And, maybe you can give us an indication if this trend will also continue in Q4. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Michael. You are interested in the development and the performance of Scania, if we can give here some more explanation &#x2013; sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, it was on &#x160;KODA, not on Scania. Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good. So, we switch to the passenger car business so it's &#x160;KODA. So, you are interested &#x2013; and this question makes much more sense, I would say. So, we would like &#x2013; you would like some more information, what's happened in the third quarter at &#x160;KODA because you saw there a weaker EBIT margin and if we can give here some background informations and if we have a guidance also for the full year. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, I think everything Mr. Klingler said in terms of the markets being difficult in Europe relates also to the &#x160;KODA situation without any doubt. But, at &#x160;KODA, there are two elements &#x2013; that's why I'm pretty happy that you are putting this question on us &#x2013; two elements which need further consideration. One is the introduction of our new Rapid model which is a pretty unique offering of a four-door sedan where really price and what you get for the price is in a pretty good relationship. So, we are very happy to be able to introduce this car, but it's clear that all the upfront investments and costs had to be carried by &#x160;KODA. And secondly, of course, &#x160;KODA is also in the middle of preparing for the model changeover to the new Octavia model; that's why the Q3 is also somewhat harmed by this very important project. Taking everything together, we should not expect that situation to change fundamentally in the outstanding quarter but it's also fair to say we also have &#x160;KODA full on track with these very important measures to prepare for a much better product portfolio at &#x160;KODA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We take question from Frank Biller of LBBW. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Coming back to China, there's one question from me. So, now you have a bit of profit here of these Chinese, Japanese kind of thing of war. And, here my question is, what are you assuming for the years to come? So, taking 2013, 2014 growth rates for Volkswagen in China, are you going to grow with the market in the range of, let's say, 5% to 8%? Or, what is your expectation here? And, maybe you can give us a sales per unit figure here for the Chinese market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Frank is interested in the performance of Volkswagen in China, what &#x2013; which growth rates do we assume for the next years and how should we think of the performance of the Volkswagen Group. Mr. Klingler would be happy to answer this question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, as you know, the Chinese Government will change in the next few months, so therefore, some will depend on what is the position of the new government concerning the growth as well in general but as well the car industry. We don't expect any major changes, so we expect that the positive position for the car industry will continue. The growth rates we see this year are in line with our expectations so we have always said it's a single-digit number, probably 5%, 6%, 7% concerning the market. And, we believe that as well the next few years to come the growth rate will be concentrated essentially in this single-digit market. And, if I talk about market, I talk essentially about passenger car market. The trucks market looks a little bit different. There is as well different indicators which needed to be explained a little bit at another time. As always, our target is to grow stronger than the market. So, this hasn't changed. So, we believe that we have a very robust basis. We have wonderful new products. We continue to launch new products. We have a very strong strategy in China and it would be feasible that our growth rate higher than the market growth. This is maybe answering your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, the revenue per car?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you can accept if we are not going into these kinds of details at that level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We go to Richard Hilgert of Morningstar for our next question. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and good afternoon. Thanks for taking my question. I was curious to get some more contrast from you compared with a competitor of yours over in Europe who has delayed new model launches in the face of the anemic demand that we're seeing throughout Europe. But, yet you are going ahead with model launches, and your product introduction schedule seems to be relatively healthy compared to many others. What's the strategy? What's the thinking? Your competitor says that they fear that they won't get the kinds of returns that they need to get to launch a model if they launch in the midst of this kind of a low demand level. Contrast your thinking and your strategy to that kind of thinking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Richard. So, you are interested in our product strategy and if we can a little bit explain why we continue to launch new models and why we believe that this is the right strategy, also in a more challenging environment. So, I would say Mr. Klingler is answering the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I think you can accept if we are not commenting on things that are expressed by our competitors. But, in general, we believe that new products are the key of success, so therefore, we have, for example, created our MQB which is a perfect base both on costs but as well on possibility to make wonderful cars and we will continue on that. So, it is true that the European market will not be very easy over the next few months, maybe even years. We have included that into our vision. But, we believe that for the customer it is very important to get very good cars, very good products, and it is evident that you only can have very good cars and very good products if you continue to develop and if you continue to be very strong on your technological capabilities. So, we believe that we have all the thinking into that direction that is very healthy to have a robust product plan and answering to that &#x2013; to the needs of our customers even better every day so that more and more customers coming into our showrooms and buying our cars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Your increasing market share bears it out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe a little additional comment from my side here from a financial perspective also. I think it is very important to understand what the Volkswagen Group is doing which is when we say and talk about new model launches, it's not just fine revisions of some single design issues; it's fundamentally new cars. And, I think the Golf just launched or also now Audi A3 are just perfect examples. And, the point here is that, without any doubt, in our view the automotive industry in the next years to come will have to go through a paradigm shift in terms of, for example, new power-trains to be installed, very significant innovation relevant for the whole car. And, if you take the Golf in just one parameter, the Golf is essentially more or less a 3-liter car. You can run the car with 3.2 liters per 100 kilometers. So, this is offering substantial additional value to the customer and we are absolutely convinced the customer will pay for it. But, of course, you need to have the package in place and that's why Mr. Klingler said that from that point, even financially thinking, it is the preferred strategy rather than trying to muddle through. And that's I would say probably the fundamental difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I completely agree. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We take a question from Rabih Freiha of Exane. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Rabih Freiha from Exane. Thank you for taking my question. Could you give us maybe more color about the evolution of your capacity utilization rate in Europe from Q2 to Q3 and maybe tell us what the contribution of the region is to your EBIT, if possible? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for your question. We cannot give all the details you are interested in. So, you are asking for the capacity utilization and the development from the first half to the third quarter and if we can also give here, in addition, the EBIT contribution by region?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Of Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, first of all, on capacity utilization, there is not much change from Q2 to Q3. We maintain in our terminology the capacity utilization of more than 100% including China and, if you take off China, more than 90%. I should say at this point, if one applied more broad and more common calculation matters to that issue, for example, the <mark type="ph" /> Harvard scheme (80:57), you would both for Europe and for China end up with numbers more than 100%. Secondly, in terms of EBIT for the various regions, and you asked the question knowing that you won't get a very precise answer on it, but it's probably that and I'll try to give a partial answer which is we are highly profitable in Europe and not only in Europe. I think that answers probably at least the core part of your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. We take last &#x2013; two last questions from analysts, and then we switch to the media. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We move onto Christian Breitsprecher from Macquarie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I have one question remaining on PPA. Now that Porsche is fully consolidated, can you tell us what we should pencil in as PPA for the full year 2012 and also a first idea of what would be remaining for 2013? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Christian, for that question on PPA. So, if we can give a guidance for the full amount for this year and also for next year. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So first of all, for 2012, everything included, we think PPA charge will be in the magnitude of &#x20AC;2 billion. With the exception of a piece of probably &#x20AC;100 million, everything on the EBIT line. And, then for 2013, we believe we will be released by several hundred millions in PPA charge so the overall amount of PPA charges in 2013 should be substantially lower than in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, last question from an analyst. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We take a question from Christian Ludwig of Bankhaus Lampe. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Good afternoon. I have a question on the Commercial Vehicle business. We've seen MAN, Scania, and also your own Volkswagen branded commercial vehicles going down. Now, in these times where business is becoming worse, it might be sensible to do some tough decisions which would help the integration of the overall Commercial Vehicle division. Is this something that we could expect in the next coming months, that there are some quicker decisions on the integration of the commercial vehicle side of things?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Christian, for the question on our Commercial Vehicle business. So, you are interested in the next steps with regard to our truck strategy, if we will see some steps with regard to the integration of those companies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, I think we should say that &#x2013; I think we've now a very clear structure which allows decent cooperation between all the three companies. We've put new management &#x2013; partially new management in place, so people were put in charge starting the 1st of September, and I simply think they should be given some time to approach us with their plans. It's very clear there is a clear target set for synergy creation and there are no reasons to believe that we would fall short of this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you enlighten us a little bit on the time schedule then, when should we see some first results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think in terms of the synergy creation process it's already effective. So, we are expecting, as you know, a number of &#x20AC;200 million per annum to be produced short term, which might not be fully available next year but probably the year after. But, you're also aware that we do expect quite significant amounts more than just that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Now, let's switch to the questions of journalists please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We take a question from Christopher Bryant from Financial Times. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I have a very general question on this very volatile economic environment you're facing now. Clearly, the nice conditions of the past where you had predictable, quite long economic cycle seem to be at the end. We have a much more volatile situation, much more unpredictable. It's not even clear some of your European competitors will survive the crisis. So, my question is what are you doing differently now? How are you adjusting to these conditions? Has your monitoring increased? Are you doing more regular budgeting and planning? Are you trying to increase flexibility in production? And, are you taking any special measures regarding Europe? We have had some of your industrial companies in Europe saying that they are monitoring things very carefully in Southern Europe, doing cash sweeps, parking money at the ECB. So, are you taking any special precautionary measures there? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris. You are interested in our strategy, how do we &#x2013; or which measures do we take with regard to the volatile economic environment? What do we do maybe differently to our competitors with regard to our internal planning or any measures with regard to flexibility?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, maybe I can get started and maybe Mr. Klingler can add on a comment then also from a marketing and sales point of view. First of all, I think I should say that we have the general assumption that with all the risks in place it will be possible to maintain what we call Europe and also the euro currency. Nevertheless, this will require a lot of decision-making in the time going forward, which might not always be possible at the appropriate point in time, which might lead to quite a decent amount of volatility. That's why to produce and create a lot of flexibility in the companies is one of the top priorities in such a situation without any doubt. At this point, I think we're able to manage the situation so far quite well. Time accounts of most of the workers are still pretty much filled. We have possible, quite flexible working schemes available, maybe one of the most flexible ones at all. We also have a decent number of temps still working in our factories.</p>
          <p>There is a high degree of flexibility already existent. And, then clearly also we will maintain our conservative approach in terms of planning because I think we've also demonstrated so far that, if circumstances allow a better performance, we were always able with the backing also of our workers' council and the unions, to perform better which is to say, if there were any special shifts necessary, it was always possible to convince our employees that the situation recommends to support such ideas. And, in that sense, we are very sensitive. We are highly linked to all the major markets around the globe, but flexibility is the name of the game.</p>
          <p>Klingler, do you want to make some further comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, if you look at Europe, which is essentially the center of concern, we are pretty well trained because the last crisis was not so long away. So, we have in our feeling all necessary tools. As Mr. P&#xF6;tsch has said, we are very sensible. We are very closer to related to the customers, as well to our organizations, as well to the dealers. We are monitoring all risks very sensibly. And, you might remember we had started to talk about Europe and the sensibility in Europe more than a year ago so at that time we started already to put and reactivate all necessary tools. By the way, we have never really stopped them. So, we are very sensible. We continue to monitor. We are flexible as well. And, for example, one name of the game is, for example, the stock; what you can see that the stock level in Europe, but not only in Europe, is completely under control. Reevaluating of course all risks on the dealer side, as well on the residual value side, as well on the used car side and we have in place, I would guess so, all measurements which should give the possibility, if necessary, to react very, very fast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So, we take now the last question from the journalists please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We take a question from Christian Wuestner of Bloomberg News. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. I have two questions if I may. One is that we have seen the announcement of a couple of closures of plants in Europe. So, how would you assess the situation here? Are we on a good way to reduce this problem of overcapacity in Europe? And, the other question is that we have seen Volkswagen halting production for a couple of days of the Passat Lingyu, for example, and Audi also in Neckarsulm. So, I would like to know are you now reaching the levels that you said that below the ideal levels, or are we going to see more of these halt of production here in Europe? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Christian. So, you have one question. It is overall referring to the capacity in Europe, if we can comment on that situation in Europe and especially then on the Volkswagen side, if we see there that we are below ideal level or if we see any measures of production cuts. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, in terms of the question on capacities in Europe, I think it's not the first time that &#x2013; just looking at nowadays situation, one might figure out that there is too much capacity. Clearly, any competitor has to take independently a decision on whether capacity has to be reduced. Now we hope &#x2013; and that's a little bit our principles how we try to act that beside these kinds of measures there were also some more positive measures in terms of ideas on new products so ideas to also fill in capacities which might be not absolutely necessary at this point in time. As I said earlier on, we are very closely monitoring the situation, and we can react very quickly. That's why, for example, in our plant in Emden we took a decision to close the plant for three days. This is not absolutely necessary by the stock levels currently in place but we want to move a little bit on the more &#x2013; on the conservative side. And, these are little measures which will contribute to stock situation at the end of the year where we'll be able to say that we are ideal level minus something. How much doesn't really matter because we can live with ideal levels, of course, but as there are some uncertainties in the further economical framework, it is highly recommendable to maintain a conservative position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So, thank you very much. We come now to the end of the conference call. Thank you very much for taking part in our call. Enjoy the rest of the day. Goodbye from here in Wolfsburg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That will conclude today's conference call. Thank you for your participation, ladies and gentlemen. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>