<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1248999" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-09-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>534</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Rick J. Hans, Divisional Vice President, Investor Relations and Finance</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Gregory D. Wasson, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Wade D. Miquelon, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">John Heinbockel</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Lisa Gill</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Scott Mushkin</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Andrew Wolf</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Mark Miller</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Edward Kelly</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Steve Halper</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">John Ransom</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Nathan Rich</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Meredith Adler</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day everyone and welcome to the Walgreen Co. Fourth Quarter 2009 Earnings Conference Call. As a reminder, today's call is being recorded. And now I'd like to turn the call over to Rick Hans, Divisional Vice President of Investor Relations and Finance. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mark, and good morning everyone. I apologize for the little bit of a late start here, a little technical problem. Welcome to our fourth quarter conference call. Today Greg Wasson, our President and CEO will discuss the quarter's highlights and the macro environment. Wade Miquelon, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer will detail the fourth quarter financial results before we begin taking your calls.</p>
          <p>When we get to your questions, please limit yourself to one question and a follow-up so that we may give an opportunity to as many investors as possible during our limited time. You can find a link to our webcast under investorrelations@walgreens.com. After the call, this presentation will be archived on our website for 12 months. We're also making the call available as a podcast for the first time. You can download that too at our investor relations website.</p>
          <p>Certain statements and projections of future results made in this presentation constitute forward-looking information that is based on current market, competitive and regulatory expectations that involve risk and uncertainty. Please see our latest Forms 10-K and 10-Q for a discussion of factors as they relate to forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn the call over to Greg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rick, and thank you everyone for listening to our call. We appreciate your continued interest in Walgreens. Today I'm going to review our progress this quarter, address the macro environment including the economy and healthcare reform and update you regarding some of the innovative programs we're implementing across the company.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter we posted solid results in a difficult economy while seeing the first net financial benefits from our restructuring initiatives. Net sales for the quarter were $15.7 billion, up 7.6%. Consumers are concerned about rising unemployment, keeping their homes and paying down their credit cards. They're focused on value and are buying needs versus wants, but even in this challenging environment our people delivered record sales.</p>
          <p>Net earnings were $436 million or $0.44 per diluted share, compared with $443 million or $0.45 per diluted share a year ago. For the fiscal year, net sales were a record $63.3 billion up 7.3%. Net earnings were $2.01 billion or $2.02 per diluted share. In fiscal 2008 net earnings were $2.16 billion or $2.17 per diluted share.</p>
          <p>Cash flow from operations in fiscal 2009 was up 35% over a year ago totaling a record $4.1 billion. Looking back on fiscal 2009 we reported another record sales year which was marked by one of the most important strategic and operational transformations in our company's 108 year history. And we did it while navigating through the most severe economic downturn in decades and preparing for potentially the biggest reform of our healthcare system since Medicare.</p>
          <p>As a result we've adjusted our retail model to respond to what we believe will be lasting changes in consumer behavior. In addition, we're positioning our company for healthcare changes that will place a greater focus on preventing and managing chronic disease and promoting health and wellness.</p>
          <p>Let me take a few minutes to talk about healthcare reform in the context of our strategy. With nearly 170 million Americans currently insured by their employer, corporate America will undoubtedly continue to play a vitally important role in the healthcare system. And most employers want to, including Walgreens. We support the Obama administration's guiding principles of improved access, greater affordability, and higher quality as part of any reform platform. And we agree with the need to shift focus to preventing and managing chronic disease and emphasizing health and wellness.</p>
          <p>We're on the front line of healthcare with 68,000 professionals who can impact people's behavior through direct face-to-face interaction. A great illustration of that is the current seasonal flu and H1N1 pandemic. We've already provided more than twice as many seasonal flu shots to patients this fall compared with the total we delivered during all of last year's flu season. And all of that is thanks to our nearly 16,000 pharmacists and Take Care health providers who are qualified to administer flu shots. No other retailer has that many health professionals immunizing the public.</p>
          <p>This is one example of how we are advancing the professional pharmacy as a valuable resource on healthcare's front line. They are going beyond the dispensing of medication to providing valuable healthcare services. Our platform for delivery in pharmacy and health and wellness services now extends to 7,000 drugstores, a specialty pharmacy and home infusion network and work site health centers and retail clinics. With that foundation we're taking Walgreens directly to employers, government entities, managed care companies and PBMs as a provider of pharmacy and health and wellness services.</p>
          <p>Our recent agreement with Caterpillar is an example of how we're doing that. As a result of working directly with Cat, we gave them proprietary transparent pricing to better manage their costs and improve overall health outcomes. And we're certainly encouraged by the traction this approach is getting in the market. Many other companies are talking to us about similar programs because of this compelling offer.</p>
          <p>In addition to taking our services directly to employers and other third parties, we're also going directly to consumers with our Prescription Savings Club. This program's offering discounted pricing on branded genetic medication to nearly two million members today. Another initiative we announced today will promote wellness and better treatment of chronic disease through a commitment to expand 90-day prescriptions at our retail pharmacies. We'll work with physicians, employers, managed care and PBMs to bring a 90-day retail option to a large population of patients across our national network of 7,000 pharmacies.</p>
          <p>Patients want a choice of getting prescriptions either through the mail or at their local community pharmacy. And when they have that choice, more often than not they choose a retail pharmacy. That increases patient interaction with their pharmacist and studies show that interaction leads to greater adherence to medications. A good example of the willingness of patients to try 90-day prescriptions can be found under the Medicare Part D plan.</p>
          <p>Part D has included a 90-day at retail option since its inception. And today more than 24% of our Part D beneficiaries' prescription volume is filled in 90-day quantities at our retail pharmacies. That takes into account that each 90-day prescription fill equals three times the volume of a 30 day fill.</p>
          <p>When a 90-day retail option is added to a prescription plan, total 90-day utilization increases. That benefits overall healthcare spending and lowers costs for both the patient and the payer. It is a great method for improving health outcomes and spending healthcare dollars more effectively. Whether patients want retail or mail service, we can serve them through whichever channel they desire.</p>
          <p>Now, I'd like to update you on the progress of our business strategies. Our success has evolved from the careful implementation of leveraging the best store network in America, enhancing the customer experience and achieving major cost reductions and productivity gains. First, leveraging our stores. After we reached our goal of 3,000 stores in the year 2000, we set a new goal to have 7,000 stores by 2010. On Thursday, we'll officially celebrate achieving that milestone with the grand opening of our 7,000th store located in Brooklyn, New York. With a total of 7,042 drugstores as of today, we're once again the largest drugstore chain in the country in terms of both store count and retail revenue. We're also now in all 50 states with our three Alaska stores opened this past summer. We reached our goal mostly through organic growth giving us an incredible foundation to build upon especially how young our stores are. For fiscal 2009, we registered a net gain of 554 stores including 70 acquisitions compared with 561 the previous fiscal year. In fiscal 2010 we expect organic store growth of between 4.5 to 5%.</p>
          <p>With our current growth strategy, we're now balancing the pace of new store openings with our commitment to improving our existing store base and enhancing the customer experience. Allowing stores to mature and drive higher ROIC is the right strategy in this economy, but it doesn't mean we're walking away from growth opportunities. We see opportunities to grow market share through continued organic store growth, driving comp store sales and pharmacy file buys. We'll also continue evaluating potential acquisitions that reinforce our core.</p>
          <p>Even before store growth slowed this quarter, we made significant progress on expense control. Slowing store growth will contribute even more to SG&amp;A control going forward. In the fourth quarter, SG&amp;A was helped by our Rewiring for Growth efforts and in fact &#x2013; and the fact that we've tightly managed store operating expenses. We were also helped by 149 stores opening this quarter down from 199 opened the year ago period.</p>
          <p>Moving to our second strategy of reinventing the customer experience, we're currently rolling out our Customer Centric Retailing format in more than 400 stores in Texas. We're pleased with the results from our CCR stores so far. The stores have better sight lines, less clutter and a brighter look. We expect CCR will not only improve comparable stores sales and the customer experience but it will also increase the number of customer visits and basket size. As we have said, CCR gives us a four way win, it helps us improve sales, it takes work out of the stores, it reduces capital deployed and it provides a better customer experience with greater relevancy and efficiencies.</p>
          <p>A key category that we're adding to our stores is beer and wine. We expect this category to roll out over the next 12 to 18 months and although beer and wine will comprise less than 1% of total shelf space in a typical store, we believe it will increase basket size and drive traffic in our stores.</p>
          <p>If you didn't take the time to check it out this morning take a look at our redesigned walgreens.com site which we launched about a month ago. It offers a much improved online experience including new convenience features, product merchandizing, integrated health content and a new mobile version. We also feature seven Health Shops that bring together products, services and latest news and information.</p>
          <p>And lastly, our Rewiring for Growth initiative remains on track to deliver $1 billion in annual EBIT cost savings beginning in fiscal 2011. We have a relentless focus on cost reduction and productivity gains and that will continue. When you combine our SG&amp;A control with our goals for gross profit dollar growth, we have a real opportunity to expand our operating margins.</p>
          <p>As you've heard, our investments focus on the customer experience, getting more from the &#x2013; our core store base and bringing innovative programs to the market positioning us for the new economy and healthcare reform.</p>
          <p>Tying all this together is a new branding campaign we launched about a week ago. Our new branding includes the tag line Walgreens: There's a way. This reflects our customers' desire for someone to help make life easier for them. They want a little reminder, a little inspiration to live all around better healthier lives. Walgreen will do that by providing simple solutions or small improvements such as flu shots to stay healthy or the convenience of photo services to connect with family. You'll see and hear a lot from this campaign in the weeks and months ahead. If you want to see the commercials on demand, check them out on You Tube. We're providing a link on our Investor Relations website directly to the videos.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Wade I'd like to mention a couple of recent additions in our management team. Jason Dubinsky recently joined us as Divisional Vice President and Treasurer. Jason is leading our Treasury department and Corporate Risk Management practice. He has a strong background in retail and consumer sectors having worked closely with corporate clients in those industries while with Goldman Sachs. And also Tim Theriault joined us as our new Senior Vice President and Chief Information Officer. Tim joins us from Northern Trust Company and brings a unique combination of leadership, innovation and business intellect with a background as both a technology and banking executive. I know both Tim and Jason will do very well in their new positions.</p>
          <p>Now Wade will update you on our financial results from the quarter. Wade?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Greg. Let me get right into the financial details. In the quarter net sales increased 7.6% while total comp sales rose 2.4%. Prescription sales rose 9% and represented nearly 67% of sales for the quarter. Prescription sales in comp stores rose a solid 4.5%. We filled 182 million prescriptions during the quarter, an increase of 9.1%. That includes a benefit of 1.4 percentage points from patients filling 90-day rather than 30-day scripts.</p>
          <p>On a comp store basis, the number of prescriptions increased to 5.9% and that includes a benefit of 1.8 percentage points from patients filling 90-day versus 30-day scripts. We exceeded by five percentage points the industry-wide pharmacy growth rate excluding Walgreens, as reported by IMS.</p>
          <p>Net earnings in the fourth quarter were $436 million or $0.44 per diluted share and that included the impact of $0.03 in Rewiring cost and $0.07 in savings associated with the company's Rewiring for Growth initiatives. This reflects a 1.5% decrease from the $443 million or $0.45 per diluted share in the same quarter a year ago, but recall that last year's quarter included the benefit of a vacation accrual adjustment of $79 million or $0.05 per diluted share. In addition, the quarter included impacts of negative $0.01 per diluted share for the LIFO reserve, negative $0.01 per diluted share for interest expense versus a year ago and a positive $0.01 per diluted share from a lower tax rate.</p>
          <p>For the fiscal year net sales increased 7.3% to $63.3 billion, while net earnings in the year was $2.01 billion or $2.02 per diluted share and that includes the impact of $0.16 in costs and about $0.16 in savings associated with the company's Rewiring for Growth initiatives. Net earnings reflect a 7% decrease from last year and also included the impact of last year's $0.05 per diluted share benefit from the vacation accrual adjustment, negative $0.04 per diluted share for this year's LIFO reserve, negative $0.04 per diluted share versus a year ago for interest expense and a positive $0.02 per diluted share from a lower tax rate. Total prescription dollar sales increased 7.8% while the number of scripts increased 6.9%.</p>
          <p>Comp front-end sales were down slightly for the fiscal year. Total comp sales increased 2% and comp scripts increased 3.6% higher than the previous year. Gross profit in the fourth quarter was $4.3 billion, a 7.7% increase versus the year ago quarter. Gross margin was up 10 basis points compared with the year ago quarter to 27.7%. This includes a LIFO provision of $48 million in this year's quarter versus a provision of $24 million in last year's fourth quarter, helping overall margins was an increase in retail pharmacy margins for the generics.</p>
          <p>Negatively impacting margin were non-retail businesses, front-end product mix, a higher LIFO provision and CCR markdowns. For the full fiscal year, our gross profit declined 40 basis points while the same factors were at play, the increases in retail pharmacy margins didn't completely offset the negative factors.</p>
          <p>Our focus on cost control continued in the fourth quarter as we recorded an increase in SG&amp;A dollars of 9.6%, now this includes 2.6 percentage points due to last year's vacation accrual adjustment and 0.9 percentage points for Rewiring for Growth costs. On a two year stacked basis, SG&amp;A dollar growth for the fourth quarter declined from 23.4% to 14.1%.</p>
          <p>And as Greg showed you, slowing new store openings will continue to benefit SG&amp;A growth as will the significant cost benefits resulting from Rewiring for Growth. We will also have incremental SG&amp;A expenses due to CCR store resets as we've previously discussed.</p>
          <p>Now this next chart summarizes the savings in cost for Rewiring for Growth restructuring charges for fiscal year 2009. $0.16 in savings were offset by $0.16 in cost for the fiscal year. Total rewire expenses for the year were approximately $257 million. So you can get approximately $140 million in fiscal 2010. We are on target for a net pre-tax savings of about $500 million in fiscal year 2010 and a net pre-tax savings of $1 billion in fiscal 2011.</p>
          <p>We talked about sales, margins and earnings, so let's review some additional income statement details now. The LIFO provision was $48 million versus $24 million in the fourth quarter of 2008. Our LIFO provision this year was 2% compared with a provision of 1.28% in fiscal 2008. We're expecting the LIFO provision for 2010 to be approximately 2%.</p>
          <p>Next, there was $51 million in restructuring cost in the quarter including $23 million in consulting and other costs, $19 million in SKU discontinuation and $9 million in costs associated with work force reductions. For the fiscal year, we incurred $63 million in write-downs related to SKU discontinuations and we're about 70% through that process.</p>
          <p>Net interest expense was $23 million compared with $7 million last year through the issuance of a $1 billion bond in January of 2009. Net interest expense benefited from a fixed rate to floating rate swap executed in July of 2009 on the $1.3 billion note issued that same month.</p>
          <p>The effective tax rate was 35.8% compared with a rate of 37.1% in the year ago period. We expect a tax rate of approximately 37% in fiscal 2010.</p>
          <p>Accounts receivable, inventory and accounts payable are the components of working capital that we most can directly impact. The net sum of these as a percent of sales has improved by 14.1% in the quarter, primarily due to inventory improvement.</p>
          <p>Total inventories were down $460 million or 6.3% against total sales growth of 7.6% and a total drugstore growth of 8.6%. FIFO total inventories on a per store basis fell 11.1% in the most recent quarter. Controlling inventory continues to be a top priority. And even with lower inventories, our in-stock conditions improved in the fourth quarter compared with a year ago.</p>
          <p>Now as you're aware, controlling inventory helps cash. Our net cash position at the end of the quarter was $236 million, which compares favorably with a net cash of $52 million at the end of the third quarter and a net debt of over $1.5 billion at the end of the first quarter. Cash and cash equivalents and short-term investments totaled $2.6 billion and long-term debt totaled $2.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Our financial flexibility and liquidity are in very good shape and our balance sheet should only strengthen as we slow our store growth, control inventory and drive cost savings over the next few years.</p>
          <p>For fiscal year 2009, we invested $1.9 billion in additions to property, plant and equipment versus $2.25 billion last year. For fiscal 2010, reducing the number of store opening will result in lower CapEx for our new stores, but we will increase our investments for systems and other improvements in existing stores. In total we anticipate fiscal 2010 capital expenditures to be approximately $1.6 billion.</p>
          <p>Now let me cover our cash flow performance. These graphs demonstrate the improvement in cash that we have generated from our store operations and improved working capital. Our cash flow from operations in the quarter increased to $852 million from $548 million a year ago, a 55% increase. Meanwhile, free cash flow this quarter stood at $459 million compared with a negative $24 million a year ago. For the fiscal year, cash flow from operations increased 35% to a record $4.1 billion. And free cash flow for the year increased 168% to a record $2.2 billion.</p>
          <p>We plan to continue returning cash to our shareholders through a combination of dividends and buy-backs. And we are developing a specific cash policy that will complement our business plan. That policy will give all stakeholders more clarity regarding our capital allocation decisions and principles going forward.</p>
          <p>So, looking ahead I am very optimistic about Walgreens' future. We have many opportunities starting with our three core strategies, which is leveraging the best retail network in America, driving CCR as a beginning of our journey towards a new customer focus and realizing the benefits of Rewiring for Growth.</p>
          <p>Walgreens is very well positioned to emerge from this economic climate as a leader in pharmacy and health and wellness services. For healthcare payers, accessibility, cost efficiency and better outcomes are the top priority. And we're able to step up here and help. On the consumer side, growing companies with wining strategies and a strong balance sheet can gain loyal customers in unprecedented ways during down economies and we intend to be one of those strong companies and a true winner.</p>
          <p>This was another quarter of strong cash flow and we're positioned to take advantage of growth opportunities and provide attractive returns. We believe the initiatives in progress that Greg and I have outlined this morning will benefit investors through accelerated earnings growth and continued dividend increases and share repurchases.</p>
          <p>No doubt we do face some headwinds such as pharmacy reimbursement and an AWP reduction for Medicaid brand named drugs that could impact us by as much as 80 to $90 million this next fiscal year. And we also face a slowdown in generic introductions for the next one or two years and an uncertain economy. But we also have key strategies and wonderful assets that give us unprecedented opportunities and I remain very confident.</p>
          <p>So I'll close by saying we are committed to return to double-digit earnings growth as soon as possible and improving ROIC as part of our overall plan to create long-term shareholder value. And I hope that I have conveyed that message to you today. And now I'll turn the call back to over to Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Wade. Mark, that concludes our prepared remarks, we're now ready to take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question today will come from John Heinbockel with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey guys, a couple of things, how far are we through the CCR-related clearance of SKU rationalized inventory and how much more is to go?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, John, Greg. We're probably a little more than 70% through and feel pretty good about that. As you know we've kind of took an early strategy to where we took the markdowns and did them within the department. So, feel pretty good, we're a little over 70%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And then secondly when you look at the &#x2013; I mean it sort of sounds like you think pharmacy margins could be down over the next year but I would also think maybe front-end could be up and overall maybe end up closer to flat. Is that that sort of a fair take on the two parts of the business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think certainly on the front-end we're going to have to &#x2013; with a tight consumer and a cautious consumer, we're going to have to make sure we stay focused and swing doors and really drive value. So we've got to balance that obviously. We think we've got some good opportunity there with private brand and CCR what we're doing there. So we think we've got opportunities to balance what we may have to do to drive value and drive traffic.</p>
          <p>As far as pharmacy margins, I think that certainly with the headwinds that Wade mentioned with the AWP reduction. We're going to be tackling that and staying aggressive there. On the commercial side, we feel like we've made good progress. Most of the commercial payers realize that they need to keep us whole. States, kind of state-by-state we'll be working with those. So, we'll see how that comes out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'd just say John you have to balance that obviously there is some reimbursement pressure but I think we've got also good traction in the business. We've got good services as we've talked things like the flu shots. And then the overall margin we've made good progress in cost control and across the board and as we move farther into Rewire, that's just going to get stronger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. One final thing from me, how do you guard against taking too much cost out to the point that it impacts service? I mean, to date I don't think that's happened but how do you guard against that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good question, John, basically by just staying on top of the surveys in our employee surveys, the customer surveys and we feel good there. We're doing, from what we see coming back from pharmacy we've got good satisfaction responses there. Our wait time has improved from last year as I mentioned a couple of weeks ago. We've actually cut our wait time pretty dramatically in pharmacy. So actually the store operators and our folks out in the stores are doing a darn good job in maintaining service levels while we take expense out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would just remind you, you know, our transformation initiative Rewire for Growth does include the growth word, and the whole key of this thing is really around reengineering the way we do work. I think the CCR is a classic example, right, how can we not only be more consumer centric and provide a better experience, but do those things in a way which take work out of the stores for employees and get a double, triple, quadruple win. So, I think it really is around reengineering, we've done a lot of that and we'll have to do a lot more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Lisa Gill, JP Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much and good morning. I was just wondering if you could comment on the Caterpillar deal and maybe just talk us a little bit through how that works and what this proprietary pricing is? And then secondly, as we think about the 90-day script at retail, is that more profitable for you than a 30-day script?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Lisa, Greg, as far as the Caterpillar deal, as I said the neat thing there is, is that's us going directly to an employer to give them wide proprietary pricing. And I think that's what's really exciting about that. Those are the two big points that we went directly to an employer and because of that we were able to give them our proprietary pricing. And I think we're encouraged as I said because we're getting a lot of interest in that.</p>
          <p>Switching to the 90-day, I think this is really a win, win, win. It's great for patients. There's definitely a market out there for it, we know that through Part D and through our Prescription Savings Club Card. As I said with Part D, a 90-day retail and mail option has been available since its inception. We're up to as I said 23, 24% penetration there. So consumers want it and the payers are beginning to see the real value. So it's been good for patients, it's good for payers, it's good for us. And obviously as far as the margin, you've got to recall when we take the cost down of three fills versus one fill at a 90-day. So we expect the margins to be pretty good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so just so I understand, so the margins generally will be better on a 90-day script than a 30-day script and then as you think about these relationships, are you signing any preferred relationships with any of the managed care companies around 90-day script to try to drive volume to a Walgreens store?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll handle the margin question, you know obviously it's &#x2013; every situation is going to be different, but we, as Greg said, I think we can provide a better experience for patients, a better cost for the payer and be fine on our end. With respect to managed care, certainly we'll working broadly with managed care, PBMs and other employers direct to make sure that they have the opportunity to avail of the 90-day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think, Lisa, as far as any preferred relationships, that's &#x2013; our intent really is just to make sure that we offer this to all payers on a broad approach. So, if somebody wants to prefer us that's great, but we really want to just make sure that we can offer this to all payers regardless of how they want to construct their network.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just one follow-up question then, as you talked about the margins on pharmacy, the fact that Apotex is out of the market and some of the generic manufacturers are raising price, are you taking that into account, in your previous comments around generic margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we have a pretty sophisticated model, obviously it's a very complex matrix of lots of different drugs, lots of different payers, lots of different parts of the country, but yeah that's all factored in. And so there's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And are you seeing an impact from that, from less manufacturers in the market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean it's all manageable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question will come from Scott Mushkin with Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks guys and obviously a real solid fourth quarter. What I was hoping to do was tag on the last two questions that were asked, number one; I really didn't understand the margin answer for 2010. The way I'm penciling it out with 500 million of savings, maybe a give back of 80 to 90 is that we could earn 240 to 250 next year? And I'm just trying to understand the margin question it seemed to &#x2013; you guys seemed to hint that margins might be down both in the front end and the pharmacy? So I was wondering if you could give us a little clarity on that, and then I want to follow up on Lisa Gill's question if I could.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I would say, obviously it's a lot more complex that just the 500 benefit and then the 80-90 AWP. I mean reimbursement pressure, there are other pressures. There is still AMP issue pending and of course there's lots of payers that are under pressure so, there are other reimbursement pressures beyond that. Now there always has been and it's kind of always, it's always every year it's always the same struggle, but I wouldn't want to say that's the only reimbursement pressure.</p>
          <p>I think what Greg was alluding to in the front end, and I think we have a wonderful opportunity to drive a much bigger basket, more traffic. There might be some balancing over time though to make sure that the value equation is right. So we'll be looking also at total gross profit dollars delivered there by becoming more relevant and driving a lot more volume versus just focusing on the gross profit percent. It doesn't mean that it will definitely go down, but again I think what we want to do over time is become much more relevant, drive much more volume through there and if we can maximize gross profit dollars that might be a better way to go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So as we look at next year, because we noticed in the marketplace, you guys are reducing your prices pretty actively with the green tags in the front end. I mean, are we, do we need a substantial uptick in front end sales to maintain that dollars that you mentioned, Wade?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Scott, Greg, as I said, retail obviously balances &#x2013; is balancing margin and traffic and so we are getting sharper on value items in our rotos, some key value items within the stores making sure we're priced right. We have to do that to make sure we stay relevant. At the same time we've got to manage mix as we always do and we have to drive private brand to be able to offset that and believe me that's what we'll be doing is focusing on that right balance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think it's also it's a portfolio, Scott. You know there is items where we just weren't competitive on key driving items and we're getting competitive. There's a lot of other items where we were far below the price of anyone and that probably doesn't make a lot of sense for our format. So, I think it's really making sure that we play the portfolio in the smartest way to be relevant on the items where we have to be dead-on relevant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now switching gears to the 90-day script issue that Lisa was talking about, I mean, you guys have always said that 90-day scripts, and I think it's always been common in the retail industry, are less profitable than three 30-days and has something changed there, because that's kind of how Walgreen and everyone else has always presented it. And I was just wondering if you could clarify that margin issue when you go to &#x2013; from 30 to 90?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Scott, Greg. I think again when you look at the gross profit dollars of a 90-day script versus a 30 and then you look at the cost to fill reduction obviously for two fills &#x2013; from three fills to one, we feel pretty happy. We launched this, if you recall, back in probably 2003, 2004 maybe with Advantage90 through WHI and that's when it really began &#x2013; 90-day at retail really began to take off. And then as you know, we worked hard to get it into Part D plans and we feel confident that if a patient wants a 90-day quantity and they want to be able to get it at retail, then we should be able to offer it. And we feel that the -- we're okay on the margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I can also tell you there is a very, very big market out there of people that are getting 90-day at mail who wish they had the opportunity to get it at retail. So, obviously for them, they'd be able to have the opportunity and the choice. As we said before, more often than not they choose retail when they have that choice. That incremental business for us is a very good business. So what we want to do is really be able to be I'd say agnostic in terms of 30-day, 90-day, drive-through, in-store, mail, you name it and give the patient, the payer, the choice that's right for them whatever that might be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then one final and then I'll give it up, is the Cat deal restricted, in other words people have to fill at Walgreen or no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Or is it preferred in other words...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll give you a simple. Obviously we don't want to &#x2013; we're not going to go into a lot of detail on our proprietary pricing, but the general construct is that the more services that Cat avails of that Walgreens can offer and the more volume that comes through, the better the pricing we can offer. So, what we're really trying to do is incent a win, win.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's similar to CVS' Maintenance Choice and it's a preferred network?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's not preferred. It just &#x2013; well it basically just incents the pricing again for the more volume that comes through the network.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Scott, I think with Caterpillar, they're certainly going to try to encourage folks to use Walgreen to take advantage of the pricing we're giving them, but it's not an excluded network by any means and that's &#x2013; and we're not interested in that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks. I'll give up the floor. Thanks for taking my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question will come from Andrew Wolf, BB&amp;T Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, congratulations on the quarter. Just wanted to ask you a follow-up on a &#x2013; first on, can you update sort of the cost to do the remodels that you spoke to last quarter, you said you learned, got some learnings on that, if you could &#x2013; where that might? And also on the flip side the kind of sales lift, either you're getting or you expect and how much of that could be offset because last quarter most of us came away trying to figure out what the net impact of that would be on this year's earnings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The cost as we said before is between 30 and 50,000 per store. I'd say we kind of tracking dead center of that so I think we've estimated that pretty accurately. In terms of the sales lift, we haven't given a number, but I would say that the payback period from what we're seeing and projecting is pretty quick. So if you take 5,000 stores times 40,000, you get to around a couple hundred million dollars but we're going to see, we believe in the fiscal year benefits in terms of sales uplift, cost reductions that should offset most or all of that. So we kind of basically called that a wash for the most part. And again because the payout period it's a very high ROIC, making these current stores more productive is really the single greatest lever we can pull on ROIC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Andy, as far as the cost, the good thing is now that we're in a couple of major markets like Dallas and Houston, where we can really leverage scale the reset teams we're looking forward to seeing what we really can do as far as the efficiencies and drive that cost down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And are these remodels, I know you still have a pretty small sample size, but it still on the sales lift, still tracking above what you had originally planned?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We're still encouraged with what we're seeing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I just wanted to flip on to one follow-up. On the Caterpillar deal, some of the industry consultants have characterized it as market share driven, but discount pricing and I'm just trying to understand what that means for Walgreens particularly since there is a large cost component removed by not using a full service PBM. How the &#x2013; whether that, using part of that exclusion of that outflow of some of the profit dollars, where that leaves Walgreens, obviously we know where it leaves Caterpillar, but where it leaves Walgreens?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Andy, again I think the neat thing is because we went direct to Cat, we were able to give them pricing that is good fair pricing for both they and us. And as Wade said, it's based on volume. It's the first time where instead of giving a price without the opportunity to grow volume or other services, that we've been able to work out an arrangement where it's good for Cat and for us. So, it's &#x2013; they're realizing the savings because there's no one between they and us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So your contribution dollars, are they going to go up exponentially or linearly with market share, let's put it that way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I wouldn't comment exactly. I would just say I'd reiterate what Greg said which is, it's a good deal for us and it's a good deal for Cat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a true win, win.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And Mark Miller with William Blair has a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. A follow-up to a prior question on re-models. About how many of the new format stores do you think you might convert in the next fiscal year? I know your plans have been 5,000, but how does that get spread across fiscal '10 and fiscal '11? Then as you look at that expense drag, net of the sales lift, how large of a negative might that be for remodels versus the benefit to earnings as you're slowing the store growth in this next year could those two balance out, or would it tip one way or the other?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're still identifying the number of stores but we're probably talking somewhere around 4,000. As you know, there is a very low-end 3,500 to five on the very upper end. But we've got a lot of new stores coming out they don't need the remodel. We have certain other formats that it really doesn't make sense to. But what I would say, Mark, as kind of for the previous comment we think that for the most part they'll balance out, right? so might it go, 20, 30 million one way or another it might but for the most part, we believe it will balance out because of the lift we're getting, some of the cost efficiencies and some of the other work we're doing around CCR to be more effective in our promotion, our pricing et cetera. So I'd say I think it's largely going to be a wash.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But my question Wade was also factoring in the benefit to earnings as you slow the store growth, does that then imply that it becomes a net benefit when I take those two dynamics together?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There will be some benefit from slowing store growth. So we haven't put a number out there, but obviously, that really compounds over time. So as we go from eight, 9% to 5% you get some benefit, but over time it really starts to roll through. So it would be even stronger the following year, and much stronger the year after that, but yeah, there could be some incremental benefit from that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, my second question is looking at the inventory, impressive management overall, how much of that is coming from SKU rationalization? How much of it from other working capital initiatives, POWER, I'm wondering if that could be a benefit? And then just how much further can Walgreens go optimizing inventory turns? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Mark, Greg. We're seeing probably about an equal mix between what we're seeing from CCR and what we're seeing from supply chain initiatives. And I'm really enthused with frankly what we're seeing more on the supply chain. I think the CCR reductions we kind of expected, but I think we're making real progress on supply chain with Randy Lewis working with our vendors. And we're also really making progress on the pharmacy side as well, and that's more from really fine tuning the safety stock and the actual quantity that we need to have on hand. So I think there is still, there is still upside for us. I think we've got a lot of potential to improve our supply chain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the real trick for as we do believe there is opportunity, but we're going to make sure we keep taking out inventory while we improve our service levels at the same time and we're going to be able to do those two things in concert by changing how we think about it and how we work, and how are processes work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're working with vendors on a much greater way than we have in the past and as I've said in the past, Randy now has vendor &#x2013; inventory from the day it leaves the vendor to the day it hits the consumers' hand. There's a lot of opportunity there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Just finally, looking for the flaw in these results, not obvious but my comment would be it would be nice if you had bought back stock sooner, and hopefully that will come. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question will come from Ed Kelly with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. Good morning guys. Nice results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wade, your D&amp;A was up only about 1% this quarter, I mean it's been up a lot more than that historically. Is there something that we should read into that, is there a reason that it wasn't up so much, and how should we look at that going forward? Is this going to be a more normalized growth rate now that your CapEx spend is coming down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's right. I think it's more normalized now what you're seeing. Slowing store growth is starting to impact it a bit and then the mix in terms of obviously where we've been spending I think the rates we're seeing I think it will be more normalized now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, at best we should be thinking about sort of low single-digit type D&amp;A growth going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe single-to-mid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Single-to-mid?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll do some refining on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then Wade, if you could just go through the $1 billion in cost saves. When you initially laid that out you had a few buckets there, could you talk about where you are in each of those buckets in terms of relative to your initial plan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, you know there was the three core big buckets, the first one was basically indirect spend that's 250 million, all the things we buy that we don't sell to people. And then there is $500 million which was corporate labor, field labor, store labor et cetera, payroll effectively and then another $250 million of benefits associated with really transforming community pharmacy.</p>
          <p>I would say that in all three of these we are on plan with what we predicted. In fact, the net benefit we had originally said would be zero this year and it basically did end up zero, but we had a lot more cost this year and lot more benefit than originally thought. And that's because we pulled forward many of these initiatives, so we pulled forward the one time but in some cases also pulled forward the benefits. So again without giving the specific year-by-year of the buckets on all three we believe we're on track, we're on track for 500 million next year and we believe we're in good shape for the billion in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then Greg, just last question for you, you mentioned acquisitions as sort of supplementing the core strategy. Could you maybe just talk little bit about what you sort of have in mind there, are we talking solely healthcare, retail opportunity are these just sort of smaller bolt-on deals, would you consider something larger? Any help there would be great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, yeah, Ed. I think as I said we want to stay flexible to look at whatever opportunities come our way. We think we've built some pretty sophisticated platforms on the healthcare side. We've got the leading infusion platform now, a strong specialty platform and we're combining those because we think there is true differentiation to take a specialty/infusion platform to the payer. So we feel good there, I think the Take Care Clinic platform gives us the ability to really launch more and more health and wellness services as we do focus more on prevention of chronic disease going forward, I feel good there. Our employer health sites as well, we've got a good a platform.</p>
          <p>So I think there's some gap fillers maybe on the healthcare side that maybe we may need to look at, but I think just &#x2013; we want to just stay flexible and look at whatever may come to us. There will definitively be some consolidation on the retail side of the business, but we'll run it through our filter and make sure we make good decisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question will come from Steve Halper with Thomas Weisel Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, good morning, just to clarify, so the AWP hit based on the settlement that was announced a couple of days ago, that's a done deal, that's what you think the cost is going to be in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't say it's a done deal, I think the range we feel very confident with, I think there's lot of work to be done, Steve, we're going to do everything we can do to even improve upon that. As I said the commercial side, we feel good about, we've got some work to do, but they've pretty much realized they want to make us whole and on the state side it'd be state-by-state. And I think states are strapped for cash, so they've been a little slower to come along. But as we've dealt with each state in the past we'll handle each one uniquely and continue to try to work with them to help them find other ways to save money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, so would you characterize the 80 to 90 as your worst case?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's safe to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And next we'll hear from John Ransom with Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, just following up on the AWP question, I think when we were out there in August you had that number at about 150 million, have you just refined your estimates or have you had any state wins to bring that number down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there has been a lot of work done John, in the last several months. Certainly all of us in this industry have had this is one of our top priorities. So we've had our folks working the commercial side aggressively and have really made some good progress there. And again the states have been a little slower, but we're going to continue to work with each state to try to help them find other ways to reduce costs. And we worked with the State of Washington, the State of Delaware and ended up with good results in both those states and we expect to do the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, second question, your script trends per store were up quite a bit year-over-year. How much of that is market growth and how much of that is market share do you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're exceeding the market share &#x2013; the IMS numbers without WAG pretty significantly. So we feel good there. Obviously we're rounding some softer comparisons from a year ago, but you know, I think we're also seeing some positive numbers from the file buys that we've made over the recent 12 months.</p>
          <p>And I think we're also seeing people begin to stay more compliant on their drugs. I think in the heat of the economic downturn, I think we saw people splitting pills and skipping doses and I think we're beginning to see that soften a little.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then lastly talking about your 90-day at retail, you're filling about 5%, I think of, up quite a bit. What &#x2013; just looking at the strictures of your commercial plans and the ones that would only do 90 days on their own retail -- their own mail platform, what's the upper limit of what you could do 90-day at retail, do you think, and how much should we expect those script &#x2013; that penetration to grow and what kind of effect do you think it has on your P&amp;L? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On an adjusted number, when I look at what's going on with Part D in the marketplace and even our Prescription Savings Club Card. Part D, the marketplace we're at about 24% as I said on an adjusted basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Prescription Savings Club Card we're looking at nearly 40%. I think there's a big upside as the payers begin to see more value as well as patients. The good thing about this is when a payer adds a 90-day retail benefit to an existing 90-day mail benefit, 90-day utilization increases, adherence improves, patients and payers both save. So I think there's a huge market out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is there a structural, at least in the short-term, a structural resistance from the Medcos and Express Scripts of the world that don't want to lose that 90-day mail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There will been some natural resistance certainly. But again I always go to the marketplace and as patients begin to want it and demand it and as the payers that are offering it begin to see value, the marketplace begins to dictate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. As you guys go through your Board process for allocation of future free cash flow which is, you're now net debt &#x2013; your cash exceeds your debt. You're obviously going to be generating a lot of cash flow. How do you plan to communicate that to the marketplace? Are you going to have some kind of press release following your Board or are you just going to talk about it on your next conference call? How do you plan to get that message to the marketplace?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we definitely once we finalize it and approve it, we definitely will communicate it. I don't know exactly how we will, but we'll make sure that we do, and we do it broadly and we're very clear about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question will come from Debra Weinswig with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning this is actually Nathan Rich filling in for Deb. First question I wanted suss on is on your Rewiring for Growth initiative. It seems like you've seeing pretty strong performance in store payroll, I was just wondering if you can share some more details on the work that you've done there and what changes we can expect going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think on store payroll as far as &#x2013; a lot of it is the work that we're removing from stores chain wide, some of that is coming from CCR, others is just us re-looking at a lot of the processes. I think some of it has been looking at hours of operation to make sure we're right for the marketplace. But really just a real good effort in improving the efficiencies, re-looking at some of the processes and the work that we've been asking our stores to do. And one of the things I'm most encouraged by with CCR and the early responses we're getting from store managers is the fact that they say it's getting easier to run a drugstore. And I think that in itself could be one of the biggest benefits we realize.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks and then just one follow-up, in terms of your Prescription Savings Club, it seems like the customer response has been pretty encouraging. I was just wondering if you see any opportunity to expand your loyalty program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, I agree with you, on our Prescription Savings Club Card, we're really encouraged with it and we think we can continue to grow it. And we are looking at a loyalty initiative and beginning to lay the early groundwork on it. We'll probably kind of pursue a CCR-type journey where we build a foundation and begin to look at a pilot and go from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, we'll take a question from Meredith Adler. [Barclays Capital]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and congratulations on a good quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Meredith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Meredith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You were talking about the three buckets from Rewire for Growth and I was wondering if the last piece was about community pharmacy and making some changes there? Are you still focused on central fill? I know you also talked about central phone calls, can you talk about kind of where that stands and how that's going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean obviously there is different components to the whole transformation pharmacy. There is what we call dynamic workload balancing, which is pushing paperwork across pharmacies. There is the front-end processing, which is streamlining and taking out call center work, paperwork, et cetera and there is central fill. I think what we're finding is, remember in the end what this is really about is being able to free up pharmacists' time to do more services, to do more consultations, to provide a better experience. It's about also being able to get scale, so that we can do some of the work more efficiently on the cost side. But we're finding in different places, there is different permutations that make more sense than others. So, sometimes central fill makes sense, sometimes it might not. Other times the central fill capability could be a great thing to link to specialty, to provide that kind of option in retail. So, it's really &#x2013; it plays key role but it depends on where we are geographically as to what makes the most sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Meredith, I'd like to add to that and certainly this has been nationwide but when we talk about transforming community pharmacy, in addition to what Wade's saying, we're really looking to not only take cost out but to improve the opportunity for our pharmacists to really play more of a greater role within healthcare. And this flu shot program that we launched and really helped provide a solution for is a great illustration of what pharmacists on the front line of healthcare can do, in addition what they've done in the past. So we're really pleased with this as an example what we can do going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, wonderful and then I have another question. Maybe to talk a little bit more about how you will leverage the Take Care centers onsite clinics to do even more in terms of managing chronic health conditions and are you putting a focus for the Take Care centers on getting managed care to pay for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Meredith, both good questions. I look at our Take Care Clinics as the platform that we have to now launch more and more health and wellness services. And as we move more toward a need for more prevention and management of chronic disease and health and wellness services we're positioned well to offer more health screenings, point of care diagnostics as we go forward. Second question was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second, I'm actually not quite sure, I mean, I think I wanted to know whether managed care was paying for the Take Care Clinics?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Managed care is, we're most &#x2013; nearly 70, 75% contracted and it depends on market, but most managed care is definitely contracted. And I think one of the neat things and the real opportunity with this business is it's been kind of a consumer pull model in the past. Where we've marketed, consumers were coming in using them on their own, satisfaction is off the charts. And as managed care now begins to see more value and understand how it can help them offer affordable, acceptable healthcare, I think you begin to see folks encourage the use of them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. This might &#x2013; maybe my follow &#x2013; final question would be about paying for some of these services. I mean that's always been perhaps the hardest thing in healthcare is to demonstrate real value from counseling and then to get paid for it. Can you talk about maybe how those conversations are developing with managed care organizations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. As I said today, obviously it's all about outcomes, and obviously we need the analytics to begin to be able to show what we are able to do. Managed care is extremely interested in paying for these services, more so than I probably have seen in the last year, two years and I think as long as we are able to show them the results and outcomes, there is &#x2013; we can monetize that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you have the analytics built?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We need a little more sophistication there, but we've got some pretty good clinical folks, some pretty good clinical teams that are helping us there and I want to begin to put a little more sophistication at it. We're ahead of where we need to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the worksite group that we have to undertake care has a big head start here because we've been able to work with a lot of employers directly with their data onsite to help manage outcomes at the really point of work and place care and I think that that's probably here a big advantage that we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Folks this is Rick, that was our final question. Thank you for joining us today. We'll announce our September sales on October 2. Please keep in mind that we include flu shots in our script totals rather than as front-end sales. Our next quarterly financial announcement will be on Monday, December 21. That's when we will announce fiscal 2010 first quarter results. Until then, thank you for listening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that does conclude our conference. Thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>