<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1319642" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-06-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>534</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Rick J. Hans, Divisional Vice President of Investor Relations and Finance</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Gregory D. Wasson, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Wade D. Miquelon, Executive Vice President, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Ann Hynes</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Edward Kelly</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Mark Wiltamuth</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Kermit Crawford</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Derek Leckow</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Meredith Adler</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">David Magee</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Bob Summers</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Deborah Weinswig</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Andrew Wolf</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to this Walgreen Companies third quarter 2010 earnings conference call. Today's call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn things over to Mr. Rick Hans, Divisional Vice President of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Erin. Good morning, everyone. Welcome to our third quarter fiscal 2010 conference call. Today, Greg Wasson, our President and CEO, will be discussing the quarter's highlights and our continued progress in executing our growth strategies. In addition, Wade Miquelon, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer, will detail our third quarter financial results. When we get to your questions, please limit yourself to one question and a follow-up so that we can give an opportunity to as many investors as possible during our limited time. Also joining us on the call and available for questions is Kermit Crawford, Executive Vice President of Pharmacy.</p>
          <p>As a reminder, today's presentation includes certain non-GAAP financial measures, and I would direct you to our website at investor.walgreens.com for a reconciliation. Also, I'm available throughout the day by phone to answer any additional questions you may have. You can find a link to our webcast under our Investor Relations website. After the call, the presentation will be archived on the website for 12 months. We're also making the call available as a podcast. You can download that too at our website.</p>
          <p>Certain statements and projections of future results made in this presentation constitute forward-looking information that is based on current market, competitive, and regulatory expectations that involve risk and uncertainty. Please see our latest Forms 10-K and 10-Q for a discussion of factors as they relate to forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn the call over to Greg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rick, and thank you everyone for joining us on our call. Before I discuss third quarter earnings, I'd like to briefly acknowledge our Friday announcement where we reached a multiyear agreement with CVS Caremark. We won't be providing specific details regarding the economics of the deal, but I would say that we are very pleased with the outcome. The agreement provides the framework we need to operate our business going forward, which is also good for our patients, our pharmacists, and shareholders. We look forward to continuing to meet the needs of patients and payers across the country. We also look forward to building a mutually beneficial relationship with CVS Caremark and other PBMs.</p>
          <p>Now let's move to the quarter. You saw from our press release this morning Walgreens reported record sales of $17.2 billion in the quarter, a 6.1% increase over last year. Third quarter net earnings were $463 million compared with $522 million in the same quarter a year ago. And we generated strong cash flow from operations of $1 billion in the quarter and $2.8 billion fiscal year to date.</p>
          <p>Our reported EPS of $0.47 included $0.04 in costs resulting from the Medicare Part D tax charge, $0.02 from the impact of our Duane Reade acquisition, and $0.01 from our Rewiring for Growth initiative.</p>
          <p>Net sales for the nine-month period grew 6.1% to $50.6 billion, and net earnings were up 3.2%.</p>
          <p>We anticipated that this would be a challenging quarter for several reasons. First, the weak economy continued to impact discretionary spending. Second, we faced prescription reimbursement pressure compounded by a slower period in the rate of introduction of new generics. And third, we were cycling last year's high incidence of H1N1 flu, which impacted prescription comps by more than 1% in the quarter. While we planned for these headwinds and saw a number of positive signs in the quarter, we also believe there is more we can do.</p>
          <p>Let me touch on some additional highlights of the quarter. We filled a record 198 million prescriptions and increased our market share to nearly 20%. We made significant progress on our customer centric retailing initiative, opening or converting 500 stores. We closed on our acquisition of Duane Reade and began the integration to drive the expected benefits and synergies. We continued on track with our cost control initiatives. We took steps to directly address some of the reimbursement pressure we're experiencing, and we restructured our health care division to bring new and unique pharmacy health and wellness solutions to the market.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a more detailed look at the quarter. This slide provides a good snapshot of the quarter's performance relative to recent trends. During the third quarter, gross profit dollars increased by 290 million or 6.5%. SG&amp;A dollars increased 307 million or 8.6%. It's important to note that without Duane Reade, gross profit dollars grew 3.2% and SG&amp;A dollars grew 6%. This rate of growth is near the low point of our SG&amp;A dollar growth over the last six years. Even at this low rate of SG&amp;A dollar growth, we are investing in areas that will generate incremental sales. These include our e-commerce group, our sales and client services organization, and our private brand business. At the same time, we continue our relentless focus on cost control.</p>
          <p>Gross profit dollars were impacted by the weak sales and reimbursements mentioned earlier. Our goal is to consistently drive gross profit dollar growth in excess of SG&amp;A dollar growth.</p>
          <p>Next, I'll give an update on our Customer Centric Retailing initiative. Here's a quick look at where we stood at the end of last quarter with total CCR stores. As you may recall, we expect CCR when fully implemented to improve sales, reduce working capital and store labor, and enhance the overall shopping experience. In order to achieve that, we are optimizing and enhancing our existing assortments. We are improving category and product adjacencies, improving sight lines throughout the store, and finally refreshing all our stores with a new in-store branding package.</p>
          <p>Through the end of the third quarter, we've completed the opening or conversion of over 1,200 stores, 500 more than we reported to you last. We now expect to have over 2,000 CCR format stores by the end of the calendar year. While this is fewer that the 2,500 to 3,000 we had previously anticipated, this slowdown is critical to applying important lessons to future conversions.</p>
          <p>Our latest CCR accomplishments include the following. The time needed to convert a store to CCR format is currently 20% less than the earlier conversions. We're adding key categories such as our successful beer and wine rollout, which is now in nearly 3,600 stores and on track to be in more than 5,000 stories by the end of the calendar year. And in the third quarter alone, this category added more than 50 basis points to front end sales comps.</p>
          <p>We added back several hundred products, primarily to the Complement product class in categories such as automotive and hardware. And we initiated the introduction of new SKUs in existing categories such as our new branded electronics set. All of this adds up to a refresh of our stores at a relatively low cost.</p>
          <p>Recall last quarter that we showed you the performance of our pilot CCR stores. At that time, front end sales at those stores were outperforming the control stores by 1.9%. I'm pleased to report today that for the 26-week period ending May 29, the same pilot stores are now outperforming the control stores by 2.6%.</p>
          <p>The Signature product class, in which we want to win versus all retailers, continues to outperform the control group by nearly 5%. Our Power product class, in which we want to be the best in the drugstore industry, has experienced an increase in sales from 2.4% last period to 3.1% this period. The Staples product class, which includes everyday needs, slipped slightly. We are sorting through the reasons now and we'll continue to focus on improving it. And in the Complement product class, which are impulse buys or convenience items, we added back SKUs to all stores, including the control group. And as you can see, the CCR stores improved versus the control group. So the Complement product class compromises (sic) [comprises] 6% of front end sales, and we are very pleased with the improved performance.</p>
          <p>Although results are preliminary, our second wave of CCR store conversions is trending well against the rest of the chain. And in Dallas, we're encouraged by the improvement in sales variance versus the rest of the chain as well. And if you recall, Houston had a larger percentage of stores impacted by the reduction of SKUs in the Complement product class that led to a more pronounced sales impact in those select stores which are now showing improvement with the reintroduction of key SKUs.</p>
          <p>We're also making good progress integrating Duane Reade into our company. Duane Reade's new format is performing well, and I would encourage you to visit our recently relocated Midtown Manhattan store, which is performing well above expectations.</p>
          <p>Duane Reade contributed $272 million of sales in the quarter. We believe that its business represents an excellent strategic fit with Walgreens. Since the acquisition, we are even more excited with our capabilities in urban retailing, loyalty, private brand, and beauty. We believe there is real opportunity to leverage these areas to the rest of our chain. And for example, an initial selection of Duane Reade's Delish private brand consumables will be issued across the chain in August.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, this was a challenging quarter, as we anticipated. Our strategy, which is built on the strength of our center of gravity, our 7,500 community drugstores, gives me confidence we can win in any environment. We're located within five miles of nearly 75% of the US population. Our plan with CCR is enhancing the customer experience and providing a low cost refresh of all stores. We continue to transform community pharmacy, to build on our nearly 20% market share, and improve the patient experience. This includes expanding our scope of services by offering flu shots and other immunizations.</p>
          <p>We're bringing new and unique pharmacy and health and wellness solutions to employers and other payers from our work site clinics to our hospital onsite pharmacies and from our specialty pharmacy to our market share leading home infusion capabilities, we offer a broad spectrum of healthcare solutions. And we continue to have a relentless focus on cost control and productivity gains.</p>
          <p>So in spite of the environment, we hit many milestones in the quarter. We generated strong cash flow, and we continue to return that cash to shareholders through a combination of share repurchases and dividends. Walgreens has already returned over $1 billion to shareholders this fiscal year.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, I'm very optimistic about our company. We're focused on leveraging our 7,500 convenient community drugstores, and I'm confident in our strategies and our goal to deliver double-digit earnings growth, increasing return on invested capital, and top tier shareholder return.</p>
          <p>And finally, I want to say how proud I am of the way our team members responded to a difficult environment and their commitment to drive sales, reduce costs, and improve customer service. I firmly believe their efforts will be reflected in our performance and future shareholder returns.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn the call over to Wade, who will update you on the financial results in the quarter. Wade?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Greg, and good morning, everyone. In the quarter, net sales increased 6.1%. Net earnings declined 11.4%. And earnings per diluted share were $0.47 or $453 million, down from $0.53 per diluted share or $522 million in the same quarter a year ago. Our reported EPS of $0.47 includes $0.04 in costs resulting from the Medicare Part D tax charge, $0.02 from the impact of the Duane Reade acquisition, and $0.01 from our Rewiring for Growth initiative, and that compares with $0.06 in Rewire costs in the year-ago period.</p>
          <p>Prescription sales rose 5.7% and represented 65% of sales for the quarter. Prescription sales in comp stores rose 1%. As Greg noted, we filled a record 198 million prescriptions during the quarter, an increase of 5.9% from a year ago. And that includes a benefit of one percentage point from patients filling 90-day rather than 30-day scripts. On a comp store basis, the number of prescriptions filled increased 2.5%, and that includes a benefit of 1.3 percentage points from 90-day scripts.</p>
          <p>Now let me say a few words about our front end comp store sales. These sales in the quarter were up 0.1% as we continue to face slower demand for discretionary goods. Also hampering the quarter were a weak flu season compared with last year's unusual H1N1 flu and the recall of certain OTC products.</p>
          <p>Despite this performance, we compare well to the industry. When viewing a true apples-to-apples time period that compares our front end comps with our top three competitors, we are outperforming them for the same periods they most recently reported, as shown in this chart. And this is another reason why we feel good about CCR.</p>
          <p>Turning to gross profit, the margin improved 10 basis points in the quarter. And the primary driver was an increase in front end margin, which more than offset the negative impact of lower margins in the pharmacy.</p>
          <p>On a dollar basis, I'll start by pointing out that the front end provided the majority of gross profit dollar growth in the quarter. As you may know, the rate of generic introductions and other factors can affect gross margins in ways that we believe distort our underlying performance. And as a result, we focus on gross profit dollar growth as an important performance metric, and that grew by $290 million in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at some of the drivers of that gross profit dollar growth. The pharmacy gross profit dollar growth was negatively impacted by two primary factors. First, we are in a period of slower rate of generic drug introductions. We expect less impact from this in fiscal 2011, and a significant benefit in fiscal 2012 due to the large number of new generic introductions scheduled for that year. And second, we continue to be impacted by reimbursement pressure, which we have experienced for years.</p>
          <p>But looking at the bigger picture, our core pharmacy business is strong and is expected to get stronger, as indicated by our record scripts filled, market share increases, our expanded pharmacy, health, and wellness solutions, and that includes flu shots and other innovative programs such as optimal wellness and 90-day refills.</p>
          <p>Moving to SG&amp;A trends, the two-year stacked SG&amp;A dollar growth showed some improvement compared with the year-ago quarter, dropping from 17.6% to 16.5%. And when you adjust the two-year stacked SG&amp;A dollar growth for the acquisition of Duane Reade, you will see it drops from 17.6% last year to 13.4% this year, and this illustrates our continued focus on SG&amp;A control.</p>
          <p>Let me walk you through this SG&amp;A adjustment. We reported SG&amp;A growth of 8.6% in the quarter. First, we adjusted for the net impact of Rewiring for Growth, which had higher costs last year. And next, we accounted for the acquisition and operating expense associated with Duane Reade, which gets us to SG&amp;A growth for the quarter of 6%.</p>
          <p>Some of our improvement can be traced to the benefits from Rewiring for Growth, and this chart summarizes the savings and costs for restructuring since its inception. The net savings in the quarter was $0.04 per share versus the year-ago period. And please note, we added two new lines to this chart to illustrate the cumulative savings by quarter and the total run rate savings over the 2008 base year. You can see that restructuring benefits are on track, with cumulative savings by quarter at $0.11 per share and the run rate over the 2008 base year at $0.37 per share.</p>
          <p>Total Rewire expenses this quarter were $17 million, and for the first nine months they totaled $87 million. We expect approximately $140 million in Rewire expenses in fiscal 2010, although some of these costs may not be fully realized until early fiscal 2011. We remain on target for net pre-tax savings of $500 million this fiscal year and net pre-tax savings of $1 billion in fiscal 2011, both versus our base year of 2008.</p>
          <p>Now, let's review some additional income statement details. The LIFO provision was $18 million versus $32 million in the third quarter of 2009. That represents an anticipated LIFO provision of 1.25% for the year net of the $17 million of restructuring costs in the quarter.</p>
          <p>The effective tax rate was 42.5% compared with a tax rate of 36.4% in the year-ago period. The higher rate was impacted by a non-cash charge due to the elimination of Medicare Part D subsidy. We expect a tax rate of approximately 37% in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Accounts receivable, inventory, and accounts payable are the components of working capital that we can most directly impact, and the net sum of these as a percent to sales fell 4.1% in the quarter compared with a year ago. Total FIFO inventories rose 4.3% against total sales growth of 6.1% and total store growth of 9.7%, including Duane Reade. FIFO total inventories on a per-store basis fell 4.9% in the third quarter. Controlling inventory continues to be a top priority. And as you can see, we have consistently made great strides over the past six quarters.</p>
          <p>Cash flow from operations for the first nine months of the fiscal year was $2.8 billion. Free cash flow increased to $2 billion in the first nine months versus $1.7 billion in the same period last year. Cash and cash equivalents and short-term investments totaled $2.3 billion, and our long-term debt totaled $2.4 billion.</p>
          <p>To update you on capital expenditures, last quarter we estimated $1.4 billion for the year. We now anticipate CapEx for fiscal 2010 to be around $1.2 billion, as we make sure we're focusing on investing in the right projects at the right time.</p>
          <p>Our strong cash flow and balance sheet allowed us to pay out $136 million in dividends during the quarter and buy back $254 million in company stock. In the first nine months of the fiscal year, we returned more than $1 billion in dividends and share repurchases. We plan to continue returning cash to our shareholders through a combination of dividends and buybacks, which nearly tripled in the first nine months compared to the year-ago period. Our current dividend payout ratio is 25%, and you will recall that we previously set a long-term dividend payout ratio of between 30 and 35% of net earnings. The next dividend announcement will be on July 14.</p>
          <p>Like Greg, I am confident in our strategies. We are focused on driving smart growth, enhancing the customer experience, and meeting our goals for cost reduction and productivity gains to create value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>And now, I'll turn the call back over to Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Wade. Ladies and gentlemen, that concludes our prepared remarks. We are now ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And we'll go first to Ann Hynes with Caris &amp; Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So my questions have to do with CCR. When I look at your estimates on First Call, they're all over the place, and I think part of that is because people are modeling the CCR initiative differently. So end of 2010, 2,000 stores should be done, and you'll have 3,500 to 4,000 left. How should we break that out annually for fiscal 2011 and fiscal 2012? Will most of those be done in 2011?</p>
          <p>And I guess the cost associated with it also, I think you had been saying that the cost per store would be 30 to 50,000. And in your last 10-Q, I believe it said was up to 40 to 55k per store now. So can you just clarify how we should model that going forward so maybe some of the estimates could come more in line on with each other? And also, does that include Duane Reade stores? And I guess that's it for now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks, Ann; Greg. I'll start with the last one and back up maybe to the first one. It does not include the Duane Reade stores as far as the total CCR. We are doing certainly remodelings within the Manhattan area to help them complete their journey of remodeling those stores.</p>
          <p>As far as CCR, you're right. If we look, there's about, as we said, about 5,500 total stores in the chain that would be conducive to a CCR fit. We'll have 2,000 by the end of the calendar year. We expect to have the remainder of those done by the end of the 2011 calendar year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you can factor that in. As far as &#x2013; you had a third question, Ann, I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I guess the cost per store, in your last 10-Q it said 40 to 55k, but I think in your previous presentations you were saying 30 to 50k. So I guess how should we model cost per store for fiscal 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'd probably use &#x2013; I'd use the latest, the 40 to 55. We're encouraged, Ann, and we may be able to pull that down. And if we are, we'll give an update on that. But as I said, we're seeing from where we started about a 20% reduction in the cost to convert these stores. We're down to about four days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think we're optimistic we may be able to get it lower, but I think that's probably a good number to use.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Ed Kelly with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Greg, you mentioned that you slowed down the conversion of CCR to apply some critical lessons. Could you elaborate on what you've learned so far and any impact that those learnings are having on the newer conversions? And then also, could you maybe give us a bit more color on the performance of the conversions beyond the pilot stores?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Ed. I think the key learnings, and we called that out I think on &#x2013; called that out on our Q2 call, was the Complement categories. And again, even though they're only 6% of total sales, there are many stores that have a high percentage of sales coming from the Complement categories. I think we took out some items that we probably didn't need or shouldn't have taken out. We've added about 200 items back into those stores in particularly those Complement categories, things like automotive, hardware. In many stores, we may be more like the general store in a particular community. So I think we feel good with what we're putting back in, and I think you could see the improvement on the Complement categories.</p>
          <p>The other thing that we're excited about is the recent rollout of the actual refresh package, the decor and branding package that we're putting out there. I think as you recall in Houston, when we rolled out Houston and Dallas, we didn't have it ready. We're rolling it now with the new conversions. And we're going back into Houston and Dallas, I believe it's next week, to put the new branding package in those two markets, so we're excited there.</p>
          <p>And Ed, I think you might have one more question as well. Did I cover your points?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The other question actually happens to relate to the reimbursement pressure that you've been talking about. Is there a way to quantify the impact that that has had on the gross margin this quarter? And then, Greg, you mentioned that you are beginning to address some of the issues causing the reimbursement rate pressure. I assume that means the CVS deal. But is there more work to do on that front, meaning are there other PBMs that you need to go talk to as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ed, maybe I'll take the first one and let Wade jump in on how to quantify it. But I think the key thing is we're focused on &#x2013; if you start back I think with the temporary slowdown in the generic pipeline that we've lived through over the past year, I think that has probably heightened some of the reimbursement focus that payers have. I think the good thing is that's a temporary period. And I think when we get into 2012 with the added generics, there will be a little relief there.</p>
          <p>But in this interim, I do think that we're focused on making sure that we get a fair value from payers for the services we provide. And I think we have 7,500 stores. We're in all 50 states. We have 24-hour stores in communities across the country that many don't, so we're just focused on working with payers to make sure we get a fair value. And I think we're recognizing that people value Walgreens and their network. Wade?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'll just add some color. If you look at year-on-year generics, let's call it two to three pennies down versus year ago. As we talked about the impact of the lower flu incidence, about 100 basis points in totality, is another $0.02 to $0.03. And then building on Greg, we did see some reimbursement pressure. I would not say that it was unplanned reimbursement pressure. I think I've said for some time that while it's always tough out of there that this is an 18-month period that we see to be a little bit more challenging than usual. But again I don't think that's anything we haven't anticipated. But I think moving forward, all three of these things have the potential to get stabilized and get stronger over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Greg, does this contract for this spat with CVS Caremark change your view on growth at all going forward, whether it be new store openings or acquisitions? Does it mean that you want to fill holes faster?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Ed, as we said, we can't &#x2013; I'm not going to comment that much on the CVS Caremark situation itself, but our plans haven't changed as regarding our organic growth rate that we sent out there of 2.5 to 3% by the end of fiscal 2011. We still have a strong balance sheet. We're going to be looking for acquisitions that make sense strategically and our plans still</p>
          <p>remain as they have been over the past several months and year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's take our next question from Mark Wiltamuth with Morgan Stanley</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wanted to get a feel for how much of a headwind we're going to be facing here from the swine flu in the fourth quarter because swine flu obviously was building from basically this point all the way through December. And I just want to get an idea of how much of a drag we should expect on both the prescription comp and the front end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, good question. Last year, as we've said, we administered 5 million, 5.5 million seasonal flu shots in addition to a couple million H1N1. And most of that was in the first quarter, so we're going against about 7.5 million total flu shots. We expect to play a big role in the seasonal flu program this fall. Last year, I think we had 16 to 17,000 of our pharmacists certified. Today, Kermit Crawford is with me. He tells me we have about 23,000 certified pharmacists. We're looking forward to adding the Duane Reade pharmacists of nearly 1,000 to participate. So yes, we did a good job last year. We certainly expect to do a better job this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd add we're certainly looking forward to another strong flu season. Like Greg said, over 23,000 of our pharmacists are certified. Over 91% of our stores have two full-time certified pharmacists in it. So when we look at pneumonia, ZOSTAVAX, tetanus, other immunizations, we look to have a very strong season this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand you'd like to get back to a normal flu season pattern, but this fourth quarter that we're working on now has got a very big swine flu year ago that it's comparing against. I'm just curious if you could quantify how big that was.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think, Mark, we actually experienced quite a bit of that this third quarter, and in fact probably a significant amount in the third quarter that we're going against. And we absolutely anticipate it in fourth quarter. I don't know if I've got the number that Wade can give, but it is a headwind. We anticipate aggressively going after more flu shots in the first quarter as well as the tail end of the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you saw the impact more of this last quarter, and then it remains to be seen in the first quarter. For the fourth quarter, I don't think there's going to be a huge impact either way. Again, there's a big upside on the flu shot part of the season, which should hopefully offset any reduction in the first quarter from the overall trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, Wade, on the SG&amp;A cost savings, for a long time we were talking about 25% of that savings coming out of the Florida central fill. Have you really achieved much of that or is that really all still to come in 2011, and what areas are you looking for in 2011 to get the additional $500 million in savings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we've actually said is that the 25% of $250 million is actually a broader umbrella called Transforming Community Pharmacy, of which Florida Power plays one part, but it's much broader than that. So as we look at our aggregate across the country, the work to be done, and Kermit's leading, and maybe he can comment, we're very confident that we'll be able to deliver that. Beyond that, and I'll put it over to Kermit, beyond that we've got indirect spend opportunities as well as corporate, field, and other SG&amp;A opportunities, so all three buckets will step up next year. And there is a big step up in the TCRx or what we call the Transform Community Pharmacy overall umbrella.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and Mark, we're very confident that we're going to meet our cost savings goal for 2011 under TCRx. But in addition to that, we talked about enhancing our customer experience and our customer service. And we've put some automation and enhanced some of our technology to improve that customer service by using up some of the additional capacity we have in the system. For example, if a patient were to touchstone a prescription in for tomorrow in one of our 24-hour stores, our scheduling system now schedules that prescription to be filled on the overnight where we have capacity, therefore freeing up the pharmacist during the day. So we're filling the same number of prescriptions, but we're creating more free time during the day. And as well, the third part of that was the script-like services, which we talked about the flu and other immunizations. So all three of those parts of TCRx we think are on track.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Kermit, while we've got you, obviously during the dispute with CVS, there was some disclosure there that Maintenance Choice was pressuring you. Is there anything you can do to counter that as they continue to try to build that out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, as we've talked about, we're very pleased with our agreement that we have with CVS. We are not going to go into any of the specific details around that agreement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Derek Leckow with Barrington Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just another question on the SG&amp;A growth, I mean 6% SG&amp;A dollar growth and that's adjusted obviously. But Wade, can you help me understand what the SG&amp;A dollar growth is doing at the store level? And is there a bigger component coming out of some of the corporate activities here in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean it's actually &#x2013; we've tried to give that bridge before. It's a fairly complex bridge. But at the store level, we have some base level store salary. We call it store salary inflation, maybe 18 bps as a percent of sales. What also is up that might have been missed a bit is occupancy. Our occupancy is up about 20 bps as a percent of sales, and that's really driven by the fact that we've skewed over the last few years more store openings to really the A+ sites on the East Coast and West Coast.</p>
          <p>Other than that, I mean we've given a little bit of a walk here in the presentation. I know we can continue to &#x2013; Rick can share with you the details. But in aggregate, I'd also say for the number of stores that we opened over the period, 6% when taking out Duane Reade is &#x2013; I mean it's about as good as we've done in many years. It's trending in the right direction. Again, what primarily drives SG&amp;A right now is new store openings. And like I said, some folks might have missed a bit of just the baseline inflation of store salaries as well as the occupancy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, I don't have the presentation right in front of me here, Wade, but the 6%, is that roughly what's going on at store level as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, store level would be much more on a same-store basis &#x2013; much less on a same-store basis, anywhere one to two percentage call it, which is really primarily driven by store salary inflation. And like I said, there is about 20 bps as a percent of sales from increased occupancy. And again, that's because of the decision to open more stores in A+ sites on the East Coast and West Coast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just one question on your working capital here. It sounds like inventory is up a little bit. And I wondered if &#x2013; store level inventory is down, but where's the rest of the inventory? Is that something we should be thinking about coming out of the system in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, same-store inventory is actually down, right? And I think we made good progress there. It's down across the board in stores as well as the distribution, our distribution chain. I think we have opportunity to continue to improve that both in pharmacy as well as the front end and we'll do so. But again, on a same-store basis, we've made progress, again albeit not as much as we've made in prior periods, but I don't think that we've run the gamut on that yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you quantify how much opportunity there is in terms of inventory reduction?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'd hate to do it here on this call. Obviously we've not said anything publicly, but I think we've obviously got a lot of low hanging fruit opportunity already from some of the assortment work, streamlining that. But now we're looking more holistically at our supply chain and opportunities there to operate a bit different, change how we think about some of the buffer stocks, replenishment, et cetera. And so I think that that's the next generation, if you will, of improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Meredith Adler with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I was hoping we could talk in a little bit more detail first about reimbursement rates. Is it fair to say that when you talk about fewer generics, you've got older generics are MAC-ing [Maximum Allowable Cost], and newer generics, there aren't as many of them coming in at a more profitable stage? And then &#x2013; or are we seeing lowering reimbursement per script for the drugs that are MAC-ed? So what I'm saying is, is it a mix of age &#x2013; sorry, or the level of reimbursement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Meredith, I'd say it's a little of both. To your point, some of the older MACs are coming down a little bit as well as the newer are coming down a little more quickly. But at the same time, I do think that the bottom line is that generic utilization is a win-win-win for everyone. And our focus is to continue to drive a higher percentage of generic utilization. And I think when we see more and more come out that the latter half of 2011, 2012 for our fiscal year, certainly we'll see the benefit there. But yes, we're watching MACs diligently with all payers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd also say, I think Greg said it, but we are in a temporary period of fewer new generics. At the back end of calendar 2011, that starts to change dramatically. So that is what it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then maybe you could talk a little bit about &#x2013; you've talked about 90-day at retail has been boosting comps. Could you talk about whether you see that concept, that kind of program expanding? Are you working on joint ventures with PBMs? And then I also have a question about limited networks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Meredith, I absolutely think that a retail 90 benefit and offering is going to become a greater and greater part of the pharmacy industry. I think as more and more generics come out and we see more and more &#x2013; a greater percentage of chronic prescription drugs, a 90-day retail benefit just makes sense. I think the good thing is that employers who have had only a 90-day mail benefit for years, by adding a retail 90 in a broad network of retailers gives them the opportunity to: one, give their employees a benefit that may have not wanted to use mail lower costs by increasing the penetration of total 90-day prescriptions, and a broader network can be put together to give choice as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think the evidence is coming out that the best way to reduce overall healthcare costs is through, one of the best ways is through better adherence. And 90-day is clearly a tool to drive better adherence and compliance. So I think that that trend is also favorable, and we're going to see that play out over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Meredith, to your point, we're working with all payers, all PBMs, managed care organizations, to provide them a 90-day retail solution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is 90-day at retail profitable if everybody is able to do it, if you're not getting any of the benefits of a limited network for 90 days?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, of course, just like 30-day is profitable with the same open network, so is 90-day. And it can be structured in a win-win for both the payer, but also for us. And like I said, it drives adherence and compliance and provides an innate lift from that over time as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When we look at &#x2013; with what we're able to bring to all payers in a situation where they're able to put a broad network together, you figure, Meredith, you take two cost-to-fills out, you have a reimbursement that makes sense. It's just a win-win for everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And limited networks, where do you think that goes? And are you concerned that that leads to significant more pressure, competition on reimbursement costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think limited networks in some form or fashion have been around for years. You can go all the way back to the '80s where HMOs restricted networks. We know that people, most folks, patients do want choice, and there are ways to provide value and lower costs and provide choice at the same time. So I think there will be limited networks around, as there always have been. I do think that folks can balance both choice and value and cost with a broader network, and I think that's what we're seeing more of.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and while I don't really &#x2013; we haven't seen an uptick in that. I mean at the end of the day, if that's where it wants to go, having a 20% share and being within five miles of 75% of the population, I think that we're positioned extremely well in that case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Meredith, I think...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...you may begin to see preferred networks based on performance, which we would welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you don't think that leads to more competition between retailers on reimbursement rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think where healthcare is going is, the provider that can really show value of clinical outcomes, reduce cost, provide choice, to lower the entire medical spend versus just the pharmacy spend is where we're headed as a country, as well as us as a company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Meredith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Moving on to David Magee, SunTrust Robinson Humphrey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of questions; one, the question about the flu season this fall, last year there was just a lot of attention being paid to H1N1 and obviously a lot of vaccines being given. I understand that you're better positioned this year than last year, in which you had a good performance. Do you think that the public will be as aware of it this year and will be as motivated as last fall? And if you had a shot last fall, do you have to go back at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, David; Greg. To the latter question, yes, the CDC recommends a seasonal annual flu shot. There was probably some heightened concern last year due to the H1N1 pending pandemic. I think the fact of the matter is that there are more and more folks getting seasonal flu shots year over year because of the effectiveness. We do know that there were around 150 million or so doses produced last year. It looks like the latest info we're getting is that there are going to be more produced this year, so we feel good with how we're positioned.</p>
          <p>This year as well, David, it's interesting. They're combining the seasonal flu shot with H1N1 in the same dose. So I think people will probably tend to be more interested, because they can get both in one dose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Then second question has to do with the performance on the CCR pilot stores. Do you expect more of a lift? You've had an acceleration here of late. Does that have upward potential to it? And I think somebody earlier asked about the non-pilot stores, how they were doing. I didn't hear an answer on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we're feeling good about the trend we're seeing in CCR. As I said, we were 1.9% in the pilot stores that reported on Q2, 2.6% in those pilot stores overall this year. I feel good that we're making real progress in that Complement category. That's where we saw the significant miss on some of the SKUs.</p>
          <p>And at the same time, what we're beginning to see, David, is that last year, when we began closing out the 4,000 SKUs, that was company-wide. And what we're beginning to see now is, as the new planograms come in nationwide, we're adding items. We're beyond optimizing the SKU level. We're actually enhancing the categories in the departments that we're putting out chain-wide. So we're not only seeing improvement in the CCR stores, but we're beginning to see improvement based on the enhanced categories chain-wide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Dave, let me just maybe address part of the underpinning of your question. But we have been very diligent about looking market-by-market, of control and pilot stores on our market share in those markets as well as the overall share and comps. As we illustrated here, we feel pretty good that our aggregate comps on an apples-to-apples basis have outperformed our top three competitors, which basically means that the control is strong too. So obviously, it's a tough environment out there, but what we have to make sure I think is that we're not only looking at whatever the comp is, but making sure that from a market share point of view and on a competitive basis, that we're actually outperforming others.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So do you think that the 2.6 is an appropriate proxy for the more recent conversions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean absolutely, and I think you can extrapolate again our aggregate versus other comps and add the 2.6 as, hopefully, baseline or better move forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And next from Susquehanna, we'll go to Bob Summers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning. Just wanted to dig a little bit more into the SG&amp;A line and better understand both the change in the net cost savings as well as &#x2013; and I can't access the presentation right now, but what the four-quarter trailing average store growth is, and understand maybe why we're not doing a little better job on that line at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob, I'll jump in and may have Wade give more details. I agree with his comment earlier. I think, when we remove Duane Reade and in light of the 5.9% new store growth, our SG&amp;A trend is pretty consistent with where we've been over the last two or three years. We certainly didn't fall out of bed. We certainly know that there's opportunity. We're going to keep pushing. The goal I have, that I've given this team, is to make sure that that two-year stacked year over year continues to go down. And when you look at the &#x2013; I'm sorry you can't open the presentation, but when you look at the bar graph, the two-year stack with Duane Reade out, we've continued to improve year over year on a two-year stack.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then secondly, with respect to the overall sales environment, two questions. First, are you starting to see any impact from people rolling off of discounted COBRA? And then second, with respect to the front end, where's the incremental pressure coming from? Are you seeing share loss to discounters or dollar stores? And are you concerned that some of this, given the overall employment market, is a little bit structural and longer term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't say that I've seen anything on people rolling off COBRA. It's something we should dig into a little bit. I can't say we're seeing that, Bob.</p>
          <p>As far as the front end, I think we're still seeing some continued pressure on the discretionary categories, although we're feeling better with where we are with what we're seeing currently. I do think that, as I said, we're beginning to roll out some new and enhanced planograms in categories chain-wide. In addition to CCR, we're beginning to roll back some of the private brands, as I said, from Duane Reade. So I think &#x2013; but as far as the pressures, mainly still in the discretionary categories, because customers are still holding onto their cash a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Bob, I would add that certainly in this sluggish economy, finances are an important cause of low adherence to prescription medication therapy. So between the economy and the tough H1N1 comparison of last spring, I think that is more of what's happening in this quarter on the pharmacy side of the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then lastly, you talked about a 50 basis point lift from the alcohol rollout. Where do you see that trending, or what's your own bogey of where it can go?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there's no reason that shouldn't be able to be 2 to 3% of the front end over time, right? But of course, it's how many you roll out and when you cycle, whatever, but I would say that's, I think, what it should comprise. So what it is in terms of actual lift will depend upon the timing of when they're rolled out and how you cycle that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And also we have to watch, Bob, the basket that comes with that, which we're encouraged by.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Deborah Weinswig with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, a few questions. I know it's early, but any unexpected benefit so far from the Duane Reade acquisition?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think, Deb, this is Greg. I think certainly, as I said, we're really encouraged and excited with their private brand, frankly, expertise and what they've done with private brand in that market. And that's the reason we're pulling back some of that in August, as we said, to begin to see what kind of lift we can get throughout the chain, so I think there's a huge opportunity there. Their loyalty card, they just relaunched it a couple months ago. They're seeing pretty good results from it. I think we can certainly learn from some of the things they're doing as we pilot our loyalty card.</p>
          <p>Cosmetics and beauty, we're excited there, I think their fresh food, urban retailing. So the more we've gotten into it, the more excited we are and the more we think that we could pull a lot of their expertise back through the chain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then actually, along the &#x2013; as you roll out some of their private label into the traditional Walgreens stores, what will that replace, if you will, in your existing stores?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's interesting. We do a terrific job, as you might expect, in the health and beauty private brand products, the WAL-TUSSINs and so forth that we're known for. Where we under-penetrate and have, over the years, is in consumables, and that's where they over-excel in their Delish, their snacks, their cookies, their food, their consumable items. So we're going to continue to drive and enhance our OTC offering, which we've done well for years, but we think they can really help us in the consumables space.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, said another way, I think we've done a great job at the me-too at a better value for consumers. But I think that, in terms of really differentiated propositions, in particular in food, they're really best in class, doing a great job.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then also, Wade, in terms of, as you look at it from today ,because obviously you've had a lot of success and traction with regards to expense reduction, what would you look at today as the biggest expense reduction opportunities going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the key thing is to deliver on &#x2013; job number one is to deliver on our Rewire commitment. We've got that plan, now we just have to run that play. So I'd say that that's a good boost. Beyond that, we're actually doing a lot of work, what I would call, in two different streams. One is the day-to-day, how do we think about making increments in everything we do every day, and we have a group now dedicated to that. Separately also, what are the next big breakthroughs? What are the big structural areas we should be looking at to transform? And we've got some ideas there as well.</p>
          <p>But I think I guess just to wrap it up, I think that the first &#x2013; job number one is to deliver on the Rewire commitment and put that to bed, while we also figure out as a company how to be more systemic and not make these cost reductions a once every five-year event, but really build into our day-to-day so we're challenging everything all the time. How can we do it better, more efficiently, faster? And we've put significant resources and a new structure around that for the company. So I feel pretty good that, on a going basis that we'll be more on a continual process there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the last question, I agreed with your comments with regards to front end comps. And when you look at your front end comps versus your peers, it doesn't look like you're losing share to anyone else in the drugstore channel. It doesn't necessarily look like there's anyone out there in the competitive landscape of all of retail that's doing particularly well, maybe the club channel. Where do you think consumers are going to buy those items?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that overall, I think consumers are just pulling back their spending in total, Deborah. But I do think that we are encouraged when we look apples to apples that we are winning against our major competitors and we are gaining share across many markets. So I think it's some that they've cut back on discretionary spend in total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, if you look at the internals, our foot traffic remains strong, which is people are coming. The items remain fairly strong. It's really the dollar ring per item, where people have had to trade down or make sacrifices. And you see it in the other trends too, in terms of people spending more after paycheck and less at the end of it, people who moved more away from credit to cash, et cetera.</p>
          <p>So I think it really is, in aggregate right now, just a bit of a suppressed consumer, which I think is good for us as this comes back. But I think the key thing we're doing is, through CCR and the other efforts to make our stores much more relevant, so I think it's a good opportunity to make those assets more accretive over time. And so the items we're launching in the new environment is going to help with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so also, as you are building out your loyalty card and as you're building out your private label, it seems like you have a real opportunity in this environment to capture, if you will, this "new consumer" as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We definitely would agree with that. I think there's a tremendous opportunity to grow our private brand offering, and that creates loyalty in itself, as you know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As Rick said before, we were talking. If you look at beer and wine, for example, beer and wine is not just what we're going to get for the lift over time. We're finding, when you do the basket diagnostics, that actually we're picking up more of that call it 12 item or less consumer...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...who might not have come by a Walgreens because there was one or two items they couldn't get from that mini-shop. And that gives us a lot of encouragement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much and best of luck with everything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question will come from Andrew Wolf with BB&amp;T Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Wade, on the generic impact, I think you said there was a couple to $0.03 in the quarter versus last year. Can you all tell us when do you think that bottoms out? You're hinting at it that it's sometime between now and next few quarters. Are you implying that even though fiscal '11 through August '11 is not going to be when the big wave kicks in that you're still going to have &#x2013; that swing will turn positive on fiscal '11 on generic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we have a step down this whole year, so we've seen it throughout the year. We're going to have another bit of a step down next year. And then really at the end of calendar '11 is where we get a really nice step up and then the following year an even nicer step up. So I hesitate to quantify the exact numbers in part because actually no one can predict exactly when these things hit, but that's the basic pattern.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is it fair to say this $0.02 to $0.03 is the worst type of impact you'd expect, realizing it's more like horseshoes than precise? But at least in terms of magnitude that's about as big as you'd expect in any one quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say next year, you could see another one to two on top of it, but we've got a lot of good stuff going as well. So I mean in aggregate there are lots of moving parts, big moving parts. But we do see a bit of a step down next year, not to the degree we've seen this year. And then like I said we start to see a sequential year step up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on the housekeeping side, I think you've talked about the AWP [Average Wholesale Price] lawsuit settlement. Is that still running at about 25 million a quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, about the same flow through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we'll cycle that and we'll start to cycle that next fall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what about, I think in the past you've called out the expense from &#x2013; the dilutive expense from clinics. Is that neutral this year or is that still dilutive to earnings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's now moving to slightly accretive on a relative basis, so it's not accretive, right, it's still a loss but it's less loss than a year ago. And I would expect that that's going to keep becoming relatively accretive moving forward. And we are still very much big believers in this, not only from an amazing experience what it does to our halo effect, but also our stores are moving into three and four years, many of those are moving into the black, and that's on the torture test of fully loaded economics with no benefit in the front end or on a script basis. So again on a relative basis, it's year-on-year accretive. But also the older ones are ramping nicely as planned, and so it gives us a lot of confidence that this is the way to go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. In terms of Bob's questions with some of the extended COBRAs falling off, it might be interesting to see since there are cheaper ways to get healthcare if you're not insured, how that goes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we definitely think we're going to be a player, a big role in the access challenges with healthcare reform, Andy, as you might expect. That's the reason we're so bullish on these clinics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the front end I mean the release &#x2013; you said that markdowns were lower. Is that due to the competitive environment in any way, or is it just due to the amount of markdowns you took last year with Rewire?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The amount of markdowns we took last year due to Rewire.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And are you saying the competitive environment is about the same or it's &#x2013; I mean I'm seeing some signs of rationality versus some of the competitors like the supermarkets where some milk prices are moving up. And I think in prior quarters they were using them as loss leaders. So you're trying to say the competitive environment &#x2013; how would you characterize incrementally the competitive environment overall in retail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say it's pretty much what we've seen the past six months to 12. I think there are folks that are out there still trying to go after the discretionary spend with consumers. I do think and as I've said, we're encouraged with what we're seeing currently, but we'll see. I think people are still watching their cash, Andy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My last question is on your direct-to-employer offering. Is there a way or is that an offering that can be run by an HR department in parallel with a PBM that has a mandatory element to it where the maintenance drivers could still be done in that type of situation in Walgreens?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andy, we have several relationships where we have direct arrangements with a payer over the years. The real opportunity we have, as you know, is our direct employer program is really &#x2013; we lead with the work site health center solution that we have. And once we get in and really begin to provide real value and build the relationship with the employer, there are other services that we can offer and that we're able to deliver. If that indeed includes prescription drugs, then we can do that as well. But what we really want to do is to get in and provide real value to an employer's medical spend in total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Folks, that was our final question. Thank you for joining us today. We'll announce June monthly sales on July 6. The next quarterly financial announcement will be September 28. That's when we'll announce fiscal 2010 fourth quarter and year-end results. Until then, thank you for listening, and we look forward to talking to you soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Once again, ladies and gentlemen, that concludes our conference today. Thank you all for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>