<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1262653" product="RawTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-10-08</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2327</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Rafael Matute, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial and Administrative Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Eduardo Solorzano, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Mariana Rodriguez, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Rafael Matute Labrador, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial and Administrative Officer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by, welcome to the Wal-Mart de M&#xE9;xico Third Quarter Results Conference Call. During the presentation, all participants will be in a listen-only mode. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder this conference is being recorded Thursday, October 8, 2009. I would now like to turn the conference over to Rafael Matute, Chief Financial Officer. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and welcome to our third quarter conference call. Here with me are Eduardo Solorzano, our President and CEO of Wal-Mart de Mexico and Mariana Rodriguez. I am glad to report tremendous quarter of consistent excellent results. The world economic environment is still challenging, we continue to deliver strong results and investing and we are working to improve our position for the long-term.</p>
          <p>We delivered our strong top line growth, which together with our discipline of constantly searching for efficiency, allow for operated income, EBITDA and net income to grow more than sales.</p>
          <p>I would like to highlight some numbers for the quarter. Total sales for the third quarter were up 11.9%, while comp store sales grew 4.7%. General expenses grew only 8.4%, this figure very positive compressed to the 11.9 increase in total sales, and 11.2 increase in average installed capacity.</p>
          <p>EBITDA increased 17.1%, earnings per share increased 19.2%, we closed the quarter with 13.5 billion pesos in cash, this is 82% higher than last year for the same quarter. For return on equity for the last 12 months, the September was 24.4%, while return on capital employed was 27.7%.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn to Eduardo Solorzano to share his views on what we are doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Rafael, thank you very much. And welcome everybody, and good afternoon. Thank you for joining us this afternoon. I agree with you Rafael, the economic environment have  &#x2013; was a certainly challenging, and we were able to turn into an opportunity. I feel very proud of what we have achieved, and of how we are growing and improving this company for the future. Let me share with you some of the initiatives that we have taken to achieve this and the future results.</p>
          <p>Starting with our value proposition, through our consisting on a strong value proposition we've been increasing customer loyalty and driving in traffic, prices as you know have been that key and we will continue to be key as clearly our customer have less money to spend and are a lot more price conscious. We have been aggressively and constantly lowering prices and sending a strong as a transparent price measures emphasizing relevant <mark type="indiscernible" />. The response from our customer have been clear. We have gain in market share both from the formal and the informal market and in all regions of the country. We don't have get figures for the industry for September but if we compare July and August, same-store sales for Walmex Self-Service formats grew 5.4%, which compared very favorably with a 3% decrease of the industry as measured by the National Retail Association on top excluding Walmex.</p>
          <p>In term of our total sales force for the July and August period, our Self-Service formats grew 12.9% compared with 2.3% growth of that excluding again Walmex. &#x2013; must indicate there was an customer lowest or the highest in the history of the company.</p>
          <p>Customer count in comparable stores increased at 5.3% during the quarter and if we consider only Self-Service stores customer grew a strong 6.3%. We have a great back-to-school season and as example, I would like to highlight the performance achieved in desktops, computers and laptops. We achieved a triple-digit growth in all stores rapidly.</p>
          <p>Let me share also with you, some example of the specific strategies for the different formats during this quarter. In Bodega Aurrera through the quarter, we underscored activities enjoy in our stores with dancing counters and karaoke events, watching soccer matches on television and looking for trainer for Mama Lucia to lower prices. These events have been very well received and have a lowest to achieve or even greater eventification with our customer. We posted some photography for you to see on the Investor Relations Section of our website. I will invite you take a look of, because they are very interesting. Also you will find there some of the advertising campaigns that we are using, I'm sure also that you will like them as well.</p>
          <p>We continue to focus on prices, in September we kick it off a new campaign titled <mark type="indiscernible" /> so we make our prices as key, where we are stressing portion of our main value at Bodega, our price.</p>
          <p>In Wal-Mart Supercenter in September, we celebrated our first 10 years of everyday low prices in Mexico, with the launching of <mark type="indiscernible" /> campaign that includes 3,000 roll-backs and unbeatable price through the store. Two programs that are worth mention again, as they continue to be very successful, are when the multi save program, that allow customers to have additional savings, when savings are when they are purchasing more than one piece of the same product.</p>
          <p>On the fresh Tuesday and Wednesday program that we call money for market and near call <mark type="ph" /> and all, where our customer find excellent prices in fruits and vegetables, daily meat, fish and sea foods and groceries and consumables. As an example we are selling almost 590,000 euro of corn per day or more than 700,000 kilos of watermelons.</p>
          <p>In Sam's Club for the first time in Mexico Sam's Club launched the campaign on television with price comparison for every major probe for a bankers and business members. In order to give more value to our memebership. We have held different event, focusing on the sales of the special items at unique prices. With payment channels of up to 18 months interest free. And furthermore, we have two events with merchandise that entitled a 50% rebate for credits to our gift card or a &#x2013; or 18 months of interest free payment terms. As well as the rent with unbeatable prices for back-to-school season and events centering around book sales for wholesalers or members who owned or operate grocery stores.</p>
          <p>In August, we launched our Sam's member magazine, which would be issued to every other month free of charge for our members. The magazine features a tutorial content from that known outsource as well as articles for interest of for our members.</p>
          <p>In Superama for the first time we've launched our campaign called as <mark type="indiscernible" /> offering our senior citizen called as customers a special catalog, with the item for heart disease, weight and sugar control. And also the most similar program continues to be very successful in Superama. As an example we have a group of 11 product from health and beauty and 16 from our basic department under this products and we have mid double digit sales growth.</p>
          <p>In Suburbia, they were different events with unique price points for all items in a given kind of order such as purses, blouses, jacket, et cetera. I would like to highlight that Suburbia have a great quarter, we have been focusing on price and assortment, will be the prices for quality closing and basic assortment complimented with some brand. As an example of basic assortment jeans and underwear have mid double-digit growth as well as more trendy clothing for juniors like T Shirts and short shirts.</p>
          <p>In this several strategies we were &#x2013; we're launch a leverage to more important events on festivities like grand parents eat for free on their day, free dessert for those who show approval having board on election day et cetera. Also to increase traffic of entire families of our kids free programs on revolve it we are having a membership with a benefit for our kids customers.</p>
          <p>We launched our loyalty card with progressive discount from 20 to 50% when consumer more than 75 pesos. Vips had a consistent improvement month-of-month with the exception of May when we have the negative effect of the swine flu. but this still have a lot challenges ahead. Banco Wal-Mart during the quarter we began the process of opening branches &#x2013; branches in Mexico City opening 23 in Bodega Aurrera unit and two in Wal-Mart. Also during October we have opened seven more branches so we have in now a total of 70 branches.</p>
          <p>On September 24, the Mexican Banking and Securities Commission authorized of the use of our shares lines in stores, clothes and restaurants under this scheme of bank correspondence.</p>
          <p>To close with our value proposition, I will say that our strongest season is starting and we are ready to have a very good season. We expect the economic environment are still be challenging &#x2013; challenging but we have great products that we will differentiate our offerings and we are lean in term of inventory to better start this season.</p>
          <p>Now let me move into productivity another highlight of the quarter. Our passion for productivity and constant search for efficiencies, has allowed us to continue to improve our position as the lowest cost operator in the market. As an example I would like to mention the productivity increased that we have driven from our distribution center. The number of cases move up or have been our double-digit growth and volume carrier for trailer also increase reducing the number of trips, which also supports our commitment of protecting the environment.</p>
          <p>And regarding on our people, as I have said before, I'm very proud of the high performance deemed up is delivering excellent results in these challenging environment, and that continues to improve this company for the future. As strong our professional management team could take long-term decisions basing in very strong processes and in the benefit of all of our shareholders.</p>
          <p>This year we are reinforcing our commitment with gender diversity and we have established Advisory Board of gender equality and inclusion, its main objective is the development of women's talent for executive positions, so as a continue reinforcing our value proposition for our female customers.</p>
          <p>Finally, on the social responsibility field in preparation for the hurricane season the Wal-Mart de Mexico foundation executed an agreement with the Mexican Red Cross, the United Nation Development and FUNDEMEX, Mexican Entrepreneurial Foundation with the purpose of well in incubators in the case of natural disaster from 7 to 32 states are nationalized.</p>
          <p>In addition, resources will be used to finance below some products that will contribute towards reviving the economy in affected states to their besizable natural disaster. Wal-Mart de Mexico and EMEA the Mexican Institute of Adult Education signing an collaboration agreement to implement a program to increase the educational level of it's associates.</p>
          <p>During this quarter, the Wal-Mart de Mexico Foundation channel some 106 million pesos benefiting programs aiming to &#x2013; at improving nutrition and development in communities of extreme poverty through the country. In this period more than 13,000 volunteers have participated in 795 volunteer activities helping in the remodeling of schools on maintenance of parks and other touring <mark type="ph" /> areas.</p>
          <p>Before I turn it to Mariana Rodriguez to go into details of the numbers, I encode as to you to again to visit our website and see the videos of our customers enjoying their weekends at Bodega Aurrer&#xE1;.</p>
          <p>Our associates of Bodega have really done a fantastic job of involving customers' industrial activities and becoming our destination not only to shop but also to spend their spare time. You will also find their videos of our current campaigns of Bodega Aurrer&#xE1;, Wal-Mart, and Sam's Club and I'm sure you will also enjoy how Wal-Mart is highlighting the additional price reduction in a very enthusiastic way how Sam's Club is clearly showing the value of our membership. Remember it is on the Investor Relation section of our website. Mariana?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Eduardo. Starting with sales, total growth for the third quarter was 11.9% while centre sales grew 4.7. In the case of Self-Service format, total sales growth was 12.6, while same-store sales grew 5.1. It is important to highlight that the difference in same-store sales growth between total business and Self-Service store is not as significant now as Suburbia had positive same-store sales growth for the three consecutive months of this quarter.</p>
          <p>The best performing formats in terms of same-store sales during the quarter were Bodega and Wal-Mart and the weakest was bit. For the first nine months of the year total sales grew 10.4% and same-store sales grew 3.2%. For the Self-Service format total sales grew 11.6%, while same-stores sales grew 4%. Sales continue to be driven by customers. Customers for the third quarter at comparable stores grew 5.3%, while average ticket decreased 0.4%.</p>
          <p>In the case of Self-Service format, customers grew a strong 6.3% and average ticket decreased 1.1. The format that have the strongest growth in customers was Suburbia and Bodega, while Sam's and Superama have the strongest growth in ticket.</p>
          <p>Growth margin for the quarter was seven basis points lower than last year's third quarter. Operating expenses was 50 basis point lower than during the third quarter of last year. Operating income was 40 basis points higher than last year's third quarter both with or without the bank. Now lets look at some balance sheet items. As of the end of the third quarter 2009, our cash position amounted to 13.5 billion pesos, 6.1 billion pesos more than last year. During the first nine months of the year, the company invested 6.1 billion pesos in fixed assets, we purchased 41.3 million shares for an amount of 1.6 billion pesos and paid a dividend of 5 billion pesos.</p>
          <p>Inventories increased 3.9 versus last year's third quarter. Average inventory per store decreased 9.2%. Accounts payable to suppliers grew 6.7%, which favorably compares to inventory growth.</p>
          <p>Now, I will leave you back with Rafael Matute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to comment that as we announced in September, we will exceed our initial expansion plan for the year. Instead of the original 253 new units, we will be opening 270 units. As of today we have opened 132 units including, 130 in Bodega of the different prototypes. This is beating Bodega Aurrer&#xE1;, 19 new Bodega Aurrer&#xE1; and 79 Bodega Aurrer&#xE1; Express, as well as 10 Wal-Mart's, 6 Sam's, 2 Superama and 1 Suburbia with these openings, we went to 23 new cities and now we have presence in 247 cities nationwide with 1,334 total units in operation.</p>
          <p>With this, we are now ending our conference call and I remind you that we will be available to receive any calls with questions that you may have. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen that does conclude the conference call for today. We thank you for your participation and ask that you please disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>