<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1508687" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-17</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2327</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Director, Chief Financial Officer &amp; EVP">Rafael Matute Labrador S&#xE1;nchez</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Scot Rank</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Q3 2012 Walmart de M&#xE9;xico y Centroam&#xE9;rica's Earnings Conference Call. My name is Richard, and I'll be your operator for today's call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. I will now turn the call over to Mr. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (00:17). You may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>The date of this call is October 17, 2012.</p>
          <p>Before we start, let me remind you that this call is property of Wal-Mart de M&#xE9;xico S.A.B. de C.V. and is intended for the use of the company's shareholders and the investment community. It should not be reproduced in any way.</p>
          <p>This call may contain certain references concerning Wal-Mart de M&#xE9;xico S.A.B. de C.V.'s future performance that should be considered as good faith estimates made by the company.</p>
          <p>These references only reflect management expectations and are based upon currently available data. Actual results are always subject to future events, risks and uncertainties, which could materially impact the company's actual performance.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll leave you with Rafael Matute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, and thanks for joining us today for Walmart de M&#xE9;xico y Centroam&#xE9;rica earnings call to review the third quarter of the year 2012. Let me start with three key takeaways for the quarter. Walmex had solid results with consolidated EBITDA growing 14.7%.</p>
          <p>Results were driven by profitability improvements in Mexico with sales trend improving and a 16.8% increase in EBITDA. We have a very strong financial position. We closed the quarter with MXN 23 billion in cash, an increase of 54% versus last year.</p>
          <p>Now, I will turn over Scot Rank, our President and CEO for Walmart de M&#xE9;xico y Centroam&#xE9;rica to go over the details of our results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rafael. Good afternoon, everyone. As Rafael said, in Mexico, we had a solid third quarter, improving sales trends and growing operating income and EBITDA faster than sales.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, we've continued to execute on our core strategies to drive sales, price leadership, in stock, winning in traffic departments and underdeveloped categories. I am particularly pleased with the way we have been improving in stock, enhancing our price leadership and creating excitement throughout the store. This is achievable by partnering with our suppliers, leveraging best practices within the company, and listening to our customers.</p>
          <p>As an example of price leadership in General Merchandise, we launched a campaign called Las Horas Contadas that provides great value via special purchases that are valid until supplies last.</p>
          <p>We are adding new technology to support higher standards of in stock. Through Walmart's Global Replenishment System, GRS, we are improving visibility and simplifying workflow for demand settings, resulting in higher fill rates and lower safety stock inventories.</p>
          <p>Another tool, on-shelf availability or OSA measures the way merchandise flows from suppliers to customers. OSA enables operations to identify products out-of-stock or with low days on hand. Through an auditor's metrics, we evaluate all stores on a weekly basis, so our customers can find what they're looking for, thereby improving their shopping experience.</p>
          <p>To drive traffic and increase our price advantage, in early October, we launched a campaign called El Ahorro m&#xE1;s Grande de M&#xE9;xico, the largest savings in Mexico. We lowered prices on basic food basket and health and beauty products that represent 40% of household expenditure in Mexico.</p>
          <p>We are focused on reaffirming Walmex's price leadership and saving our customers money ahead of the upcoming holiday season.</p>
          <p>We are growing sales above 10% in underdeveloped categories that we have targeted to improve. A good example is Superama, where we're increasing differentiation and driving sales in categories like pastas, tea, salad dressing and marmalades.</p>
          <p>Our strategies are working. Customers are responding favorably, and it's good to see that reflected in our comp sales improvement. To exclude calendar effects, we use the Wal-Mart 4-5-4 retail calendar, and we see Mexico comp sales for the five-week period ended September 28 increase 4.6%, compared to 4.4% in August, and 2.9% in July.</p>
          <p>Mexico's comp store sales also showed an improving trend versus the rest of the industry as measured by ANTAD. In September, Walmex comp store sales grew 180 basis points more than ANTAD excluding Walmex. As for the third quarter, comp store sales for Walmex grew by 4.8%, while ANTAD's comp store sales report for the rest of the industry excluding Walmex grew 4.4%. Comp sales growth is priority for our company. We are pleased with the momentum going into the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Mexico's gross margin rate increased by 60 basis points over last year, primarily due to seasonal merchandise flow. Expenses grew faster than sales, primarily due to increases in rents, utilities and maintenance and remodels in the quarter. During the quarter, we remodeled 150 stores. These remodels will allow us to deliver a great shopping experience this holiday season.</p>
          <p>The bank continues to show significant progress. Supplier and consumer loans almost doubled, and we reached 405,000 credit cards, 1.5 times what we had a year ago. Deposits amounted to MXN 4.0 billion, 1.9 times the amount that we had at the end of the third quarter last year. Though the bank had negative impact on consolidated EBITDA of MXN 145 million, it was lower than the negative MXN 238 million of last year's third quarter.</p>
          <p>Results for the third quarter in Mexico, including retail stores and banking, can be summarized as follows: total income increased 10.6% to MXN 87.3 billion. Operating income and EBITDA grew faster than sales, 18.1% and 16.8%, respectively, as the increase in gross margin offset the growth of expenses as a percentage of total income.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to Central America. In Central America, we're taking the strategic steps to strengthen the consistency of our execution and meet our long-term goals. Transformation of the business, as I mentioned in our second quarter webcast, will take us longer than we originally thought.</p>
          <p>As I've commented before, systems integration in Central America is key for the transformation of the business. We have completed our systems integration at the store level. We have also converted four Distribution Centers, while five more are ongoing. We will finish integrating distribution systems by mid 2013.</p>
          <p>For the third quarter, sales in Central America increased 9.4%, while comp store sales were up 3.2% on a constant-currency basis. I wish to highlight the improvement of the growth trend during the quarter. We had a 0.7% comp store sales decrease in July, 2.8% growth in August, and 8.1% comp store sales growth in September.</p>
          <p>For the third quarter, gross profit margin on total income was 20.5%, a 130-basis point reduction compared to the same time last year. As I mentioned during the second quarter webcast, we have been liquidating obsolete inventory in Central America via aggressive markdowns that impact gross margin. Days on hand have been sequentially improving during the third quarter. And as a result, we expect a better trend in gross margin going forward.</p>
          <p>Central America reported total income of MXN 13.6 billion, a 16.9% increase over last year's third quarter. This includes currency impact. On a constant-currency basis, net sales increased 9.4% over last year's third quarter.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses grew slower than sales and were 18.5% of total income for the quarter. Operating income and EBITDA were down 30.4% and 16.2%, respectively, on a constant-currency basis, as a result of the decrease in gross margin from our inventory liquidation program.</p>
          <p>Rafael will now take us through the consolidated results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Consolidated total income increased 11.4% or MXN 10.3 billion to MXN 100.8 billion for the quarter. As a percentage of total income, Walmex's third quarter gross profit increased 40 basis points. Operating expenses increased 30 basis points also as a percentage of total income.</p>
          <p>Operating income and EBITDA grew faster than sales for the quarter, 15.7% and 14.7%, respectively. EBITDA amounted to MXN 9.4 billion, MXN 1.2 billion more than last year. Net income amounted to MXN 5.3 billion, an 11.1% increase versus last year.</p>
          <p>As I highlighted at the beginning of this call, our financial position remains very strong. We closed the quarter with MXN 23.4 billion in cash, MXN 8.2 billion more than last year and 54% increase.</p>
          <p>Inventory grew 10.8%, driven primarily by the 347 new stores opened during the last 12 months. Inventory levels improved in both Mexico and Central America, as compared with the level they had at the end of the second quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>We continue to drive a strong cash generation. Over the last 12 months to September, we generated MXN 40.7 billion from our operations, plus MXN 2.8 billion from negative working capital, thus a total MXN 43.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Our priorities for cash remain growth and returns to shareholders. Capital expenditures were MXN 15.7 billion. We returned MXN 10.4 billion to shareholders through dividend and share repurchases, and paid taxes for MXN 8.5 billion.</p>
          <p>During the year, we have opened 162 new stores in Mexico and Central America. This includes 49 new stores in the third quarter of this year. As of today, our revised year end goal for store openings contemplates an increase in installed capacity of 7.7%, 8% increase in Mexico, and 5% increase in Central America.</p>
          <p>We added approximately 5.4 million square feet, a 9.2% increase in installed capacity. With the opening of Mi Bodegas and Bodega Aurrer&#xE1; Express that we will have during the fourth quarter, we will reach a new milestone of 1,000 small format stores in Mexico.</p>
          <p>We have an efficient distribution network, which we continue to modernize and expand. We expanded two of our Distribution Centers: one in Monterrey and one in Mexico City. And we also relocated our Distribution Center for Suburbia.</p>
          <p>Now I turn it back to Scot for some additional comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Social responsibility is a comprehensive part of our corporate culture and our future. As an example, this year Wal-Mart de Mexico Foundation launched an initiative called Mujer, cuentas con nosotros (Woman, you can count on us) through which we will finance training courses for 39,000 women that want to start their own business, improve an existing one or study a technical career.</p>
          <p>We also received recently two recognitions regarding social responsibility. We received a recognition from Poder y Negocios magazine. We were rated first place in the ranking Las verdaderas verdes (The Truly Green Companies). We were certified under the Gender Equality Model by the National Women's Institute for Mexico for the fifth year in a row.</p>
          <p>I remind you that Walmart de M&#xE9;xico y Centroam&#xE9;rica is participating in an independent investigation into possible corrupt practices, initiated by the audit committee of Wal-Mart Stores Inc. and revisions into similar matters by competent authorities. Our complete statement can be accessed at the Walmex investor relations website as part of the second quarter 2012 financial information sent to the Mexican Stock Exchange on July 23, 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Before I close, let me summarize some of the key points for the quarter. We posted a strong quarter in Mexico, and we are encouraged by the ongoing sales momentum. We still have a lot of work to do to improve our business in Central America, but we remain committed to growth and to improve execution. Our earnings performance continued to translate into strong cash generation. Looking ahead, we are ready for the upcoming holiday season.</p>
          <p>Thank you for listening today, and I remind that we will be available to receive calls with questions that you may have. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. This concludes today's conference. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>