<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1385737" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-04-15</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2327</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Scot Rank, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Rafael Matute Labrador, Chief Financial Officer, Director and Executive Vice President</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Wal-Mart de M&#xE9;xico and Centroam&#xE9;rica 2011 First Quarter Earnings Conference Call. My name is Sergio, and I will be your operator for today's call <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Please note that today's conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Mr. Scot Rank, President and CEO of Wal-Mart de M&#xE9;xico and Centroam&#xE9;rica.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, and welcome to our first quarter 2011 conference call. Here with me is Rafael Matute, CFO of Wal-Mart de M&#xE9;xico y Centroam&#xE9;rica First quarter results were in line with our expectations and the investment activities included in our 2011 business plan.</p>
          <p>Same-store sales growth was below 2010 due to the change in the Easter calendar. We had positive trends in margins and our expenses reflected the investments that we are making in new stores and distribution infrastructure. We'll start with Mexico.</p>
          <p>We are on track to meet our new store expansion program for this year. This program includes 365 new stores in Mexico and is a key component of our historic annual CapEx investment of $14 billion pesos.</p>
          <p>During the first quarter, we added 79,000 square meters of new store selling space and more than twice as many stores and selling area as we did last year in the same period of time. We opened 38 stores; five Bodegas Aurrera, seven new Bodegas, 19 Bodegas Express, three Wal-Mart Supercenters, three Sam's Clubs and a restaurant.</p>
          <p>Now, Rafael will comment on the details of the financial results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Scot, and good afternoon. Sales in Mexico, as Scot mentioned, were challenging, as the economic environment was slightly tough. And we had a negative Easter calendar effect. This effect should reverse in April.</p>
          <p>As for the consumer, we still think the purchasing power will slowly recover. We are working on being more relevant for our customer, offering an appropriate assortment at the best possible price. And, at the same time, we are investing to drive future sales, building new stores and remodeling existing ones so as to guarantee the best shopping experience for our customers.</p>
          <p>In the meantime, we have been able to protect and even improve gross margin. Also, our discipline in expenses will allow us for more future leverage. Expenses in Mexico grew more than sales, but if we consider only retail expenses and we exclude depreciation, they grew less than sales, despite investment in remodels, and more than double the number of openings during the quarter compared to last year.</p>
          <p>Now, let's move from Mexico into Central America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>A lot is going on in Central America, and we are making strong investments in getting the region to be more like a true Wal-Mart operation. Be more Wal-Mart means different things. First of all, our associates. We aligned compensation schemes and introduced cash bonus based on individual store performance for the first time.</p>
          <p>We also are launching Every Day Low Prices, which started yesterday in Honduras, and the other countries that will follow in the coming months. Every Day Low Prices is a fundamental part of how we go to market. And it will help us generate trust and loyalty for the long term with our customers. In this first stage, we lowered prices on 3,000 items. Price reductions go from 2% to 25%.</p>
          <p>Yesterday, we launched our first Walmart Supercenter in Central America in Honduras. We are remodeling at this time all of our hypermarkets and launching in parallel EDLP programs in all of these new stores, which will be branded Walmart Supercenters.</p>
          <p>We are improving the assortment and introduced initially 3,500 new SKUs. This number will increase to reach 4,400 new items by the end of the year. Particularly important is the number of general merchandise and apparel products. Improving supermarkets means bringing the value proposition of Superama Mexico to Central America.</p>
          <p>Every Day Low Cost is part of Wal-Mart's DNA, and we are taking measures to gradually reduce our expenses throughout Central America.</p>
          <p>Integration of Central America is key, and our systems implementation program is on track. We currently operate with Wal-Mart systems fully in two countries. Being more Wal-Mart should translate in the medium term in serving better our customers, increasing sales and reducing expenses. But in the short term, it requires investment.</p>
          <p>Rafael, why don't you comment on the numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>In Central America, the negative Easter calendar effect on our sales is even stronger than in Mexico. Excluding this effect, same-store sales trends for 2011 have been strong, with January and February growing at an average of 5%. Even in March, the trend prior to the Easter comparison was even stronger than the 5% recorded in the first month of the year.</p>
          <p>Total sales grew 5% affected, as I mentioned, by the Easter shift. Gross margin was slightly down, as we did markdowns in the hypermarkets in order to clean inventories and have the new assortment for the launching of supercenters.</p>
          <p>Expenses grew more than sales as a result of our strategic decision, as Scot explained, to make strong investments in getting the region to be more Wal-Mart.</p>
          <p>Now let's move into consolidated results. Last year, we consolidated only March information for Central America. Gross margin showed an improvement versus last year, driven by Mexico. Expenses, as we said before, grew more than sales as a result of our planned investments, both in Mexico and Central America, to improve the operation and drive future sales.</p>
          <p>EBITDA margin was slightly lower than last year as a result of the consolidation of Central America. This is the last quarter that we should have this effect. Since March, we have a comparable basis, last year. Pro forma numbers should show an EBITDA margin of 9.5% last year compared with 9.7% this year; thus, an improvement of 16 basis points.</p>
          <p>Now let's move into the balance sheet. As of the end of the quarter, our cash position amounted to $21.3 billion of Mexican pesos. This is $4.2 billion pesos more than last year. During the first quarter of the year, the company invested $2,317 million pesos in fixed assets and repurchased 4.4 million shares for an amount of $153 million pesos. Inventories increased 9.6% versus last year, a good number, considering that we opened 325 units during the last 12 months.</p>
          <p>Scot, we also received some recognition this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, Rafael. The Euromoney magazine awarded us recognition as the company with the best corporate governance in Mexico; also, as the company with the most convincing and coherent strategy in Mexico and in the Consumer Goods sector in Latin America.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, we were granted for the 11th year in a row the Socially Responsible company distinction from the Mexican Philanthropy Center and the Alliance for Socially Responsible Companies in Mexico [Alliance for Corporate Social Responsibility (AliaRSE)]. We are one of 10 companies and the only retailer that has obtained this distinction from the moment it was created.</p>
          <p>The Ganar-Ganar magazine that specializes in subjects related to social responsibility and sustainable development awarded us recognition for the best corporate social responsibility event in relation to our first sustainability forum, Together for a Better Planet.</p>
          <p>And, finally, the National Institute for Adult Education and the Public Education Secretary awarded us recognition for the commitment with the future in Mexico, thanks to support for the education that we offer our associates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Before we finish, I would like to remind you that this year, ordinary and extraordinary dividends of 38 Mexican cents and 17 Mexican cents per share, approved at our last shareholders' meeting, will be paid on April the 29th.</p>
          <p>With this, we're ending our conference call. Thanks again. And I remind you that we will be available to receive any calls with the questions that you may have. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>