<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1456211" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-02-20</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2327</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO, Director &amp; EVP-Administration &amp; Finance">Rafael Matute Labrador</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Scot Rank</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Q4 2011 Wal-Mart de M&#xE9;xico, S.A.B. de C.V. (Walmex) Earnings Conference Call. My name is Eric and I will be your operator for today's call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Please note that this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Rafael Matute, Chief Financial Officer for Wal-Mart Mexico, Central America. Mr. Matute, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and thanks for joining us today for our earnings call to review both the fourth quarter and the full year of 2011. Here with me is Scot Rank, our CEO. We will review the key highlights for the quarter and also cover the year details.</p>
          <p>We are pleased with our strong earnings performance and in particular for the Mexican operation. In the fourth quarter, Mexico delivered total income of over Ps. 100 billion, an increase of 15.4% from last year and 7.1% at comp stores.</p>
          <p>Based on a good planning for the season and despite investment in prices, gross margin for the quarter was flat to last year at 22.7% of sales.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter operating income was Ps. 10.3 billion, up 18.9% from last year. EBITDA was 11.9% versus 11.6% versus last year. Operating income and EBITDA grew faster than sales for the quarter as we leveraged expenses. Expenses in Mexico grew 13% compared with a 15.4% increase in total income.</p>
          <p>We had a very successful holiday season in Mexico delivering sales above our expectations. We are seeing comp sales momentum, as well as total sales benefiting from the new stores we opened.</p>
          <p>Price leadership was critical to our success and we also delivered merchandise and assortment relevant to our customers during the Christmas season. Most categories had a good performance, especially fresh, grocery, apparel, health and wellness, home and others from general merchandise departments. Worthy of note is the fact that every format contributed to the strong sales growth.</p>
          <p>Comp ticket and traffic increased for the period by 5.1% and 1.9% respectively. For the fourth quarter, our comp store sales for self-service format grew 7%, while ANTAD comp store sales growth, excluding Walmex, posted a 5.2% growth.</p>
          <p>Now let's move on to the discussion of our operation in Central America. Central America increased total income from the previous year by Ps. 2.3 billion. This represent a 17% increase in peso terms or a 6% increase on a constant currency basis. Gross margin was down 130 basis points as a result of our aggressiveness in pricing.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, we leveraged expenses for the quarter. EBITDA grew at the same rate as sales. This is 17% in peso terms.</p>
          <p>As we commented during the second and third quarter, one of the steps in our strategy for Central America was to redefine the formats.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter, we opened 35 stores aligned with a new format strategy. We added more than 320,000 square feet of sales area, which favorably compares to the 110,000 square feet added during the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Now, let's get to the consolidated numbers. Total income grew 15.7%. Gross margin went from 22.6% to 22.5% as a result of the decline in gross margin in Central America. Operating income and EBITDA grew faster than sales by leveraging expenses. Net income increased by a very solid 26% for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Full year results were as follows: On a consolidated basis, total income for the year amounted to Ps. 381 billion, a 13.4% growth as compared with the previous year. EBITDA amounted to Ps. 37 billion, a 12.4% increase with respect to 2010. Net income for the company represented 5.8% of total income and grew 14%.</p>
          <p>As we grow and reinvest in the business, our balance sheet becomes stronger. We continued to deliver strong free cash flow, closing the year with Ps. 25 billion, Ps. 505 million more than last year.</p>
          <p>We had a strong growth in inventories in December as a consequence of the following: We wanted to guarantee supply for replenishable product for the beginning of the year. We made a big bet on the Kings Day (sic) [Three Kings Day] and warm weather impacted seasonal apparel inventories. Inventories will be back on track by the end of the first quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>Our cash comes from our operation. We generated Ps. 39.7 billion pesos for the full year, in addition to the Ps. 1.4 billion from negative working capital requirements. We invested Ps. 18.4 billion in fixed assets, paid dividends in cash for Ps. 9.7 billion, repurchased company shares for Ps. 3.7 billion and paid taxes for Ps. 8.9 billion.</p>
          <p>Now, I will now turn the conference to Scot to update on the accomplishments of the objectives for the year 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rafael. I would like to briefly compare the objectives we have set for the year versus our actual financial and social responsibility results. The first priority we set for ourselves last year was to accelerate sales growth. On a pro forma basis &#x2013; this is consolidating Central America for the last two years &#x2013; our sales grew 9.3% in 2010, increasing 180 basis points to 11.1% last year. So I think that we accomplished this objective.</p>
          <p>We also committed to reinforce our core Every Day Low Prices strategy in Mexico. We relaunched Every Day Low Prices in Mexico in the second quarter, reducing thousands of prices across the entire store. The investment in Every Day Low Price is paying off, with sales increasing steadily month-to-month and quarter-to-quarter.</p>
          <p>In 2011, we invested in the growth opportunities across all six countries, exceeding our expansion program for the year by roughly 500,000 square feet. In Mexico, we increased our installed capacity 13.2%, exceeding our goal of 12.2%. In Central America, our growth was 9.8% compared with the 8.8% announced at the beginning of the year. Total sales floor growth for the company was 12.8%. Total investment for the year was Ps. 18.4 billion, 3.4% less than what we had budgeted.</p>
          <p>Central America transformation was executed as planned, but it is still an ongoing process. We made considerable investment to bring the Central America operation closer to the Mexican one, including format alignment, introduction of the Walmart brand, launching of EDLP, and a regional structure by business format and systems. With these investments, we have set the foundations for our future growth.</p>
          <p>Driving our bank and financial services operation is also an ongoing process. Last year, we had significant progress in growing our credit business. Supplier loans almost doubled. Consumer loans are five times larger than a year ago and we have 4.6 times as many credit cards as we had in 2010. Deposits are nearly Ps. 3.0 billion, 2.2 times the amount that we had a year ago. We are rapidly approaching scale to achieve breakeven by the first quarter of 2013.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding that Walmex has the lowest cost structure in the market, we continue looking for additional opportunities to drive efficiencies, including labor productivity and distribution efficiency. In 2011, these productivity programs did not produce savings sufficient to offset our expansion costs. In 2012, we will continue looking for efficiencies to do more with less.</p>
          <p>Associates are our primary strength in leveraging growth. In 2011, we have more than 21,000 promotions. In fact, 80% of executive positions were covered with internal talent. We are confident that we have the quantity and quality of people to support our growth.</p>
          <p>Our commitment to being a good corporate citizen includes improving the places where we do business. Among other things, this year we channeled financial and in-kind donations amounting to Ps. 569 million. I feel very proud of the 134,000 associates who participated in more than 3,000 activities of voluntarism. With these kinds of efforts, we will continue our commitment to assisting the most vulnerable communities in the region.</p>
          <p>We continued our leadership position in the field of sustainability. In keeping with this purpose, we invested Ps. 2.6 billion in energy efficient equipment. We also continue promoting our culture of sustainability among our commercial partners, associates, and customers, thereby creating a multiplier effect in the favor of our planet.</p>
          <p>We offer our shareholders profitable growth, expansion, dividends and the repurchasing of shares. This year, Walmart de M&#xE9;xico y Centroam&#xE9;rica paid a regular and extraordinary dividend of Ps. 0.55 per share. Both dividends totaled Ps. 9.7 billion.</p>
          <p>Moreover, throughout the year we invested Ps. 3.5 billion to repurchase 103.2 million shares. In the last five years, stock yield including dividends was 72%. This is 11.4% compounded annual growth.</p>
          <p>Now, I will turn it back to Rafael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Scot, to finish I want to remind you that we will be hosting our 8th Annual Analyst Meeting tomorrow, February 21. Management presentations will be webcasted and we will be available at the company's Investor Relations webpage also at the same time.</p>
          <p>Likewise, I would like to inform you that approval was given today at the Board of Directors meeting to call for the annual shareholders meeting, during which there will be a proposal made for a regular dividend payment of Ps. 0.44 of per share and a special dividend payment of Ps. 0.11. And this is giving a total dividend of Ps. 0.55. This will be prepaid against coupons 53 and 54.</p>
          <p>With this, we conclude our conference call. Thank you once again. And I would like to remind you that we will be available to receive phone calls and address any questions that you may have.</p>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. This concludes today's conference. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>