<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1230417" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Interim 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3150</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Gail Kelly, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Phil Coffey, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Craig Williams</participant>
      <participant id="4">Gail Kelly</participant>
      <participant id="5">Phil Coffey</participant>
      <participant id="6">James Ellis</participant>
      <participant id="7">James Freeman</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jonathan Mott</participant>
      <participant id="9">Ben Koo</participant>
      <participant id="10">Philip Chronican</participant>
      <participant id="11">Richard Wiles</participant>
      <participant id="12">Brian Johnson</participant>
      <participant id="13">Greg Bartlett</participant>
      <participant id="14">Stewart Oldfield</participant>
      <participant id="15">Scott Manning</participant>
      <participant id="16">Brett Le Mesurier</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone and welcome to the presentation of Westpac's First Half 2009 Result. Joining me today is Gail Kelly, CEO and Phil Coffey our CFO.</p>
          <p>If I can please ask under the normal protocols to switch your mobile phone off and of course we'll have plenty of time at the end of this session after Gail and Phil's presentation to have questions. And I'll take over the reigns from them again but I want to hand over to Gail. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Andrew, and good morning to everyone here and thank you for joining us at our results briefing be it here in Westpac Place or via the telephone or via the webcast. I know it's been a busy time for you all with banks reporting on what has been a very difficult period for the financial system globally. I must say it would be hard to think of a six months period that would rival this one in terms of intensity, volatility and challenge.</p>
          <p>It's been a busy time for us as well to navigating the current environment, integrating St. George, while making sure we strengthen and bolstered our overall franchise. We certainly recognize that there is additional complexity in our results at this period, from the merger and other business model change. We've tried to make it as easy as possible to work through and we've aimed at providing clarity and transparency. And Phil and I would certainly welcome your feedback on this.</p>
          <p>In addition to Phil and I, we have the whole executive team here today, including our newest member George Frazis, who is on the telephone from New Zealand. And we look forward to taking any questions that you may have at the end of the presentation.</p>
          <p>Let me start by outlining what we believe are the key messages from the result. Firstly, against the background of this extraordinary challenging operating environment, we would describe the result as sound and one that clearly shows the benefit of having a diversified portfolio of businesses in markets that we know well.</p>
          <p>Overall, Westpac is in good shape and I am pleased to say that throughout this difficult period, we are continuing to apply to actively support our customers and further strengthen our relationships with them.</p>
          <p>The merger with St. George is progressing well and the St. George business is showing much improved momentum after what was a slow start to the half.</p>
          <p>With regard to asset quality, as the numbers show, we've had a marked deterioration. As mentioned at our February briefing, the major element here has been the rate of change. Against that background, we are working to ensure a significantly stronger balance sheet, high capital, improved funding profile and really excellent provisioning coverage.</p>
          <p>Lastly in terms of key messages, while the economy is still slowing with unemployment rising, we think the Australian household sector remains solid and we believe will hold up much better than it international peers.</p>
          <p>So turning to the financial scorecard, our headline cash earnings were down 6% for the year. This is on a pro forma basis as if we had owned St. George from the 1st of October, 2007. While this is a lower result, we see it as sound in the context of the overall environment.</p>
          <p>Core earnings growth of 24% was very strong with a healthy 15% revenue growth and 4% cost growth. This revenue cost mix has led to a marked improvement in our cost-to-income ratio which now stands at 40.4%.</p>
          <p>The impairment charge to average loans is also significantly higher standing at 73 basis points up from 27 basis points on 31st of March last year and 31 basis points at in September. And I think this reflects the rate of deterioration, which I referred to earlier and Phil will talk to this in some detail.</p>
          <p>Finally, the board has declared a $0.56 dividend down 20% from the previous year and I will provide some further comment on this shortly.</p>
          <p>We are benefiting from having a diversified portfolio as our business unit title highlights. Our Westpac Retail and Business Banking division, which effectively covers all Westpac consumer, SME and Agri costumers, has had an excellent six months period. We've seen good performance on both sides of the balance sheet. This is a business we've been investing in and it's good to see the uplift coming through. It's also worth noting that this business has had no distraction at all, from the St. George merger.</p>
          <p>The Westpac Institutional result looks quite extraordinary at summary level, core earnings up 44% and cash earnings down 62%. This business has both benefited from and suffered from the significant market volatility evident throughout the period. Higher revenues and higher impairment charges characterize the result.</p>
          <p>St. George is the story of rebuilding momentum after a slow start to the half. In its middle market and corporate segments St. George has seen higher impairment charges coming through largely in residential property development.</p>
          <p>While BT's core earnings and cash earnings are down on last years, I am pleased with the performance. Rob Coombe and his team have responded to the challenges of lower asset markets, with flat expenses. Market share gains are continuing to be made, particularly in Wrap and Corporate Super and the integration of the St. George Wealth businesses is going very well.</p>
          <p>New Zealand is and has been experiencing an even more difficult operating environment than Australia for some time. Our underlying performance is good, but unfortunately offset by higher impairment charges and impacts here are being felt in both the commercial and the residential sectors.</p>
          <p>The merger with St. George is of course the key feature of the past period, and we are now just over five months in. From a financial point of view, the synergy benefits are on track and we're beginning to see early savings out of our operating model, with more in the pipeline.</p>
          <p>In terms of employee engagement and customer engagement, conventional wisdom suggests that both should suffer in a merger, particularly in the early stages. This has not occurred here, which I think is a real feature of our merger. Overall, across the Westpac Group, employee engagement has come in at 82%, which is up from 78% last year. The St. George division has scored 81%, which is very strong in the light of a merger. Customer retention is pleasing too indeed the St. George franchise has grown in terms of customer numbers and there is no evidence that we've lost customers as a direct result of the merger.</p>
          <p>We are also underway with various projects to leverage revenue opportunities that arise across the Group, as a result of the merger, and I hope to be able to tell you at our November results briefing that the first BT Super for Life product has being sold to St. George customer, but certainly if not in November, it will be the case by early next year.</p>
          <p>Before I move on however, I should mention that we have a lot of heavy lifting work to do in the months and years ahead to truly fulfill the potential of this merger. And this involves the lining systems, lining operations and processes across the brands, which will drive both productivity benefit and enhance the service delivery. This will all take time and it will also take care.</p>
          <p>With this slide, let me return to the macro environment. As we look ahead into the second half of 2009 and into 2010 we see further deterioration and further slowing of growth and further drive to further strengthen our balance sheet. With regard to capital, we've raised 4.7 billion of Tier 1 during the half and our Tier 1 ratio now stands at a healthy 8.37%, well above our internal target and APRA minimums.</p>
          <p>On dividend, the 20% reduction reflects the earnings per share is some 16% lower. Reducing the dividend is of course not an easy decision and the Board balanced the number of considerations in making this decision including the imperative of retaining capital strengths. $0.56 gives us a payout ratio of close to 70%, which is consistent with what we have paid out in prior periods. It also provides a fully franked yield of around 7.5%.</p>
          <p>On provisioning coverage, we've clearly bolstered our position. Our specific provision cover stands at 48% and our collective provision to credit risk-weighted assets has increased to 125 basis points, a significant uplift over the 12 months as is reflected in the middle chart on the slide.</p>
          <p>Finally, we've also materially enhanced our funding profile. The success we've had in gathering customer deposits, combined with initiatives to lengthen the profile of our book have led to an uplift in our stable funding ratio to 81%, which is up from 67% a year ago.</p>
          <p>Before I hand over to Phil, let me take a moment to reflect on some of the highlights and lowlights of the period from my perspective.</p>
          <p>I'll start with the lowlights, and there's three to call out. Firstly, as I've mentioned already, the significant and rapid rise in stressed assets. Secondly, our margin lending impairment charges. While we conducted portfolio reviews during the course of 2008 and improved our position, we were unable to mitigate the downside as effectively as I would have liked. We are taking steps to further strengthen the overall management of this business.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, and more generally, redesigning operational processes and reducing complexity in Westpac is challenging and can be quite frustrating. It's disappointing that we sometimes make it hard for our customers to deal with us, resulting in poor service experiences. On the positive side, the merger with St. George will actually assist us in this work, and we have a growing number of examples of using best practice from one brand across the whole.</p>
          <p>Turning to the highlights, I've mentioned most of these already. So perhaps I would expand on just one, the restored deposit momentum. You may recall that a year ago in delivering the first half results, I spoke to the need for us to improve our focus and our capabilities in deposit raising. At the full year result, while we'd made some inroads, it was still disappointing. We've now turned the corner on this. Through a range of initiatives, we've materially strengthened the organization's understanding of the importance of raising customer deposits. And we've strengthened our capability in this area. I'm particularly pleased that this work has been embraced across the organization with strong product management working very closely with all of our distribution businesses.</p>
          <p>So in handing over to Phil, my sum up would be, we've delivered a sound performance with underlying businesses in good shape. This is a challenging environment and one that has deteriorated quite rapidly. Our response has been to build a much stronger balance sheet.</p>
          <p>So Phil, I'll hand over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thanks, Gail and good morning, everyone. Before kicking off, I wanted to reiterate how we've approached our reporting in this half, given we've now completed the merger. We sought to apply an approach that provides clarity now and in the future. As we indicated with our template release, we've calculated pro forma performance for each of the past three half year periods. This recast our results as if Westpac and St. George had merged on the 1st of October 2007. We haven't adjusted any of the Westpac or St. George cash earnings results but we have aligned the accounting and risk approaches.</p>
          <p>As part of the adjustment for this half, we've calculated the result including a full six months of St. George earnings not just from the 18th of November, 2008. And we believe this is an appropriate treatment given that while we only merged with St. George on the 17th of November, we also acquired their retained earnings for the period from the 1st of October to the 17th of November. Our statutory results of course record just the results from the 18th of November and we have provided a full reconciliation of our statutory and pro forma results.</p>
          <p>As in prior years we've adjusted NPAT for our usual one-off and non-cash items, so that we can focus on the underlying business drivers. And we have consistently referred to that as our cash earnings and we've done so again today. You'll note that the merger fair value and acquisition accounting processes impacts both our statutory balance sheet and profit and loss, but had little impact on our cash earnings.</p>
          <p>So turning to the result and as Gail has mentioned our performance for the half was sound with cash earnings 6% lower of the prior corresponding period, which was not surprising in the context of the environment. The highlight of the half was the exceptionally strong revenue growth and of course the lowlight was the steep increase in impairment charges.</p>
          <p>The factors that we identified in our February update as impacting the P&amp;L have broadly continued. Revenue growth at 15% was supported by good volume growth, strong margins and an excellent markets performance, whilst impairments reflect higher in impaired facilities and additional customers stress, especially in the commercial business segment. Our provisions also included a further increase to our economic overlay in the half by $112 million. These factors were also the main drivers of performance when it's compared with the prior period.</p>
          <p>In recent years a ready reckoner of net interest income growth has been lending growth of between 12 to 15% offset by margin decline of say five to 10 basis points. This year we have a different mix with lower lending growth and improved margins maintaining good net interest income growth.</p>
          <p>Margins have been a particular focus over the year and they have recovered back to levels we saw in March, 2007 or just prior to the onset of the global financial crisis. Our margin composition, however, is still a bit different with a significant part of the recent rise coming from our treasury management.</p>
          <p>Retail and business margins recovered seven basis points as higher spreads on lending offset reduced spreads on customer deposits. The increased lending spreads reflect the greater risk now obvious in the current economy, as well as the higher funding costs that are affecting everyone and that will continue to roll through.</p>
          <p>At the same time competition in the deposits space has been fierce and we've seen a material decline in our deposits spreads. This is both from the higher rates that we have to pay and from the effect of growing faster in the higher rate products especially in term deposits.</p>
          <p>A feature of this period has been our management of interest rate risk in our treasury and in our markets areas and these groups made a significant contribution to margins in the half. You can see in the upper half of this chart the steady decline in margins that we've experienced over the last decade and that margins today are still well below the average of previous years.</p>
          <p>I mentioned how pleased we are with the results of our management of market risk and we have high quality and stable management teams across the markets and treasury areas. And they have capitalized on the current environment. Conditions clearly have been favorable and strong banks around the world have recently reported good trading results.</p>
          <p>In Australia, we've recorded big moves in interest rates, the official cash rate was reduced by 375 basis points during the six months and FX volatility was also very high. The Aussie/U.S. rate fell from a high of $0.80 at the start of October to a low of $0.60 during the period. For Westpac, the strength of our customer franchise and AA rating has also supported our result. Around half of our performance can be attributed to the increased flow originating from our own customers, who were seeking to more actively manage the risks that they have in these more volatile conditions.</p>
          <p>Our customer-based businesses saw little change in the level of VaR market risk, while our treasury reported high levels of VaR. Their structural risk positions were similar in size, and the higher VaR reflects the sharply increased market volatility.</p>
          <p>Expense disciplines were tightened this half and underlying expense growth has slowed. Growth, however was impacted by a number of one-offs, especially higher expenses for the defined benefit Super plan and for the redemption of credit card loyalty points associated with the change in the Qantas reward arrangements. These one-offs more than offset benefits that we have from lower software amortization. However, we've also continued to invest in the front line with more people and new and better branches in the Westpac Retail business. We've also invested in improving our IT capability.</p>
          <p>The trend in underlying expenses is best looked at compared with the prior half and you can see by business unit, where investment is taking place and where the tougher growth environment is leading to appropriate expense restraint and that's shown on this chart. Expense growth is easing but we're not being diverted from our strategy and we will continue to invest where we believe it's sensible.</p>
          <p>Given we're now reporting under our new operating model. I'd like to briefly highlight the major elements of performance for our major business units. Our Westpac Retail and Business Banking supports our Westpac consumer customers and smaller business customers, big companies with facilities typically under $15 million. This unit produced a really pleasing increase in earnings with strong mortgage growth including from RAMS and excellent deposit growth. In both these critical areas, Westpac grew solidly ahead of system. Notwithstanding a considerable reduction in deposit spreads, margins overall had improved. Given the 17% rise in cash earnings, it's clear this division has not been diverted by the merger, nor have we been diverted from our strategy, which continues to invest in front line and the roll out of our new local model.</p>
          <p>The WIB result now includes our Premium Business Group or PBG, which covers Westpac business customers with facilities typically within the range of 10 to $100 million. This has been an extreme period for WIB. Cash earnings were lower in the half and WIB has borne the brunt of impairment charges with $751 million in total from the Institutional Bank and PBG, and the $156 million in the margin lending business. And I will provide some more detail on this latter area in a moment. Helping to offset this cost, revenue growth was exceptionally strong, from the markets results and from good growth of 17% in our transactional banking business.</p>
          <p>Our SCG business, on the other hand, was disappointing with a writedown in investments reducing revenue by 125 million. These investments covered assets we've acquired and which are designed to be cornerstone assets for the future funds, small direct equity investments and big investments in various existing listed funds. The slide highlights the residual value in these areas post the writedowns and that is modest. We remain committed to supporting the core funds management activities, but with a materially lower amount of capital tied up in principle exposures.</p>
          <p>St. George, Retail and Business Bank also serves consumer customers in small businesses, but also continues to serve large commercial and corporate customers as well, with facilities up to around $150 million. Coming to this half, growth in this business had slowed as merger uncertainty had diverted focus and investment. And you can see in the lower section of this slide, mortgage lending was running about half a system in September, October and November, but since December momentum has improved, and for the last three months mortgage lending has been running at or above system. And deposit growth has similarly improved.</p>
          <p>Impaired assets and charges have significantly grown in the half as the economy weakened and as St. George commercial and corporate customers, especially those involved in residential property, evidenced higher financial stress. On the other hand, St. George consumer customers continued to perform well.</p>
          <p>Bedding down the merger and getting underway with our multi-brand approach has clearly been critical for St. George, and we are really pleased with the solid customer satisfaction and retention performance. Our BankSA result in particular was a standout and performance there hasn't skipped a beat.</p>
          <p>Our BT Wealth division now includes the results for Asgard, the Advance funds and Securitor advisory group. Not surprisingly, the decline in investment markets throughout the half has lowered <mark type="inaudible" />. Cash earnings were down around $36 million due to weaker investment markets. Underlying investor flows, however, continued to be relatively good with our platforms capturing one-third of new industry flows. We also continue to focus on cross-selling our wealth products through the bank and our insurance products and Super for Life in general insurance sales continue to be strong.</p>
          <p>Our insurance earnings were better overall, with earnings growth of 10%, mainly from life insurance and the LMI book.</p>
          <p>Claims in general insurance were higher from those well-publicized storms and fires that we experienced in the half.</p>
          <p>This business has been dealing with downward pressure on revenue for 18 months now and has reset expenses for these lower levels of activity. So there has been no expense growth in BT when compared with the pcp. Overall, BT has responded well to the tough growth environment.</p>
          <p>And now turning to our New Zealand group, which post our merger with St. George makes up about 7% of Group earnings. And New Zealand is another business aiming to make the best of a more challenging environment. We've been dealing with a deeper and larger economic recession in that country and customer credit stress is considerably higher. The business mix also tends to have a higher concentration towards the residential market and that is one of the softer sectors. Mortgages delinquent more than 90 days have risen to 82 basis points as falling house prices have pressured borrowers and much of the stress has been from borrowers that rely on business income rather than wage earners.</p>
          <p>Commercial property often also related to residential development is also an area showing stress and behind a large amount of the $123 million growth in impairment charges.</p>
          <p>The increase in impairments has more than offset good growth in our core earnings. Revenue has been underpinned by improving margins at the same time as we have improved the depth of our customer relationships. And expenses continue to be tightly managed growing only 2% over the prior period.</p>
          <p>So let me now turn to the critical issues within the results and starting with credit health and this slide is the best representation of the credit health of our portfolio and one we have shared consistently. It stands out because it not only shows what's happened to impaired loans but it also looks at the certain lease that have been downgraded to watchlist and substandard and hence are getting increased management attention.</p>
          <p>The picture we reviewed in our February update is similar to the story shown here. Our total stressed exposures as a percent of our total committed exposures have risen and are at 206 basis point and that's up from 100 at the end of March and from 130 basis points at the end of September and they were 173 basis points at the end of December.</p>
          <p>All component parts of our stressed assets have deteriorated starting from the bottom with our impaired assets reflecting the three corporate exposures previously identified, which totaled $700 million, a $160 million increase in the margin lending portfolio and from general increases from the commercial lending portfolio facilities between 10 and $100 million and that means you will see them both in our PBG business in WIB and in the corporate portfolio in St. George.</p>
          <p>Our greater than 90 day but well secured increase is due to small business and housing exposures in Australia and New Zealand although Australian housing delinquencies and losses are still very modest.</p>
          <p>The watchlist and substandard increase is also mainly in commercial lending exposures although we've had little net increase in St. George watchlist as downgrades offset new exposures. Most of the increase was in WIB.</p>
          <p>Following the merger with St. George, we've now reviewed some 3,000 files to ensure alignment of the Westpac and St. George risk rates and this review has given us a very good assessment as to the quality of the book. As we indicated in February, you can see that combining St. George into the Westpac portfolio has not changed our overall risk profile.</p>
          <p>Our impairment result in our margin lending portfolio is a disappointed, as Gail called out. Notwithstanding reducing our exposures to larger risks early in 2008, we did not reduce this risk sufficiently. A further sharp weakness that we saw in asset markets over the half, together with the closure of some specific funds resulted in our assessment that a small number of larger facilities were impaired and we have taken an individual provision of $110 million in the half. I should add that the problem in this portfolio has been linked to a relatively small segment. Most of the portfolio is comprised of smaller, diversified exposures that are well secured and that have generated minimal losses over the past 18 months.</p>
          <p>Of the larger exposures, there still remains around 310 million of some more concentrated facilities and we have topped up the collective provision by an additional 46 million to account for additional risks in this business.</p>
          <p>In recognition of our increase in stressed exposures and the clear uncertainty in the outlook, we have significantly increased our provisioning coverage over the half. Through new impairment charges and adjustments to provisions in the merger accounting alignment, we've added just over $1 billion to our individually assessed provisions and over 1.3 billion to our collectively assessed provisions or CAP. The CAP includes our economic overlay for specific risks from the economic environment and certain segments, which includes New Zealand and property and that now totals 510 million.</p>
          <p>When looking at coverage, it's important to also look separately at the different aspects of the book at both individually assessed and the collectively assessed coverage. Focusing only on the total can be misleading particularly if the book has a higher proportion of impaired loans. On our impaired assets, specific cover has risen to over 48% and that includes a higher cover required on some of our more recent impairments. On the CAP, we've increased our cover by over 25% over the year. Collective provisions to credit risk-weighted assets now stands at 125 basis points. I believe by any measure our provisioning coverage is now clearly the most conservative in the industry.</p>
          <p>The overall impact of provision charges to the P&amp;L in the half totaled a charge of 1,611 million and the increase in the charge at the half was mainly for individual provisions in the areas that I've already called out.</p>
          <p>In the new CAP, write-offs have shown only a modest increase as the consumer unsecured portfolio continues to perform well. We had seen a large increase in new CAP provisions predominately for the commercial sector but this increase was partly offset by movement in CAP provisions into individual as some facilities re-graded to impair. The increase in the economic overlay was an important component of the CAP charge.</p>
          <p>A major highlight of the half was the improvement in the funding profile of the Group. Customer deposit growth, which has been a specific focus of ours for sometime, saw particularly strong activity and growth over the past six months and that growth was 13% in six months. This lifted the composition of customer deposits to total funding, a full eight percentage points. At the same time, wholesale investors have supported our government-guaranteed debt issues and we have extended the duration of our wholesale issuance. We've raised approximately $21 billion in new wholesale funding since the end of October with an average duration of 3.6 years. The combination of these two elements, deposits and term wholesale funding and more modest loan growth has seen us reduce our lines on less certain short-term wholesale funding and offshore short-term funding in particular is now less than 10% of the total funding base.</p>
          <p>We also topped up our liquidity buffer and liquid assets at $62 billion are equivalent to more than 12 months of offshore maturities. Although, our overall funding costs will be higher, the quality of this funding base is a material improvement. And it also deals directly with concerns expressed by rating agencies on the funding risks of Australian banks generally.</p>
          <p>Another key balance sheet strength of the Group is the quantum and quality of the capital base. We were very active over the half in managing our capital through institutional and retail share issuance and in the hybrids issue. These raisings have facilitated the redemption of the St. George hybrids as part of the merger. The impact on capital of lower investment returns to the defined benefit Super fund and that had a negative 12 basis points impact. Accounting adjustments from the merger, which ultimately saw a large deduction than originally estimated at $379 million, and that was also equivalent to 14 basis points. And from risk-weighted asset growth from volumes and change in risk.</p>
          <p>And this slide also highlights the impact of pro-cyclicality on our capital ratios and in the half it was six basis points from re-grades and 24 basis points from higher individual impairments. Notwithstanding those deductions, our Tier 1 capital ratio has improved from the end of September pro forma level of 7.06% to 8.37% at the end of March. And if you use FSA methodology, our Tier 1 ratio would now be approaching 11%.</p>
          <p>A strong capital position is a critical requirement for banking especially in these times and that was the ultimate driver of the reduction in our dividend that Gail has mentioned.</p>
          <p>Gail will talk about the economic outlook, so perhaps I can make some comments on some areas of the P&amp;L likely over the remainder of the year. Revenue from activities related to markets is unlikely to be as strong as what we saw in the first half results. Our customer franchise remains a major support; however we don't expect the unique events of the December quarter to recur. Lending growth is also likely to continue to slow, especially in business lending as investment contracts and companies focus on their balance sheet strength rather than on growth. Partially offsetting the slower system growth, we expect further gains in market share in all of our core lending portfolios.</p>
          <p>On margins, higher funding costs including from deposits are likely to continue to impact, and lending spreads are also likely to continue to rise.</p>
          <p>On expenses, we will continue to invest in extending our front line capacity especially in our consumer and business distribution areas, including enhancing our technology. However, we will also see more material benefits from merger expense synergies and expect the overall expense growth rate to continue to slow.</p>
          <p>Lastly, impairment charges are expected to continue to reflect the deteriorating economic circumstances in our home economies. And whilst additional large one-offs are not on the immediate horizon, we are preparing for our enlarged watchlist. And our strong provisioning coverage is proof to that.</p>
          <p>So let me quickly sum up. Our performance reflects an extremely eventful six months. Notwithstanding extraordinary components, the overall result was sound. Impairment charges showed a steep increase during the half, due to the global financial crisis and as our regional economies moved into the first economic recession in 18 years. Strong revenue growth however helped to offset the higher impairments.</p>
          <p>Underlying these aggregates, our diversified portfolio of activities continued to deliver and our market positioning improved including through the addition of the St. George suite of businesses.</p>
          <p>The outlook remains uncertain, not surprising, given the local and global economic pressures and we are prepared for this challenge by materially strengthening the balance sheet with stronger capital, funding and provisioning.</p>
          <p>Let me hand back to Gail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Phil. What I'll do in this section is make a few comments on our strategic agenda as well as say a few words on the period ahead. So this slide and the next deal with our strategic priority areas and provide and update on progress. I intend to touch only lightly on this today but obviously would be very happy to take questions.</p>
          <p>As you will recall from previous briefings, at the core of our agenda is driving a significantly stronger customer culture. We quote our five key priorities areas and this year we added a six being the merger. Overall I am very pleased with the progress we've made. In terms of the customer priority and earning all of our customers' business, I've already referenced the strong uplift in deposit gathering. We've also have excellent cross-sell results particularly wealth and insurance products into our Westpac customer base. We continue to be able to sell over 2,000 Super for Life products per week through our Westpac branch system.</p>
          <p>Possibly the most significant progress has occurred with regard to distribution. Our multi-brand approach is taking shape and will be a real differentiation for us. In the Westpac brand, we've materially strengthened our footprint and our banker capability. Over the past six months we've added over 500 people to this business. Our local market strategy is well underway with 35 regional general managers in place and bank manager appointments in training.</p>
          <p>Within St. George momentum is rebuilding. St. George has a very distinctive set of of brand attributes, which are all about being warm and friendly and people orientated, about being down-to-earth and passionate about service. We are making sure that we preserve these attributes and understand how best to deploy them segment-by-segment and within each geography.</p>
          <p>Technology has been a big focus for us this half. As I've previously mentioned, the Westpac systems environment is inherently very complex and is subject to reliability issues. Bob McKinnon, who's been with us since August last year, has significantly strengthened the team and introduced discipline, rigor and analytics into our IT environment, so improving reliability and stability. Under Bob's leadership, we've also developed a strategy and an IT roadmap for the years ahead, which is pragmatic and executable and will drive further benefits from the merger.</p>
          <p>I'll finish with some thoughts from a looking-ahead perspective. Firstly, it remains uncertain how deep and how protracted the Australian economic downturn will be. As noted already in this presentation, we've seen the economy decline more rapidly than was expected. You may recall that the debate in early November was whether Australia would be able to avoid a recession, and the debate today is, how bad will it be and how long will it last.</p>
          <p>Certainly, demand for credit has slowed materially, particularly in the business sector. This sector is going to remain very challenging and we expect business credit growth to be negative by September this year and remain so for 2010.</p>
          <p>Growth has slowed for the housing sector too although demand is being supported by the First Home Buyer Grant. From a credit quality point of view the housing sector remains solid and this is important. Although, we will certainly see further pressure on delinquencies as unemployment grows over 2009 and into 2010, we believe this sector will hold up relatively well and will be the first sector to lead the economy out of recession in 2010.</p>
          <p>There are lots of reasons I can put forward for the relative resilience of the sector, including the significant reduction in interest rates for home borrowers over the past nine months. The absence of subprime lending in this market. There is no overhang of unsold houses. In fact, there is demand for housing as evidenced by the response to the First Home Buyer Grant. And house prices, particularly in New South Wales have moderated over a period rather than as a sudden fall. The fact that the banks have exercised strong credit quality disciplines and will actively work to support their customers who are in a hardship situation to stay in their houses will certainly further assist.</p>
          <p>Having said all that, when the recovery emerges it is likely to be a slow haul, as balance sheets are repaired and confidence improves. It'll take a while for growth to be firmly established and when it is, consumers and businesses are likely to operate with more conservative settings.</p>
          <p>Certainly our settings in managing Westpac are conservative. Caution and disciplined risk management is the best way we can support our customers and our shareholders at this point in the cycle. And so in this past period in delivering what we see is a sound result, we have actively worked to strengthen our balance sheet. I am pleased that we enter the second half of the year with a strong capital position, a much improved funding profile and very healthy provisioning coverage.</p>
          <p>In summary, I believe we're well placed to deal with the issues ahead. We are also well placed to continue to support our customers and to assist them through this period.</p>
          <p>So thank you for listening to Phil and I and I'll now hand over to Andrew, who will introduce the question-and-answer session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gail. Can I just remind everyone -- I can hear the &#x2013;  someone's phone may be on, like an incoming through the system and I just want to make sure that if people could just check their phones again. It's pretty distracting for those on the webcast and on the phone call.</p>
          <p>I might just also ask if we could limit the questions to one at a time, please, and we'll go ahead. I'll start with Craig, I'll just start with you, Craig Williams, just in the front, there, Mandy. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Craig Williams at Citi. As you noted, Gail, the business is in very good shape. St. George gives you some synergies in the next couple of years and credit cost will normalize and help keep some earnings growth. But you painted the picture toward the end there of a lower growth outlook for credit in Australia and New Zealand presumably as well. So with that backdrop in mind, where does Westpac source its revenue growth from all the Australian banks over the sort of five to 10 year period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think my comments really relate to the next &#x2013; the balance of this year and &#x2013; into next year, well, where clearly growth is slowing. As I indicated I think the housing sector will be the section of the economy that really takes us out of the recession and there is, and remains demand for housing &#x2013; I mean, demand for housing at the moment would stand &#x2013; system growth would be around six to 7% and we expect it to remain of that order. Now in later years I think it will pick up again. Housing is a very, very strong sector within Australia.</p>
          <p>Within Westpac as a whole though one of the reasons I think that we are very well placed for the future is that we are using this environment, this more difficult time to really strengthen our core franchises. And you've seen the evidence of that. In our Westpac Retail and Business Bank we've been putting in additional people, we're implanting our local market model, we're building banker capability. We're really &#x2013; just it's really having business facing &#x2013; a business model that really supports our distribution putting a lot of effort and focus there.</p>
          <p>And then with St. George we are really doing a key piece of work at the moment. As I have indicated around making sure that we leverage the strengths of the franchise, the strengths of the brand attributes, segment-by-segment and geography-by-geography. And so through this rich set of brands that we have that are iconic brands St. George, BankSA, Westpac and RAMS, we really think that we are in a excellent position to grow at above system growth for each one of those brands in the core markets that we want to target.</p>
          <p>So revenue growth will come through from there so additional growth through those core segments. And over time, I mean, clearly with regard to the margins side, we are busy; funding cost remain high and they will do I think into the foreseeable feature, but we clearly are also making sure that there is appropriate risk-based pricing that we will play through into all of our businesses in the future. So I think we are well-placed for the longer run.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could I just add, I think, obviously, wealth has been a drag in our earnings for the last 18 months and given the structural set up of wealth in Australia, we would really expect that to be a very positive contributor in the medium to long-term and so we would expect that to absolutely come through in our results as we head out of this period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's absolutely right. Thanks, Phil. And I know that one of the things that Rob Coombe is most excited about with the St. George merger is the additional 3 million customers that come with additional opportunity, because St. George has always been quite poor really would be probably the best word with regard to cross-sell of wealth products into the St. George customer base. So there is a big opportunity with our really excellent products that we offer through BT and insurance products to use that opportunity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I gather from the early parts of your response that you don't see some high loan-to-deposit ratios for Australian banks or high household gearing levels as representing too much constraint.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the funding composition piece is clearly an issue for all the banks in Australia, and you've seen how we've looked to address it. I think it's wrong to just look solely at deposits. I think we've called out and a number of other of our peers does as well that the stable funding ratio which also looks at longer term wholesale is the way to look at the quality of the composition of your funding base, because if you have got wholesale funding for over 12 months, you know you've got it for over 12 months regardless of what kind of uncertainty might come through. And so we think that through the combination of both the wholesale term and through deposits we'll certainly be in a position to support the loan growth that we are looking for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sir James Ellis from Credit Suisse. Just a question on the margin; obviously, it's an environment where there are big pluses and minuses on the margin and where it finally comes out at, but just sort of focus on the three influences that Phil mentioned for the outlook, the two negatives of higher funding costs and also deposit spread pressure on the negatives but then on the positive side the lending spreads. If we just focus on those three influences and exclude all other impacts on the margin, do you think in the second half those two negatives will be greater than or less than the positive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We deliberately haven't called that out because there is a lot of unknown factors in how that's going to work through into the second half. But all of those are the major factors. And I think we haven't as banks communicated well enough really the quite extraordinary pressures on funding costs on those two elements that you mention the retail deposit side of things &#x2013; term deposits and the very expensive basis at the moment of raising money there. It's very attractive obviously for all of us but actually very expensive. So that's one element.</p>
          <p>And the other of course is on the wholesale side of things. A consumer was telling me yesterday that through &#x2013; over recent months using the government guarantee, we've raised something like 19 billion of term wholesale funding. And he was telling me that the average cost of that 19 billion was 178 basis points. Now, if we graded that two years ago that's inclusive of course of the 70 basis points that gets passed on to the government, if we'd &#x2013; if we graded that two years ago it would have been more like 20 basis points.</p>
          <p>So that's the materiality of the shift in funding cost and of course, that's the average cost of funds is going to increase as those new terms settle in and replace the terms that are moving off. So those are all quite material factors but at the same time, we are actively repricing our loan book. We're actively engaging with our customers and repricing for risk there too. So I don't want to say we are going to settle off, but actively doing that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe something <mark type="inaudible" /> what portion at the end of the business book has been repriced <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's different in different parts of our business. Certainly WIB and Phil Chronican would say he's into his second round really because our WIB business would reprice on a two-year average really and so there is a level of second round whereas maybe at the beginning of the crisis it was appropriate to raise prices by a certain amount, now that we are further in and funding costs have only got worse, there is a little bit of repricing that's going on there.</p>
          <p>And in the Peter Hanlon world and the PBG world we are probably around 25 to 30% of the way in and it would be similar perhaps 30% or so in the St. George world too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>James Freeman from Deutsche bank. Just having a look at the slide 19 where you've given us the stressed exposures and then comparing to slide 49 in your investor discussion pack where you've given St. George's stressed exposures. It's showing St. George's stressed exposures at 4.5%. Yet if I look at the Group it's saying it's a bit &#x2013; round about 2, 2.06. Just wondering how St. George does not have a material impact on the Group in terms of stressed exposures when they are running almost double that of the Group?</p>
          <p>And just if we can get an idea as to what's in that stressed exposure and any other security levels over those and whether a 1.25% collective provision coverage is actually required when you've got stressed exposures of 4.5% range running through one part of the book?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we've called out on that slide. Yeah, James, that's the exposure to the business TCE, and if you looked at &#x2013; look at our PBG portfolio for example that would also show a similar picture. And as I called out, it is that commercial customer 10 to $100 million type facility, which is definitely experiencing the most stress. And so the St. George business customers in that segment look very similar to the Westpac business customers in that segment. And clearly that's the segment that you would expect to have the highest percentage of total stressed exposures as a proportion of their total committed exposure. But when you put it all together with lots of other parts of our portfolio including obviously the very big part of the portfolio that is mortgages, which are running at a much lower level of stress, so that overall stress ratio comes down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. What's the size of that portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have that number off the top of my head.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can get that for you later James....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, James, I just don't have it right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just confirming the WIB one on page 47, where you're showing actually 2.5% for Westpac, that's not on a comparable basis to the St. George business portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, because WIB obviously has the big corporate. It has the PBG. So it has a more blended portfolio of customers. And so that's what drives the overall WIB picture. And once again, in WIB, as I mentioned, the big growth in watchlist that you saw, which is in WIB, is largely in that middle market area, the PBG.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, and that's about 4.5% as well then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Matt Davison from Bank of America-Merrill Lynch. Just following on from James' question and maybe moving it back to impaired loans, if we have a look at your new and increased impaired loans for the Group, about 1.8 billion; and then looking at the move in the St. George impaired loans to about 1.5%, it does seem to imply that the move in the St. George book was larger than the Westpac book. Just wondering if you could expand a bit more on that trend? And just how it coincides with the provisioning and whether those impaired loans have been viewed as relatively low loss given default or likely losses and whether they've been provided for in the merger adjustments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me kick off...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...and then you can add on. I can give you a little bit of color into the impaireds in St. George because it's actually quite &#x2013; it's quite interesting to drill down and actually understand what's happening in that portfolio. In the 70% of &#x2013; if you look at the top 10 impaireds and the top 10 impaireds of St. George's impaireds commercial portfolio is actually 70% of its total. So the top 10 is a good first look. Nine out of the top 10 are actually residential property developments. So it's quite interesting that that's where the impaireds are. They aren't in investment property, they are actually in residential property developments. And if you understand a little more about that, typically they are in Southeast Queensland, Western Australia and outside of CBD areas within the New South Wales or Victorian arena.</p>
          <p>And typically what's actually happened there is cash flow issues with developers, difficulty in getting sales away, some process issues around documentation and also to be honest in this environment valuations coming under pressure. So we had a fresh look at the valuations as you can imagine as part of the &#x2013; bringing this portfolio into the Westpac world and had a good look at every single one and made sure that we got appropriate valuations for those developments.</p>
          <p>So that's the biggest chunk of the St. George impaireds which is actually quite different really from the PBG, and Westpac scenario which is more broad based, it's the property in it, but it's more broad based, it goes to other sectors as well. So quite interesting to see that difference.</p>
          <p>So let me stop at that and pass on to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the additional rate of impaireds in St. George. That's right; I mean if you look at the total stressed movement in the half, in St. George portfolio it's more impaired rather than in watchlist and substandard. I don't think that actually reflects necessarily a difference in the portfolio. I actually thinks it reflects that we've moved into utilizing the Westpac credit approach and I think we've erred on the side of caution there. But when I look at the overall growth in stressed in total, whilst they are different components as Gail just called out, as I said, the aggregate picture of both stressed is very similar.</p>
          <p>In terms of just how it plays through with what we did in the acquisition accounting, the approach we've taken is to make sure that when we looked at the portfolio that we had graded the St. George portfolio as it stood going into the merger appropriately and we've taken that adjustment through as an accounting adjustment. And then really from that point onwards, we treated the St. George portfolio as utilized in the Westpac approach for grading any impairment charges from then on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just on that point, it would appear that the new impaireds have quite a bit worse in the last five months for St. George, but it would also appear that the assumed losses against those are not particularly high.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the point I was making actually, over the last six months or five months markets have actually significantly deteriorated. The economy has significantly deteriorated over that period. We've seen &#x2013; and across both Westpac and St. George you know, quite a significant shift through the grades. And those particular impaireds there are a couple of large ones in there. Those are the ones we've looked at the property valuations, made absolutely sure that we're comfortable with those. And as a consequence a number of those went into impaireds. Clearly, there is some security there because they...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>... have residential property development. So clearly there is some security there. But we deemed it wasn't sufficient and therefore, we put it in impaireds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's why the provisioning is lower because they've got security whereas you look at the big three that we had in the first quarter and which led to big improvement or big increase in impairments. Obviously, the provision we've had to take for that is higher than normal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gerard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gerard Martin, Royal Bank of Scotland. My question is in relation to the second dotpoint on slide 30, just regarding the recovery and your comment that you expect the recovery will be slower and take longer than prior cycles. What's the implications of that in terms of bad debt charges? Do we now see a longer more sustained higher level of bad debt charges over FY '10 and '11, rather than a short sharp pick in BDDs  is that the implications of that type of recovery?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think so. I think more the implications are it will be slower growth, that's what I think the implications are. Because typically what happens when a recession is driven by financial system crisis, which is what's happened here. That's when you actually have the slower harder recovery rather than the v-shape recover. Because what households do and what businesses do is actually want to repair their balance sheets and so they are busy, busy repaying debts and deleveraging. And that means slower growth and it means slower spending and it means just a longer harder road out of the recession. But I don't think it means great level of impairments.</p>
          <p>I expect we are still in the rising trend. It's going to be another very tough second half. Obviously not prepared to put a number on it but we expect impairments to remain high into the second half and indeed into the first half of 2010. But at that point we're going to find that we are into recovery and it begins to stabilize. So I think the major impact on what I am saying is more the slower growth, more conservative approach towards managing businesses and more conservative approach from households as well with regard to managing their indebtedness.</p>
          <p>It's great at the moment though I mean the deleveraging in some respects, something like 75% maybe even a bit more, I think it is a bit more, of our home lending portfolio is paying as if back when interest rates were 425 basis points high. So they are repaying at rates prior to these interest rate reductions coming through. So that's great from a point of view of improving the strength and stability of that sector.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jon Mott from UBS. Just following on from that comment and a question on the growth in the mortgage book. You saw in the half that mortgage book grew by 6% and as you are saying that a lot of people in the back book  are paying off very quickly. If you combine that with the brokers going from 38 to 43% of the new flows, it  would suggest that you are seeing a very big rise in the level of new lending and most of that would be the first home owners. If we do get to a situation where rates start to rise, unemployment start to go up, aren't we just sitting here in two year's time with a big issue of not a  subprime but an underperforming mortgage market and a hell of a lot of stressed consumers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we are &#x2013; obviously, yeah, paying an enormous amount of attention to make sure that the business we write at the moment is appropriate and follows our policies and standards that we don't put ourselves into a poor situation and nor do we put customers into a situation of indebtedness that they wouldn't be able to afford either. So you can be absolutely sure that we are all over that.</p>
          <p>By the way, on the broker percentage you need again to look at it brand-by-brand and the St. George brand has come back a bit; it's mostly the RAMS brand and that is it involves a specific dedicated specialist home branding channel and the increase in broker flows are typically coming from that particular channel.</p>
          <p>We have a tightened credit criteria across the board, but very specifically in this segment as well. So we typically won't lend more than 90% to this particular segment. And, of course, it's not just a loan-to-valuation ratio analysis that we do. We clearly look at the borrower's ability to be able to afford the loan, the borrower's track record, has the borrower been a customer of ours for a period of time, what other debts of relationship might that borrower have. The combined situation with partners. So it's a range of things that we're looking at there not simply a loan-to-valuation ratio. So we're very comfortable with the position we've got.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just add Jon to the risk of if rates move back up does that put pressure on borrowers, one of the things that we use is an affordability threshold, which says that the borrower is going to be able to afford paying off at, I think, it's 7.46%? So it doesn't really matter how much further rates fall, that 7.46 threshold is a requirement and as rates move back up so that threshold rises.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's a spread over the current rate because 7.46 is where we were four months ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>... And you write so much customers were well over 9% eight months ago. So that rate that you stress test will start rising?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will move back up again if &#x2013; but it also &#x2013; it means it won't back down again. It won't move any further lower. And I think people are worried that if rates bounce back up, can people afford it? I think at 7.46 it's already got quite a big buffer above where we are today and goes to the affordability question that you had.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Ben Koo, Goldman Sachs JBWere. Just getting back on to the funding point and how those high costs are flowing through when you pass them on to the customers, can you just elaborate on the capacity of your business lending and the institutional customers to absorb higher funding costs being passed through and what margin we're passing as we go into a recession?</p>
          <p>And then just flowing that through to your  outlook comments, I mean when we are looking at Westpac as a Group, you probably are going to have &#x2013; you are already back to pre-credit crisis margins, your margins might go up even further from here, you're going to growth potentially some writebacks on your bad debts, you are going to have a better cost-to-income outlook. So what's &#x2013; the recovery profile for the Group looks very strong like &#x2013; and when you get past this period of high impairment charges as we go past '10, just wanted to get your thoughts on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I wouldn't want to overstate that. I think frankly it's going to be quite a difficult next six months I mean, balance of this year, as I have indicated, we've seen quite a rapid rise in deterioration and quite a rapid rise, in stressed assets. So the next six to nine months of balance of this calendar year is going to be hard and hard into 2010.</p>
          <p>And clearly the approach that we have with customers is to seek deep relationships with them, support them across all of their business, so it's going to be an appropriate management of our customer relationships into the future. So I really wouldn't want to overstate that.</p>
          <p>The first part of your question, I am not sure if I fully understood it, the capacity of our business bankers, so in other words, handling the pressure, or managing the pressure of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Yes. Just as the &#x2013; because the &#x2013; as the economy slows their top line revenues are going to be under pressure as well. Will they be able to withstand high funding costs as you pass on margin increases on top of the &#x2013; given your funding costs are rising?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look I think the key is that we have business bankers increasingly speaking very regularly and very close to their customers and making sure that they understand the cash flow pressures that customers have and work with their customers to anticipate the exact issues and circumstances that each business might need to deal with. And then it's a negotiation and a conversation and working with your customer. We are clearly not wanting to put ourselves in a position where we put a customer into a delinquency situation. But clearly do need to make sure there is appropriate risk-based pricing in place. So I think it's just person-by-person or business-by-business management of the situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you want to make a comment, Phil?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  I am going to just add to the answer. I think the &#x2013; you've got to bear in minds that we've seen the base rate that is the official cash rate fall around 425 basis points. So what we're talking about here is the ability of a customer to be able to service a debt where the fallen pricing will still have fallen materially and where that customer has been de-gearing in line with the overall market trends.</p>
          <p>So while there will be some cases where the higher credit spreads that have been required by the banking industry will cause some stress, in aggregate, it is not an adverse situation from where these customers have been over recent times. So we don't see the repricing itself as being the cause of stress because in most cases it is merely the financial services industry clawing back some of the reduction in the overall base rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Richard Wiles, Morgan Stanley. Well, I can see you don't want to make a specific forecast for loan loss charges. Does your gut feeling tell you that 2009 or 2010 will be the peak of the loan loss cycle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I think what I flagged in my comments already is that we expect that the second half of this year, we're going to continue to have a high bad debt situation or high impairments. I mean we are still on a rising trend and you've seen it's &#x2013; the stressed assets have risen quite sharply over the course of the past half. So we're still on a rising trend and that's going to continue into 2010. But as I've indicated, I think that into 2010 we will start to see an improvement coming through, and that coming out of that recession is going to be housing led. I think that is a strong sector within the Australian economy. It's very differently placed from the housing sector that the United States or the United Kingdom might have and I think that will lead us out of the recession for the reasons that are outlined. So continued high impairment charges in the second half of this year; I think continued high impairment charges for the first half of next year, hopefully moderating from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian Johnson, CLSA. Gail, having &#x2013; had a bit of a break, coming back, there hasn't been too much to congratulate any bank executive on. And I don't think anyone can congratulate anyone on the quantum of results, but I think you guys have spent the market's revenue a little bit more sensibly perhaps than your peers. But that being said if you have a look at the restructure you basically transferred over the exposures greater than 10 to $15 million into WIB.</p>
          <p>But in St. George, you've actually retained the exposures there, all the way up to $150 million. And I know that you're going to probably answer that that's because the brand is so much better, but I can't believe that anyone who's borrowing a decent slab of money doesn't realize that Westpac actually owns St. George. Can you give us some feeling as to why we should be so confident that we won't see this kind of worst credit history that we've seen historically at St. George coming through in the future, given that those loans are still sitting in that business? And if that is the case, why did you feel the need to transfer them into WIB in the Westpac business? Just seems to me that two brands seem to be very different.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, they are different and &#x2013; they are different in lots of ways. Both brands are very strong. So just to comment on your first statement there, both brands are very strong. But St. George is a very distinctive brand and in that middle market and corporate banking segment, it retains highest customer satisfaction and very deep relationships. Its key account relationship managed model, as you'd be aware, has products for customer or depths of relationship of close to nine, and across its business segment, as a whole, over five. Those are industry-leading metrics.</p>
          <p>So deep relationships with customers and if you go out and visit customers as I do and I've done that in the last several months, been to South Australia and been to Victoria, been to Western Australia, been to Brisbane, been to Canberra, visiting St. George customers, they absolutely love St. George. They love the people at St. George and they love St. George.</p>
          <p>Now, clearly, we are applying Westpac credit standards and Westpac credit disciplines to all of that so we run risks centrally. Rob Whitfield is our Chief Risk Officer and has oversight for risk overall. He has got risk officers in each line of business who report through to him but in the line business as we're applying consistent policies, consistent standards but we're doing that in line with the brand attributes and values that exist.</p>
          <p>So St. George has been a strong player in the business banking world for a long period of time, starting with the acquisition of the Barclays Bank franchise many years ago. So have a strong and deep franchise there and customers who love them and that's what brand management's about. So very comfortable with that there.</p>
          <p>With regard to Westpac it made sense for us to make this particular model. I actually wanted Peter Hanlon to be really able to focus very explicitly on retail and SME and Agri business side of things so that we could actually once and for all make the investment and get the cut through with this very power Westpac retail franchise that we haven't done for a while. So that made sense and there was an alignment in the PBG corporate side within WIB under the Westpac brand. So it's horses for courses and what makes sense for us overall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So Gail, sorry, does that mean that we should expect to see the St. George business banking perhaps give up a little bit of share as you apply the Westpac credit sense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Even now in these last six months Greg Bartlett could tell you &#x2013; and Greg's here somewhere. Are you here Greg? Yeah Greg Bartlett would tell you that 86% of the new business that's come in into St. George has come from its existing customers. So this is not a go out and find new customers approach and I expect that we will see some moderate growth. Look, frankly, business credit overall as I've indicated is going to be down to zero by September and in our view negative the whole of next year. So clearly it's going to be more moderate growth.</p>
          <p>And the other thing is we do across the Group have a property concentration exposure meter that we deal into. And so over time we are absolutely reducing property exposure and what Greg Bartlett is doing with Greg Kinney and his team is actually continuing to diversify the St. George business into the other segments in which they have core expertise and focus. And Greg you might want to mention you have reduced that already quite somewhat from property into your broader industry segments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks, Gail. I think probably the best evidence of that is through the pipeline of new business. And you know the pipeline has reduced from something  like &#x2013; from 55% property-related business six months ago down to around 36% today, Brian. So very much focused on that and really driving that diversification strategy we've had in play for sometime at St. George. Probably good evidence of that would be that 91% of the business that we've actually written in the last six months actually comes from our chosen industry segments that we've previously called out, so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Want to take a call from the phone. I've got Stewart Oldfield.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, everyone, Stewart Oldfield from Baillieu here. Perhaps wanted to &#x2013; Phil's -- just Mike Smith's comments last week about some of the top end exposures going from investment grade to basket case overnight. It's great to hear you say you don't have any new troubled exposures in the pipeline at top end at the moment, how much confidence have you got in that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Stewart we called out that we don't have anything on the horizon that we would describe as being in terms of larger exposures that are concerning and that really our issue is much more in that middle market area, which, by and large, are not investment grade counterparts in anyway. You don't sort of think of them as investment grade. So it's not a situation of investment grade to basket case for that group. But there has &#x2013; it is fair to say though that there has been some rapid movement in terms of deterioration in that group. And that's as Phil pointed, it's actually not so much to do with interest rates, but to do with the drop off in demand that's taken place in the economy in the last three, four, five months and that's certainly the pressures that we're seeing in the portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry,  Scott?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott Manning from JPMorgan. I was going to ask the rationale of offering zero balance transfer credit cards straight after Christmas but seeing as I've only got one question I'd like to focus on capital. The 30 basis points that you've called out on slide 24, with the price cyclicality movement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A lot of your peers have called out some optimization client benefits that have been compensating for that. If you've got a number on that and if there is any potential offsets going forward?</p>
          <p>And also if we've seen deterioration in this period from large single name exposures leading to this 30 basis points pro-cyclicality impact, as you move into the next phase where it's a large number of smaller exposure, do you expect that 30 basis points under the new mix to be higher or lower going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not sure that the size of the exposure will actually affect the picture going forward, Scott. I mean, pro-cyclicality at least in some parts of the industry tends to only be called out as if it's to do with the change in risk rates and therefore people say gee! You've got quite low pro-cyclicality and if we only focus on that, then yes, we've only had the six basis point impact. But we think of it as actually the overall impact on capital, and that therefore has to take into account what's happened to your impairment charges and that's why we've called out that 24. So regardless of the size, I think what you'll will find is as impairment charges start to diminish as a total of the overall impact then your pro-cyclicality will start to reduce as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of optimization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I think everybody looks at whether or not you've got your portfolios scored and graded correctly. It's not been a major feature of our capital metrics and you can see that in our Pillar 3 disclosure and &#x2013; that's being released next week and that you'd seen in the past. So it's not been a big feature of our capital management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is an opportunity for us of course as St. George gets advanced accreditation in sort of 12 months or so time. So that's something we're working on quite heavily at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brett, way at the back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Brett Le Mesurier, Wilson HTM. Back on to credit quality the impaireds increased by 150% in the last six months when you adjust for the St. George acquisition. In other six months if you had a rate of increase half that big would you be happy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just have a look at the &#x2013; what's gone into the increase in impaireds; it's worth just sort of understanding what's there. Because some of that I don't think, well &#x2013; I certainly hope, won't be repeated. Within the last period, we've seen those large single name exposures and those were quite material for the first quarter that occurred in the December quarter. And as you've heard Phil indicate and Phil Chronican indicate too, we're not seeing any more of those large single name type exposures likely at this point. We're just not seeing any of those at the moment. The issues is much more broad based across your commercial, and corporate portfolios. So that's one that was in this last period that we don't think will be there to the same extent to the next.</p>
          <p>The other of course is the margin lending exposure that we've called out. It was quite a material impact in this set of numbers. But again, we think we've allowed for appropriately and we've got across.</p>
          <p>And the third, of course, is &#x2013; in this impairment was the economic overlay. We put an additional 112 million of economic overlay. So those are just additional factors that have gone into that increase. So we think impairments would remain high, as I've indicated, because of the broad based deterioration that's occurring in this commercial sector.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll just &#x2013; hold on one second. Just James there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>James Freeman from Deutsche Bank. I just want to follow-up Gail on the comment you made regarding your top 10 for St. George on impairments. You said nine out of those top 10 were residential property development. Just wondering how big that book is and what is the impairment rate within that book. And how much comfort can we get that you've pretty much got that covered at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The one thing I can absolutely tell you James, as you would do in any merger, is you absolutely scrutinize these larger transactions or larger relationships, absolutely each one individually. So there's no portfolio approach, it's looking at each one individually. And you make absolutely sure that they're appropriately understood and conservatively positioned, and valuations are appropriate because in this residential property development side of things it's ultimately the valuations that are absolutely key. So all of that's occurred, and if anything, we're probably erring on the side of caution with regard to the way in which we've tackled that.</p>
          <p>Will there be more? Well, I think there are likely to be more in this kind of environment where the economy is still deteriorating. But what we've had in that top nine are some fairly sizable ones and that comes off a very low base within St. George because there have been very low level of impairments before. So it's quite marked increase off that very low base.</p>
          <p>So what I am trying to do is give you comfort that we've absolutely scrutinized the portfolio and been so very thoughtful about how we've aligned it to Westpac, the grading system that we've aligned it to, the provisioning methodology we've provided it to, and all the credit risk management disciplines that we've aligned it to. We've taken the treatment that we believe appropriate. Will there be more? Yes there is likely to be some.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have a quantum in terms of the size of portfolio and impairments, or is that something you can get back to me later on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we can get back to it later but I think the size of the property development portfolio what &#x2013; Greg, it's on 10% is it of your...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Less than 10%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Less than 10% of the commercial portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will take one question from Alex.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Andrew . It's Alex from Credit Suisse. I just have a &#x2013; sorry to hop on the stressed asset disclosure, but my question relates to slide 56 of the investor discussion pack, which breaks it down by commercial property and I guess if you look at it there and the trends that are going from Westpac from second half '08 to first half '09 in isolation is quite marked in terms of stressed assets jump. But then when you incorporate St. George the jump up is about the same in terms of impaireds and the stressed, which is different I guess to the Westpac experience and what the lenders are calling out in commercial property.</p>
          <p>So I am just wondering there whether &#x2013; and particularly given the fundamentals have deteriorated in that segment quite significantly in the last six months, so I just wonder if you could add some more color around those trends. And if that is the case then whether you are saying that potentially 90-day past dues and watchlist loans have reached its peak in that portfolio of St. George?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Alex I think what the chart hopefully shows is that the increase in impaired assets, when you included the St. George property portfolio did actually lift the overall percentage of property that was stressed. But the stressed assets from sales actually had a very small impact, and that is consistent with what I have talked about in terms of the St. George portfolio having a high growth in impaireds but actually having a less high growth in the watchlist.</p>
          <p>We've provided kind of the information we think actually helps in sort of determining where is that impairment, where are those stresses coming from and we've called out the residential development area as being a sensitivity. You can see across the various states as well, those states where there is more pressure versus those where there is less pressure.</p>
          <p>I think in terms of have we topped out, in terms of where we've got impairments and stressed assets, I think it very much depends on what your view is in terms of economy. We think the economy is still going to be slow for at least the next two halves, and therefore, I think it'd be unwise for us to say that we've absolutely peaked at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thanks very much for attending today. We will, of course, be available for further questions during the day, if you'd like. Thanks very much. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>