<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1508528" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-11-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3150</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Andrew Bowden</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer, Executive Director &amp; MD">Gail Patricia Kelly</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Philip Matthew Coffey</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Australia)">James Freeman</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Jonathan Mott</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Australia Ltd.">Victor German</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Executive, Westpac Institutional Bank">Rob Whitfield</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Australia Pty Ltd.">Craig Williams</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley (Australia) Ltd.">Richard E. Wiles</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Australia) Ltd.">Jarrod Martin</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="CLSA Australia Pty Ltd.">Brian Johnson</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="BBY Ltd.">Brett Le Mesurier</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Michael Wiblin</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Scott Manning</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good morning, everyone, and welcome to Westpac's 2012 Full Year Result Announcement. Presenting this morning, of course, will be Gail Kelly, our CEO; and Phil Coffey, our CFO. And as per usual, we'll get Phil and Gail to give their perspectives on the results and then we'll open up for questions.</p>
          <p>So, Gail, I might get you to come up, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us this Monday morning for the presentation for the 2012 Westpac Group's full year results. It's unusual for us to be doing or results on a Monday morning, but we decided this year that we'd try and get in front of the Melbourne Cup Day, so here it goes.</p>
          <p>Let me start by saying that our full year 2012 Westpac group results is a strong result. It builds on the solid performance of the first half, but it's important to note that this result isn't a product of one year's work. It certainly is a reflection of the very hard work that's gone into the business over the course of the past five years.</p>
          <p>The four key highlights or messages will take us that I'd like to spend some time on in my presentation, and they're listed on this slide. Starting with the very material strengthening of the balance sheet across all dimensions of our business, capital, funding, liquidity and asset quality. As you know, there's been considerable work in this area over the course of the past several years, and it's very pleasing to see the heavy lifting paying off this year.</p>
          <p>Second key point is the excellent portfolio of businesses that we've got. All of which have good momentum. And it's great to see they're playing through to stronger financial and non-financial metrics.</p>
          <p>The third point is productivity. And as you know, that's been a strong agenda for us growth going back to 2009 when we recognize how changed the world is going to be in a much slower growth environment, and we identified the need for strong productivity agenda. This year you can see that agenda contributing to improved efficiency while also supporting investment into our target areas. So we have a revenue growth of 6% this year, cost growth of 4%, and expense to income ratio of 40.8%.</p>
          <p>And the last point to make, take &#x2013; key part of the results this year is that the strategy is delivering, it's being well-executed. And also that we have a clear forward agenda, and I'll say a little bit more about that together with the outlook before I hand over to Phil for his presentation.</p>
          <p>So moving on to the first point, the point about strength and the strong company that we have here in Westpac. On the far side there, cash earnings, as you would have seen already, up 5% year-on-year, and if you look at the second half, 7% second half on first half.</p>
          <p>The second point, net interest margin, that's a key &#x2013; been an area that we've called out that we want to make sure we manage in a very disciplined way. And I think you can see we've done that this year. We've recognized how important margin is, more important than volume in a slower growth environment. So margin is down 5 basis points for the year. But I think that chart shows the consistency and discipline that we brought to bear.</p>
          <p>And third one, customer deposit to loan ratio, has been a real highlight for us this year. And you'll recall over several reporting periods that we've spoken of the importance to the Westpac Group of driving deposits and customer retail deposits. And you can see here, over this year, a very big step up in our customer deposit to loan ratio from 62.5% in September last year to 67.6% this year, with a particularly marked uplift in the second half. And we've done that without hurting the margin. So we've done that while managing the margin. Another element on the funding quality is that we've also improved our stable funding quality is that we've also improved our stable funding ratio from what was 77% a year ago to now 83%. And that's on the back of not just the increase in retail deposits but also significantly reducing our short-term wholesale funding. So $31 million &#x2013; billion down over the course of the past period.</p>
          <p>Stressed assets to total committed exposures, you can see the continuing pattern there of decline in our stressed assets, but it is coming at a slower rate. And as you know, the environment does remain challenging out there. So we took the opportunity in the second half to add a modest overlay and to make sure that we remain well-provisioned.</p>
          <p>With regard to capital, these ratios here are stated in terms of the APRA Basel III common equity ratios, and a big step up over the year, 7.4% last year to 8.2% this year, 42 basis points up in the half. Phil will outline a little more further on about the range that we've established for our capital Basel II, Basel III common equity ratio, which is a range of 8% to 8.5%. And as you can see, we sit comfortably within that range. And if you compare that range to a fully harmonized scenario, our 8.2% is equivalent to 10.6% on a Basel III fully harmonized basis.</p>
          <p>And the last point on this slide goes to employee engagement, which is a proxy really for organizational heath. So that 84% that you see on that slide is the highest that's been for at least the past five years. And I could afford any one of several metrics down to evidence the strong organizational health that we have, whether it was retention of our high-performing employees, the strength of our leadership index, measuring leadership competence and capability, the reduction in lost time injury frequency rate and then indeed our women and management where two years ago we set a target of achieving 40% women in management by 2014. And actually, we've achieve that target two years ahead of time in 2012.</p>
          <p>I should mention the last one actually, it's particularly pleasing to see this in the background of a very challenging and changing year for the Westpac Group and where we, in fact 2000 less staff overall. So really pleased to actually have strong levels of employee engagement, such strong levels of employee alignment.</p>
          <p>You may recall that at the half year I put this slide up really pointing to those four key priority areas of growth, return, productivity and strength. And the point of them is to talk about how we balance and manage our performance across those areas where naturally there can be some trade-offs between the areas. And so for example, as we focus on strength in improving our funding ratios and improving our capital, we've had a very good watching brief on ROE and made sure that we've maintained our ROE above 15%. We've also paid a lot of attention, as I've mentioned, to margins, making sure that we're disciplined with margins and we don't chase unprofitable growth.</p>
          <p>When it relates to growth, we've made sure that the growth goes to support the strength and the returns. So our growth in customer deposits clearly enhancing strength. And then growth in areas where there's higher growth to be obtained, better ROEs are to be obtained. And obviously in our wealth strategy, very significant focus in platforms, significant focus in superannuation and in insurance. All of which actually enhances our ROE, strong non-interest income as a consequence of that focus and has limited capital cost associated with it.</p>
          <p>On productivity, we've made sure that that supports each one of the other quadrants. So as we've driven the efficiency in the organization that improves return but also as we strengthened our technology infrastructure, as we've strengthened our compliance regime and stabilized our system, that enhances strength. And also as we invest into our distribution, invest into planners, invest into Asia, invest into Bank of Melbourne that enhances our growth.</p>
          <p>Returning to have a brief word about each one of our major divisions and as you heard me say upfront, really pleased with the strength of the portfolio that we have and that there's strong business momentum across all of our business units. Starting with the performance in financial terms, and as you can see there, core earnings, which is the first slide, core earnings up 4% for the second half, with each one of our business units contributing.</p>
          <p>I'll start with our comments on Westpac Institutional Bank because of their particularly strong core earnings over the course of this year, core earning strength of 13%, and that's really come on the back of excellent activity with our customers. As you know, our institutional bank is the lead institutional bank in Australia.</p>
          <p>I'm particularly pleased with each element of the business units within Rob Whitfield's overall portfolio. Each element has had very strong revenue growth. Transactional banking, particularly strong 13% revenue growth and as you know in the Peter Lee survey, for the ninth year in a row, that we've been awarded Lead Transactional Banker within Australia.</p>
          <p>Looking at the cash earnings element, sticking with Westpac institutional bankers, you can see it's much more modest pickup and that's directly of course attributed to last year, we had a positive benefit out of impairments through write-backs, which hasn't occurred this year.</p>
          <p>Then having a look at Westpac New Zealand, and on both the cash earnings and core earnings dimensions there's been a very solid and consistent performance. Core earnings is up 10%, cash earnings is up 22% and that's in a very low growth environment. So the business is growing well. It's managed its margin well. It's managed expenses well and it's an improving credit quality story there. That's on the back of investments in its front line and investments in its credit skills.</p>
          <p>Turning to the three business units that make up our AFS division, Westpac RBB, St. George and BT, and starting with Westpac RBB. You'll recall going back to end of 2008 and the whole of 2009, early 2010, we put significant investments into our Westpac retail and business banks through the Westpac local initiative and it's great to see the outcome of that playing through the financials. And so this year, core earnings growth of 8%, cash earnings growth of 14%.</p>
          <p>Good growth in the areas adjacent as targeted for our retail deposits. Very strong margin management and costs that are effectively flat over the division, very good cross-sell activities and retention of our customers in that area.</p>
          <p>In St. George, a strong story for the second half. We really have turned a corner. We have an energized management team in St. George and really good growth in mortgages, in retail deposits, strong margin management, excellent cost management, pretty well zero even allowing for Bank of Melbourne and improving credit quality.</p>
          <p>With regards to Bank of Melbourne, it's been an excellent first year for Bank of Melbourne and achieving its milestones. We've grown customer numbers by 13%, which equates to about 50,000 new customers and we've had mortgage growth of 12.5%, taking our mortgage balance of up to $13 billion, and we've had retail deposits growth of about 35%. So, a good first year for Bank of Melbourne.</p>
          <p>BT, and if you look at BT, very strong second half but overall, BT's cash earnings were down 10% for the full year and that's really stock to equity markets. And also in the first half of the year, we suffered from non-repeats, as it were, benefits that we had in the second half of last year. But if you look at the second half of this year, cash earnings is up 17% for BT and I'm really very proud of the underlying quality of our BT franchise. We are number one in the platform space with very healthy net inflow onto our platforms, very strong growth in insurance, sales, particularly in life insurance, strong performance in our private bank, but also excellent cross-sell activities through into our distribution businesses.</p>
          <p>And it's probably a good &#x2013; I'll move on then to the next slide which speaks to our strategy of deeper customer relationships because while it's good to see each business unit performing well independently, it's good to see the linkage and the leverage that we can achieve between them. And so for example, Westpac RBB, the number one of the major banks in terms of wealth penetration, that's in terms of the Royal Morgan Survey. So 20.8% of our customers have our wealth products with them in our Westpac brand. Very pleasing too to see that uplift from a low base for St. George starting September 2009, and now actually into third spot but on a rising trajectory. The third spot amongst the top five in terms of wealth penetration.</p>
          <p>We also measure customers with four or more products as a metric to track our strengthening of customer relationships and you can see the progress that we've made there in Westpac and in St. George, also actually in Bank of Melbourne.</p>
          <p>Customer deposits, up 24% over the two-year period, and up 12% this year. Big focus there on quality too, as we drive this customer culture, making sure that we're winning the transaction account business, the savings accounts business of our customers, be it in the retail businesses or in our institutional business. And all of that translates into the shareholder metric of customer return on credit risk-weighted assets. And you can see the upward momentum there.</p>
          <p>On productivity, it's been a good year for us. Productivity, a range of initiatives that have supported the $238 million expense savings we've achieved this year, really in three buckets, the restructures that we've done through AFS and group services, the ongoing nature of the productivity program and then the early benefits out of our supply program with more benefits to come on that program over the following year. If you look at the two-year, just over $500 million in savings and indeed quite a significant reduction in our overall staff, something like 4,000 or more reduction in overall staff over that period.</p>
          <p>It's great to see these efficiencies, these savings being invested in key areas and those investments actually delivering returns. And so we've spoken about Westpac local and its contribution to the performance in Westpac RBB, it's also contributing to the performance in Westpac New Zealand.</p>
          <p>Our SIPs materially improving the operating environment, materially improving the stability and reliability of our environment, and as well as revitalizing our front end through the investment we made in front end systems, tele-systems, contact center systems assistance and mobile. We're now 70% through with our SIPs.</p>
          <p>Asia, our revenue from Asia is up at 46%. It is an area of focus for us, I know you'd expect to see more of that in years to come, but obviously of a small base. Wealth I've spoken of and Bank of Melbourne I've spoken of.</p>
          <p>So overall, you can see the expense to income ratio that was 45% in 2007, now actually down to 40.8% and a lot low, well lower than our peer banks, which means of course that for every dollar of revenue we earned, a lot more of that floats through to the bottom line.</p>
          <p>So in summary for the results, it is a strong result with good momentum. I haven't spoken to cash EPS, so that's up 3% for the year and 6% in the second half, and the reported NPAT, which as you see, is 15% down, and that's &#x2013; the change in reported NPAT from last year to this year is largely on the back of the St. George consolidation benefit, which was a very big positive last year and there was a small wind back of that in this year. If you were to eliminate the St. George element from both years, the 11-year and the 12-year, the growth in reported NPAT would be 4%.</p>
          <p>In terms of dividend, up $0.02 for the half, so $0.84 taking it to $1.66 for the full year. If we were to look at TSR and we were to start with January 1 this year and up to today's date, our TSR improvements is around 30% and for that time period, the leading of the major banks.</p>
          <p>Before I hand over to Phil, let me just say a few words about the outlook and then a few words about our strategic priorities relative to this outlook. Certainly, we expect 2013 to remain a challenging year. But actually when you think about it, 2008, 2009, 2010, 2011, 2012, we used that same word, challenging year, lots of challenge, lots of volatility. So we wouldn't expect this one to throw up any more than we've actually had to deal with along the way. And what is certain, is how well placed we are to deal with whatever comes our way.</p>
          <p>From an Australia point of view, we're clearly going to the structural change that's' occurring in this economy. And so what we are seeing, and you can see is it in our book too, you're seeing actually, from our point of view, commercials property has decreased in stress but there's an increasing level of stress in areas such as manufacturing and in areas such as retail trade. And this reflects the structural adjustments that are going on here and it's directly a consequence of the high Australian dollar, the persistently high Australian and the persistently cautious consumers. So manufacturing, retail, tourism, education, those are the sort of sectors that suffer from that.</p>
          <p>Overall, however, the Australian economy does remain fundamentally in good shape. If you think about the level of unemployment, which remains low, if you think about the low government debt that we have. If you think about the interest rate scenario that we have with more room to move in order to simulate growth and build more confidence. And if you think about our proximity and linkages to Asia and the trade flows in Asia, our perspective on Asia, yes, it's been a softer year but our perspective on Asia is that the medium term actually looks strong there.</p>
          <p>So against that backdrop, our strategic priority is, well, they're very consistent with the journey that we've been on, and they're certainly taking into account the changed and challenging environment in which we operate, and some of the big shifts that have been and will occur in the world. But priority number one starts with priority number one, and that's to be and remain a strong company. And that's absolutely imperative if we're going to play our role of supporting our customers with their investment and borrowing needs into future and supporting the communities in which we operate and making sure that we can consistently increase our dividends to shareholders. We obviously will also measure capital and measure funding and measure liquidity.</p>
          <p>Point number two, and you can see how we've &#x2013; orientating our business this year. You can see the outcomes this year on the implementation of point number two. But a point about re-orientating our business to the higher segments, the higher growth and return sectors and segments, so from a product point of view, that includes retail deposits, includes the wealth products and superannuation and insurance, includes trade finance, includes transactional banking.</p>
          <p>From an industry segment point of view or sector point of view, it clearly includes natural resources. It includes health. It includes professional services. From a retail point of view, it includes our pre-retiree and post-retiree segments. And then also, SME where we're putting significant focus on both Westpac RBB and in St. George. And it also includes our stepped up focus in Asia.</p>
          <p>And so a benchmark for us since we're drawing a line in the sand for us is to make sure that in focusing on where the growth is, where the base return is. We want to make sure that we maintain our ROE above 15%.</p>
          <p>Strategy point number 3, and that's very consistent with where we've come from, it's very much about building deeper customer relationships. Again, pleasing to see that translating into financial results in this particular reporting period. But we're driving deeper relationships with customers. We're driving the wealth penetration into our customers. We're driving the cross-sale between our institutional bank, products and services into our business banking customer set in Westpac and RBB.</p>
          <p>One key measure from a shareholder point of view is to continue to grow our customer return on credit risk-weighted assets.</p>
          <p>Point number 4, our productivity agenda, and while we've come a long way we've got a lot more here to do. So materially or radically, focusing on simplifying our products and our process we remain a very complex organization.</p>
          <p>So we've got a very clearly mapped out program of work here. It's co-led by John Arthur, our Chief Operating Officer; and Brian Hartzer, our CEO of AFS, there are about 100 people dedicated to this, that look at things like taking transactions on the branches and other contact centers, improving sales processes, freeing up capabilities for sales, simplifying the range of products we've got on offer for sale and reducing those, and simplifying of course process across our brands and standardizing this. So our five-year agenda of work that we've got ahead of us that will continue to drive efficiency and customer service benefits.</p>
          <p>The last point is of course our one team approach where we continue to be focused on the customer-employee engagement that I touched on earlier, our leadership capability, diversity, and flexibility. And my objective here is for us to be the best rate of management team.</p>
          <p>So with that, I should thank my group executive and indeed general managers and all of the staff across the Westpac Group for what has been a very strong result.</p>
          <p>So thank you very much in the new positive results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thanks, Gail. And good morning, everyone, and let me just say it's very nice to be standing here today and talking to you all. In today's presentation, I'd like to take a slightly different approach and I'd like to concentrate on four themes rather than running through the P&amp;L and the balance sheet statements.</p>
          <p>Let me address, I think, four areas where there's been quite a lot of interest from the market over the last year. And they are, firstly, the quality and sustainability of performance; secondly, drivers of returns as they occur across the business; the investment and productivity focus and outcomes; and then lastly, the risk profile and the franchise strength elements of the company.</p>
          <p>So starting with quality and sustainability, and I'm pleased with the quality of their results the past six and 12 months, and I think there are good reasons to be confident of its sustainability. An important feature of the result is its revenue foundation. Given the lower credit growth environment that we've been operating in, our consistent 6% annualized revenue growth in each of the last two halves is a very solid performance.</p>
          <p>The most recent periods have benefited from the inclusion of J O Hambro. And like any year, we had some &#x2013; we had a few infrequent items. But I'm happy to discuss this more fully as we get into Q&amp;A. But I don't think that the one-off items are any more distinctive this year than they have been in prior periods.</p>
          <p>When looking at earnings quality, it's important to appreciate the revenue headwinds that we've also been managing as we've strengthened our company. And this year, they have included the de-risking of the LMI insurance book and a very material shift in our funding base and the impact of the funding shift alone was over $200 million of revenue.</p>
          <p>Our statutory earnings are lower than cash earnings this year but mostly, as Gail mentioned, because of the swing in the tax line and if you look at the aggregated stat earnings over the last two or three years and compared it with cash earnings, you'd find that the reported numbers are in fact higher than the cash earnings. And if you look at growth in pre-tax earnings, whether it be year-on-year or half-on-half, they are very similar. Whether you use statutory or whether you use cash earnings.</p>
          <p>Another component that usually gets attention when looking at quality is the contribution to the result from the revenue in our markets business and that's because particularly the risk elements can be more volatile or less predictable and both that's the risk elements and the CBA income contribution that flows through the markets numbers.</p>
          <p>Our markets income was better this year and not withstanding in the full year drag from the CBA but in the second half, which is our high point over the last couple of years, total markets income was still only 4.3% of total revenue, that's up marginally from 3.8% in the first half and so that's a good outcome but it's not the driver of performance.</p>
          <p>When looking at momentum I think it's one of the other perspectives that we need to take when looking at sustainability and you can see in this slide the half-on-half components of both core and cash earnings and how growth has improved in both those measures through the second half and I've been talking for a while about our focus on core earnings rather than a simple jaws target and I think the second half result was what was particularly pleasing from that front with a 4.5% uplift in core earnings. And the result was clearly built on good revenue growth and a disciplined expense approach and it didn't rely on a lower impairments charge boosting the bottom line.</p>
          <p>The diversification benefits from our portfolio were also encouraging, and Gail has mentioned some of the underlying issues that underpinned each one of our divisions and this slide shows you how the different divisions contributed to both core and cash earnings throughout the year. The individual divisions in a growth in any one half can be quite distorted by what's happened in the prior period. And BT and WIB are good examples of that where their core earnings contribution was quite different half-on-half.</p>
          <p>BT for example recovered strongly in the second half with the underlying business supported by better markets and lower general insurance claims and that was the direct opposite of what occurred in the first half.</p>
          <p>WIB on the other hand had a very strong first half, which was sustained into the second half and there are individual drivers for each division, and I'm not going to elaborate on them now, they are in the ASX deck but it's really the combined impact of I think is most relevant here and you can see how the combined portfolio contributed to the strong growth throughout the year.</p>
          <p>Finally, on this theme, there's been quite a lot of attention lately around dividend returns and that's really I think because yield has become such a keen focus for many investors. And our dividend strategy has been quite consistent for some time now and we've lifted our dividend again by another $0.02 this half.</p>
          <p>As I've indicated previously, we are keen to grow our dividend in a cents per share basis and to do that in a predictable way. And we want to return our franking credits as rapidly as we can, frankly as rapidly as appropriate. We're a large tax payer in Australia and so we generate substantial franking credits each year and they have a real value to shareholders and therefore, it's our desire to return them.</p>
          <p>In setting this policy though, it is important to maintain a sustainable payout ratio. And you can see in the bottom left of this slide, that we've had a consistent dividend path but it's also been matched with a consistent capital accumulation. Now part of that capital accumulation has been due to share issuance for the DRP. Even though we haven't offered a discount on this issue for the last three years.</p>
          <p>The inclusion of the DRP means that our effective payout ratio has been lower than the cash payout. And we've averaged after the DRP in the low 60% range for the past three years. The DRP has added about 15 percentage points to capital each half and so you can see on the slide, even though it's been valuable, it's only part of the capital generation story. And we will have a look at the dilution impacts next year.</p>
          <p>Capital has also been assisted by the St. George tax impacts but even adjusting for this the picture doesn't change much. It's the combination of solid returns and healthy capital generation that has fully supported our payout ratio and dividend path.</p>
          <p>Turning to return and I've included a very simple DuPont style model here to outline the impact on returns from both performance and leverage.</p>
          <p>The table on the slide highlights the returns on average interest earning assets from the various aspects of our P&amp;L statement and it shows how that has accumulated to impact our overall cash earnings return on assets. We recorded a one-basis-point drop in our ROI over the year from 115 to 114 basis points.</p>
          <p>But we had a good pickup in the second half and that's mostly from higher non-interest income. And in the second half, expenses and impairments had little impact. At the same time, our leverage or our average assets to average equity ratio has declined mostly when you're looking at the year-on-year picture and this was the consequence of building our capital base.</p>
          <p>So when you combine that cash earnings return on assets and the leverage you can see that it's really the reduction in leverage that's been the primary driver of our ROE decline over the course of the year. When we look at it half-on-half, our ROE actually has picked up and that's because of the improved return on assets that we're able to generate in the half. And given that we had very little change in asset mix, you can see that in that second half we generated better returns with little change in risk.</p>
          <p>One of the principal drivers of our ROE is that our net interest margin and 2012 saw our underlying margin and that's what I want to focus on here, which excludes treasury and markets and it declined through the year. If you look at the year-on-year, our underlying margins were down six basis points.</p>
          <p>When we look at each half, you can see that the high spread or the high cost of deposits was the principal cause of the margin decline, and that had a negative 9 basis points impact in each half.</p>
          <p>This included the mixed impacts of more growth in higher cost term deposits and online deposits, and the impact of lower rates on our low interest transaction accounts. We held, on average, over $10 billion more of liquid assets over the course of the year. This didn't have much of an impact half-on-half, but it did have a 3-basis-point impact over the whole year. So year-on-year, our margins were down 3 basis points because of those higher average liquid assets.</p>
          <p>As Gail mentioned, if you're looking at a low credit growth environment, we believe margin disciplines are even more important and our 2012 relative result reflects that.</p>
          <p>Over the last few years, higher levels of capital have reduced our ROE, and we're very focused on boosting that ensuring we have an appropriate return on the capital that's employed in the company. To assist in that, we have refined some of our key internal performance metrics and that's to ensure we allocate our resources, including our capital and our funding in the most appropriate way, in a way that optimizes returns. And this meets the changing market and regulatory dynamics that we're operating in.</p>
          <p>So we've introduced over the course of the year two major changes. One to our economic capital allocation and one to have, we transfer price the cost of funds through the company. On economic capital, we've refined our risk allocation methodology and we've ensured that capital that we used to previously considered as a surplus to our economic capital needs and we used to hold at a group level, we now allocate that out to divisions. And you can see how that plays out in our economic profit tables in our ASX document.</p>
          <p>On transfer pricing, we've updated our models to be more dynamic to changing market pricing and to better reflect the growing liquidity costs of holding those higher average liquid assets. Both of these changes support our focus on achieving appropriate return on capital and funds employed.</p>
          <p>We've also wanted to ensure our regulatory capital ratios are also managed efficiently. And we've made some progress on this in the half. And as the new regulatory capital rules get finalized, we believe there remain opportunities for us to become more efficient.</p>
          <p>Turning to investment and expenses, and expense management clearly is an area of keen focus across the market with quite material investment programs being undertaken across the industry. Over recent years, we've focused on investing for sustainability, for productivity, compliance and growth. And we've looked to offset those impacts with efficiency initiatives.</p>
          <p>In the past six months, normal operating expenses from inflation, from the full period impact of annual wage rises, from higher project spend and higher advertising spend, have been offset by the productivity benefits that we've had, as Gail's mentioned, from our AFS and group services consolidation and nearly benefits from our supplier program.</p>
          <p>The expense growth in both our retail banking divisions actually was the real highlight. So if you look at the total Westpac RBB and St. George expenses, when you look at it year-on-year, when you look at a half-on-half, the expense picture is flat.</p>
          <p>The expense growth of 2% that we had in the half has resulted from, if you like, the impact of past investment and the impact of ongoing investment. From a past investment perspective, we've had higher amortization and depreciation expenses and from the SIPs program that's been going on. And we've continued investment spending especially around our Asia business and our wealth and Bank of Melbourne initiatives.</p>
          <p>In the half, the impact from higher amortization and depreciation was $48 million while over the year the total impact was $119 million. And so that $119 million added 1.7% to our expense growth rate over the year, and that's broadly what we expected and what we've been calling out.</p>
          <p>The composition of our investment spending has moved over the year with fixed spending starting to reduce a little as projects were delivered, and that's allowed us to accommodate increased spending on compliance requirements that have continued to grow and to boost our business investment as I've mentioned in wealth platforms and in Asia.</p>
          <p>The nature of some of our investments and their long term effective life has seen our average amortization period lengthen slightly. But as you can see on the slide, we remain the most conservative in the peers, and frankly, we're trying to avoid the risk of kicking the expense can down the road.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding the uplift of investment spending over recent years, our capitalized balance is a little different from our peers.</p>
          <p>The last thing I wouldn't mind touching is around the risk profile of the group and what changes are occurring. And starting with credit risk and our measures of credit health continued to improve through the years, as Gail mentioned, although the rate of improvement has slowed. When we look at the overall stressed asset ratios, whether it be the watchlist category, whether it be credit 90-days for well secured or impaired assets, the ratios have all actually declined in a reasonably consistent way.</p>
          <p>Looking across the business sectors as you can see on the right hand side of this slide, commercial property remains our most stressed sector but it has continued a reasonably healthy trend of improvement. In contrast, as we highlighted after our third quarter APRA presentation, wholesale and retail trade in manufacturing companies are reflecting the mixed economic picture in Australia and the impact of the high rate dollar, and you can see that we've had a small uptick in stressed in those sectors.</p>
          <p>Given that, we didn't think it appropriate to the release economic overlay and say you can see that overlays that we utilized during the course of the year or that were released because we could no longer justify them, for example, with regard to the earthquakes and flood provisions, we didn't think that it was appropriate to release those back through the P&amp;L. And so we've actually topped up additional provisioning for emerging industry pressures.</p>
          <p>Our provision coverage remained strong and at the upper end of peers. We have seen some easing in collective provision balances and they reflect the portfolio trends. And I would like to spend a little bit of time just elaborating on that now.</p>
          <p>So this is a slide that provides a simplified view of how our provisions are comprised and what they cover. And it's a useful picture as it explains why total provisions in their balances may change yet effective cover of the portfolio remains strong.</p>
          <p>So the slide shows how our portfolio can be thought of in four components and these are the four components that we've been talking about for quite some time. If you look at the fully-performing part of our portfolio and two categories of stressed, they tend to be covered by collective provisions whereas our impaired assets tend to be covered by our individually-assessed provisions.</p>
          <p>Now the level of our overall collective provisions will increase as the volume of our exposures increase, or the volume of our stressed asset growth. That is as the level of our financial stress increases. The higher the stress, the higher the probability of default, the higher the required provision.</p>
          <p>And you can see quite quickly comparing the performing portfolio, and the provisioning that we would have to TCE there, which is 0.25 of a basis point compared to exposures that are in watchlist and substandard, where we basically have between 6% and 8% of those exposures would be covered by a collective provision.</p>
          <p>So if something goes from fully-performing into stressed then clearly it leads to an increase in collective provisions required. But even within those buckets, you can have variability in the ratio, so you can have a different average credit-risk weighting if you like even within the stressed bucket. And so from time to time, you can have one stressed asset go from stressed back into fully-performing, given the size of that exposure it can change that ratio. And so you can see in watchlist &amp; substandard again if I use that as an example. Our ratio of provisioning the TCE is ranged from a low of 6.69% to a high of 7.86%. So you can get some variability, but it's reasonably within a reasonably tight band.</p>
          <p>So when you &#x2013; the last pace of this slide shows you, which is on the left-hand side, the size of our total exposures that are in these various categories. And what you can see when you multiply the size of exposure by their provisioning required, is that it's because we've got less exposures that are in stressed assets, that we've got less collective provision balances. So it's actually the reduction in those overall provision requirements that have led to the lower provision balances. I'm sure I'll get a question on that, and I'll look forward to having another go at it.</p>
          <p>The final picture of credit risk covers our consumer books, which obviously are a big part of our loan portfolio. And you can see that delinquencies have gradually eased over the period in both the mortgage and unsecured books. The New Zealand exposures in particular have shown some really good improvement. Two areas where we are keeping an eye on are Queensland exposures and low doc, but neither are giving rise to unexpected losses today.</p>
          <p>Moving from credit risk to funding and liquidity. And as Gail has mentioned, 2012 was a really important year for our balance sheet strength with strong growth in deposits that more than fully-funded our lending, and with a very material reduction in our short-term wholesale funding. And the sources and uses of funds gives you some sense of those dramatic shifts. As a proportion of total funding, our short-term wholesale funding balances which declined by $31 billion over the year, they're now at the lower end of the peer group.</p>
          <p>It is part of our cheapest funding, as Gail said, so it's come at a cost and some of that cost will flow in the 2013 but we've really made some very material shifts in there. I've often thought that concerns regarding our relative funding balance were overblown either way, we're now obviously in a relatively strong position.</p>
          <p>Termed funding markets also improved through the course of the year and particularly, late in the second half and we've taken advantage of that to be comfortably positioned for our 2013 maturities.</p>
          <p>The last aspect of risk and strength is our capital position. And our common equity ratio under the current Basel 2.5 requirements was up 42 basis points to just under 8.4%. And that translates into 8.16% on a Basel III APRA basis. Those numbers already incorporate the higher operational risk weighted assets that is being applied across the industry, so we've already got those in our numbers.</p>
          <p>When assessing our ongoing capital requirements, we aim to achieve an appropriate balance between being unequivalently strong but also achieving an attractive return for investors. And to that end, we've assessed how our capital ratios would be affected by a severe economic downturn. And we aim to ensure that our APRA ratios don't fall to a point where capital management and dividend management gets forced on us by the operation, the automatic operation of the conservation buffer.</p>
          <p>At the same time, when thinking about what is an appropriate capital metric here. We need to think about accommodating the greater variability in our published ratios, which under Basel III will be more variable especially because of the dividend inclusion.</p>
          <p>It means everything else equal, our common equity Tier 1 ratio will be higher in March and September as we built up earnings for our dividend and lower in June and December after dividends are paid. So our preferred common equity Tier 1 operating range will be 8% to 8.5% and that gives us the comfortable Basel that we need over regulatory thresholds to deal with severe downturns, but also allows us to operate as a strong and efficient bank. So we'd aim to be at the top of that range in March and September and towards the bottom of that range in June and December.</p>
          <p>I hope that that helps investors know how we intend to operate and where capital management plans will be in our thinking. If you think about today, with APRA Basel III common equity Tier 1 ratio at just under 8.2% at end of September, whilst we're comfortably within our range, we would aim to operate at the top of that range. And as a consequence, we are issuing shares for the DRP. Once again, they obviously won't have a discount.</p>
          <p>Whilst it's not relevant for this room. It's certainly relevant elsewhere to talk about our common equity Tier 1 ratio in a fully-harmonized sense. Sure that everybody in this room understands the conservatism that APRA applies. But unfortunately, many investors outside Australia are still unaware of that. And so let me emphasize that our 8.2% common equity Tier 1 converts to 10.6% on fully-harmonized basis and that's really one of the highest levels of banks globally.</p>
          <p>So let me finish with sort of considerations as we look into FY 2013 and we expect many of the trends evident in the past year to continue. Balance sheet growth is expected to reflect faster deposit growth than lending. And so our funding composition will likely continue to improve.</p>
          <p>In this low credit growth market, we will continue to focus on targeted growth, on margin management, and enhancing cross-sellers that are better drivers of return than chasing above system market share growth on a price basis.</p>
          <p>We've also got further investment to do and we've got clear priorities that we've set out in those areas. We've also got to deal with the impact of rising amortization and depreciation expenses. And those investment cost will need to be balanced against our revenue performance and our productivity programs. I think you'll find that the realization of expense benefits from our programs and our investments will continue to be a feature of our result.</p>
          <p>Like others, we see the stress caused by the strong currency and changed consumer behaviors and their impacts on some of our customers. The flip side is that lower interest rates help many borrowers. And so overall, we would expect the credit health of our book to be stable rather than improving. Having said that, we're very pleased to improve &#x2013; to have already improved the quality of the book over recent years and to be strongly provisioned.</p>
          <p>Lastly, the very material headwinds to our returns from improving funding quality and lifting capital that we've seen over recent years, are likely to be easing over 2013 as we approach our balance sheet goals. As Gail highlighted, we will continue to pursue balanced and sustainable improvement in the performance of the company.</p>
          <p>With that, let me hand back to Andrew, to organize the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob. Gail, can you come back up again? Thank you. I will just ask everyone to take one question, I think, for everyone to give it &#x2013; make sure we shared it around a bit. I've got James' hand up there first would be great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's James Freeman from Deutsche Bank. Gail, I was just interested in your cost-to-income chart that you put up. As that shown that you've been around the 40% to 41% now for around sort of four years. You seem to be unable to crack below 40%. If I listen to what you're saying today, it's more investment spend to be coming. Can I just get an idea as to when you expect to be able to actually improve that cost-to-income ratio? It's been relatively steady now for a few years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We came down a bit just this year, James, as you would have seen. But we haven't got a particular target on that. The target is to remain best placed amongst all of our peers with a decent margin. So that's the target because ultimately, what we've been looking to do is manage to core earnings and it has been a slower revenue growth environment. So manage to core earnings and make sure that we remain best placed relative to our peers.</p>
          <p>So I would expect that we're going to continue to find very significant cost efficiency benefits because we've got significant momentum in our cost agenda, in our productivity agenda. And I spoke briefly to the work that Brian Hartzer and John Arthur have got underway. So we'll continue to drive the efficiencies but we're going to want to continue to invest that because we want to build a growth agenda for the long run. So we're very concerned about top line growth, very pleased this year with a 6% top line growth. We want to make sure that we can continue to grow top line growth. So it's not just all about cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jonathan Mott from UBS. I just got a question and so you talked about it quite a lot, risk capital. And you talked about wanting to be at the top end of the range at the end of each half year. And also, you talked a lot about franking and also the need to stop the deleveraging, which is impacting the return on equity.</p>
          <p>So if I read between the lines, it looks like you're trying to flag that you're generating a lot of capital and sooner or later, you've got to start doing something about that more actively. So should we start to be thinking that from next year on DRP probably starts to look to buy back and offset the dilution from the DRP then going forward from that, you have to get a bit more active with the &#x2013; your capital management if we remain in a profitable environment with limited credit growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gee, I hope all that pays out. The logic of your argument is right, Jon. I mean, we would like to &#x2013; first of all, we wanted to say, what kind of capital level do we need to have and to achieve the priority one, that Gail called out being strong. And so we stress test that and then we said, well, we need to have a buffer that means that our common Tier 1 ratio is over 8%</p>
          <p>Then the second thing was, well, there's variability in it and so we need to make sure that we call out what kind of range you should expect. Once we consistently operate where our ratio is pointing higher than that range, then we've got options to look at. And we're not a believer that you just keep building capital forever because of the deleveraging impact that you mentioned.</p>
          <p>There's a number of different options that we can consider. I'm sure the directors will give thought to all of that when we're in a position to manage our capital. But it will be something that we would like to think we're looking at as we get through 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Victor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thanks. Victor German from Nomura. Very strong performance on deposits in the half and I think AFS has grown by that $14 billion, institutional growing by $12 billion. Are you able to just talk perhaps a little bit about where you and how you were able to derive that growth and also give us an idea whether any part of that growth has been driven by sort of larger end financial institution deposits say over $10 million, which are not necessarily going to be as attractive as we move into Basel III environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I mentioned, Victor, we've definitely put a big focus on the quality of the deposit rating that we do obviously bearing in mind we're moving to a new liquidity regime, of liquidity coverage ratios and so on. So the quality element really matters that's been part of the culture of raising deposits and making sure that we first and foremost win our own customers' transaction and savings accounts. So I think that about 11.5% increase in transaction account balances and that's pretty pleasing.</p>
          <p>Obviously, RAMS is a new launch for us so that's another vehicle for deposit raising and we've raised over $1 billion in the six months or so that RAMS has been up and running. In institutional bank, Rob, you may want to comment on the progress that you've made in institutional bank in the Pacific region that Victor asked the percentage of financial institution deposits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks, Gail, and thanks, Victor. Look, it's true to say we'd really been able to leverage off the deep relationships we've got and the leadership position in the transactional banking. And so we've competed very aggressively for balances right across the board from the working capital balances. But certainly all the way through to term deposits as well and that has seen really solid growth this year.</p>
          <p>In terms of deposits over $10 million, of course lots of them are over $10 million but we are very alert to all the Basel III requirements and so we have really focused on raising our deposits in a way that's going to be sustainable under the new rules and regulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Deposits and wealth, Victor, would be the only other elements I'd add to that. So quite a focus on self managed super funds element and the deposits in our platform. So that will be an increasing area focus for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Craig.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Craig Williams from Citi. Acknowledging Jon's earlier question and your response, Phil. Whilst the payout ratio is high and credit costs are low, you may not want to build in a more permanent sort of dividend uplift or trajectory or permanent payout uplift with $1 billion of franking credit plus, is perhaps a one-off special dividend consideration in the mix?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's great the way you guys are spending all my capital before we've got it. Yes, that's possible, Craig, but we'd have to get to a point where our capital is consistently above that range before we would consider any of those things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Richard Wiles from Morgan Stanley. Gail, you mentioned that there's good momentum across all the businesses that's clearing your retail and business banking franchises. I'm not sure exactly in institutional. There's a good markets income performance and while we don't want to criticize you for that, it may not be sustainable going forward.</p>
          <p>And in the second half, the institutional margin fell 20 basis points. I wonder if you could outline the reasons for that. And also, comment on what you expect to happen in 2013, particularly in relation to lending competition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, let me kick off, and again, I think Rob may want to provide a little bit more specific insights and detail on the margin piece. I am really pleased with how our institutional business has performed over the whole year. Yes, you're right the stronger performance was in the first half, but year-on-year, you look at all of Rob's businesses, be it debt market, debt capital markets or foreign exchange or global transactional banking, Hastings, all of them, have actually &#x2013; or Asia, had very good pickup in revenues, sort of almost double-digit revenue, I think, for across the board.</p>
          <p>So and that's largely on the back of excellent customer relationships. So that's the key for Rob and his business is driving that deep customer relationship with our &#x2013; with institutional customers. I mean, clearly on the margin side, I think we're consistent with peers that there clearly has been a squeeze on margin and it's mostly on the financing side and going forward, I'd be interested to hear what Rob says, but it certainly, it seems to me the financing margin pressure is likely to continue somewhat due to the intensity of competition but perhaps, ease a little on the liability side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely. Thanks, Gail. If I could just build on that a little, Richard. Just to give you some insight into the half-on-half margin story that you picked up on, it's true to say that our second half margin did decline by 20 basis points. But we've called out in the IDP pack that that was largely due to one-offs. And if you remember, that was really the bringing forward of the establishment fees that we've called out in the second half of 2011 and the first half of 2012.</p>
          <p>And so when you strip that out, I would actually refer you to the underlying annualized decline in margins, which is 11 basis points. And so if you wanted to think through how that's going to translate for 2013, that's probably as good a crystal ball as any. We've heard our competitors talk about the &#x2013; in a slow growth environment, there really is competitive intensity on the asset side of the balance sheet. And if the slow growth environment continues, as we expect it will, then the margin pressure, competitive pressure will continue on the asset side.</p>
          <p>Perhaps the opportunity for us is on the liability side and that may be if the reserve bank continues to reduce the absolute interest rate in Australia. That might ease a little the competitive pressure on the liability side. So you'll see active margin management from us, we do expect a decline and I would focus on that annualized number as a best guess indicator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jarrod?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jarrod Martin from Credit Suisse. Just in reference to the table on slide 11, and particularly the second half over the first half metrics, I think you talk about the good momentum in the business with cash earnings growth, revenue growth, et cetera. But the one aspect where it's actually missing is the dividend growth of only 2%. So while, I suppose, you're talking a story of good momentum, proof in the pudding is that it's not there in terms of what you see in terms of dividend. I'm wondering whether there is a bit of hesitation, a bit of conservatism or whether the payout ratio previously was unsustainable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Look, I'm surprised that that's an area of concern. I mean with $0.02 dividend increase is, we thought, imminently appropriate based on where we are. But there is no concern that underpins that. It's been pretty much our pattern of increasing dividends. And so another $0.02 is a continuation of that pattern of increasing dividends. I think as Phil has said, we've still got a way to go, a little bit of a way to go to be entirely where we want to be relative to that preferred range of 8% to 8.5%. At this time at end of September, you want to be at the top of that range.</p>
          <p>And so we're not there yet. So we just, that's a factor here, but this was actually an easy dividend decision to make, relatively speaking I have to say. There wasn't a whole lot of discussion about this one. It seemed like fairly straightforward one, best in the strong performance, 6% over the year, $0.02 &#x2013; 2% and $0.02 for this half. There wasn't a lot of discussion points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The cash earnings were substantially above consensus yet the dividend was only up $0.02. It's an easy choice to actually go up $0.02 yet overall earnings were well ahead of the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We didn't feel we needed to do more than $0.02. It's consistent with our pattern and we're still in a process here of building our capital to get to the level that we want it at and that range of 8% to 8.5% we feel very well placed and that we've done the heavy lifting. We want to be in a good spot next year. So all of those were the factors that made it an easy decision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian Johnson, CLSA. I know everyone here is encouraging you to ramp up the payout ratio. What I'd been interested, Phil, in the text you say financial conglomerates, you're not quite sure but you don't think it'll be significant. But the domestic SIFI rule hasn't yet come out. Would that 8.5% target potentially move or should we be thinking that perhaps there's a few unknown pieces there, that you could actually see that number adjusted up?</p>
          <p>The second one is that when you actually have a look at this result, it's quite significant that the previous difference between economic capital and the regulatory capital has now been allocated out to the operating units, which I would applaud. But the two questions on that is because you don't have to put regulatory capital away for deposits. You'd be sending a bit of a false signal to Mr. Hartzer's business. And the second one is does this mean that you're fundamental pricing of mortgages or pretty well most of your products goes up as of tomorrow, because clearly you're getting a lower return on equity in the operating units? So these SIFIs, product pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the logic we would use is that if the domestic SIFI implementation led to a higher regulatory threshold then we would have to think about that because we're looking to maintain a buffer over that threshold. We don't know where the domestic SIFI regime is going to land in Australia and to the best of our understanding, APRA has been pretty happy with the level of capital that Australian banks have got and hasn't been looking to push that higher. So I guess the question will be, as they look into domestic SIFI knowing that it's potentially 2016 type implementation, what do they actually do and does it actually lead to a higher regulatory threshold? That's the most I can say at the moment. We felt confident enough with where we stand today, with what we understand today to establish that operating range.</p>
          <p>In terms of the economic capital allocation, I don't think Mr. Hartzer believes that he's got a free kick here. And we clearly look to allocate capital, not just on the credit risk-weighted assets, but the operational risk in the company and deposits end up wearing a fair bit of that because of the amount of the company that's attributed to raising deposits across the company.</p>
          <p>Our pricing is clearly a function of not only the ROE that we generate, but the alternatives that we have, the growth opportunities we have, the competitive environment that we're in, the ability to cross sell out of one product into another. So there's a lot of things that go into our overall pricing strategy, and so you shouldn't expect any dramatic changes tomorrow, in fact, we've been operating with these change transfer pricing arrangements for a while now. So what you see is what you get.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brett?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Brett Le Mesurier from BBY. Gail, in your outlook statement, you commented on a number of the financial characteristics of the business, but you stopped short on giving a direction as to whether you thought the EPS would be higher or lower from 2012 to 2013. Can you comment on the concerns that you have that led to you stopping short of making a comment on EPS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, look, I think I was pretty specific on a range of things. So I'm really pleased to have put a floor under the ROE, and really pleased to talk about increasing our dividend, and really pleased to be specific about where we stand with regard to our expense to income and expect to remain lower. So I'm not going to put a marker on every single metric. But clearly, if we get &#x2013; if we deliver on the strategy as we have been this year, you're going to see an improved ROE and you're going to see an improved EPS. I mean that's clearly very much a key driver for us of our performance. So it's one we measure, it's one we track, it's one very high on our radar screen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we will endeavor mightily to not give earnings guidance, Brett.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wasn't thinking earnings guidance, I was just curious as to what was... I thought I might have shaken something out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike Wiblin from Macquarie. Look, just a question on mortgage re-pricing. Given out of cycle mortgage re-pricing recently, it would seem to indicate that there's been a bit of pressure on funding costs, right across the sector but <mark type="ph" /> voice back (1:05:30) back as well. And when I look at this result and I look at half-on-half margin improvement for RBB and St. George, I couldn't really have told that, obviously got a pretty big increase in margins. Could we get some color as to what's going on there? What's driving the margin improvement, I suppose whether more re-pricing is needed and where the spot margin you're seeing today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me kick off on that. I mean obviously look at the margin overall and the margin overall has come down with regard to the customer-related margins. So Phil's chart which separates out treasury and markets. You can see the margin has come down, in fact, in both halves. But I think we'll being quite disciplined in offsetting the additional cost of raising retail deposits because that's we're the biggest factor of competitive intensity has been, has been in raising retail deposits. So we've been able to offset that quite effectively in the re-pricing that we've done on the lending side.</p>
          <p>In the latter part of this year, we've also done more in the way of term funding. So we didn't do much in the early part of the year, as you know. But in the latter part of the year we've done more there. And we've also, in the latter part of the year, repaid some of the short-term debt, which, as we've discussed earlier is the cheapest form of funding that we have. So that will give us some margin headwind into this coming year. And from an exit margin point of view, if you look end of September, it's clearly lower than the printed margin here for the second half on our customer-related margin.</p>
          <p>But we've immunized that to some extent already, of course, with the October re-pricing on mortgages that's already done. So I think it's leads and lags, it's understanding these different factors and making sure that we're disciplined and that we are consistent. And I think you can see we've got that pattern so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott Manning from JPMorgan. We actually did a report a little while ago that suggested your ROE line in the sand is 15%, I had a whole bunch of questions lined up on that. So thanks for clarifying that in the slide pack today.</p>
          <p>As a consequence of that, one of the things we've noticed is quite substantial, out of cycle rate rises in the mortgage book here at 10 basis points above <mark type="ph" /> this there (1:07:32). How are you thinking about the profitability versus growth argument? And if you're allocating capital, and you're transfer pricing mechanism of funding is on one level but your peers is on another level, you might lead to different outcomes. How comfortable are you that you've got it right and how flexible are you to adjust to the peers' reactions to your pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again, let me kick off, Phil, and you or Brian may want to add something to this. But very much in the mortgage space in the low credit growth environment that we've been having over this past year. We've been happy to make sure that margin is the priority. Because we've actually grown our mortgages at around 0.7%, 0.8% of system. We said we'd grow a little under system, at or around or a little under system, but system is really low. The system has been 4.7%, we've grown at 4%r. We're really happy with that especially if you take a four-year view where we've grown mortgage market share two percentage points.</p>
          <p>So four-year view growing two percentage points this year, low credit growth environment, really have work to do on the retail deposit side, wanted to make that a priority in the organization, I'm happy to grow somewhat under. On the pricing differential, I mean it's been pretty much of that order for a long period of time. This isn't something new. And our retention of our customers remains outstanding. So you can have a look at the Westpac RBB in particular have a look at their &#x2013; the detail information in the IDP and you'll see the retention of customers remains outstanding.</p>
          <p>Phil, do you want to add to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I think, the volume margin tradeoff is something that's really important and we look at the whole time and Gail's sort of indicated to you where we though the greatest returns are going to come from. Your questions, Scott, around if the industry goes in a different path from where we're at, then we will obviously have to look hard and say, were right, or is the market right. Right now, I think we feel that the metrics that we're putting out really supports the strategy and helps to embed the strategy through the company. And so we will be looking to pursue that path in a pretty disciplined way for quite some time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just one more thing I could that actually, Scott, is that you've got the benefit of having several brands then that does allow us to price differently and manage it as a portfolio. So our Bank of Melbourne brand for example has exactly the same rate as NAB and CBA so we've got that benefit , brands is below that stuff that those customers are looking for the cheapest of all the mortgages brands is below Bank of Melbourne and then we've got St. George sitting in between, Westpac and Bank of Melbourne and Bank SA sitting also in between. So we've got as a benefit of a range of brands that allow us to run it as a portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One last question I think then, Victor again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's Victor German again. I just wanted to also ask a question about your liquidity. We've seen one of your competitors increased, well it appears as though they've increased the liquidity quite substantially in the last half. Are you able to talk about how you see your position relative to your peer group and do you think there is some catching up to do on that front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, no, I think we're looking to make sure that everybody is reporting liquidity in the same way. I guess from our perspective, you can think of liquidity in two ways. You can think of it as what's available on any particular day to meet outflows or you can think about it as what's the regulatory liquid assets that I have to meet my LCR ratio requirements.</p>
          <p>Our focus when we report liquid assets is the latter so we're going to take into consideration assets that might be held by Rob Whitfield's trading team that are repo eligible. You could say that they are eligible liquid assets, but if they're held in a trading book then you can't rely upon them to be there when you would need them for an outflow and certainly the regulator won't include them in your LCR calculation. So you can see them in our results but you won't see us add them into our liquid asset calculation.</p>
          <p>When talking to the regulator about LCR and we've all recently put in the first round as the three-year funding plans and how that plays through to the LCR, I think what we're seeing, quite rightly, is just as much focus on how you will manage the outflow side of that equation as the liquid asset side of that equation and we're definitely focused on both those elements. And just to simplify the answer with regard to your liquid asset question, we don't feel that we're, we've got a shortfall in liquid assets and why we are looking at those to comply with the LCR requirement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you very much, everyone. Thanks for coming and good afternoon. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>