<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1268644" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>FY 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-11-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3150</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Andrew Bowden, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Gail Kelly, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Phil Coffey, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Jonathan Mott</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">James Ellis</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Craig Williams</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Bob McKinnon</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Brian Johnson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">James Freeman</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Jarrod Martin</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Richard Wiles</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Ben Koo</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Matthew Davison</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Brett Le Mesurier</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Johan Vanderlugt</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Scott Manning</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">TS Lim</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Stewart Oldfield</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good morning, everyone, and thanks for joining us for the Westpac Group's Full Year 2009 Results Presentation. It's been a very busy year for us. We ended the year a much larger organization, with a bigger balance sheet, much stronger balance sheet, more customers, and at the same time we delivered a very sound result.</p>
          <p>Today, presenting our performance is Gail Kelly, our Chief Executive Officer, and Phil Coffey, our CFO. With that introduction, I'll pass over to Gail. And would you please make sure you just &#x2013; I know you all know the drill with phones, etcetera, but if you could just double-check that they are switched off it'd be great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andrew. Well, thanks, Andrew. And good morning, everyone, and we really appreciate you joining us today for our full year 2009 financial year results. We have the whole team with us here today. So once Phil and I have completed the presentation, we certainly look forward to question-and-answer and some discussion on the results.</p>
          <p>It's certainly been a very big year for us in the Westpac Group, and I thought what I'd do upfront is just put a little bit of context around what we've been focusing on. And essentially, there have been four key areas of focus for us over the course of the year.</p>
          <p>The first one, as you would expect, was very much about managing through the global economic financial crisis and the resulting economic downturn, really making sure that we positioned ourselves as strongly as possible for any scenario that might occur and also making sure that we position ourselves to support our customers, as they had to deal with the difficulties and issues arising through the crisis.</p>
          <p>The second really important area of focus was actually following through on our strategy. We put in place our Westpac strategy in 2008, signed off by the Board in July 2008, a strategy that's very much focused on customers. It's about strengthening and empowering our distribution, about making it easier for our customers to do business with us, about strengthening our operations and our processes, and also about focusing and making sure that we pull together as one team, so working on those cultural and team elements of the business.</p>
          <p>The third key priority for us was very much our merger with St.George, which as you know came into effect on the 1st of December last year. And the priorities that we had there were really clear &#x2013; as quickly as possible to rebuild St.George and restore it to momentum. The second key priority is we set ourselves a strict goal of not losing a single customer. And the third was to go after those cost synergies as quickly as possible.</p>
          <p>And the fourth key area of focus for us over the course of the year had to do with technology. We recognized during the course of 2008 that we had work to do on technology. And so Bob McKinnon joined us towards the end of 2008, and we charged him with strengthening the leadership team, stabilizing our environment, and indeed putting in place an IT strategy to support our business strategy with a roadmap to go with it.</p>
          <p>Now, in all of these four key areas of focus, I'm delighted to say that we've really made excellent progress. And so in lots of ways what we would call is 2009 as a transformational year.</p>
          <p>And starting out with a comment on our brands, we've added the very strong iconic banking brands of St.George and BankSA to our existing banking brands of Westpac and RAMS, and we've added the St.George wealth brands of Asgard and Securitor to our overall BT stable of wealth brands.</p>
          <p>From a customer point of view, our customer numbers have grown from seven million to now at around 10 million, and we have a 40% uplift in our distribution throughout the Westpac Group.</p>
          <p>From a market share point of view, as the slide points out, we've got materially larger market share positions in all of the major product categories. That's largely due to the merger, but we've also grown our market share in key areas organically over the course of this year.</p>
          <p>And then from a balance sheet point of view, we've strengthened our Tier 1 ratio now at 8.1, and we paid a lot of attention to funding and so I'm very pleased to see the improvement in our stable funding ratio now to 84%. We pay particular attention, as you know, to our retail deposit growth. So overall, we finished the year saying actually we're a different company from the one that we were at the outset.</p>
          <p>Just to have a quick look then at the numbers, and from a point of view of our cash earnings, coming a little more than 4.6 billion which was down 8% on a year-on-year basis. Core earnings has been particularly strong, as you can see, up 19%, with strong revenue growth of 13% and cost growth managed at 5%, and that's led to an overall cost to income ratio just a little over 40%.</p>
          <p>Of course, the impairment charges have gone up materially, as you would expect, in this year, and Phil would have a lot to say about impairments during the course of his presentation. But it suffices for me to say, at the moment, our third quarter was our worst quarter from a point of view of impairments. We've certainly seen a stabilizing situation in the first quarter, and we didn't feel it necessary to add to our economic overlay during the second half.</p>
          <p>From a dividend point of view, the directors declared a $0.56 dividend for the first half, which was down 20% on the prior period. And this half, the directors have declared a $0.60 dividend. So it's good to see the rising trajectory again and that indeed is a sign of confidence.</p>
          <p>Having a look at our five key business units, and the standout performer is indeed our Westpac Retail and Business Banking business. Peter Hanlon and his team have really done an excellent job over the course of the year, and I think that reflects in the numbers &#x2013; a 9% uplift in cash earnings and a 15% uplift in core earnings for the year.</p>
          <p>We put significant investment in our Retail and Business Banking business over the course of this year. A little more than 560 front-facing staff in our distribution networks, we've opened eight branches and four business banking centers, and you would have seen a little bit about our Westpac Local initiative, more recently, which is about 60% of the way through in terms of rollout.</p>
          <p>From a market share point of view, it's been a very strong year overall, and we've grown mortgage market share something like 1.8 times system growth. That includes an excellent performance from RAMS. And our deposit growth is 1.4% system growth &#x2013; or 1.4 times system growth.</p>
          <p>And customer efficacy, one of those really key metrics us, we measure it in terms of Net Promoter Score. It's been pleasing to see that improving too over the course of the year and most markedly in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Looking at St.George, it's been a story of rebuilding for St.George off a slower start in the first period of the year, but really great to see that healthy core earnings of 16% up over the year. And I think that's testament to really three things. Firstly, to the strength of the underlying franchise within St.George. Secondly, the experience and stability of the management team at St.George, led by Greg Bartlett, who is a 20-year-old veteran of St.George. And thirdly, it's, in fact, the business model that we've put in place that's allowed St.George to absolutely focus on its customers and not be distracted. And there's still customers that come up to St.George &#x2013; to Greg today and can actually say, when are you going to do that merger, when is that merger going to happen, which really points to just how focused that business has been able to be. And in fact, we've grown customer numbers over the course of the year.</p>
          <p>That core healthy earnings has been offset by commercial stress. And if you think about it, not surprisingly, that's in commercial property for the most part. And if you drill down one level lower, it's in property and development &#x2013; construction and development segment. And if you drill down one level lower to say where is that most being felt from a regional point of view, it's actually being most felt in Western Australia where valuations have come by 70%.</p>
          <p>Looking at our Westpac Institutional business. It's been &#x2013; look at the numbers there and you can see core earnings up 29% and cash earnings down 58. So quite a remarkable year, very like the first half results and really reflects the extreme volatility that we've had in global financial markets.</p>
          <p>Really exceptional revenue growth, and again Phil will talk to that through our markets business. That's due to increasing customer activity through our markets business. It's also due to really skilled people that we have in that area and strong risk management that we run in that area.</p>
          <p>From an impairment point of view, if you look at the quarter by quarter &#x2013; and Phil will talk to this, but if you look at the quarter by quarter you can actually see the phases of the global financial crises working through the Institutional Bank impairment loan because the first quarter with those high single-name exposures was obviously the worst quarter from a Westpac Institutional point of view.</p>
          <p>Our BT group, an improving trend, not surprisingly on the back of the improving markets we've had more recently. I think this is a very solid result, down 4% on core earnings and 8% on cash earnings. Rob Coombe and his team had a very, very full year. They've actually been dealing with the integration with St.George that's gone incredibly well.</p>
          <p>We're ahead of target with regard to synergies to achieve over that business. And the various platforms down alongside each other so if you look at our BT wrap platform alongside our Asgard platforms together we occupy the number one spot from market share point of view and we're actually capturing a higher than market share of new flows. So one in every $3 comes into let's say to platforms.</p>
          <p>Insurance business has been excellent too cash earnings up by 20% that's notwithstanding increasing claims as a result of storms and other natural disasters. And that's a very significant improvement in cross-sell activities across our retail businesses particularly our Westpac Retail business.</p>
          <p>New Zealand I think we all know what a tough operating environment it's been within New Zealand. And certainly this result is a disappointing result from our point of view. And the second half was particularly disappointing as a direct consequence of materially higher impairments. There were two large single-name impairments that particularly impacted in the second half. I visited New Zealand a couple of weeks ago and spent time with George and his team. George has been with us since March of this year. He has strengthened his team and I really did come away with a sense of improved momentum. George has put some specific initiatives in place to restore momentum within the franchise and some additional risk management disciplines within the business as well. And I also got a sense actually of a slightly improving economic environment within New Zealand too.</p>
          <p>Talking about balance sheet really three elements on this slide; firstly, capital, secondly, provisioning coverage, and thirdly, our funding profile. If you look at capital, we have a strong Tier 1 capital position of 8.1 and particularly strong when you look at the fundamental capital ratio or core capital ratio which stands at 6.6. Phil will talk to this in a lot of detail. The fact is we're generating healthy organic growth in our capital. We're comfortably about our target ranges of 6.75 to 7.75. From a point of view of the provision coverage, we are industry leading in that regard with our 142 basis points of collectively assessed provisions against credit risk-weighted assets and we think we are in excellent shape there. Our economic overlay remains at 500 million, a little over 500 million. And as I indicated we didn't feel necessary to add to that in the second half.</p>
          <p>From a funding point of view, as I mentioned, significant focus on that over the course of the past year. Since I've been in Westpac going back to the beginning of 2008, this has been a real area of focus for us to really put focus on raising customer deposits and pleased with the outcome this year, 17% growth in customer deposits. And actually if you look at Australia, it's 20% growth in customer deposits. And we've increased the amount of term funding as a proportion of our overall funding. And we've also lengthened the actual term of that term funding. So a lot of focus and effort in funding and an improved stable funding ratio of 84.</p>
          <p>The merger has been a big element for us this year and there are perhaps two things I'd most like to call out. The first is what's in the box on the right. And that's that St.George is actually more strongly positioned than ever, is a healthier position than ever from a strategic point of view.</p>
          <p>St.George occupies the position of being Australia's first largest bank. St.George occupies the position of being by far the largest regional bank. The positioning of being big enough and yet small enough that St.George adopted in about 2003, actually now resonates more than ever.</p>
          <p>And what Greg Bartlett has done more recently is put in place a new regional structure with six managing directors running regions as businesses and putting additional empowerment and authority to those managing directors running their businesses in the regions. He's drawn quite heavily from a model, which as you know is a long standing model, local model in BankSA. And just a quick look at BankSA's results shows you how successful a local model can be. BankSA has delivered a cash earnings uplift of 20% and indeed it's its ninth, successive year of double-digit earnings gross performance. It's had revenue growth of 11%, cost growth of 3% and perhaps most material of all in this year is impairments that are only six million that's across its retail, its business banking and its Agri lending. And that's indeed lower than it was last year.</p>
          <p>So a really outstanding performance and really does demonstrate the strength of local, strength of knowing your customers, longstanding relationships with the customers and working with your customers through the cycle.</p>
          <p>The other key elements I'd like to make with regard to the merger, is that this is a true merger and we're getting very effective sharing of best practice from one part of the Group into the other. And for example, Peter Hanlon who is also South Australian has been timed with Rob Chapman in South Australia learning a little about the key factors of success in that BankSA model to add those in and implement those as part of the Westpac Local approach. Learning from the St.George context into management that's won numerous awards over numerous years, and brining some of those capabilities into the Westpac context into world, and similarly the St.George complaint management process introducing that into Westpac. Many examples of course going the other way as well with the implementation of the Westpac risk grading models across the whole of St.George, the expert judgment process across the whole of St.George and of course new products. We will very soon be launching the BT Super for Life product through the St.George distribution network. That's in pilot now and will be rolled out within weeks from now.</p>
          <p>So if I stand back and assess the overall full year performance as I said a really very big year for us and starting on the negative side of the ledger, clearly the disappointments are the credit losses. In the first year, I mentioned specifically the asset writedowns related to ECG and of course our margin lending losses. In the second half, the issues are more to do with development property both in Australia and in New Zealand. And talking about New Zealand we of course also have some additional disappointments in New Zealand the most recent of which was the decision that was made with regard to the tax issue that goes back some period.</p>
          <p>On the positive side of the ledger there, I've mentioned a number of those points, so perhaps just to call out the bottom two consumer asset quality has been a standout for us, very strong performance really showing the resilience of the housing sector, so indeed our 90-day delinquencies have actually come back quite materially across all of our brands from the first half to the second half and sustainability is something we take very, very seriously. It's an area we focus on extraordinarily and this year particular focus on our customers. A particular focus on supporting our customer as they deal with the difficulties and the uncertainties that this environment has created.</p>
          <p>So there are lots of proof points of that. We've remained open for business. We've grown our balance sheet over this period. Of course our Westpac Assist and St.George Assist has been there to proactively provide support to customers before they get into a stress situation. But the element of this slide that I'd most like to draw your attention to is with regard to the Institutional Bank, Westpac Institutional Bank and the relationship strength slide there.</p>
          <p>I've been really exceptionally pleased with the proactive approach that our relationship managers in the Institutional Bank have taken to supporting their customers at the institutional banking and corporate banking when those customers actually most needed it. Rob Whitfield and I have spent quite a bit of time over the last six to eight weeks out and about meeting customers and in fact the feedback coming from customers has been exceptionally strong of how they have appreciated it that Westpac stood alongside them being proactive supported them, given them help at the time that they most needed it.</p>
          <p>And I think that slide that measures customers view of relationships with their bank really shows how strongly in this year, this difficult year of 2009, the Westpac customers have given us a very high absolute score and much higher than prior years and indeed the differential to our peers has even widened further. So I think testament to a really strong approach and strategy within the Group overall.</p>
          <p>So with let me stop and hand over to Phil to give us more insight on the details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thanks, Gail and good morning, everyone. Let me start by just highlighting our approach to reporting, which aims to assist clarity with regard to our performance. And there are two primary adjustments that we make to our statutory results. We've calculated pro forma accounts for the merger with St.George, which involves calculating the combined result for the full six months of St.George earnings for the first half of 2009 and for all of 2008.</p>
          <p>The second adjustment is that as usual we've calculated cash earnings by adjusting the statutory results for significant one-off items that have distorted the reported results, and you can find a detailed reconciliation of our statutory and pro forma cash earnings in the ASX release.</p>
          <p>Turning to the results, and as we've done in recent presentations, I'll focus on key factors that I think would benefit from further discussion. We've achieved a sound financial performance in what was an extraordinary year and several elements of our earnings reflect the extremes that we saw in the year.</p>
          <p>Our revenue growth of 13% was very strong and when combined with expense growth of 5% produced core earnings 19% ahead of 2008 and that's the highest rate of growth that I can recall. Very strong interest income from both volume growth and improved margins and excellent market-related income were drivers of our revenue result.</p>
          <p>On the other side of the ledger, impairments rose 2.1 billion as a number of customers struggled with the impact of the global financial crisis and the slowing economy. And so that led to an overall cash earnings result which showed a decline of 8%.</p>
          <p>Our statutory reported NPAT was down 11% and that includes a number of significant items including the New Zealand tax provision and the impact of only looking at St.George from the 17th of November, 2008.</p>
          <p>When we look at the half-on-half performance, there were some similar trends in each half. Although, given the change that we saw in the environment over the year, there were also some pretty material differences.</p>
          <p>On the similarities in the second half, net interest income continued to be strong from good volume growth, especially in Westpac RBB and St.George and treasury income was always again an important contributor in the half.</p>
          <p>Impairment charges were also similar half-on-half at around 1.6 to 1.7 billion.</p>
          <p>The differences though were significant, although some of the major items were offsetting. Customer margins in the second half were basically flat after an eight basis points rise in the first half. And markets income in the Institutional Bank was lower, especially in FX after the outstanding results that we saw early in the year. Wealth income was better as average FUM and average FUA improved as we saw confidence returning to the equity markets. And expense growth slowed in the second half as our merger synergies kicked in.</p>
          <p>With impairment charges although the quantum was similar half on half the composition was quite different and I'll spend a bit of time in a minute outlining those differences. So the net impact of those moves was a P&amp;L with less dramatic individual components, but with a pleasing improvement in earnings, cash earnings were up in the second half by 2%.</p>
          <p>A real feature of our result is the balance sheet growth that we saw in all of our customer divisions. The focus on deposits saw great results and as Gail mentioned, the Australian businesses in particular had strong growth.</p>
          <p>Loans also grew in our targeted segments with only the institutional division showing a pullback in loans, and this was expected given the deleveraging focus that corporations and institutions around the world really have had.</p>
          <p>In total, growth in deposits more than offset or more than fully funded our loan growth. So Westpac has remained open for business throughout the year, and combined with the focus on customers, has led to us seeing good balance sheet growth.</p>
          <p>Looking at margins, 2009 saw a recovery in customer margins and they were up seven basis points over the full year. And you can see that in the chart on the top right hand part of this slide. Asset spreads improved as we repriced our loans to reflect higher business risk premiums and to partly recover the rise in funding costs that we'd seen in 2008. This improvement more than offset liability spreads which declined in line with the higher rates that we are paying for customer deposits. The hedging that we do of our risk to falling interest rates helped to moderate the overall liability spread compression.</p>
          <p>Mix impacts had a negative overall impact on margins with faster growth in Australian mortgages and an increase in the proportion of our deposits that were in term deposits or higher rate online call accounts.</p>
          <p>As called out in the first half our margins also saw a material benefit from treasury risk management activities, and over the year the higher net interest income from treasury added 14 basis points to margins.</p>
          <p>Lastly in WIB and other, we saw a further nine basis points added to margins, three basis points of that was really just due to income composition and the other six basis points was mainly due to the Group's mix impacts.</p>
          <p>In the second half, which is the bottom half of that slide, customer margins were unchanged on both asset and liability spreads showing little movement, while treasury continued to contribute up 11 basis points and WIB and other added also another four basis points.</p>
          <p>I'd say the key underlying trend in the second half has been rising wholesale funding costs on an average basis and our re-pricing activities have really just kept pace with those movements.</p>
          <p>Margins overall were well managed over the year, although we expect some decline over 2010 as the treasury result moderates.</p>
          <p>The volatile markets and the large moves that we saw in interest rates and exchange rates were a positive environment for market related activity for our markets teams and our treasury teams. The higher uncertainty stimulated more customer activity which played into the strength of our customer franchise and the larger market moves rewarded successful risk management. The performance of the two halves was somewhat different. In the first half, we had exceptionally strong growth in both debt markets and foreign exchange both handling the uncertain environment well and getting the benefit of wider market spreads. And that was especially the case in FX.</p>
          <p>In the second half, our debt markets business continued to do well, it benefited from reduced credit spreads, although our FX business was less successful in capitalizing on the big moves and they also had to deal with what was quite a rapidly narrowing market spread environment. The lower markets revenue though in the second half was almost offset by increased treasury revenue and the treasury business also benefited from the narrowing in credit spreads and in their case it was on the large liquid asset portfolio that they're managing.</p>
          <p>Pleasantly what this slide also shows you is that average VaR was not the major driver &#x2013; or changes in average VaR was not the major driver of risk results. So we're not generating this by taking more outright risk.</p>
          <p>Expense growth was tightly managed. Growth of 5% over the year and just 1% in the second half was achieved at the same time as we invested in two really important areas. The first area has been our continued investment in the retail network, both in the terms of its reach and in terms of its capability. More customer facing employees, more branches and business centers combined with the rollout of the local operating model were significant achievements for Westpac RBB.</p>
          <p>Whilst in St.George we've reinvigorated the brand, implemented a new operating structure and we also continue to build at its presence and added five more branches there.</p>
          <p>Secondly, there has been more spending on IT reliability, capacity and service and that's included putting over 12,000 new PCs in the line and upgrading our network to the new Telstra next-gen network. Offsetting this investment was a broad-based focus on productivity; improved processing efficiencies especially in BT and product and operations area; there was lower discretionary spending and smaller bonus pools; and lower software amortization expense. And we've also sought to quickly capture the benefits of merger expense synergies.</p>
          <p>So the impact of those moves has seen our cost to income ratio down to 40.2% and the banking cost to income ratio is already below 40% and that provides us with a substantial productivity advantage and there is more to come.</p>
          <p>I mentioned merger synergies were an important part of the efficiency of the company and at 143 million in 2009 we are 19% ahead of schedule and with a healthy run rate going into 2010. However, the biggest additional benefit from the merger for us has been in the area of revenue and customer attrition. When we announced the merger, we estimated that a good outcome would have been to restrict customer loss and revenue attrition to 4% of St.George income. And quite a few people questioned us at the time around that optimism and they highlighted the fact that previous Australian transactions have seen much greater loss.</p>
          <p>Of course the major difference between those transactions and the St.George merger with Westpac is the operating model. And by keeping and strengthening the St.George distribution network and people we've minimized customer disruptions. And as Gail mentioned over the first year, we had an internal goal, not to lose a customer and to see net customer growth over the year has been fantastic. But importantly, from a financial perspective it adds $150 million per annum to our valuation model.</p>
          <p>There's also the risk that we'd be distracted from continuing to develop the Westpac RBB business and I think the results as Gail has mentioned speak for themselves in terms of not being diverted there.</p>
          <p>And lastly, this is a transformation transaction. So the benefit of best practice across the group of cross-sell of product, of sharing of IT infrastructure has really only just started. And we'll see more material benefits of that in 2010 and onwards.</p>
          <p>Probably the area that this room has had most focus on in recent months has been what's the shape of impairment expenses over this cycle? And certainly for the first three quarters of 2009 the credit health of our business, corporate and institutional portfolio deteriorated at a fairly rapid rate with the GFC issues combining with financial stress. Especially for customers in our commercial segment and they are customers that generally have facilities between 10 and $100 million.</p>
          <p>And you can see in this slide, how our stressed exposures have grown from around 130 basis points at the end of 2008 to 280 basis points at the end of the third quarter. And they're just over 300 basis points at the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>Whilst impaired assets have grown, they are at 57 basis points, up from 24 and that's the red bar on that slide. The biggest increase is in the watchlist and substandard group which increased from 91 to 223 basis points. Now some 80% of this category is in the high rated watchlist. And in that category is, I stress, companies that are not in default, but we are giving them increased management attention as we look to nurse them back to full health.</p>
          <p>You can see that the rate of increase in stressed assets slowed in the fourth quarter and that was something that we had expected and we indicated to the market that that was our expectation in our third quarter update.</p>
          <p>Probably one of the most important things to note though is that customer delinquencies have actually improved over the past six months, and already little changed over the course of the year. And we are seeing this actually emerge across quite a broad range of stress indicators and it demonstrates the resilience of this sector. And loans to household make up 65% of our total loans. And that proportion is up from 60% in 2008 when it was Westpac standalone. And I think that increase is yet another benefit of the St.George merger.</p>
          <p>Looking at the quarterly impairment pattern in more detail, and you can see on this slide the divisional drivers of our impairment charges for each of the last four quarters. And you can see how the charge in institutional spiked in the first quarter and then has subsequently eased as the GFC impact is sort of washed through and being replaced by the impact of the slower economy and the tighter cash flows that are having a bigger impact on that commercial segment. The second quarter had the additional impact of an increase in the economic overlay and in payment charges for our margin lending exposures but it was also the period in which we saw the commercial stress accelerating.</p>
          <p>New Zealand had a significant impact on the third quarter due to two large impairments and it also combined with additional charge for the weak property development picture.</p>
          <p>I'd say the fourth quarter was characterized by further stress in that commercial sector particularly in PBG business and in St.George but it was also due to a very rigorous assessment that we took place in terms of our credit rating, utilizing current asset and yields.</p>
          <p>So combining the slowing rate of increase in the stressed assets that you saw in the previous slide and the composition and pattern of impairment charges suggest to us that its likely that we are now at the top of this impairment cycle.</p>
          <p>Now, that's not to say we won't see continuing increase in new stressed exposures and there are still many small to mid sized companies who are feeling the pinch. But more customers have actually used this period of low interest rates and fiscal stimulus to reduce the risk in their business and we would say the overall picture is definitely stabilizing.</p>
          <p>The area that's been hardest hit for us has been in commercial property and in particular property development. And in fact many other elements of our property exposures are still performing very soundly and they're benefiting from the capital injection that's taken place, particularly for the larger diversified property groups, and the fact that we went into this downturn without the large over capacity that sort of characterized the early 90s downturn. So when we separate out our property exposure into these components, you can see quite large differences in the extent of stress in the portfolio.</p>
          <p>So this slide distinguishes our property development from other Australian property exposures and you can see that the exposures in the development segment and the New Zealand portfolio which also has a relatively higher weighting towards property development, the stressed experience in those two groups is more than twice that of the remaining property portfolio and these two more difficult areas for us comprise 20% of the total property portfolio and just on 1.8% of the total Group.</p>
          <p>So they are an important issue to manage, but they are not one to be alarmed by, particularly given that these facilities are secured and that there is a fairly large proportion of our provisions that are earmarked against this segment.</p>
          <p>The total property exposure of the Group declined modestly over the year as facilities have been reduced by customers who have used capital raisings or their cash flow or assets sales or completions to reduce their gearing.</p>
          <p>And as we've called out previously, we're keen to support our existing customers in this group, but we're not looking to aggressively grow in the property segment. And property now comprises 9.1% of our total committed exposures, down from 10% at the start of the year.</p>
          <p>From a P&amp;L sense, the impairment charge over the past year was 3.3 billion, that's 2.1 billion higher than the previous year, and we expensed over 0.50 billion in collective provisions over the year, which included the $112 million increase in our economic overlay. And Gail mentioned, we didn't see the need to add to that in the second half and it stands at just over 500 million. But it does mean that we've continued to grow our collective provision balances, and that at 142 basis points to credit risk weighted assets. We continue to lead the sector on provisioning cover.</p>
          <p>We had 1.6 billion increase in our impairment writedowns, sorry in our individual assessed provisions and that 50% of that was in the Institutional Bank. Notwithstanding some uplift in our impairment writedowns in the second half, the impairment provision to impaired assets ratio still stood at a very healthy 39.3% at the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>So we've taken a position that we'd rather maintain higher provisions until the credit cycle shows clear evidence of improvement. At that point re-grades should also show a proportionate benefit as we move into the better part of the cycle.</p>
          <p>Turning to capital, another area of considerable focus and Gail's called out the strength of our capital position. The past 12 months have seen some quite large factors that have impacted our various capital measures. Most pleasingly was the excellent organic capital generation, so cash earnings added 160 basis points and that was versus growth and risk weighted assets which was 39 basis points and our dividends of 79 basis points, so in an organic sense we created a net addition of 42 basis points to out Tier 1 ratio.</p>
          <p>The other major addition was from the capital raisings earlier in the period as we manage the impact of St.George merger and as we move to a stronger position due to the uncertain world net, added 139 basis points to our Tier 1 ratio.</p>
          <p>However, there were also significant negative one-offs and the two largest where the increase in the deferred tax asset and the impact of taking additional provisions for the New Zealand tax. So we end the year with a Tier 1 ratio of 8.11% and that's using the APRA definition and that's equivalent to 10.7% using the FSA standard.</p>
          <p>When considering capital management into 2010 and beyond, we think it's worth looking at the various components that make up our capital base. And starting with the core or fundamental capital, which is clearly the ultimate line of defense against loss and the indisputably highest quality of capital. And this segment of capital is also likely to get increased attention when the regulatory change is applied through.</p>
          <p>At 6.6% the Group fundamental Tier 1 ratio compares favorably with most banks around the world. And if again we use the FSA basis the fundamental ratio will be 9%. We'd expect this ratio to further improve over 2010 as the impact of pro-cyclicality unwinds. And also achieving advanced Basel II accreditation for the St.George portfolios should also add at least 30 basis points to this ratio. And we have an additional one billion in contingent capital that could be converted into equity in need. This is currently recorded as debt and so, if we did the conversion, it would lift our fundamental and total capital ratio an additional 35 basis points.</p>
          <p>The secondary support in the capital base comes from hybrid capital and I think it's demonstrated its secondary position in that losses to date in the industry have been written-off against equity and dividends have been cut, and that's before hybrids have been converted or hybrid distribution have been cut. Nevertheless these forms of capital would kick-in before regulatory requirements were breached and so they do act as an important buffer.</p>
          <p>We have 1.5% Tier 1 capital in the form of hybrids today and we have 1.8 billion or 64 basis points of additional hybrid capacity under current APRA requirements. And so we'll weigh up our options for hybrid issuance as the further regulatory positions become clearer over time.</p>
          <p>In summary, capital management is nearer with quite a few moving parts not least the regulatory changes that are likely to become clearer over the year. But we start with a strong fundamental position and we would expect to see further improvement in that over the year, and our Tier 1 in total is very healthy. Given this, and the flexibility we have in managing our capital we are in a position to fully support our growth aspirations for our customers and for our dividends. Lastly, I'd say we're also conscious of not unduly diluting returns for shareholders and consistent with what has been our practice in the past, we will not hold surplus levels of capital for possible acquisition opportunities that may or may not eventuate.</p>
          <p>So looking into 2010 and the major factors that will impact our financial performance and we start the year with strong business momentum in all our operating divisions and wealth revenue in particular should continue to recover. But as is always the case, there are headwinds and our market related revenue will likely be lower after the stellar 2009 and the mix here and the composition of that market related revenue could also be different with interest income lower from treasury. Lower exception fees will also be recorded and we should expect modest credit growth in line with the economy although we would expect to be able to grow as we did this year ahead of system.</p>
          <p>On the expenses front, we will continue to invest particularly in our IT related projects however merger synergies and lower compensation increases from arrangements that we have already agreed will assist in moderating our expense growth rate. Lastly, on impairments, as I've already called out today we're likely to be at the top of the credit impairment cycle notwithstanding continuing business risk. And mortgage exposures in particular look to be continuing to be very solid and we have very modest delinquency levels as we start this cycle of monetary policy tightening. And with 61% of our total exposures in Australian and New Zealand mortgages we have a quality base of our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>On that, let me hand back to Gail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Phil. Look, I'll say a few words in a moment about our Westpac outlook. But before I do that I thought it might be useful just to share a few thoughts about the conditions we're operating in &#x2013; the conditions post crisis. What will the sort of new normal as it were look like? What's the kind of world we'll be operating in? We will know one thing is for certain and that is we won't be going back to the world the way it was before.</p>
          <p>So if you think about it from a customer point of view, the one thing we all know is that higher savings will be a priority and certainly higher savings will be rewarded. The other thing that we absolutely know is that customers are really going to value deep relationships with banks. I think we've seen that over the course of the past period, the relationships with banks that they can trust. And similarly, banks and financial services companies again value deep relationships with customers and will make decisions based on the depth of relationships with customers.</p>
          <p>If you think about it from an industry point of view, we're certainly going into a lower growth environment. And the deleveraging and the easing of stimulus packages are certainly impacting on the growth environment. Deposit growth, again mentioned by deposit growth seem -it's going to be a greater driver or determinant of the amount of lending that actually gets done in the system. Average funding costs continuing to rise, even though marginal funding costs are lowering average costs continue to rise and that's as we replace cheaper funding with more expensive funding and as we pay more for those very valuable saving, customer savings.</p>
          <p>I was talking to Curt Zuber a little while ago and he was reminding me sort of two and a half years ago if we were able to raise three year money, wholesale money in offshore markets at 15 basis points over the benchmark rate, and as you all know at the heart of the crisis that was 200 basis points plus, and now maybe around 100 basis points, but it certainly weren't be going back to those days of 15 basis points or anywhere near there. So funding costs overall from an average point of view are rising.</p>
          <p>On the regulatory front clearly there is more change here yet to come, changes flowing from the G20, changes flowing through from the Basel committee work, and I think business models are being adjusted for that already. We certainly can expect higher minimum capital levels and we can expect higher quality capital being required.</p>
          <p>And again I recall when in those days we were implementing and working through the process of implementing Basel II advanced accreditation and those were the days we were talking about releasing capital and those were the days we were talking about 6% Tier 1 ratios. So those days have gone. There'll be higher minimums for us.</p>
          <p>Similarly with liquidity, more liquidity and indeed a focus on the change of composition within liquidity, June 2007 our total liquid assets stood at 17 billion. They now stand at 74 billion. So changed environment, the new normal is going to involve more of it.</p>
          <p>Obviously what this is going to require is the regulators being very sensible in how they go about implementing some of these new changes and we'd expect regulators to understand and distinguish between the different jurisdictions, the different starting points of different jurisdictions and different elements of different jurisdictions and certainly we'd expect the regulators to work closely with the industry in consultation and in transitioning to the new regulatory world and I am certainly hopeful that that will actually occur.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Westpac and just looking ahead into 2010, we're very much building on the platforms that we've established over the past period with a very strong focus on these four big planks of customer, people, our brands, our multi-brand strategy and productivity. You've heard me say a lot about some of the customer initiatives already, Westpac Local which is 60% underway in terms of rollout so still in a building phase. Similarly within St.George, the new model at St.George is now in place with initiatives underpinning each one of those. But each one of our businesses have very clear customer initiatives. In people, which is critical to delivering on a customer service proposition huge focus with regard to training, skilling and coaching and a huge focus with regard to increasing the level of accountability and decision making authorities in our businesses.</p>
          <p>Brands we're still learning in a multi-brand world, really delighted with the platform that we have but there is so much more potential out of this platform and so what we'll be doing into the future is looking segment by segment, geography by geography to think about how do we best use the opportunity set that we've got with our different brands in those different geographies.</p>
          <p>And then productivity, in a slower growth environment, clearly productivity is absolutely key. And so not only will we be focusing on cost management and efficiency per se but absolutely also improving and redesigning our processes taking out errors simplifying, which has a cost benefit as well as a customer service benefit.</p>
          <p>I should mention on December the 7 I think it is, we'll be doing a briefing for the market on strategy and indeed a further update on the merger, so just a fuller look at all of those elements on the 7th of December, really marking one year of the merger I suppose.</p>
          <p>Just a final slide then in terms of looking ahead, continued uncertainty in the global environment is very much a given if anything we've seen over the last week that continued uncertainty and that volatility underway. So certainly there's been some recovery but it will be gradual and there will be aftershocks. In the Australian environment we've seen quite a strong recovery over recent months. You may recall in the May update, we were at that point actually expecting a much more serious economic downturn within Australia and in the budget time in May, unemployment was forecast to be something like 8.5 in mid 2010 and clearly all of those forecasts have come back to now more &#x2013; something more like 6.5. So in improving environment and consumer confidence, business confidence have improved. However, still fragility and still cause I think for caution and again in the last week has evidenced some of that.</p>
          <p>With regard to impairments, I think Phil has actually spoken to that. We think the third quarter was our highest quarter and likely to be our highest quarter. We've seen stabilization. But clearly there will be more impairments to come through in next year because impairments lag the cycle as the cycle moves through.</p>
          <p>A very clear focus on our strategic agenda. We know exactly what we are about and we have strong execution capability. And so we are starting the 2010 with strong momentum in our key businesses.</p>
          <p>So thank you for listening to me. And I'll ask Phil to come and join me and we'll take some questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's start with Jon just wait for Phil to get settled. Just keep the questions to one per person please and as per usual just state your name and company will be great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi it's Jonathan Mott from UBS. I have got a question on slide 89 of the investor discussion pack, if you've got that there. So this one just looks at the St.George asset quality, and one thing I've just noticed is in the &#x2013; that last half you saw a very substantial increase in the stressed exposures in St.George going up to 11% of TCE now stressed. And if you back out the big mortgage book, it would look like almost one-third of the St.George exposures which are non-mortgage are pulling down that stressed category. I just wanted to get a feeling for what's coming through there and the impact this is having on the growth of that business going forward given the substantial change that it's had.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe if I could just correct that. That's the percentage of the St.George business TCE, Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Business in fixed mortgage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's &#x2013; you don't take mortgages out again and start with a third, it's actually 12% or just under 12% of the St.George business TCE that's stressed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Maybe you can go through where that's coming through given you do notice that in the second half that St.George bad debt charge is actually larger than it was in the retail and business bank of Westpac.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jon. Look, it's primarily property as I mentioned in my upfront remarks. And property development in there, and a lot of it's residential property development. So I think if you look at the top 24 it's in there, somewhere, isn't it? The top 24 impaired assets over 10 million. 20 of those were in property and 11 of those are in Western Australia. So there is a bit of an over concentration in property in Western Australia that's been built up over the last few years and obviously we all know that Western Australia is one of those record rise and then record fall type environments and so valuations have come back something like 70%.</p>
          <p>A large number of those are not actually unimpaired, they are in, they are stressed, they are in our watchlist, so they are there so we have got a very, very close scrutiny and look at. I must say though that we've paid a lot of attention to the St.George portfolio overall during the course of the year. And we've applied the Westpac risk grade models across the whole portfolio I think we're 95% of the way through the expert judgment process. So the good news of where we are now is a really good understanding of exactly what's in that portfolio. But to summarize, in property, in residential construction development property, and a particularly big concentration in Western Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's James Ellis from Credit Suisse. Just a question on your capital base. Obviously you are sitting comfortably above the target range. But just what your thoughts are in terms of the regulatory changes, which might come through. How comfortably above your range do you think you have to see it? And within that, do you see coming through any further significant items charges, which might put further downward pressure on your capital base which you've seen <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I'll ask Phil to speak more to that. And I think he gave quite a full explanation in his remarks itself. I mean, we had quite a big year really from a capital point of view, this 2009 year, and a couple of large sort of one-off impacts, which certainly won't occur again. The most recent of which was clearly that New Zealand tax case.</p>
          <p>So as we look forward, we're well above our own internal ranges of 6.75 to 7.75. We'd expect to be above those ranges at this time in the cycle. We can look ahead and see the St.George Basel II accreditation actually coming through regenerating strong organic capital growth, which is pleasing too. And the impairment cycle as that begins to improve that will improve the risk weighted asset position as well, as the re-grades come through.</p>
          <p>With regard to the regulatory environment, look there is lots of uncertainty there, still a lot of work to be done on that front. We'd expect that minimum levels will be required to increase, but we're sitting well above any minimal levels and well above our own internal targets. So at this point, we feel that we're well-placed capital wise.</p>
          <p>Phil, do you want to add to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess, one item. I think, that the composition of the capital. I mean we've called out the core fundamental ratio because we think that that is clearly a focus of regulators. Having said that, APRA already has, in a relative sense reasonably restrictive elements to hybrids and so it could may well be that the rest of the world comes down to that kind of additional hybrid capacity that we already had as opposed to anything more extreme.</p>
          <p>But as Gail said, one of the things we've done in the last 12 months is an awful lot of stress testing, not only for the environment we're in but all for all of that perspective or possible environments that regulators and rating agencies around the globe have thought possible. And that's really if anything reaffirmed our comfort with where our capital is today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Craig Williams from Citi here. I noticed that on your first slide technology got a mention just on that matter. In the battleground for retail customers you're seeing two other banks replacing their core banking system at present. You've elected at this stage to take softly, softly approach to minimize disruption to customers. So how are you thinking about driving out cost through technology and processing? Does it require off-shoring? Are you thinking about changing the timing perhaps to your agenda given you've actually had better customer retention and probably a better outlook for credit costs and therefore core profitability within the Group? And how are you driving superior service to customers through technology as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A lot of questions in there Craig. The first thing I'd respond to, it doesn't feel like softly, softly, I might add internally. There is enormous amount of work that we've done with regards to technology over the past year and really setting up a very clear strategy, a very clear roadmap for the future that's mapped to our business strategy. I mean it's quite a deliberate process of actually being commercial, being practical with regards to how we go forward. So the first phase this year with regard to the merger was really focused on the front end and make sure that we get the momentum going with our customers in the front end.</p>
          <p>But over time, what we've got now in terms of our strategy and our roadmap is leveraging parts of St.George, across Westpac and parts of Westpac, across St.George. That will be staged and managed over time. For example, we'll be utilizing the St.George telesystem and implementing that across Westpac. Now that's a cost avoidance for Westpac because Westpac would have needed to implement a new telesystem anyway. We've implemented the people information system from St.George into Westpac. Similarly in the reverse we're implementing the treasury system across the whole and similarly the GL, one GL, which is the Westpac GL.</p>
          <p>But it's a staged and managed process over time. The priority will be our front facing systems. So the priority will be our online systems, our telesystems, our customer information systems, our payment systems. And there's been a lot of advancement and work done on that over this year. I think Phil mentioned the rollout of PCs across the branches, additional bandwidths in the branches.</p>
          <p>Bob, I don't know, if you'd like to add anything to that. I'm now throwing you a curved ball here.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was anticipated. The &#x2013; I'm not quite sure which other of the questions you asked we can sort of focus on that but the focus really has been on getting the technology to service the customers and putting the weight of our technology investment around making sure that we're leveraging the things that can make a difference in terms of customer service.</p>
          <p>At the same time we have a longer-term objective of bringing the two technology platforms together. So while we're doing that we will start to do work in St.George. So while we do a lot of customer work in Westpac, we'll start to do work on St.George platforms to &#x2013; around some of those more core banking elements, so that a year or two down the track we can stop to bring those elements together with Westpac. So we're trying to make the back ends more consistent, using St.George as the base for that while we work within Westpac around the customer facing element. So that's the overall plan. It's a five year plan that we're working to and it's one that suites our strategy. I think the important thing with technology is it actually has to be the plan that supports where your business is going and that's definitely where we have been putting our focus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian Johnson, CLSA. Question for Phil. Phil, some of these numbers won't necessarily be 100% accurate because I am just running on memory. But at the third quarter the Tier 1 ratio was down at 8.1% and that was a bit of shock. If you have a little bit at the time you basically said that there was a 25 basis point decline that related to the increase in the deferred tax asset which was driven by the asymmetric hedge accounting and also the absence of write-offs coming through on the loan loss provision which makes sense.</p>
          <p>Shortly thereafter, we basically &#x2013; the next day virtually the indication was that those things reversed, the Tier 1 ratio is back up to 8.4. New Zealand tax comes through, <mark type="inaudible" /> the effect down to 8.1 which you are very happy about but which certainly looks low compared to the <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>If I have to look on page 125 I see that the deferred tax asset deduction has only increased by about 200 million, two to three million half on half and what I'd like to understand is that what is the risk, what's the capital shock risk of basically this asymmetric hedge accounting coming through 25 basis points unexpectedly off the Tier 1 ratio just because currencies move rather than any operational change brings the Tier 1 ratio down below the eight percentage point. You wouldn't be quite as happy as you are today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, and so I think the numbers are broadly right, Brian. And the other thing that we had in the fourth quarter was we had a about a 14 basis points impact from interest rate risk in the banking book and you can see that in the ASX document as well and that's just because the embedded gain and the hedge reduced as interest rates started to move back up. So we've had to observe that in our 8.11 as well.</p>
          <p>And in terms of the DTAs as I mentioned two components, one due to the asymmetric nature of the FX hedging of our short term offshore borrowing. If the currency appreciates by another 30 odd percent which is where it has come in the course of this year then there's a risk that we will have another big increase in that item. That's not what we're intending and we are obviously focusing on a much harder now in terms of what we can do through the period to manage that down. So I don't really expect that but obviously it's still got that as a sensitivity. But the other item is we built up a lot of deferred tax on individual provisions that we've taken and we hadn't written anything off.</p>
          <p>And you know that the accounting for that and obviously as we start to go into the cycle now of writing things off, so that reduces the tax balance. And that's one of the reasons why it didn't increase as much in the second half as you'll see we took some quite chunky impairment losses in the fourth quarter, we write things off against provisions and that helped to moderate the impact on that loan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But the point is that the capital ratio is still vulnerable to appreciation in the A dollar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's lots of items that will go into the capital ratio but then as we pointed out, we're also generating &#x2013; what I think is the most important element is that we're generating significant capital through our organic activities. This is not a period of high-risk weighted asset growth and you know the reasons for that as well.</p>
          <p>I mean the other thing is we had got &#x2013; we've taken &#x2013; we had the hit on the structured finance tax provisions and we haven't taken &#x2013; haven't had the benefits of the two others items that can go our way including the St.George Basel II accreditation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So Phil you're saying if &#x2013; am I right in interpreting that you're saying you might even buy some hedges in case the A dollar, to cover that risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It just means we would just make sure that the hedges are able to match off in an accounting sense against the underlying. So we won't do it across the period but within the period there's things we can do in terms of managing those hedges and how they come through on the accounting line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's James Freeman from Deutsche Bank. I was just wanting to actually get some more comments on the margin. You obviously mentioned that your &#x2013; that margin will struggle a little bit, because of the treasury coming back next period. Just as you look at the customer margins, just your expectations for that, are you still seeing rising costs of funds offsetting all the asset repricing or do you expect some improvement in customer margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look I think you picked it up James in terms of distinguishing between those two major drivers of our margins. And certainly on the treasury front, we know we've had a very strong year and we don't think that's going to be necessarily repeated and because it's all interest income it will lead to that element of margin coming back.</p>
          <p>On the customer front, the second half we've been able to maintain customer margins after improving them in the first half. And there tends to be leads and lags in terms of how our customer assets are we repriced. We are about 40 to 50% of the way through repricing our business books in the St.George area and in Westpac RBB. And so we would expect that we can continue to appropriately price our lending for what's happening in our average cost of funds. And so we would absolutely be expecting that we'd be at least maintaining our customer margins in the next 12 months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jarrod?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Jarrod Martin, RBS. Question for you Phil, just in reference to slide 21. You made a comment that you would maintain higher provisions until the cycle changes. But at same time, I think you're calling out that the cycle is just about changing. So my question is should we expect the provisioning level to begin to drop first half '10? What sort of level do we expect provisions to ultimately fall to, from a coverage ratio for the cycle? And is there any regulatory pressure to actually maintain those higher levels now through the cycle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's difficult to say exactly where we think that those coverage ratios will come back to, in part because of the second point, which is that there may well be other accounting changes or regulatory changes that impact that.</p>
          <p>To get the benefit we basically need to see the expected loss calculation also decline because otherwise the provisions just get eaten up by capital reductions for that. And so you'll need to see the expected loss come back. We would expect to see that come back as our assets are regraded through the cycle and that will mean your provision in reduction is able to flow through to the bottom line.</p>
          <p>So, and the overlay, I think we called out actually in the third quarter that first thing you have to do with regard to identifying where your impairments are going is to stop increasing your economic overlay. And so we're at a point now where we said &#x2013; we're hopeful that the first half was the end of that, second half basically unchanged, and we'll be looking at over the course of the next couple of halves to see whether we can actually justify holding that other additional buffer, which is this economic overlay against losses that are somewhere in the book.</p>
          <p>So overall, we would absolutely expect that that coverage ratio will come back, both from provision reductions and as the economic overlay comes back. And where it ends up? I don't know. You can look back in history and say that losses at the better part of this cycle should be 25 to 30 basis points rather than 73 as they are today. But as Gail's called out this is a new normal and I'll let you do that calculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Richard Wiles from Morgan Stanley. You've flagged lower margins from treasury possibly weaker markets income, the impact of lower exception fees and also moderate line growth outlook. So I am just wondering where is the revenue growth going to come from in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is going to be tough year. There is no question from a revenue growth point of view. It's going to be a tough year. Clearly wealth will be an improving business for us. We've seen an improving trend in the fourth quarter, and we expect that to continue to improve.</p>
          <p>And then on the back of our customer relationships we've got a very significant focus on deepening all of our customers' businesses and strengthening those relationships and across all elements of transactional baking and across all elements of wealth products will actually assist with that.</p>
          <p>Our businesses are growing. We're actually &#x2013; our customer base is growing and our businesses are growing. So that's another help. As you've seen that in the &#x2013; during this past year, we've grown our balance as we've grown our balance sheet whereas perhaps some of our peers didn't. So that's a help too to support revenue growth for the next period.</p>
          <p>Do you want to add to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No I think that's good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We may take a call from the phones. Ben Koo [Goldman Sachs JBWere]?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Koo your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, a question on the margin, and just to clarify, can you just confirm that when you are talking about the business spreads on page 14 of the result, business product spreads in Australia actually declined over the half. Can you just clarify why that was the case and given that 40 to 50% of it's been repriced, can you just try to tie that in, and then just the outlook for that product spread margin? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben it's got mostly to do with the timing of how our transfer pricing was passed through into the business divisions and the spread impact on that not yet being reflected in terms of the overall customer pricing. So the transfer prices tend to hit across the entire portfolio, whereas obviously the repricing takes place on a incremental, more incremental basis. And so that higher transfer price fee now needs to ultimately find its way into the rates that we're charging our business customers. And so that would then repair that business spread.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take a call from Matt Davison.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, thank you. Good afternoon. My question was also on the revenue outlook, but specifically around the non-interest income outlook. With regard to the treasury dropping back next year, I was just interested if the trading income in the second half was actually at or below trend, or above?</p>
          <p>And then more broadly when you look at banking fees, if we exclude the loyalty fee issue, the trends were still pretty subdued. So I'm just wondering the outlook there into next year notwithstanding that you do have exception fees coming out. And just wondering whether the move by one of your peers to abolish monthly fees is something that you see as putting pressure on your fee line going forward as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I'll handle the last part first, and Phil can handle the rest. I mean, we have a range of products and services with customers that don't have monthly fees, so &#x2013; any number of them within both Westpac and St.George. So it's another customer choice, that's appropriate and relevant for us with our customers. So we don't expect to make any further material changes along those lines. We're always introducing new products and with a range of features and value propositions for our customers. But we have a range of products and services right now across our businesses that don't actually carry monthly fees.</p>
          <p>So I'll stop at that and Phil you can perhaps answer the broader question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think on the &#x2013; on the other elements of non-interest income, what the slide showed in the presentation was that our markets-related income totaled 367 million in the second half of '09, which is obviously well down from the first half, but about the same as what we saw in the first halves &#x2013; oh sorry in the two halves of '08. And so, to your question we would hope that that means that we don't have markets income as a headwind for us if you look at that in terms of the half's performance.</p>
          <p>And the other thing I would call out is that we had quite significant writedowns in our assets in the whole specialized capital group over the course of the year and that's also a negative item that we would not expect to see repeated in the course of 2010. So not having a negative means that you've actually got a positive there helping us in our revenue growth story.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Brett Le Mesurier, Axiome Equities. A question on your cost to income ratio going forward. Phil did you mean to imply that your cost to income ratio is going to fall in 2010 from what you are saying? And to sneak in another one, should we be thinking about on the bad debt charge and net write offs relationship, the net write offs may well exceed the bad debt charge in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, on the cost to income you know it's a function of both items. And so we've had a very material benefit this year from income growth which has driven that down. What I was really highlighting was just the degree of operational leverage you get when you are sitting at a 40% cost to income. And so over time, yes, but whether that happens in a straight-line basis that's probably unlikely, but I would absolutely I'd be looking. For us we think we've got the productivity opportunities coming from the merger and from the other elements of the company to over time drive that ratio further.</p>
          <p>With regard to net write-offs could they exceed the impairment charge? I guess it's possible. It's not something that we are particularly focused on. We've obviously wrote them off against existing provisions and so it's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We want to write some of them back too actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Might take a call from Johan Vanderlugt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, everyone. My question is about the capital allocation and also the divisional ROEs, particularly around Westpac and St.George RBB. I sort of noticed a widening of the ROE gap between the two divisions and if you look at the first half and the second half it's widening from 11 percentage points to about 13 percentage points on an ROE basis.</p>
          <p>My question is about the capital allocation. If you look at ordinary equity you are allocating 6% more to the St.George half on half and 3% more to Westpac half on half and from an ROE point of view I'd rather see the capital being allocated to Westpac's RBB rather than St.George's RBB. So the question is could you talk a bit about the dynamics there and also could you talk about the likelihood of you guys being able to narrow the gap between Westpac's ROE of what was it around 31% for the second half and St.George's RBB about 18%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just start by saying, they're very different businesses with very different business mixes Johan, so you can't actually compare them directly. St.George includes obviously middle market as well as corporate which in the Westpac world are actually in the Institutional Bank the PBG which is the middle market or segment for Westpac actually sits in the Institutional Bank and then there's corporate for Westpac in the Institutional Bank. So you can't really compare them, they're very different business mixes.</p>
          <p>So let me just start with that as a comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that actually goes to why the returns were different over the half because we called out that the commercial segment is the area feeling greatest financial stress and that meant that St.George business had a higher impairment charge impact and that obviously detracted from the ROE in St.George. But you know that &#x2013; and that also is why they've actually had more capital allocated to them because they've got, that credit impact flows through into the amount of economic capital that we would allocate to one of our divisions. But the critical thing to note and it actually goes back to a question from you, Johan, and try to compare Westpac RBB and St.George is not really an appropriate comparison simply whilst they both have big mortgage books in RBB that's a much bigger weighting for Westpac than it is in terms of how the St.George picture is looked at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you compare the St.George middle market or corporate middle market with the PBG which is the equivalent in Westpac they've actually performed very similarly except for Western Australia. So with exception of that Western Australia outlier they've performed very similarly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott Manning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott Manning from JPMorgan. You touched on some liquidity changes, a lot of people seem to be focused on the assets side of the balance sheet in terms of the transition from buying each other's paper into government securities and the like. I'm more interested in the liability that's funding that. If you can't buy each other's paper that's no longer an eligible funding mechanism, which I would assume therefore puts more pressure on deposits or increased long-term wholesale lending. Does that mean that your asset side of the balance sheet needs to slowdown dramatically as your liabilities recalibrate due to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Gail really called out what the critical element here is and that's the transitional aspects of this. I seem to have lost my, my..</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There you go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The transitional aspects of this are really important. And the notion that we can operate in Australia with the same liquidity requirements that might be appropriate in the U.K or the U.S seems a difficult one to understand if for no other reason that we don't have sufficient government securities to even meet those liquidity requirements. So it is an important industry wide issue that needs to be worked through with the government, with our regulators in terms of A, what's appropriate for Australia and secondly, how do we transition to that in a why that doesn't have the impact and you called out, which is that there is a credit crunch, credit in the country and I'm sure that neither the regulators nor the government want to see that happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those are exactly the debates and conversations that we're having with regulators and with government and as you heard me say I mean I'm hopeful that we'll work it through because clearly there is systemic economic impacts if we don't get this right. So I think we will get it right because we just can't afford to not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. TS Lim from Southern Cross. Competitors are making inroads into wealth management locally and also pursuing offshore growth options. Are you concerned about being left behind? Or in other words, do you have enough growth options locally to sustain earnings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>TS, we don't see ourselves being left behind. We think we've got a very strong wealth business, actually. When you look at the BT business and you add in the St.George wealth business, the Asgard business and the Securitor distribution with that, it's a very strong overall position we have. As you heard me indicate, we're number one in the platform space overall and we're punching above our weight and gathering in one of every $3 into platforms. What we're doing remarkably well actually is the cross-sell elements of our wealth business &#x2013; our wealth product into our distribution. And if you look at both insurance and Super for Life, those both have been outstanding successes for us through our Westpac distribution force. And we're implementing that now safely over the next year within the St.George distribution network. So lots of future upside for us across our 10 million customer base to use the strong wealth products and platforms that we have with our own customers. So that's our first immediate priority.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We might take a call from Stewart Oldfield [Baillieu Stockbroking Ltd.], please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day everyone. Gail just on your desire to grow faster than system this year, you added 400 customer-facing staff in the past. Are you going to go very aggressively on that front again this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we've been Stewart is actually strengthening our distribution. That was a very important strategic plank for us that we called out last year was to empower and strengthen our distribution. And we recognized in Westpac in particular that distribution had been underdone over prior year. So it was quite important for us to in fact focus on that. We have a new model in place that we're busy steadily implementing. That involves new bank managers, it involves new business managers, it involves running it as a business. That's what our bank manager initiative is actually all about. So &#x2013; but that's about earning all of our customers' business. It's not about growth per se. It's actually about understanding our customers, meeting all of their needs and through referrals and advocacy, getting new customers come on board that could meet all their need. We are not a single product shop, we're a relationship business. So that's the kind of strategy and approach that we're following.</p>
          <p>Certainly we would expect to grow above system growth in mortgages again. We would expect mortgage growth for this current coming year to be being perhaps a little more than the year that we've come through. Perhaps about 8.5, I'm looking at Bill Evans in the audience here, 8.5 will that do, Bill? About 8.5% system growth for mortgages. This past year it was around 7.5 or eight. So we'd &#x2013; but we'd expect to grow a little above system growth there. But on the business side of course we're expecting negative growth. So overall credit growth will be much more modest of the three, perhaps increasing a little over the balance the back end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you very much everyone. I've got a couple of more questions. I've got to follow-up but &#x2013; on the phone but &#x2013; and I thanks for your patients. And myself and the team will be around all today to respond to any of those, and good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>