<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1530082" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2013 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-02-13</date>
    <companies>
      <company>10148</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer, Non-Independent Executive Director &amp; MD">Richard J. B. Goyder</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Managing Director, Coles Group Ltd.">Ian McLeod</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Managing Director, Home Improvement and Office Supplies">John C. Gillam</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Managing Director, Target">Dene Rogers</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Managing Director, Kmart Australia Pty Ltd.">Guy Russo</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Managing Director, Wesfarmers General Insurance Ltd.">Robert Scott</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep" affiliation="Managing Director, Wesfarmers Resources Pty Ltd.">Stewart Butel</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep" affiliation="Managing Director, Wesfarmers Chemicals, Energy &amp; Fertilisers Ltd.">Tom O&#x2019;Leary</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep" affiliation="Managing Director, Wesfarmers Industrial &amp; Safety NZ Ltd.">Olivier Chretien</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep" affiliation="Non-Independent Executive Director">Terry J. Bowen</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley (Australia) Ltd.">Thomas Kierath</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities Australia Ltd.">Ben Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Commonwealth Securities Ltd.">Andrew McLennan</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Shaun Cousins</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch Equities (Australia) Ltd.">David Errington</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Australia Pty Ltd.">Craig Woolford</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="CIMB Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Daniel Broeren</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs (Australia) Pty Ltd.">Phillip Kimber</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="CLSA Australia Pty Ltd.">David Thomas</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Australia)">Michael Simotas</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Australia Ltd.">David Cooke</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="corprep" affiliation="Analyst, Macquarie Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Greg Dring</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for holding, and welcome to the Wesfarmers 2013 Half Year Results Briefing. Your lines will be muted during the briefing. However, you will have an opportunity to ask questions immediately afterwards and instructions will be provided on how to do this at that time. This call is also being webcast live on the Wesfarmers' website and can be accessed from the homepage of wesfarmers.com.au.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand the call over to the Managing Director of Wesfarmers Limited, Mr. Richard Goyder.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, and welcome to the Wesfarmers 2013 half year results briefing. The usual format, I'll commence by covering the Group's performance highlights and that'll be followed by the Group divisional managing directors, who'll each provide a performance summary and outlook for their respective divisions. And then, Terry Bowen, our Finance Director will provide commentary on the performance of our other businesses and capital management, then I'll conclude in providing a brief comment on outlook for the Group. And there'll be plenty of time for questions at the end of the formal part of the presentation.</p>
          <p>So If I can move you to slide four. Overall, we're very satisfied with the performance of the Group in the first half, and as you all would have seen, net profit after tax was up 9.3% to $1.285 billion, driven by good revenue growth of 3.2% and continuous improvements in operational efficiency and the execution of our divisional strategies, solid operating cash flows of just over $2.2 billion, reflecting the cash generative nature of our businesses and a continued focus on working capital management.</p>
          <p>Gross capital expenditure for the group was just over $1.3 billion, 7.4% or $105 million below the prior corresponding period with net capital expenditure down 11% to $1.12 billion, supported by disposals of the group's trading retail freehold property, which accelerated during the half.</p>
          <p>Free cash flows for the half decreased 13.9% to just over $1 billion, but if you exclude the cash prices associated with the sale of the Premier Coal mine and the engine businesses that we recorded this time last year, underlying free cash flows increased to a pleasing 30.4%. And the Board today declared a fully-franked interim dividend of $0.77 per share up 10%, sorry, $0.07 and 10%.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide five, during the half strong retail earnings growth in Coles, Bunnings and Kmart together with a turnaround in the insurance division's performance more than offset reduced earnings in Target and the Resources division.</p>
          <p>Coles delivered strong earnings growth of 15.1% to $755 million, three times the rate of revenue growth and building on the earnings growth of 14.1% achieved in the prior corresponding period. Good progress was made in continuing to improve the quality, value and service that Coles  offer, resulting in further solid growth in customer transactions and above market sales performance. I think its 17 consecutive quarters now of positive comparative sales growth and 14 consecutive quarters of above market growth.</p>
          <p>Bunnings achieved a solid result with earnings up 6.8% on the prior corresponding period to $518 million, with Bunnings strategic agenda continuing to deliver good growth in consumer and commercial customer segments, sales increasing across all key product categories in trading regions.</p>
          <p>Kmart recorded very strong earnings growth of 24.9% to $246 million. Customers continue to respond positively to Kmart's strategy providing the lowest prices on everyday items for families. Target reported earnings of $148 million, 20.4% below the prior corresponding period.</p>
          <p>From a trading perspective, early progress in implementing Target's transformation plan was encouraging, with sales momentum improving through the half and a positive customer response received on a number of new initiatives aimed at strengthening Target's offer. However, significant additional expenditure on repositioning Target's strategy, management resources and customer offering was incurred during the half.</p>
          <p>Earnings growth of 11.8% to $38 million was achieved by Officeworks, with improved cost control and strong growth in online sales offsetting ongoing deflation in technology related categories and challenging sales conditions in the small to medium sized business customer segment.</p>
          <p>The Resources division reported earnings of $93 million, 62.8% below the corresponding period's earnings of $250 million , due to lower export coal prices, a strong Australian dollar and the lagged effect of the Stanwell rebate. In a difficult trading environment, strong cost control was achieved at both the Curragh and Bengalla mines.</p>
          <p>The Insurance division recorded earnings of $104 million, $87 million above the prior corresponding period. Earnings improved mainly through better underwriting performance, which was driven by higher premiums and a reduction in claims, including catastrophe costs. Growth in broking earnings was solid.</p>
          <p>The Chemicals, Energy and Fertilisers division reported earnings of $104 million, up 5.1% on the first half last year. Higher chemicals earnings were achieved due to good plant performances and improved pricing, but were partially offset by a lower contribution from Kleenheat Gas and the fertiliser business.</p>
          <p>Earnings for the Industrial and Safety division were $88 million, 9.3% below the prior corresponding period, mainly due to lower sales and increased margin pressure, particularly from our customers in the resources industry as they focused on cost reduction intensified through the half, and Terry will talk about the other businesses later.</p>
          <p>And briefly on slide six, you will note down at the bottom, we continue to improve their return on equity although I'd add we still have a way to go to get it where we'd like to.</p>
          <p>On slide seven, the divisional earnings, the managing directors will later talk more to their respective earnings outcomes of their presentations, although I would like to note in Rob Scott's final presentation as CEO of the Insurance division, that our share of divisional earnings from Insurance has escalated from 1% to 5% for the half, well done Rob and the insurance team.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide eight in terms of return on capital, we maintain a very strong focus on return on capital throughout the group. Pleasingly, return on capital for calls increased by 100 basis points to 9.2% and Kmart's strong improvement in return on capital to 22.5% reflects the benefits of reduced markdown activity, and a strong focus on cost efficiency and working capital management.</p>
          <p>The difficult market conditions in the Resource Division and additional expenditure incurred repositioning Target strategy affected returns through those divisions. At Bunnings, the key growth platform remains the investment in the store network, which has included an opportunity in recent years to invest in property assets given the recent property development environment. Disposal of the freehold property accelerated during the half reflecting Bunnings and the group's ongoing focus on driving an appropriate return on capital, and John Gillam will touch more on this later.</p>
          <p>I won't spend much time on the strategic growth initiatives on slides nine and ten because each of the managing directors will talk to their respective initiatives. At a group level, we will continue to manage the portfolio to deliver satisfactory returns to shareholders, improved capital efficiency, we will maintain a strong balance sheet and access to capital and most importantly we will leverage and build our human resource capability.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll hand over to Ian McLeod  to talk on Coles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Richard. I believe these first half results demonstrate the Coles' turnaround momentum has been maintained during its fifth year. The work just <mark type="indiscernible" /> (8:10) to established in either one, it's now clearly embedded within our business as we focus on utilizing internal efficiencies and volume growth to fund further value in Coles investment for the benefit of our <mark type="indiscernible" /> (8:19) customers.</p>
          <p>We've established a much stronger platform for Coles than the one we inherited to be the first to recognize the opportunity exist to achieve more, and I'll turn to slide 12.</p>
          <p>Coles revenue for the first half of the year increased by 4.8% to $18 billion, $800 million more than the same period last year. Earnings before interest and tax increased more than three times faster than revenue, up 15% on the prior comparable period of $755 million.</p>
          <p>Our Food and Liquor business has grown strongly and profitably with sales revenue up almost $700 million to over $14 billion, and EBIT increased to $677 million. a margin increase of 40 basis points from the prior year. Comparable store sales grew 3.8% in the half and while easing of produce deflation and had to bearing on deflation overall, underlying volumes in all our categories remained as strong as previous periods.</p>
          <p>Our Convenience business, Coles Express, performed well during the half with revenue growth of 4.2% and EBIT growth of 20%. This result was primarily driven by strong growth in fuel volume as customers took advantage of premium fuels, and investment in discounted fuel offers.</p>
          <p>I'll turn to slide 13, on the strength of the turnaround over the last four years. Over the last four years, our sales have consistently grown faster than the market. This has been driven by existing customers spending more, new customers steadily increasing and the growing proportion of fresh food sales within the basket. Our profit growth has consistently outperformed our sales growth demonstrating the significant progress we've made in improving efficiencies through our business to reduce our overall cost base.</p>
          <p>The changes I have made to drive growth in customer numbers and customer baskets have been successful, but with the recognition of our need to improve returns to shareholders also. Our return on capital has improved by 100 basis points against the prior comparable period.</p>
          <p>I now look at our strategy implementation in slide 14. The final phase of the initial turnaround farmers is aimed to firmly embed Coles as a strongly competitive business once more. Development of in-depth people capability has been critical at all levels of management as well as developing career paths in stores through our retail leaders program.</p>
          <p>Stronger offers, longer term Down Down price reductions and a reinvigorated loyalty program of all combined to improve customer trust and Coles' value. Private label <mark type="ph" /> cost (10:25) has been radically improved with innovation driving over 1,000 new products last year.</p>
          <p>Our distribution network has also contributed to our value investment through various cost saving initiatives including DC consolidation, transport load optimization and better workload planning and stock management. From a network perspective, we have and we'll continue to place greater emphasis on the quality of new space rather than the quantity of new stores.</p>
          <p>Coles made the mistake previously of placing too much effort into opening new stores in poor locations. Those mistakes will not be repeated. We're also very encouraged by our progress on multichannel initiatives, and the early growth we're making in financial services.</p>
          <p>I'll now comment on the key strategies in more detail starting with value, quality and innovation on slide 15. Our stronger push to invest in value and drive prices down this year began three years ago with the introduction of state-based wide pricing for our grocery and dairy lines.</p>
          <p>This has remained in force and continues to drive significant benefits to our customers, particularly those in regional and rural Australia. Our investment in everyday low prices through the Down Down campaign has been running for over two years now, and will continue to be part of our value investment strategy.</p>
          <p>Our ownership of FlyBuys has enabled us to develop targeted customer base to provide offers of specific appeal. Such targeted offers are very much a complement to existing offers which are open to all customers. Our intention is not to restrict value offers to only a chosen few.</p>
          <p>Investments such as these has driven prices down in Australia after <mark type="ph" /> 45 (11:42) years of food price inflation. Our efforts have enabled our customers to save well over $1 billion in the last 12 months. The effort we have made to improve fresh quality of stores and shorten the supply chain is</p>
          <p>paying dividends with continued growth and fresh food participation of the Coles basket.</p>
          <p>Customers have responded very well to our animal welfare programs where hormone-free beef, sow stall free pork, free range egg pricing, sustainable seafood, and so on.</p>
          <p>Initiatives such as these require strong collaborative relations with our suppliers, something we are committed to for both the benefit of our farmers and also the benefit of our customers, who are experiencing better quality and are buying more as a result.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn to our internal efficiency program on slide 16. Our ability to lower prices and grow profit ahead of sales has been possible through significant efforts to improve productivity and generate savings in all parts of our business. As an example, we consolidated the operations of one of our Queensland DCs, not only have we significantly improved cost for cotton, but has also provided greater visibility of stock flow and product quality.</p>
          <p>Our plans to improve the control and visibility of our transport network are also progressing well, we've entered into more open collaborative relationships with supply partners, which affords us greater control and targeted efficiency, but we know there is still opportunity for further improvement.</p>
          <p>Efficiencies in our stores also continue to improve as we further invest in the use of technology and enhanced training. We've added a further 826 sales <mark type="indiscernible" /> (12:54) in the half for example taking the total to over 3700 units in 570 stores to reduce queues for our customers.</p>
          <p>We have also begun trials of extending the use of our automated easy ordering system to fresh categories. It's still relatively early, but results have been encouraging to-date and we are aiming for broader roll out later on this year.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn to slide 17 to discuss how we're growing our network and trying new formats for future growth. Our network strategy is very much focused on optimizing space quality over store quantity. In the last four years or so, we've opened 98 stores and also closed or transferred 94 suboptimal outlets, growing that space by almost 6%, significantly improving the quality of our estate in the process.</p>
          <p>In the last 12 months, we further increased net space by 1.8%, which includes a space rationalization in each of the two oversized pick and pay stores in Queensland. Redundant space is now being converted into two new Kmart stores, giving us the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (13:45) for which I'm sure he'll express gratitude in a moment.</p>
          <p>We continue to experiment the formats for the future with a CBD convenient store now opened in Perth and a remodel of <mark type="ph" /> Southlands (13:28) in Melbourne for a new food service superstore. The <mark type="ph" /> core annual (13:33) program continued unabated with 48 new stores <mark type="ph" /> are renewed in the past (13:39). As I touched on earlier, we have made encouraging progress with many of our multichannel plans. Our online businesses continue to grow and our investment in the re-platform the <mark type="ph" /> legacy Coles (13:42) online system is tracking according to plan also.</p>
          <p>Our Coles Magazine app for iPod users have been welcomed by customers and recognized by Apple as one of the best apps in 2012. As mentioned previously, FlyBuys is innovating the way customers interact with Coles and drive value. As such, over half of our sales are with FlyBuys members now. Our financial services business is going well, increasing market share in both insurance and credit cards. Trials of payment using near field communication, technology and mobile devices are also underway, which is, as far as I know, with a global faster supermarket retailer.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn to slide 17 to discuss the improved Coles liquor performance, I've been particularly encouraged by our improved our liquor business throughout the half. While liquor remained a drag on total food and liquor sales growth, profitability in liquor improved significantly in the prior comparable period.</p>
          <p>The liquor sales impact lessened over the course of the half, as we'd expect that trend to continue as we <mark type="ph" /> circle (14:34) the cessation of both beer sales in the second half of the year. Better performance has been driven by new store openings, a more profitable sales mix and a better customer communication. We opened six new 1st Choice Liquor Stores and 20 collocated Liquorland stores. These have included trial formats for both brands with encouraging early results. We expect to cycle the cessation of both beer sales during the second half and see the sales growth drag diminish.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn to slide 19 to look at the ongoing success of our fuel strategy. Due to strong focus on core product and tight control of costs, our convenience business performed well. Our customers responded well to our premium fuel and diesel offers and the double fuel discount offer which ran for most of the half. However, we do recognize the need to improve the performance of our shop sales, which have suffered mainly as a result of category declines in areas such as tobacco and prepaid mobile top ups. Shop sales are being supplemented now by a broader level of impulse promotional offers, as well as aligning pricing in key supermarket Down Down lines such as bread and milk.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn to the outlook on slide 20. Our focus for the rest of this financial year is to ensure that we successfully complete the final phase of the turnaround, and build a solid foundation for the second phase of Coles transformation. Investing in truly better value will remain a major platform on our growth aspirations, delivering better value and involve a multi-pronged approach through strong promotions, everyday low prices and targeted offers through our various channels.</p>
          <p>We'll also extend our loyalty programs and continue to right size ranges in our stores to ensure we best meet customer needs. Improving the quality of products will strengthen our relationships with suppliers. Greater collaboration will foster opportunities for innovation as well as shared investment in new categories and products. We anticipate 2% net space growth per annum and our renewal program will continue at pace.</p>
          <p>In order to invest in these strategies and reward our shareholders, even greater focus is needed on delivering sustainable productivity savings at the center in our stores and throughout the supply chain. In short, we believe great progress has been made to-date, for which I'm enormously grateful to my 100,000 team members at Coles for their significant effort. But we are also the first to appreciate that much opportunity remains. I'll now hand over to John Gillam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ian, good afternoon, all. I'll start with Bunnings and if you skip through a couple of slides, we'll start at slide 23. The Bunnings performance in the first half was good across three levels. Firstly, there is solid momentum in the business that stems from our strategic agenda. Secondly, we made decent progress on our longer term growth plans. And thirdly, our day-to-day trading and financial results were pleasing.</p>
          <p>Healthy revenue growth of 5.8% underpinned good earnings growth of 6.8%. Return on capital at 25.5% remains industry leading. Included in the supplementary pack at slide 11 is a 10 year view of our ROC performance, where you can see the relativity of current return levels and our track record of investing successfully for long-term growth.</p>
          <p>Our plans show ROC lifting in the next 12 to 18 months as we convert land into trading stores and we recycle property capital. Our trading margin of 12.8% was in line with the levels we achieved two years ago at the half year and the positive trend in our safety measure reflects a much better safety performance across the past eight or nine months.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 24, there are a number of highlights in the half. We have a multi-pronged growth focus with strong efforts aimed at improving the customer offer in value, services and merchandising. Customer feedback and research shows healthy responses to all aspects of the improvements we've continued to make. It was terrific to achieve a new record sales day during Christmas trading.</p>
          <p>Looking at the performance across the half, the lift in both volumes and in the underlying customer participation rate demonstrates the positive responses we are seeing from customers. We achieved growth in every key trading region, in all key product categories and in consumer and commercial segments. The range reset project benefits for customers, suppliers and our business assisted these outcomes.</p>
          <p>Operational execution of service initiatives in store was also a highlight. Network development activity continued, this work expands our reach and reinvests to refresh existing stores. Progress made in both near term outcomes and longer term positioning reflects the high levels of capital invested since 2008. In the half just gone, CapEx was $350 million and around 85% of that level was invest into network development work with 15 locations opening. The longer term property pipeline now sits at just above 90 sites and the depth and site quality is reflected of terrific work from our property team.</p>
          <p>Finally, important internal initiatives that provide fresh productivity gains in areas like stock flow and other core prices has continued  in the half to good effect with more gains that are anticipated. In terms of outlook, slide 25, we anticipate further uplift in both consumer and commercial volumes driven by our multipronged growth focus. Current work plans being executed by our operational merchandising and commercial teams are getting good traction. Other way to sustain high levels of both team engagement and retention is also providing additional drive.</p>
          <p>Weakness in the property market following the GFC gave us a real opportunity to build a very strong pipeline of new stores. As a result, since 2008 we have invested at significantly higher levels in network development than in prior years.</p>
          <p>Across the next three financial years, the rate at which we convert that investment into trading stores will increase. We have for many years provided a forecast of new warehouse store openings in the range of 10 to 14 per annum and we've consistently delivered on that forecast. We expect to materially exceed that guidance in each of the next three financial years as the strong property <mark type="ph" /> part (19:58) volume we have established is developed into new Bunnings warehouses. In summary, Bunnings today is well positioned to continue to perform in a robust manner.</p>
          <p>Turning now to Officeworks and I'm on slide 26, trading revenue for the half just exceeded the same period last year at the headline level, but that top-line result belies the underlying story. Good progress in key areas resulted in earnings growth of 11.8%, and pleasingly EBIT margin continued to improve as did return on capital and safety performance.</p>
          <p>Macro trading conditions have not been easy, particularly for the medium and smaller business sector that is so important for Officeworks. And against that backdrop the positive results are very pleasing.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 27, there were a number of highlights. Officeworks has established a terrific fully integrated offer across every channel, stores, online and direct. Leveraging that every channel positioning has provided a platform for improved performance. Annualized online sales now sit at around $180 million.</p>
          <p>Customers have enjoyed good merchandising and service initiatives. Strong growth in customer transactions was a highlight for the half, as was the good progress made in the business sector. Internal work enhancing productivity and maintaining cost disciplines more than offset the adverse impacts of deflation, particularly in tech and supported earnings growth. During the half, nine new Officeworks stores were opened and reinvestment in existing stores continued.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 28, the outlook for Officeworks is for modest top-line growth in the remainder of 2012-2013 with pressures on sales and margins expected to continue. Mark Ward and the Officeworks team are focused on continuing to invest in a fully integrated offer across every channel. This will leverage ongoing good merchandising value and service benefits for consumer and business customers alike.</p>
          <p>Earnings growth and higher returns are expected through good execution of this agenda. And just  a final aside, the Officeworks full year result is heavily skewed towards good performance across the second half. January saw a pleasing start to the second half from back-to-school trading including a new record sales day, which was a real credit to the Officeworks team.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand over to Dene.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much, John. Good morning everybody. Starting at slide 30, Target's EBIT was $30 million lower than first half of fiscal 2012. This lower EBIT is the result of one-off transformation expenses which I'll speak about in a minute. It's important to state that the underlying trading performance was solid. The comparable same-store sales trend improved versus half one of fiscal 2012 to negative 1.8% from negative 3.5%. As you know, the mid-year toy sales normally run in the first half of financial year was moved to half two of fiscal 2012.</p>
          <p>Ife half one fiscal 2013 sales are adjusted to the toy sales shift, the same-store comparable sales would have been positive for the half. In addition, both customer accounts and the number of items sold increased in this half, even without adjusting to mid-year toy sale having being moved.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 31, the margin also improved in this half from increased direct sourcing, a higher regular balance of sale, and selling less product below cost and having greater control of clearance</p>
          <p>product. The cost of doing business, the expenses were higher in this half by tens of millions of dollars. These one-off expenses related to the full year transformation. The transformation related expenses caused the EBIT to be less than the prior year and were necessary to progress the transformation.</p>
          <p>The one-off transformation expenses were related to upgrading the online platform and operating systems, conducting pilots in womens, intimates, shoes, kids and home, to test how to manifest the core target strategy, quality plus fashionability plus experience equals value and become Australia's leading mid-tier retailer. Inventory levels were also higher in the half, in order to increase in stock levels in advance of the supply chain being transformed from a push system to a pull replenishment system.</p>
          <p>I'd like to give a brief update on the full year transformation. Firstly, the mid-tier to complement Kmart's position and successes. Successful pilots conducting in women's, Internet, women's shoes, intimates, kids and home. These learnings will be implemented in half through fiscal 2013 and fiscal 2014.</p>
          <p>We've kind of tested a shift to a higher regular balance of sale, a more mid-tier store experience and marketing that focuses on the products versus the promotional depth or price. Significant growth in Target essentials, which have a quality price position above the deep discount stores and represents Target's opening price points. The Designer for Target programs, which sell high priced fashions were successful. These programs included Collette Dinnigan, Roberto Cavalli and Ksubi. The current priority is for ladies wear.</p>
          <p>Speaking briefly about online, the number of SKUs online increased significantly to 54,000 by the end of the half. A new platform and operating system was installed and performed flawlessly during the peak Christmas period. Sales growth online continues to be strong, as is the profitability improvement. In the half, a net of seven new stores were opened. And speaking briefly about supply chain, a comprehensive three year transformation plan is being created to transform the current push system with a limited ability to replenish, to a pull system with shorter lead times and majority of SKUs being replenished based on sales. The end goal is 60% of SKUs with short lead time being replenished.</p>
          <p>Touching briefly on direct sourcing, the plan to convert product purchases from importing by importers to direct importing is underway with good progress. And then finally, the fifth activity related to transformation, organizational capability.  Eight new general managers have been appointed in the half. These are mix of Australian, North American and European leaders.</p>
          <p>The capabilities and resources of various teams are being progressively improved and new capabilities are being added to the organization. This include a project management office, finance online teams, social media and marketing, customer insights and sourcing resources.</p>
          <p>And then finally turning to slide 32, the outlook. A focus on expenses is the priority for half two of 2013. The one-off transformation expenses experienced in half one have been reduced significantly. Project management office and dedicated transformation teams have replaced the external consultants used in half one. An update of the transformation rates expenses will be given later in half two at the Investor Day.</p>
          <p>Rollout of the learnings of the successful kids, shoes and home products will occur in calendar 2013. And also, a continued priority on the gross margin improvement will remain. This means a shift to a higher regular balance of sale and a focus on marketing the product qualities versus the price, better <mark type="ph" /> controller clearance product (26:56) outcomes and direct sourcing.</p>
          <p>In closing, as always, our  primary goal is to win the shopping choice of our customer and become the leading mid-tier retailer in Australia.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand over to Guy Russo of Kmart. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dene, and also I want to acknowledge my big brother at Coles for acknowledging us. I'd now like to run through the Kmart performance for the half and also provide you some insight into our current journey moving to slide 34.</p>
          <p>Kmart's revenue for the half was $2.3 billion, total sales growth was 3.5% and comparable store sales increased by 3%. EBIT grew to $246 million, which was an increase of $49 million or just under 25% for the prior period &#x2013; prior year. This represented an EBIT margin of 10.7%, an increase of 190 basis points above last year. Our return on capital of 22.5% was up 650 basis points also on last year. Our rolling 12-month safety record was unfortunately slightly higher than last year and continues to remain a focus for the business.</p>
          <p>Turning to page 35, I will go through a number of our highlights. We've now achieved 12 consecutive quarters of growth in customer transactions and units sold, which tell us that our vision where families come first for the lowest prices on everyday items continues to resonate very well with Australian and New Zealand families.</p>
          <p>A strong performance of our everyday core ranges, as well as a strong seasonal trade with less markdown activity, has contributed to the earnings growth for the half. Improvements in sourcing also continues to provide benefits to the business. Inventory management has remained a focus and has contributed to a strong cash position. Our investment in the network has also continued, with six new Kmart stores opened in the half, six stores were refurbished and four new Kmart Tyre &amp; Auto services were opened.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 36, our outlook, we see the next phase of transitioning to growth as comprising the following key elements and these will be our focus moving forward. There are to be a volume retailer, to drive operational excellence, to create adaptable stores, and most importantly, to have a high performance culture. And we will always continue to focus on team safety and invest in our store network. The key to each and every decision we make is to ensure we link back to our vision and the simplicity of it. This has been critical to our success to-date and will be vital as we grow the business going forward. Kmart remains committed to providing Australian and New Zealand families with everyday products at the lowest prices.</p>
          <p>Thank you, and I'll now like to hand over to Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Guy. I'll start with slide 38. Revenues for the half increased by 9.5% to just over $1 billion. JWP increased by 8.7% in underwriting and broking revenue grew by 10.2%. We reported a record first half EBIT of $104 million at an EBIT margin of 10%. The growth in earnings was predominantly driven by improvements in underwriting performance. On a rolling 12 basis, our return on capital increased to 13.3%, and this is after adjusting for the increase in Earthquake reserves in June last year.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the highlights on page 39. The improvements in underwriting performance reflect the benefits associated with better risk pricing, premium rate increases, exposure management and claims efficiencies. Loss ratios have improved across most portfolios, with the exception of our runoff portfolio in builders warranty. Whilst the half was absent to any material catastrophe event, there were various storms in the region of Western Australia, New South Wales and Queensland which resulted in claims in line with our internal allowances.</p>
          <p>We have been pleased with the growth in personal lines, particularly through Coles insurance where many drivers aged 30 years and above have achieved significant savings on their car insurance, backed by an Australian insurer with 90 years of experience. Many customers are choosing to transact with us online, so we continue to invest in our market leading online capabilities to improve user experience.</p>
          <p>Broking operations continued to deliver earnings growth and we achieved 8.6% EBIT growth for the half. As signaled last year, the implementation of a new IT system in New Zealand, and recent acquisition integration costs have resulted in a slight decrease to margin. Earlier this month, our new CEO of OAMPS Australia, Mike Cutter, joined us in the business and we welcome Mike to the Group.</p>
          <p>The settlement of claims associated with New Zealand earthquake continue to be challenging, however we've made good progress for the half, having settled 70% of commercial clients and over 30% of our domestic clients. And there was no change to our earthquake reserves as at the December 31.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the outlook. We expect to see further improvements in underwriting performance as a result of our commitment to underwriting discipline, exposure management and cost containment. Further growth in broking earnings is anticipated however the SME sector does remain challenging. The extreme weather events associated with Cyclone Oswald and bush fires during January will result in claims for us in the order of $30 million and $10 million, respectively. Although these events will have an impact on earnings in the second half, the level of claims reflect the improved risk selection and exposure management efforts, particularly in Northern Australia, that we've undertaken in recently years.</p>
          <p>The second half of the financial year tends to have higher weather related claims and after the events of January, we would expect second half earnings to be below the level we achieved in the first half. However, we are pleased with the year-to-date performance and the earnings momentum within the business has enabled us to absorb the cost of recent catastrophe events.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, any further decreases in interest rates and material cat events between now and June represent a downside risk to full year earnings.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand over to Stewart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob, and good afternoon, everyone. I'll refer you to slide 42 titled Resources performance summary. Revenue at $826 million is 24% below last year, reflecting the tough operating conditions being experienced in the export coal marketplace. The major contributing factors to this reduction in revenue is significantly lower coal prices, average met coal prices are down 36%and thermal coal down 20%, plus continued high exchange rate offset by higher sales volumes following the completion of expansions at both the Curragh and Bengalla mines.</p>
          <p>Royalties for the half year at $148 million is slightly down on last year due to lower state government royalties. The Stanwell royalty remained high at $91 million for the half. Mining and other costs were significantly lower this half due to a major focus on cost reduction and control. More details on Curragh's cost reduction program is presented in slide 35 and 36 of the supplementary pack. Earnings before interest and tax at $93 million is 63% down on last year, reflecting the difficult market conditions being experienced.</p>
          <p>I'll now refer you to slide 43, Resources highlights. Following continued focus on safety performance, our lost time injury frequency rate continues to improve. As previously stated, export revenues have significantly declined during this period reflecting difficult trading conditions being experienced. However, on the positive side, coal production at both Curragh and Bengalla had increased markedly this half on the back of completion of mine expansions.</p>
          <p>At Curragh, we have implemented major operational changes in response to the current difficult market conditions. These changes include rationalization of contractors and supply usage and cost, a partial mine shutdown over the Christmas, New Year period and improvements in operational efficiencies and productivities.</p>
          <p>Mine cash costs have reduced by greater than 20% compared to this time last year. Mine costs are expected to reduce by a further 11% in H2, the second half of FY 2013, before rising slightly in FY 2014, following the depletion of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (35:35) events during FY 2013.</p>
          <p>I'll now refer you to slide 44 resources outlook. The export market continues to be impacted by global economic uncertainty resulting in variable metallurgical coal demand. We expect a continuation of difficult trading conditions, with low export coal prices and high exchange rates expected to continue during the second half of FY 2013.</p>
          <p>The outlook for FY 2013 is as follows. The aftermath of ex-cyclone Oswald has had a significant impact on Curragh's production and sales for this financial year. Coal production at the site was disrupted for approximately two to three days by wet weather associated with the ex-cyclone. The ship loading of Curragh coal at the Gladstone Port was interrupted for a total of 11 days with coal rail haulage initially cancelled for 13 days due to rail track damage, but extended last Friday for a further six days following a major derailment of a coal train between Rockhampton and Gladstone.</p>
          <p>As a result, Curragh's metallurgical sales volume is now forecast to be in the range of 7.5 to 8 million tonnes for financial year 2013, subject to no significant wet weather conditions and the satisfactory performance of rail and port operations post cyclone Oswald. Curragh will continue to focus on mine cost reductions and control. Stanwell royalties are expected to be in the range of $160 million to $170 million for the full year based on current exchange rates.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand it over to Tom O'Leary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Stewart. Looking now at Chemicals, Energy and Fertilisers performance summary on slide 46 and starting with safety performance at the foot of the slide. It's disappointing to report a slight increase in the Lost Time Injury Frequency Rate for the division despite the continued investment and efforts made during the year. As I've said previously, we continue our strong efforts to improve safety in the division and to find ways to ensure that safety is front of mind for our people at all times.</p>
          <p>As an example, in October last year, we launched a new division wide identity, safe person, safe process, safe place, through which we've consolidated all of that safety systems and processes under one common umbrella.</p>
          <p>Turning to financial performance, earnings for the half increased by 5% to $104 million compared to the previous corresponding period. This was despite flat revenue and lower external sales volumes. The improvement in underlying performance was driven by strong results from the Chemicals businesses, in particular those exposed to the Resources industry.</p>
          <p>In addition, our equity accounted earnings from the 50% interest in Queensland Nitrates were significantly higher than the previous corresponding period which included a major shutdown and some plant issues. As we equity account those earnings, we don't recognize any associated revenues. Hence there is no impact on the revenue line. So QNP's performance had a positive impact on the increase in EBIT margin.</p>
          <p>The rolling 12 month return on capital was 19.8%, an improvement on the 18% achieved at the same time last year. This includes the impact of the investment up to 31 December in the ammonium nitrate expansion in Kwinana of $190 million which has and will continue to place downward pressure on return on capital until the plan is commissioned in the first half of calendar 2014.</p>
          <p>Turning to highlights on the next slide, construction of the ammonium nitrate expansion is progressing well. All long lead time items have now been delivered to site and assembly at the major components is underway. The project remains on budget, and on schedule to be operational in the first half of calendar of 2014.</p>
          <p>At an operational level, our chemical business has benefited from good production performance over the period, and also strong pricing for ammonia, ammonium nitrate and sodium cyanide. Approval was also received from both Australian Gold Reagents venture partners to expand our sodium cyanide production capacity at Kwinana at a cost of $22 million. This project will see solution capacity increase from 64,000 to 78,000 tonnes per annum, and solid production capacity to increase from 34,000 to 45,000 tonnes per annum, and we expect it to be completed by the end of the 2013 calendar year.</p>
          <p>Economic conditions have remained challenging for the Australian Vinyls business during the period with the continuation of higher input costs exacerbated by a high average Australian dollar. In the Kleenheat business, LPG production was around 9% lower than the previous corresponding period because of further declines in the LPG content in the Dampier-Bunbury pipeline. As I've highlighted before, the LPG business continued to experience margin pressures and earnings overall lower compared to the previous corresponding period.</p>
          <p>Earnings from the fertiliser business were lower than the previous corresponding period as a result of a lighter and poorer harvest. The harvest was significantly lower than last season, and despite higher prices, farmers were generally worse off following this season's harvest. As a result we've experienced some delays in fertiliser purchasing for the upcoming season.</p>
          <p>Turning to outlook on slide 48, the two major expansion projects with ammonium nitrate and sodium cyanide will continue to be the key focus. Our business is exposed to the local resource sector excepted to benefit from continued strong demand. Over the remainder of the financial year, we have planned shutdowns in our sodium cyanide business that will moderately affect production volumes and therefore earnings. Our next planned ammonium nitrate plant shutdowns and they are expected to take place early next financial year.</p>
          <p>Our ammonia business will become increasingly dependent over the period on international ammonia pricing, as we experience a full period impact of the transition of existing supply agreements to import parity pricing, although ammonia pricing is expected to moderate somewhat over the second half.</p>
          <p>Kleenheat earnings are dependent on the outlook for international LPG pricing and we also expect to be challenged by poorer LPG content. The fertiliser business, as always, is dependent on the seasonal break in the second half as well as farmers' terms of trade.</p>
          <p>Thank you. And, I'll now hand over to Olivier Chretien.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tom, and good afternoon. I will now cover the Industrial and Safety division. As you can see on slide 50, the division's half year result was impacted by the market slowdown. Operating revenues were down 0.7% to $837 million. Earnings before interest and tax decreased to $88 million, a decrease of 9.3%, while maintaining a solid EBIT margin at 10.5%. Return on capital increased from 14.5% to 16.1%, and we had a relatively stable safety performance.</p>
          <p>Looking at some of the key highlights for the half on slide 51, the division was impacted by a slowdown in resources and constriction activity, with a higher customer focus on cost savings, also resulting in increased margin pressure. This was partially offset by strong customer retention and continued growth in Western Australia supported by large natural gas projects as well as in the Coregas, Bullivants and New Zealand businesses.</p>
          <p>Across the group, we continued to focus on strengthening our customer relationships with division-wide key account management and online capabilities. We also continued to improve our service and product offer, including a range of<mark type="indiscernible" /> (43:30) to better meet customer needs in a cost focused environment.</p>
          <p>Network and supply chain enhancements delivered a record solid performance while improving productivity. Our cost focus extended across all our businesses with implementation of number of efficiency measures during the half. Additionally, the division was restructured in October into three business streams across Australia and New Zealand. Generally, delivering a wide one-stop shop offer customers, safety specialist delivering safety solutions to protect people in the workplace and industrial specialists supporting specialized value propositions by a depth of expertise in specific technical areas. More details on each business stream are included in the supplementary pack.</p>
          <p>Finally, strong inventory management and targeted network investment contributed to our return on capital results.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to the outlook for the Industrial and Safety division on slide 52, business activity is expected to remain subdued and competitive for the remainder of the year. However, the division is well placed to respond to any earlier recovery. In the meantime, the business is focused on growing its share of customer spend by continuing to broaden its service offer, continuing to leverage its major project activities as a key platform for growth, particularly in WA, North Queensland, and the Northern Territory. And ongoing focus on industry and customer diversification and importantly further reducing of cost of doing business, driving productivity gains for greater use of technology including online channel.</p>
          <p>Finally, the division continues to be focused on developing new growth platforms including for acquisitions.</p>
          <p>Thank you. I will now hand over to Terry Bowen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Olivier. Good afternoon, everyone. I'll provide an overview of the group's other business results during the half as well as cover off on the balance sheet and capital management side of the group. Turning to slide 54, other businesses, non-trading items and corporate overheads reported an expense of $51 million. This compared to an expense of $84 million in the corresponding period.</p>
          <p>The result from associates was above that of last year recording a gain of $4 million in total, largely due to Wesfarmers share of loss recorded in Gresham Private Equity Funds reducing down to $11 million this half compared to $46 million the previous year. The downward revaluation largely is due again to mark-to-market revaluations of Fund II investments, but there was some activity as well as half in exiting some of the investments. This was offset by a $12 million gain recorded by the group's interest in BWP and earnings of $3 million recorded for Wespine.</p>
          <p>Interest revenue in the half of $5 million was down on last year and this reflects lower levels of cash on deposit across the half. We had no non-trading items this period relative to last period. And at the bottom of the table is other &#x2013; this typically includes the effects of foreign and the results of our group insurance program. It's worth noting that in January, we're likely to see an adverse impact of around $20 million in this area due to the effects of Cyclone Oswald and related flooding impacts of the cross-sale operations. Higher corporate costs risk recorded relative to last year and this reflects a bit of increased activity in some corporate areas as well as higher costs associated with share based payments.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 55 and operating cash flow of the group. It's important to note that operating cash flows at December are typically higher in this period due to the inventory buildup that goes on prior to the lead up to Christmas and then the subsequent timing of creditor payments, which typically appear in January in a number of divisions. So notwithstanding this, the cash realization ratio for the half of 121.5%, we continue to think is strong. The result included an increase in operating cash flows across most divisions, with the first half operating cash flow of $2.2 billion overall. Strong cash flow generation was supported by solid earnings growth and also some good working capital management continuing.</p>
          <p>Looking specifically on slide 56 at working capital, the net working capital decreased across the group was some $365 million for the half and this build on $256 million improvement achieved in the prior corresponding period. The result includes -- obviously by our mathematics -- a $545 million reduction in working capital across the retail portfolio, which reflected not only the seasonality that I've referred to, but a strong focus on inventory management and improved trading terms, particularly in Kmart.</p>
          <p>The solid retail business performance was offset by an increase in working capital for the group's industrial businesses of $180 million. This working capital outflows in the non-retail businesses were largely due to lower creditors in our Resources division and this follows the cost reduction initiatives that Stewart has referred to.</p>
          <p>There is further information on working capital and other areas of the balance sheet and movements on slides 51 and 52 of the supplementary pack number, and I'll refer you to that. Turning to capital expenditure on slide 57. In line with our retail strategy that's been spoken of today to actively manage freehold property, it's important that we do focus on net capital expenditure, which includes both the purchase and sale of property in any given period. Now over the half the group continued its strong capital investment phase, investing some $1.12 billion in net capital investment, this was our 11% below the prior corresponding period.</p>
          <p>Net investment in land and buildings in the period was $244 million and this again largely related to retail network expansions in Bunnings and Coles. It was $72 million lower again, <mark type="ph" /> higher (49:19) than the same period last year. In the result, this includes $203 million of cash proceeds from the disposal of property, and this is ahead of similar activity that we conducted this time last year and shows that acceleration and this again is mainly due to the sale and leaseback in this period activity by Bunnings.</p>
          <p>The group remains focused on the time we retail freehold property disposal to ensure that we enhance our return on capital position in all divisions and for the group as a whole. Retail investment also continued as our businesses improved their store networks and most significantly in the half was the continued Coles store renewal program, which included fitting out 11 new supermarkets in the period and 37 refurbishments during the half. Other significant capital investment included the expansion of ammonium nitrate at Kwinana, which Tom has referred to.  And as he said, this project is progressing well, currently on budget and remains forecast to be completed in line with prior guidance.</p>
          <p>Looking towards the 2013 whole financial year, we anticipate net capital expenditure of between $1.5 billion and $2 billion. And this is marginally below our prior guidance in August. But as always, this is dependent on freehold property activity, which can be quite volatile.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 58, the balance sheet remains in a very sound position, strong cash flows and ongoing improvements in our financing facilities resulted in further improvements in liquidity metrics with fixed charges cover in particular increasing to 2.9 times and cash interest cover increasing to 11.8 times. Reflective of this, Moody's Investor Services over the period upgraded Wesfarmers' issuer and senior unsecured long-term debt writing from Baa1 positive to an A3 stable outlook during the half. This is consistent now with the group's credit rating from Standard &amp; Poor's which remains unchanged at A minus stable.</p>
          <p>In regards to dividend, as Richard announced, as we have declared a dividend for this half of $0.77. This position considers the current liquidity position, our rating and through the cycle cash flows. As again, the dividend will be fully franked. The record date for the final dividend is February 25 and the dividend will be payable on March 28. In line with our recent practice, the group will continue to provide shareholders with the option to participate in the DIP or dividend investment plan. No discount will apply to the allocation cost and the program will not be underwritten.</p>
          <p>The required number of shares will be acquired on market, which will be consistent with recent years in neutralizing any dilutive effects of shares issued under the DIP. It's worth mentioning that we've had this, if you like, practice now for nearly four years which has meant that both employee share plans and for shares issued as part of the DIP effectively have been bought on market, which in form is we think a pretty effective form of capital management ongoing and again subject to the group's cash position and outlook.</p>
          <p>In November 2012, the Wesfarmers' Board elected to extend the lapse date associated with the Wesfarmers partially protected shares for a further period of 12 months. The lapse date is now the November 23 2013. The Board has the right to extend this lapse date for a further 12 months up to another two times subject to the terms and the conditions of those shares.</p>
          <p>Turning to the group's debt profile on slide 59. During the half the group issued its first 10 year bond and we raised &#x20AC;650 million and this is in line with our strategy to diversify and extend our debt maturity profile. As shown on slide 59, the group's debt profile is in we think a very good shape these days and average debt tenor of some 3.4 years. The achievement of a good staggering of maturities as seen on the bar chart to the left of this slide is reflective of a very low level of debt repayment now due in any one year. And the pie chart to the right indicates the broad diversification of our current sources of debt and shows that debt financing contributed by banks is now reduced to something like 25% of total debt facilities and on a drawn basis, typically much less than this.</p>
          <p>In relation to finance costs based decreased in the period to $229 million compared to $264 million in the first half of last year. The group's effective borrowing cost decreased 98 basis points to 7.05% for the half, and we expect to continue reduction in borrowing costs as a result of successful refinancing initiatives that we've completed over recent years. Obviously falling cash rates as well in the progressive expiry of pre-GFC interest rate hedges that the group had in place.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll now hand back over to Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Terry. Just before I go to outlook I understand that we lost some &#x2013; on the webcast we lost at least the detail of Dene and Guy, so I apologize for that. I think the call was fine, so we'll continue and we'll move to Q&amp;A in a second, but apologies for those of you on webcast for that technical difficulty. We'll try and find out what caused it and make sure it doesn't happen again.</p>
          <p>Turning to outlook for the group on slides 61 and 62, I'll be reasonably quick as most of the divisional managing directors have covered off on this. In relation to the retail portfolio, we expect earnings growth to be supported by continued investments in value, merchandising service, the store networks, our online channels, and productivity initiatives. It is worth noting that our annual online sales across the group until <mark type="ph" /> December 31, 2012 (55:15) were approximately $1 billion, so this is a channel where we are growing scale, to which we are applying a very strong focus.</p>
          <p>For Insurance, as Rob said, strong underwriting <mark type="ph" /> disciplines (55:30) with a focus on operation, efficiencies are expected to further improve our underwriting performance in the absence of a higher number of catastrophic events and obviously we don't want in that division interest rates to fall too much, although some of Rob's colleagues rather would be happy to see lot of interest rates.</p>
          <p>In the Resources division, we'll continue to be impacted by low export coal prices from the high Australian dollar. And so our focus will be very much on cost reductions, but over the long run, we continue to think that the export coal market fundamentals remain very, very sound.</p>
          <p>In Chemicals, Energy and Fertiliser, we expect solid demand for chemicals to be continually supported by group plant performance, although our outlook for Kleenheat gas remains challenging because of low LPG pipeline content. And in Industrial sector as Olivier has said, subdued demand and competitive market. Conditions are expected to continue in the near-term. But this division is very well placed to respond to any market recovery.</p>
          <p>As I said earlier, at a group level we continue to invest and strengthen our human resource capability and our balance sheet strength and improvements in capital efficiency for the group, the opportunity to invest. We continue to make a very strong focus on delivering satisfactory shareholder returns.</p>
          <p>We are always looking for opportunities to manage the portfolio for the long-term benefit of our shareholders.</p>
          <p>And now, we'll be happy to take any questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question today comes from the line of Tom Kierath from Morgan Stanley. Tom, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, afternoon. Just a question for Terry, can you just run through the impact of increasing discount rates and how that impacts on the different businesses. I think it was a headwind of about $100 million last year, but it could actually be a tailwind this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's virtually been no change in the government bond rates over this period. So it's been pretty stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And the second one is, on the CapEx, obviously there is not much CapEx coming through in the second half. Are you basically flagging here that there is a lot of property sales just around the corner?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I guess the range, I mean, what we've said is that we obviously focus on this area and work on it. The group, as the balance sheet shows, is under no desperation to complete if that turns out appropriate for us. So the wide guidance at the moment is really a &#x2013; if you like a view that obviously that gross CapEx side is it will continue in line with where we thought. But we could actually complete some reasonable sales in this period. But again, this is always open to negotiations at the time and making sure that again we get the right long-term outcome for the group</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question today comes from the line of Ben Gilbert from UBS. Ben, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, all. Just first question on Target, I'm just wondering if you could elaborate a little bit more just the magnitude of the costs that came through in the first half, because it seems, I mean, you said there's tens of millions, so it seems like a pretty large number. And on that just wondering, if there's any provisional related on that $40 million like in second half of last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And guys, just for everyone just that you know, Guy Russo's had to go and get on the airplane. So Ian Bailey, who's the Chief Operating Officer for Kmart, he's online and Ian will take any Kmart questions.  After you, Dene.</p>
          <p>`</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Ben, it's Dene. I won't add any more details to the statement I made during the presentation, which was we spent tens of millions of dollars and those were operating expenses. As you referred to, we had a provision of around $40 million at the end of fiscal 2012. And we drew down approximately 10% of that, and I would plan to update our transformation related expenses, and the use of that provision at the end of fiscal 2012 at the Investor Day later on in the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just one for Ian as well, I know you don't want to start disclosing gross margins across the same business, but just wondering if you could give us a little bit of color around what the driver of the 40 bps of margin expansion was? Sort of how much of it you saw in terms of gross margin for mix and liquor, and how much is around the cost curve for some of the benefits of easy ordering and is your warehousing coming though?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as far as <mark type="ph" /> EBIT (1:00:18), it's a combination of those factors. But a lot of what we've been doing is driving higher levels of improvements in productivity and efficiency, and lower our cost of doing business, and then a combination of that &#x2013; and investing back in prices is giving us an overall cash improvement. So that's really what we've been doing for the last four years and that's continuing. So I'm not prepared to break it down, but the underlying cost of the core objectives of how we're driving our business has continued.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the timing from the easy warehousing and easy ordering. Is that really starting to flow through now, should we see it accelerated, should we start to see refine that system and you said pushed into fresh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's been progressive over a period of time. We've just started to move into fresh. So it's going to take some time for that to work its way through, but obviously the benefits we've had of Ambient and we still got more to do in terms of healthy working capital there. But in terms of how the system operates and how it develops improvements in the stores, we want to see those benefits come through in fresh as well where we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question today comes from the line of Andrew McLennan from Commonwealth bank. Andrew, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. My first question is for Ian. The strategy of optimizing this existing capital base at Coles has been very well executed. We're now starting to see that same strategy being executed in Coles Express. We've done a very significant run around in terms of the stores around Sydney to see how you're executing and clearly is a very big push on improving your in-store offer of groceries, both in terms of offering and value. How far do you think you can push that? Obviously the UK gives a good guide as to what that convenience shall can effectively do. What constraints are you anticipating around this approach?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think if you look at the shop sales in convenience, we've seen them dip off in this reporting period. And much of that has been down to  a slowdown in tobacco sales and also on top ups for prepaid mobile phones. So that's really a function of the market as much as anything else. We therefore try to supplement that with looking at more focused way on how we can drive our incremental sales through a more effective grocery business and see what we can do in terms of improving <mark type="ph" /> our commercial (1:02:48) offer. So we've looked to more impulse promotions which you've commented on through grocery as one of the aspects of what we're looking at within our convenience business. And we'd expect to see similar things develop further forward as well.</p>
          <p>So that said, it's encouraging what we've seen coming through on that. I think that in terms of the overall convenience opportunity, it's obviously something that we're looking at. We've got a trial of a store in Melbourne, a standalone convenience store. We also got one, we opened in CBD in Perth. So we'll review it. I think that what's worth considering here in relation to how convenience works in Australia and how convenience works in the UK, I think you find that in terms of supermarket densities per head of population it's actually much higher here. So people will go great levels of susceptibility on their doorstep, particularly metropolitan areas in Australia. So whilst I think there is an opportunity, I wouldn't regard it as being a forefront priority that might have been in areas in the UK where large scale supermarkets opportunities are starting to decline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. And obviously liquor licensing is different between the two, of course. The second question just relates to the capital position, so possibly Terry. Clearly, there's a lot of capital, excess capital sitting on the balance sheet. Is it possible that we could see a special dividend coming at some stage? There's been a pretty significant rally in the share price and in the market as a whole, so that could potentially reduce some acquisition options?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I wouldn't necessarily be looking at debt-to-equity and where our group is concerned. I think we got a lot of off balance sheet leases, as you know. So fixed charges cover is the best, I think the best measure for the group. And that's running at about 2.9%, which is a reasonably kind of healthy A- rating and not too strong, not too weak.</p>
          <p>And so we're pretty comfortable with where the gearing of the group is at the moment. And then clearly another thing we do is our dividend payout ratio tends to be reasonably full at about &#x2013; on a full year basis, it's been up into the 80%s of net earnings. And so frank and credits is something that we do watch and try and get those back to shareholders as quickly as we can. I mean to the extent that we look forward and are gearing &#x2013; sorry, not gearing, our fixed charges cover starts to get, if it moves too strongly, than obviously we look at various initiatives that kind of keep the group leverage to the degree that we want. And that could involve all kinds of capital management options. But at the moment we think we're in pretty good shape.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, I'd like to just add. I think in many ways where the markets side irrelevant to how we look at opportunities for investment, because clearly when the market is higher, our currency is more valuable, if it's to be script element and that in some ways albeit, the increase in what might be P/E multiples ratifies. But you have to think about what we've done in terms of portfolio management over the last couple of decades really. A lot of it's been to do with discontinuities and us  and us being prepared to act when things like that have happen. And we've done very little in the way of sort of hostile acquisitions.</p>
          <p>So I would think that the likelihood of us doing something in M&amp;A is just as strong now as it was a year ago and two years ago and five years ago. And that's not saying anything. It's just saying that we'll look in the long run that whether we can think anything we do done in portfolio, whether it will be a good thing for our shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question today comes from the line of Shaun Cousins from JPMorgan. Shaun, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. Just a question for Terry. Could you just talk a bit about what drives the provision impact in terms of the difference between your cash and your impact this year. I think it was around $95 million in the first half of 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously part of its Target, but maybe how much of that was Resources as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you are talking operating &#x2013; is this impact to operating cash flows? Is that what you mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The major point I think, Shaun, at this time &#x2013; in the first half last year, we effectively had more tax paid by our installments the year before than we needed. So we got effectively last year a tax refund. And so if you look on the operating cash flow statement in the <mark type="ph" /> 4D (1:07:45), and particularly the reconciliation of net profit after-tax, the net cash flows from operations, which page 12 I think, you will see quite a big swing in current tax payable, which is kind of this year is $148 million outflow and last year it was a $2 million inflow in the same period. So just adjusting for that gets you pretty close to kind of 9% growth in operating cash flows.</p>
          <p>On top of that, when we make provisions for claims in insurance typically in the year when that first occurred you're making a provision that you don't have cash flows and then the claims subsequently comes. So if you look at other liabilities, there is a big swing there, which is effectively the insurance division. And then we've got provisions declining a little bit, and that's really just seasonality coming through a little bit versus June, certainly on <mark type="ph" /> long service and even you leave if taken (1:08:35) and we've also got the unwinding of the <mark type="ph" /> meter (1:08:41) contract. That's the mining, we just rolled that out, I think you'll see that in our cash flows is healthy</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so what was the day or the met contract this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For this half $37 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep. And for this question maybe for John in terms of Bunnings. In terms of the obviously, you're getting quite further into margin expansion and you've got a lot of initiatives that are coming through. How far through are you getting the benefits of range reset, has &#x2013; effectively has much of the good work there been sort of contributed to earnings already or is there more to come? And I guess how much further consolidated initiatives drive your earnings higher from a margin perspective, I guess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, answering the second part of your question first, Shaun. I have consistently said we don't model our net margins increasing. In fact, we model them declining modestly over time. So we don't look to drive that number higher through our growth initiatives. We look to drive returns. And we look to drive market share positions. So the net margin will be what it will be.</p>
          <p>In terms of range reset, we're through all of the execution work both from a merchandising perspective and operationally in store. And there was only a fraction left of operational execution in store in this half. So now, in this year, we'd expect to get a full run rate benefit of that. So there's a little bit to come in the second half, but we are very, very keen to make sure we keep rewarding customers with more and more value, so, and more and more service and service initiatives. So I will be choosy about where we use those benefits rather than just letting it flow through to the bottom line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And until you got a lot of stores that are opening up in terms of the next few years. How is that going to sort of weigh on in terms of store maturations sort of impacting your business as well in terms of will that be to any sort of drag either?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we are going to have a lot of stores open. And in the next three financial years, it looks like we'll be more than 25 Bunnings Warehouses next financial year opening. and around the same sort of number the year after and maybe 20ish in the third financial year out from now. Obviously, property and construction is also swings and rounds abouts, but that's sort of the best guidance I can give you. And that's kind of dragged down the average age of our fleet quite considerably because we might be slowing down on the refresh work we do in existing stores.</p>
          <p>And we're looking to see acceleration in what we can do in terms of network growth as a component of our multipronged. So maybe from sort of 2005, 2006 or maybe 2004, 2005 onwards, network growth became less than the biggest component and just become another component of growth. And that's going to poke up a bit hard in the next few years because of the number we're opening. But I wouldn't say that's going to really knock the other important avenues of growth we've got of their purchase. So what we can do with our merchandising initiatives and our service initiatives are going to be equally as strong, and that has us quite excited about where we see that this is going in the next few years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question today comes from the line of David Errington of Merrill Lynch. David, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, Terry, I'm a bit cheesed at the moment, because I'm going to have use one of my questions up for a clarification.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we'll give you two and a half then, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Richard that's excellent. Because I have no idea with regard to Ben's question regarding the Target transformation costs, because you got hit with $40 million at the second half of 2012, that is your EBIT line and that has increased transformation costs over and above that hitting this first half in the tens of millions of dollars. So it's got nothing to do with provision or FX or anything like that. It's that your transformation costs are actually blowing out. And I'm somewhat scratching my head as to why that might be. So that's sort of like &#x2013; that's the clarification I suppose to what's being asked.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hey David, it's Dene. So the provisions at the end of fiscal 2012 was to provide for the shutting down of offsite reserves and they are roughly 36 of those, plus a couple of other facilities as we transform the supply chain. So given that we had committed to shutting those sites down and yet we had a commitment to the future lease cost, which would extend beyond the use of those facilities, we took that provision. So that's what that provision is for and consistent with good accounting principles.</p>
          <p>The increased operating expenses that I referred to in the presentation of tens of millions, was to accelerate the transformation as well as spend money on some needed areas. So in my presentation I referred to upgrading online platform and systems, some of the pilots that we have conducted which we'll roll out. I think more importantly going forward, we have been able to reduce that depends on those one-off transformation costs. So throughout the last half, we engaged management consultants, for example, we've been able to transition those expenses to a project management office and dedicated teams that work on specific transformation activities, reducing the cost quite significantly.</p>
          <p>We expect that our online platform will service well and to grow to sales of around $400 million and a lot of the pilot tests that we do in home, kids shoes, relied upon additional marketing expenses to payroll and logistical expenses, and I think after showing through those pilots how to conduct those processes that marketing means to experience it differently, we won't be incurring same elevated level of cost related to those pilots going forward.</p>
          <p>So as I mentioned, what we will do at the Investor Day later on in the year is give you an update of both the operating expenses related to transformation as well as the use of the provision at the end of fiscal 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks guys. Thanks, Dene. Second one, Richard, is with regard to the coal business and particularly Stewart's statement that <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:15:44) costs for the first half were 20% lower. Now, I can't reconcile that because when you go to the supplementary statement, I think it's got slide 34, but I think you might refer it to as 35, but when you actually look at the Resources financial statement, costs actually &#x2013; you refer to the $602 million compared to the $517 million, but that's misleading because in that $602 million, there is $84 million of costs that reflected traded coal costs and also if you &#x2013; in the other costs in the second half of 2011, you've also got Premier's costs. Now on my reconciliation, I know that Bengalla's increased by about 0.5 million tonnes, but Premier produced 1.7 million tonnes &#x2013; 1.75 million tonnes this time last year. And the cost of that mine is probably about $80 million of costs and the extra Bengalla costs were probably $30 million because of the extra 0.5 million.</p>
          <p>On my reconciliation, I can't say hey you could say carried Curragh's costs came down a little</p>
          <p>. In fact, on my numbers, the true number you should be looking at is the other costs, which has gone from $463 million to $507 million, but again that $463 million has got Premier's costs in it and if you adjust for that, I actually think Curragh's costs have stayed flat on a unit basis. So I think saying that it's 20% lower is grossly misleading.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I'll let <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:17:15) reply on this one. I think if you look at slide 34, which is the one you're referring to, what you really got to do is back out the <mark type="ph" /> trial (1:17:24) costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For both years. You got to back out the costs associated with Premier. When you do both of those, the reduction in costs is around 15%. Now, Curragh's cost reduction is considerably higher than the 15% and Bengalla is less than the 15%. And that's why that the straight maths come out with. And basically, you got to take the traded call and pass the Premier cost out of that calculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the Premier's costs <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:17:54) what's Bengalla's increased costs, because I can't get anywhere near that. I reckon Curragh unit cost is flat year-on-year, because if you've got about 1.7 million tonnes that Premier Coal costs in that number and the only 0.5 million tonnes have been Bengalla's cost increase and as I said you're going to put Curragh unit mine costs down 20% when in fact it's actually the biggest drop is actually doing no traded coal for the half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's not right, Dave. Look, Curragh's costs have come down by 20% and as I said if you back out the traded coal and the Premier costs out of the pro forma we've given you, the actual costs year-on-year actually go down by 16%. So what I'm saying in terms of 20% for Curragh is the actual number that <mark type="ph" /> was brought down (1:18:47), I think comparing last year to this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I suppose the question in short is how much of the costs are in &#x2013; how much of Premier is in there and what's the increase in Bengalla and then we can split that out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will not disclose that, David, but you have take that what I have quoted in the presentation is right and I'm standing by those numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question today comes from the line of Craig Woolford from Citi. Craig, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Richard and Terry. Just wanted to ask a question about the food and liquor business, you said looking at 2% space growth going forward. If my math is right that's about 15 stores. How did you come out with that number and does the company consider protecting its turf a reason to open stores if there is a rival retailer that may want to open an attachment, but the return on capital doesn't stack up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what we've maintained a fairly consistent approach towards space, Craig, and we talk more about in space stores rather than absolute number of stores. The stores we've been opening have been roughly 50% bigger than the ones we have been closing. So as I mentioned that in the presentation, the number that we closed is pretty similar to the ones that we've opened, but obviously the space growth there, Net 6% since we started the transformation. And we're looking at sort of between 2% to 3% of space growth over the next, the next few years, is really what I'd estimate coming out at. We've got a return on capital requirements. We want to make sure that we focus on quality of space, not quantity of stores. And that's served us well in the past and it will serve us well in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So the &#x2013; is it 2% to 3% or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it be somewhere within there. It varies depending on, you cannot really be that precise about it, it's a guide because you don't know when deals are ultimately going to be done and when actually does the stores are physically open, they can flip over from half into the next or one year into the next. But broadly, as a guide, that's what we would expect along the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Craig, I'm not aware of any new store in retail, I'm only &#x2013; actually in my history at Wesfarmers, aware of once we've approved a capital expenditure below our hurdle rate. And that time was when I was running our Rural Services division and we had to build some cattle yards which we knew wouldn't going to make any sense, but if we didn't we were going to exit the cattle industry. I'm not aware of any instance where we've approved based on our forecasts, CapEx on a new store below our hurdle rate and cost of capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, though, but...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we wouldn't do it for defensive reasons, because that's just a recipe for disaster.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. <mark type="ph" /> As long as other rates have the final price, I guess. (1:21:36)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well it may not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. My other question was around wage pressures. From what I read of the ABI agreements on Bunnings and Kmart, there probably is some wage pressures coming as they have to move towards the General Retail Award on Sunday loading and overtime.</p>
          <p>Could you just talk to whether that is a pressure that the company faces and how they <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:22:03)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll let John kick off in a second, Craig, but I was asked this at a press conference a little bit earlier, I don't think there's much difference at the moment.  We've got ABIs on the go all the time in different parts of the business. We settled Curragh last year and you might remember when we did Curragh, there was actually a lot going on. BMA had a long dispute and we're able to settle our arrangements in Curragh very quickly. We've got a terrific workforce at Curragh . And my assessment at the moment is not much had changed on this front, there's always a robust negotiations at an ABI level, but I wouldn't say from where I'm sitting that there's an increase in expectations above what we've been saying. John, Dene anyone else want to comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, It's Richard. From a Bunnings point of view and from Officeworks point of view, your comments are very well founded. And Craig I'm not sure what information you're looking at because it doesn't accord with our thinking with the right sorts of pressures and particularly relevant to the way we've structured our ABI. We've have very, very high retention amongst our permanent team, the ABI covers &#x2013; we have in place covers from earnings point of view, a huge number of our team across Australia, and what we know that they're happy and we'll look to reward them in lots of different ways and those sorts of pressures just aren't relevant for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So just a technical one around the Sunday loading rights having to match the General Retail Award?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. There's lots of intricacies in Fair Work Craig, and we've managed to have some very good discussions. The first time we went through the Fair Work process where those issues were understood against the balance of all the things we do around weekends, public holidays and the way that we gauge and remunerate our team.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question today comes from the line of Daniel Broeren from CIMB. Daniel, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good afternoon. My questions relate to the Coles Express and specifically the recent price caps. To my understanding is up to 100 products are now priced in line with supermarket pricing, so given the cost to operate a convenience store are relatively high compared to a supermarket, can you please talk about the sustainability of having the same prices but with different cost basis? And just the second question is given that a large number of Express customers would be Coles docket shoppers, would the impact of any volume growth in Express have more impact on Coles' supermarkets rather than competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think so, I think that as far as pricing is concerned, that the two areas operate independently and clearly with shop sales looking to try and see if we can improve upon them, we're looking at the relative competitiveness. But they operate independently. The biggest impact, I guess, is a more of a high profile lines where we reduced the price of bread and milk into alignment with the Down Down products that we've done as well. So we've looked at that quite specifically. But I thought it was going to be an adverse impact in terms of our sales growth in supermarkets as a result of actions taken in the convenience chain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it fair to say or is it possible for you to say that the bread and milk categories within Coles Express are profitable on a standalone basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in our world, <mark type="ph" /> we actually wouldn't be doing something that we didn't think we could actually believe we can get a fixed return from it (1:25:25). So we've aligned the pricing. It's consistent with what we're doing in other aspects of Express as well. It's an area that's obviously quite profiled in relation to the &#x2013; what the consumer sees as well, and we recognize that as well but we're happy    with the profitability that we're generating out of Coles Express, both in terms of fewer line shop sales. And we'll aim look to see if we can improve the shop sales from where they are currently.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question today comes from the line of Phillip Kimber from Goldman Sachs. Phillip, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. I'm just wondering if you could talk a little bit about sales trends you've seen since being the end of the financial year? Has there been any noticeable change or are we sort of similar to the trends we saw in the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Phil. As always, I'm slightly reluctant, but it's worth calling out there's been a bit of government money flowing around in January, obviously, in January and February because of the back-to-school bonus payments, if you like, for kids that the government released. And we've seen some impact of that. And can actually see it by demographics by store, particularly Target and Kmart. Might have been a bit in Officeworks as well.</p>
          <p>And the reason we can say  is tactually when the checks get released, we can see the impact of store levels. So we know that's had an impact and might have had in some, in those businesses up to 1% improvement in sales through January. So if I leave that to one side, I'd say January, February has been pretty much a continuation maybe in &#x2013; I don't think there is any reduction in confidence. Maybe a marginal improvement in confidence.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Ian McLeod's just sort of said, hey, hang on what are you talking about, don't raise expectations. But I just think if you think about it, there's less bad news and marginally more good news around these days. But consumers are being very careful and I think that's where we're at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a clarification question on the resources. I think Stewart mentioned Resources costs are up 11% in the second half.  I wasn't sure if he meant on the second half of last year or on the first half of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Costs up, you mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I just heard him talk in his main part &#x2013; not an answer to a question. In the main part he mentioned resources costs will be up another 11%, sorry down another 11% in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right. We expect that further costs will come out of our business in the short-term, in the next six months. That'll be another 11%. But it's fair to say looking into FY 2014, we think costs will go up from that bottom, which is about 30% odd down, up by about 10%. And that's basically as a result of consuming, I suppose, work that we've done at Curragh over the last couple of years following the floods in 2011 where we moved a lot of <mark type="ph" /> other than the head of active coal phases. (1:28:38)</p>
          <p>We've run that <mark type="ph" /> other burden advance (1:28:43) down in this current financial year. That's work we've already done ahead of where we should have been. And for next year, we'll see a slight increase of 10%. So that's &#x2013; so looking at the second half of this year, it'll be a further 11% down. And looking through that reduction process, we'll be up about 10% next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And that's on prior year, not on the.....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's right. On the prior year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question today comes from the line of David Thomas from CLSA. David, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Just Richard, really I think this question is probably for you. A lot of your businesses are operating on a pretty even keel now, particularly sort of the retail operations. The CapEx has occurred in the Resources division and everything else is obviously a little bit going on but not a lot. Is it time to be really starting to think about acquisitions? I know that you sort of half mentioned it in the previous question on capital management, but I guess it's more about than bandwidth for the executive team, I think. And obviously, there is perhaps a little bit more today than there has been in the past couple of years. Can you give some areas of thought around that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, in a general sense I will, David. I think we probably thought for a year or so that we've got the management capacity now to do something of interest of scale was to arise. I mean, there is lots of things we're looking at, at divisional level and things like that. But, significant for a division but relatively modest for the group. And we'll continue to do that. From a group point of view, though, I think, I do think we've got the capacity financially and management wise. I actually think we've strengthened the capabilities across the group at management levels fairly significantly over the last few years.</p>
          <p>So it's a matter of an opportunity or opportunities coming along that make sense to us. And we're always actively looking and thinking about things. We're not going to be rushed into it. We'll be very patient and we'll be very disciplined about anything we may or may not do. Often making any decision not to do something is more important than the decision to do something. So yes, we've got the capacity financially and human resources, it's a matter of the right opportunity coming along otherwise. We've got significant investment going into our businesses. We've still got I think a heck of lot of work to do in all of our businesses to improve how we're operating to provide better outcomes for our customers, to innovate and create new opportunities within each of the businesses. So we'll keep doing what we've been doing and hopefully make a decent return for our shareholders on the way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you extend that to so far as to look internationally? Particularly, obviously Asia obviously is close enough and the success stories out there, at least in our consumer land, have been those that do have an Asian operations. Is there any thought process to international acquisitions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is certainly a thought process at both divisional and at the group level. But we've got our eyes wide open every time when we go into those markets, you've got a have a good look of who is playing in there and what you need you to do to be a winner. We've beefed up or we're in the process of beefing up some resources overseas at the moment, which is just improving our connection too. We've got some resourcing now in Hong Kong and that's all about improving our connection into that part of the world. I wouldn't necessarily say that signals anything other than a preparedness for us to be engaging with people and looking for opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Given Rob's lack of honor, I thought I might ask a last question on the insurance side of the business...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:33:02) you have David, and I didn't ring you off and ask you to do this either.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess it's around the &#x2013; obviously there is fantastic improvement in the underwriting profits in particular. And I was trying to get a handle on how much of that was coming out of the personal lines. Obviously as a revenue intensive gross return premium is up to 27%, which is a good evolution. But I was wondering if you might be able to give some split or at least some guide in terms of what the driver of that improvement in the underwriting profits and how much of that came out of the personal lines in particular?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So, from a profitability point of view, we've made fairly significant investments in our capabilities in personal lines. So the actual contribution to profits is not material, but what we are finding is that the improved capabilities around risk pricing and claims management, particularly through our national repair network, is starting to drive improvements in average claims cost and loss ratio across personal lines in Lumley, WFI and so forth. So that is having a benefit. You're right that the key, the key area of growth in premium is personal lines. But we have achieved reasonable premium rate increases across the entire portfolio and an overall improvement in the quality of the portfolio, particularly in our property book, by exiting high hazard areas, high hazard locations, and just general improvements in risk management?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And are you finding those new customers sticky?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we're quite happy with retention rates and we &#x2013; just on the personal lines side through Coles we just recently went through the 150,000 policy level and we're looking to move that up because we see opportunities in that space. When you look at industry profitability, Australian private motor insurance, there are quite strong returns being generated in that area. So we think there is an opportunity for our customers to save some money and for us to make decent return going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Before the next question, just coming back to David if you're still on the line and I'm sure you are &#x2013; I've just been doing a fair work on the supplementary side of the Resources pack and the Curragh mine cost reduction that we mentioned being 20% down on last year. I think you've got &#x2013; I think what may be confused here is the 2011 flood recovery in particular $55 million on 5.5 million tonnes effectively works out to about $10 a tonne. And so if you look at the difference, so that's part of the 20%, but obviously you've got more coming in, in the ordinary costs. So I think that potentially may help your modeling. If it doesn't, give me a call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question today comes from the line of Michael Simotas from Deutsche Bank. Michael, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys. Just another question on Target. We've heard about the revenue impact of the toy sale. Can you give us some sense of the margin impact that that might have had had given the changing mix, and also whether the one-off costs are effectively down in the first half and the second half, <mark type="ph" /> base (1:36:28) will be what we should think about going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Michael, two questions I guess? So on the toy sale, I probably won't add any details other than to say there was, if you were to adjust for the toy sale being in the first half of fiscal 2013 so that comparable store sales being down 1.8% that would have been positive. I think to release more information would compromise our competitive position.</p>
          <p>And then second, your second question in relation to transformation related expenses, I would say that the first half of fiscal 2013 had very elevated, and in a going forward perspective, one-offset of expenses, and that we have taking steps to reduce the needs for those one-off costs in several ways, which I mentioned in response to a question from David earlier, including making sure that we have got our own internal capabilities that we don't need external management consultants, and other assistance, which tends to be very high cost, as well as having spent money on online platform, and other investments of a similar nature online that will serve us well for the next few years. So we don't see a necessity for a constant high level of investment in those sorts of transformation initiatives.</p>
          <p>But I can say at Investor Day later in the year we'll update on two aspects of the operating costs associated with transformation, as well as the use of the provision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but it sounds like it'll take another half or maybe even a little bit more than that for it to fully play out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that the first thing I can say in direct response to your question, Mike, would be that the expenses in the second half have been significantly reduced in comparison to the first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Cooke from Nomura. David, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys, a couple of questions to Stewart on Resources, if I may. Stewart, just looking at your cost out in the second half of 2013 and increase in 2014, can you give us an indication please as to how much of that cost base is in your control? And how much is dependent on volume growth to fractionalize a fixed cost base. Or conversely if things, if volume comes down, what impact that could have on your ability to pull those costs out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we are not reliant on c volume increases for next year. We're currently in that 8 million tonnes to 8.5 million tonnes in terms of met coal. Just looking at the cost decreases, of the total decrease in costs, about two-thirds is sustainable long-term with a third not sustainable. So we've come down 20% in the first half, there's a further 11% in the second half. That gives you, I would just add a 30%. We will go up by that 10% in next year. And as I said before, the reason for that going up is that this year we're consuming work we've done in advance from, basically from overburden renewals getting well ahead in terms of truck and shovel, well ahead of where the <mark type="ph" /> dry down (1:40:31) operations are.</p>
          <p>So this year we are obviously consuming that work we've done in advance, so therefore our costs are lower as a result of that. But when we get into FY 2014, we would have consumed all that work in advance that we've done. So in terms of the total, the cost reductions, two-thirds of that's sustainable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The thing could suggest, Stewart, that you're trying to make a short-term number look better by not continuing on with the overburden removal and trying to benefit from &#x2013; in fact mining rather than overburdening now. Is it a mine operational thing or is that a case of you're trying to achieve a short-term cost target?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well at the moment, we're clearly focused on reducing our costs. The marketplace is pretty tight. You've seen our EBIT numbers. We've done a lot of work in advance of where we should have been and that's directly attributed to basically the major flooding we had in 2011. The difficulty in getting back and operating at full capacity down in the pits, the areas that were dry for operational were truck and shovel pre-strip ahead of <mark type="ph" /> drag along (1:41:48). So we got well ahead of our business and we're currently taking advantage of that in this current financial year at a time when obviously coal prices and exchange rates are very difficult.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sorry, a clarification question, your hedging profile doesn't look has changed since June, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have sort of backed off putting hedges in place at the moment. Clearly when exchange rates are in the 1.03, 1.04, 1.05, it's very hard to put hedges in place when potentially all the downside is &#x2013; if you put it into the higher rates and the exchange rate comes off and then clearly you're causing a problem for yourself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So effectively, you're increasing your proportion of spot sales quite considerably at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just say that again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not the steel contract, just hedging. I mean, we have a range of hedging and we're just headed toward the lower end of the range, that's all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And David, I don't think you have to be cynic to ask the question about what we're doing. What we're doing is managing cost of the business, and we got criticized last year for not making enough money. We said at that time, we've actually done a lot overburden removal and because of that work we were doing a commissioning of the new wash plant we're taking advantage of that this year, as Stewart said, in circumstances where we understand conventional pressure of the mine. I think it's just a sensible thing to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Richard. And final one from me is the carbon tax, can you give us an update please as to how much that have cost you since this thing is implemented for six months now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that to Resources or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, that's across the whole business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:43:35) $100 million or thereabouts. And half a year. That looks in that kind of order. If you look at the key operational impact across the various divisions, you've seen the electricity line office.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's in addition, David. So there is a carbon tax impasse that every one of our businesses is incurring higher energy costs at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Greg Dring from Macquarie. Greg, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon, Ian. You speak quickly, but so do I and that's okay. But I want to make sure I caught what you said about value, around about slide 15 you made this comment. You've actually said that value is not just for the few, but obviously with retail loyalty you've got to give some special reward. And you alluded to the fact that 50% of your transaction volume or value, I'm not sure which one, is on FlyBuys. So I'm just wondering about this whole value platform and how you differentiate it between loyalty and value for the masses if I can use that term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we look at it as an integrated approach. I think I mentioned this before, Greg. So we're obviously looking at the balance of mix of fewer, stronger promotions, which we've executed as part of our strategy. We've clearly got levels a Down Down price investment to bring prices down and operate more of an EDLP platform when they stay down for prolonged periods. We use fuel discounts as well and then Target Loyalty programs through the dates that we now have available. So those loyalty programs can either be in terms of spend stretch in relation cash or indeed to points or indeed back into fuel. So we'll use all those metrics in order to make sure that we've got the right balance or mix to motivate customers broadly and specifically in terms of spending more at Coles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So your reference to value not just for a few, I thought you were trying to allude perhaps to the loyalty program and then you didn't have to be a FlyBuys member to get that value?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well I think that's &#x2013; there's not a lot of truth in that. I think that if you're going to establish yourself as a retailer focused on value, you have to make sure that that value is open to all. I think if you're going to try and restrict your level of value investment you're going to make to target a limited number of customers in isolation, then that's probably a strategy we wouldn't support.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But you're roughly 50:50, aren't you, didn't you say 50% of transactions are on FlyBuys?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well 50% of our transactions are on FlyBuys now. So you have opportunities then to look at that particular customer set. But also there's again 50% that aren't. And clearly what we're focused on very much is at improving and growing our overall transactions attracting new customers, not just trying to protect our existing ones.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then is eth priority to get more FlyBuys members or more customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think it would be to get more customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But clearly, there is a loyalty program out there we reinvigorated last year and as a result of that, we've got more active users of FlyBuys than ever before. But it's a balance in this to make sure that you're giving some offers and deals and value to other customers without excluding others that perhaps haven't got a card.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Greg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Shaun Cousins from JPMorgan. Shaun, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Just a question in regards to the working capital at retail. Could you talk about which divisions made be the biggest progress this year, pardon me, this half in terms of other working capital out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of &#x2013; on a net basis, <mark type="ph" /> indiscernible (1:47:29) has made the biggest progress. And we saw good performances from all the other divisions on a like-for-like basis in terms of net working capital days. And obviously, new stores coming down for some divisions more than others. And I think the only other thing we would call out is that Target, as we mentioned, finished December with a bit more inventory than this time last year because of &#x2013; looking to fix up some availability issues in that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is Coles comfortable with the level of inventory that they've got in terms of &#x2013; we understand they tend to run a little richer on inventory relative to Woolworths just in terms of where Coles is at in its broader working cap out program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We've got an approach where we want to try improve our working capital over time and we've progressively done that, but there's obviously more to go as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Shaun.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no further questions at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you all very much. And if you got any follow-up questions, please contact Mark Scatena or Alex and we'll be happy to help out. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude our conference for today. Thank you for participating. You may all now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>