<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1245886" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-20</date>
    <companies>
      <company>10148</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Richard Goyder, Managing Director</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ian McLeod, Managing Director, Coles</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John Gillam, Managing Director, Home Improvement and Office Supplies</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Launa Inman, Managing Director, Target</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Guy Russo, Managing Director, Kmart</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Stewart Butel, Managing Director, Wesfarmers Resources</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Robert Scott, Managing Director, Wesfarmers Insurance</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Keith Gordon, Director, Industrial Divisions</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep">Terry Bowen, Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="10">Phillip Kimber</participant>
      <participant id="11">Shaun Cousins</participant>
      <participant id="12">Craig Woolford</participant>
      <participant id="13">Grant Saligari</participant>
      <participant id="14">Greg Dring</participant>
      <participant id="15">Ben Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="16">David Cooke</participant>
      <participant id="17">David Errington</participant>
      <participant id="18">Richard Barwick</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker>
        <plist>
          <p>[missing audio] Operator: Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for holding and welcome to the Wesfarmers 2009 Full Year Results Announcement. Your lines will be muted during the presentation. However, you will have an opportunity to ask questions immediately afterward and instructions will be provided on how to do so at that time.</p>
          <p>A copy of the presentation can be downloaded from the Wesfarmers website or alternatively can be viewed on the live webcast. In addition to the PowerPoint presentation, there is also an information pack, which provides additional information regarding the full year performance. This pack can also be downloaded from the Wesfarmers' website.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to hand the conference over the Managing Director of Wesfarmers Limited, Mr. Richard Goyder.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good afternoon, everyone, and welcome to this presentation of our full year results. I'm joined in Perth by Ian McLeod from Coles; John Gillam from the Home Improvement and Office Supplies Division; Launa Inman from Target; Guy Russo from Kmart; Stewart Butel from Resources; Rob Scott from Insurance; Keith Gordon, who will look after the other three, Industrial Business, Industrial &amp; Safety, Chemicals &amp; Fertilizers &amp; Energy; and Terry Bowen, who has been Group Finance Director since May.</p>
          <p>Now, I'm going to give a bit of an overview of the results and some of the highlights and then Ian will commence to run through from the various businesses. And so if you want to follow the presentation through I'm going to kick off on group performance highlights, which is slide four.</p>
          <p>And obviously today we've announced an increase in revenue and earnings. Earnings up 44% to just over $1.5 billion. There are some one-offs, which we detail later in the pack, so the 1.535 billion is after $106 million net of one-offs, that on $51 billion of turnover. Importantly and pleasingly a really strong cash generation here, with operating cash flow of around $3 billion.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share down on last year, reflecting the increased number of shares we have on issues. And we've announced today a fully franked final divined of $0.60 per share, which is more than previous guidance we've given of no more than $0.50. That really reflects the strong operating cash flow we've had in the business and what we see as the outlook.</p>
          <p>Moving to the next slide, the Coles turnaround, which Ian will talk in detail about, continues to meet our expectations both from earnings and cash generation. Most importantly though, in terms of the markets we've got, on improving the performance of that business. I think we had just a great performance from Bunnings and Target over the last 12 months and their performances were very strong.</p>
          <p>The turnarounds at Officeworks and Kmart are progressing well, albeit Kmart in an early stage, Guy only started in the business late last year, but we are pleased with the impacts of the turnaround strategies there and we are certainly pleased with what's going on at Officeworks.</p>
          <p>The result from the Resources division for the year was really terrific. Record profits, record production at Curragh and Premier, and sales, and so a really good performance from that business.</p>
          <p>The other industrial businesses had a tough year, things like the Varanus Island gas explosion and consequent interruption to gas supply and more expensive gas supply options. The impact of the global financial crisis on businesses that the Industrial and Safety division was supplying to in construction, mining and manufacturing and obviously interest rates and how that's impacted insurance as well as claims events. So we've had the Industrial and Insurance divisions impacted by that in the last 12 months.</p>
          <p>And finally, and Terry will talk a bit about this later on, balance sheet is in very good shape. Net debt to equity of around 18%, supported obviously by the equity raising and strong cash flows for the year.</p>
          <p>In terms of group performance summary, I don't intend to go through that in any detail, it's there for you to see. The bottom line in terms of return on shareholders' funds, I'll deal with when I talk about divisional return on capital.</p>
          <p>On the earnings per share, as I said, $1.60 per share, really two factors there, growth in earnings, but more shares on issue because of the equity raising, which has diluted that earnings per share number.</p>
          <p>Our cash flow per share has very strong, both operating cash flow and free cash flow per share and that's highlighted on slide eight, and a strong improvement over last year. And we're really pleased with that. There has been a focus on cash flows in the group and managing working capital, as well as obviously making sure we're executing the business strategies around revenues and profits and so the cash flow performance that I think was really good.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide nine, divisional EBIT. As I said, Coles is on track. I think actually I've given a reasonable rundown on the divisions, so I won't go through those, I'll let the divisional Managing Directors talk about that. Where there is no meaningful comparison to 2008, we just haven't put it in there, and &#x2013; because, as we've said before, the 4.5 months of Coles ownership in the first half of the fiscal '07 &#x2013; '08 year provides meaningless comparable numbers and we're just not using them.</p>
          <p>Divisional &#x2013; finally &#x2013; divisional return on capital. A number of the businesses have gone backwards in terms of return on capital this year, the &#x2013; obviously Resources being a highlight. Insurance has gone back on, really on the back of its performance. Industrial and Safety back a bit, again just because of the more difficult operating environment in the second half. Chemicals and Fertilizers down, we had a full year of the ammonium nitrate capital expenditure added to capital and then we've had the impacts of Varanus Island and a slow fertilizer season eating into earnings there, so we'd expect improvements in return on capital in that business going forward.</p>
          <p>The same with Energy, we've got the impact of the LNG &#x2013; new LNG facility on capital employed. The Coles businesses, we knew these businesses were low returning businesses when we acquired it, and there is a very strong focus in Coles and Officeworks and Target and Kmart to improve those return on capital.</p>
          <p>Outcomes, in fact, I don't think the focus on return on capital in the group has ever been as strong as it is, and that includes, in terms of new investments, ensuring that new investments meet robust hurdle rates. So that through improved performance of our existing businesses, including the turnarounds and ensuring that investments meet strict return requirements would expect return on capital, and as a consequence return on &#x2013; group return on equity will improve in the coming years.</p>
          <p>And, with that introduction, I'll make some closing comments on outlook. I'll now hand over to Ian McLeod to take you through Coles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Richard. Before I talk about the FY '09 results, I think it's worth reflecting on where we've come from over the last 12 months. When I arrived just over a year ago I inherited a business that was bureaucratic and top heavy, lacked a cohesive strategy and direction, was inward facing, not customer focused, priorities were on costs and not sales, and its general under investment in stores and infrastructure decaying.</p>
          <p>We're moving fast to address these issues as well as a range of other complex challenges across the business. Sustainable change will take time to achieve, but I'm encouraged by the early progress we're making after my first year of the five year turnaround program.</p>
          <p>I'll now take you through the key points of the Coles' full year results for FY '09 on slide 12. The FY '09 numbers show early signs of improvement, with revenue of $28.8 billion and EBIT of $831 million. Comparable stores sales in food and liquor were 4.6% and comparable store sales for convenience excluding fuel was 6.4%.</p>
          <p>Slide 13 provides a better analysis of relative performance between the second half of FY '08 and second half of FY '09. Sales of 11.3 billion in food and liquor generated a 19% increase in EBIT and a comparable store sales growth of 6.9%. Sales in convenience, food and fuel of $2.8 billion reflect significant price deflation year-on-year, although EBIT still grew by $1 million against the second half of last year.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn to the fourth quarter food and liquor performance on slide 14. During the year, significant effort has been made to increase availability, increase fresh food quality, improve service, improve quality standards and invest in price to deliver better value to increasingly cost-conscious consumers.</p>
          <p>Despite a rate of inflation in the quarter slowing to 2.2%, our comparable store sales were still the highest of the whole year at 7.3%, reflecting both increased customers and growth in basket size.</p>
          <p>As well as driving sales and service in stores, slide 15 highlights several change programs that have been initiated to improve overall business efficiency. The number of distribution centers have been rationalized from over 40 down to 23, we've improved product handling and also improved order management, but more work is needed to leverage the supply chain fully.</p>
          <p>Nonetheless, on-time delivery is consistently higher than this time last year. We've worked hard to drive down our excess stock positions, enabling us to eliminate the clothes hanger mountains and olive oil lakes inherited from the past.</p>
          <p>While store managers were constrained from replacing light bulbs without committing to a multi-tiered approval process, buyers were able to place significant overseas orders without reference. Approval processes have been revised to avoid repetition of these problems and we've achieved a five-year reduction in our net working capital position in food and liquor.</p>
          <p>As part of a $600 million capital expenditure program, we've opened 31 new stores including nine replacements. Through a combination of new stores and refurbishments, we've extended our pilot renewal formats to 13, with examples now in each state and have had an encouraging customer response to a significantly different supermarket experience. The transfer of 45 smaller Coles stores to FoodWorks will take place over the next few months, as we focus on larger footprint stores as part of our turnaround strategy.</p>
          <p>The next page and slide 16 shows that we have been working hard to build a solid foundation in Phase I of the turnaround program. We've focused on providing a better customer experience in all of our stores, existing and new over the last 12 months. For example, we've removed 636 store entry barriers, replaced 90% of outdated cash registers, reducing queuing times, installed almost 1000 new deli slices and scales, completed 120 major refrigeration upgrades and acquired over 160,000 new trolleys. We've also worked hard on in-store education and attention to quality of our fresh food offer.</p>
          <p>Our focus on improved availability is helping to increase sales, with average stocks down from an average of 175 in the third quarter of FY '09 to 150 by the end of the fourth quarter. And the latest Roy Morgan survey shows customers are responding positively to these initiatives, with the highest satisfaction score in over two years.</p>
          <p>Our easy ordering trials on order replenishment are almost complete, and we expect to move to a carefully controlled rollout plan shortly. We've also installed self check-outs in 12 pilot stores, with encouraging results.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn to the performance of liquor and convenience on slide 17. The appointment of a new leadership team led by Tony Leon has enhanced the focus on retail basics within our liquor business.</p>
          <p>Tony has accelerated the change program in liquor and we are seeing better store standards as well as improved service and execution. A new targeted brand strategy across 1st Choice, Liquorland and Vintage Cellars, and a significant pricing investment has resulted in strong sales growth across our liquor business.</p>
          <p>Turning to our convenience network; while comparable fuel volumes increased, sales value has been impacted by significant price deflation. The fuel price is declining from a price peak of $1.45 per liter in the fourth quarter of '08 to an average of $1.13 per liter in the fourth quarter of '09. Easter adjusted comparable shop sales increased by 6.7% in the period.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn to an outlook on slide 18. Given the scale of change required at Coles, we believe year one is a strong step in the right direction. However, we remain cautious about the broader economic outlook. With less fiscal stimulus to boost consumer activity, the market will remain competitive, if not more so.</p>
          <p>Our intention is to continue to invest in pricing to help our customers stretch their dollar further. In this environment we'll focus on quality, service and value to help our customers through tough times and improve business performance. We'll also roll out further renewal stores in FY '10 to support the regeneration of the fleet over time.</p>
          <p>Our priority focus in the early stages remains on the existing store base. Whilst improvement opportunities are clear, it will still take time to deliver consistently well, given the scale of change required.</p>
          <p>We'll no doubt hit some bumps along the way, but the first full year results are a positive and encouraging start. The job is far from over. We are actively driving change at pace. We remain confident that, with continued hard work from all our team members, sustainable improvement can be delivered within the five year turnaround plan. I really appreciate the support I've had within the company since I arrived.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to hand over the John Gillam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ian. I'll start at slide 21 and comment firstly on the Bunnings headline result. Bunnings finished the year well, with trading revenue growth of 10.3% driving an uplift of almost 14% in trading earnings. And we were pleased to see our trading margins strengthen to 11.2%.</p>
          <p>Including property activities, our overall earnings grew by 11.9% in lot of market conditions we chose to hold rather than sell some developments resulting in a more modest property contributions here. We continue to invest in new stores and land banking sides for future store development. We're also maintaining investment levels in existing stores. CapEx for the year exceeded 330 million and we maintained our ROC above 30%.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 22, highlight for the year was cash sales growth of 13% within that annual cash store-on-store growth was 10.1% and a pleasing 12.9% in the second half. We saw strong performances from our existing stores as a result of excellent operational disciplines and good merchandizing work.</p>
          <p>On the trade side of our business, sales declined by 2.8%. Given the significant weakness in Australia and New Zealand housing construction markets, this is a satisfactory performance. Good progress was made on our trade strategy and the sales result is reflective of the traction we are achieving.</p>
          <p>The Bunnings network continues to expand. We opened 10 warehouse stores, three smaller format stores and ten new trade centers. Our property team have been very busy and the pipeline for new stores is arguably in a healthier state today than at any other time. As you can see from page 11 in the supplementary pack, at 30 June we had 11 stores under construction, in addition to that we have 20 more sites in a planning approvals phase of development. These sites underpin our network expansion plans for the next two to three years and our property team are actively adding to these.</p>
          <p>We've been pleased with the performance of the new multi-level warehouse store format unveiled in our Hawthorn store in December. This format opens up more areas for new stores.</p>
          <p>Investment to bring current building and merchandizing standards into older stores continued. This included specific category expansion initiatives with a complete revamp of decorator and tools successfully completed. More recently, we started the rapid rollout of a new range of kitchen cooking appliances to leverage the success of our exclusive customized kit kitchen product.</p>
          <p>Improved team development was another highlight, as were ongoing business effectiveness and productivity gains. We reduced our cost of doing business which helped lift net margins.</p>
          <p>In terms of outlook, slide 23, the Bunnings business is well-positioned in the current trading environment to continue to grow. Although we will cycle against the Australian government's recent consumer stimulus actions, we have a positive strategic agenda that is focused on improving the customer offer through value, service and range initiatives.</p>
          <p>The trade business is well placed for any upturn in housing activity and more immediately to benefit from sector-specific government stimulus actions. And we aim to further improve the business from a cost perspective. Network expansion will continue at similar rates to previous years and we're also investing in the new store pipeline for the longer term.</p>
          <p>The home improvement and outdoor living market exceeds 36 billion in size in Australian and our share is quite modest. There are good long-term growth prospects for the Bunnings business if we keep delivering customers the best offer.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 24, I'll comment on Officeworks. Revenue for the year topped 1.3 billion and we produced earnings of 65 million. We were able to slightly improve our EBIT margin to 5% and plan to lift this further in the coming years. Looking at the results in more detail, there were some pleasing highlights from Mark Ward and his team, which are summarized on slide 25.</p>
          <p>Headlines sales growth for the Officeworks retail store network was 7.7%. Store sales growth in the second half lifted to 11.1%. This was underpinned by a good uplift in transactions whilst margins remained under competitive pressure. It has been encouraging for the Officeworks store to achieve this while successfully making the significant transition to everyday lowest pricing.</p>
          <p>The new white store look and feel is delivering good results and there are now 19 of these new format stores. Eight new stores have been opened during the year and seven full refurbs were completed. 46 stores in total have been rebranded and new internal livery work has reached 96 stores. Actions that removed wasteful admin processes and addressed poor cost positions are bearing fruit, more will be done here.</p>
          <p>The Officeworks' website, a key selling tool and sales channel, was rebuild and re-launched and the historical silos between the business and retail channels were removed to deliver a more consistent one Officeworks' offer. Unfortunately, adverse sales trends were experienced in both the Officeworks' BusinessDirect segment and in the Harris Technology operations. Sales were hurt by a lack of confidence amongst small to medium size business customers. There was also a disruption from resetting the strategic agenda in these businesses, which included closing five Harris Tech stores.</p>
          <p>The second half of 2008-'09 has allowed us for the first time since the change of ownership to complete a meaningful comparison of financial halves. Second half trading revenue increased by 2.5% with double-digit sales growth in the Officeworks store network. Perhaps most pleasingly, normalized earnings in the second half grew by 10.5% after adjusting for the impact of one-off items incurred last year.</p>
          <p>Looking at the outlook for 2009-'10 which is on slide 26, the primary aim remains to reinvigorate Officeworks for long-term success through a focused strategic agenda. Investment to further enhance the customer offer and expand the network will continue, as will work to lower costs and remove operational complexity. Moderate sales growth is expected in a volatile trading environment.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll now hand over to Launa Inman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. I'm going to basically talk about slide 28 and 29 jointly. Our results overall were pleasing, specially given the market conditions with an EBIT of 357 million for the year.</p>
          <p>Our EBIT margin remained very strong at 9.4% and we've continued to maintain our margins overall. Our EBIT for the second half was 142 million, a 38% increase on last year. For the full year we achieved a growth in revenue of 7.2 with a comp store growth of 4.2. Our comp store sales maintained the first half momentum with the comp store growth for the last six months of 4.4. All our merchandized departments recorded growth for the year.</p>
          <p>In particular over the last six months we've had strong outcomes from toys and leisure and baby related merchandize. When the government announced the stimulus packages, we analyzed the opportunities and responded to them with the right product at the right price. As a consequence, we did see sales by constant stimulus money hit people's accounts, while the pre-Christmas stimulus package definitely saw a high take-up in our electrical and leisure products, the recent package was undoubtedly spend more broadly.</p>
          <p>Target was therefore able to pick up market share, basically consistently through the last 12 months, and we're comfortable with the progress we've made. In the tough trading environment, we've also focused on improving our cash flow and controlling costs. This has been achieved by working with our major international suppliers to implement more robust payment process that suits both parties.</p>
          <p>In addition, we've maintained strong management over our cost and inventory levels. As a result, our inventory remains fresh and as around the same levels as last year. This we've achieved even with the increased volume of products in key categories that we've identified and with nine additional stores on the ground.</p>
          <p>During the volatile year, we've also managed our margins on imported product via a careful price management process. Our customers continue to look for value in what they buy. Our pricing now however has also been very much influenced by competitor activity.</p>
          <p>Target now has 286 stores as of the year-end and 5% more sell inflows based on a year ago. This year, we are planning to open six new stores, replace one and close one. We are also continuing to invest in our existing stores, recognizing that the number of in-store need refurbishments, in fact in that last half of this past financial year, we completed 11-store refurbishments. And that impact made a total of 33 for the year, and the further seven were underway as we completed the year an additional 20-year plan for the current financial year.</p>
          <p>Our outlook for the foreseeable future is definitely cautious; Target is well-positioned to remain nimble and adaptable to consumer sentiments and competitors. And we will continue to seize opportunities to convert sales. We are confident that we'll ride out this uncertain time, particularly because we're going to closely manage our inventory levels and costs while continuing to invest in our store network, so that we're well-placed for the future.</p>
          <p>Now with that, I'm also going to hand on to Guy from Kmart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Well thanks, Launa. So on page 32 Kmart's reported an EBIT of $109 million, compared to 111 million for the fall. And with the changes that we're going through and we capture or renew, we managed to do &#x2013; that was maintained similar sales to the previous year.</p>
          <p>Slide 33, definitely the Kmart renewal has begun and with a lot of enthusiasm from myself and the entire team when we look at the second half of '09 versus the second half of '08 EBIT with EBIT recorded at $34 million versus 10 and up 240% on the previous year.</p>
          <p>We note that the improvement in this second half occurred basically from exiting unprofitable categories, reducing discounting, which has increased margins, savings in the above store costs, and finally, the supply chain rationalization that has commenced and we note the one-off non-trading cost that incurred during this period as well.</p>
          <p>The inventory is healthy with still being $100 million below last year. And we also had very pleasing strong sales and profit performance from John Sink and his team at Kmart Tyre &amp; Auto.</p>
          <p>The outlook on slide 34, we'll continue to focus on improving profitability by driving profitable sales, continuing to exit unproductive discounting, continue investment in the supply chain rationalization, and leveraging the benefits of reduced cost base. We'll focus on ongoing investments to custom to the customers' experience by being very focused on providing very friendly service, fast service, clean, tidy and easy to shop stores.</p>
          <p>Finally, we'll continue to execute strategic changes with product, price and the way we promote, providing lowest prices for products for families, simplifying customer choices and improving in-stock position, improving the profitabilities of the Kmart events. We expect to open two new stores during this year. And for our people we have incentives in place to drive performance. Rebuilding sustainable growth will take time.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to pass over to Stewart. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Guy. And I'll refer you to slide 36. Operating revenue at $2.4 billion was 83.9% above last year. This is primarily as a result of higher export coal prices experienced in the first three quarters of this year. This revenue included $170 million of traded coal revenue and $88 million of forward exchange contract losses on close-out contracts.</p>
          <p>Earnings before interest and tax at $915 million was 116% higher than last year. This increase in EBIT is due to record coal prices, increased coal sales, offset by mine cash costs, higher export royalties at 208 million, increased Stanwell amortization of $170 million, opt-in exchange losses of 88 million, plus the write-down of an $8 million char plant at Premier.</p>
          <p>Depreciation and amortization, excluding Stanwell, increased $13 million, up 14%. The division's royalty payments to state governments also increased by 285% to $208 million for the year. Coal production for the year increased by 5.5% from last year to 15.1 million tons, and importantly, our safety performance with a lost-time injury frequency rate of 2.5 was significantly down on last year, highlighting our commitment to creating an injury-free workplace.</p>
          <p>We move forward to slide 37, the Resources highlights. The division reported record production sales and earnings for the year, earnings at 815 million was up 116% on last year. This period of record production and sales was aligned to a period of record coal prices for metallurgical and steaming coal exports.</p>
          <p>We achieved strong operational performance through the global financial crisis due to ongoing strong customer focus and demand. Curragh remains at the lowest quartile producer despite industry-wide cost increases.</p>
          <p>In December 2008, an incident occurred at Curragh, which caused major structural damage to one of our dragline booms. This dragline was repaired and returned to service during May 2009, ahead of expectation.</p>
          <p>The $130 million Blackwater Creek diversion project is underway. It's on budget and on schedule for anticipated completion in December 2010. And feasibility studies to expand the Curragh and Bengalla mines continue.</p>
          <p>We move forward to slide 38, the Resources outlook. There are positive signs that the global &#x2013; that the global steel production recovery is underway, with raw material restocking on consecutive month-on-month steel production improvements by our customers.</p>
          <p>Negotiations with major customers during the year have concluded with price relatively being maintained for our Curragh product. And exports of metallurgical coal from Curragh this coming year forecast to be in the range of 6.2 to 6.7 million tons for the year ending 30th of June 2010.</p>
          <p>The sales mix estimate for this coming year is expected to be in the range of 47 to 50% hard coking (28.55) coal, 20% semi-hard or Curragh-B with the remainder being PCI coal. Earnings will significantly decrease in the coming year to &#x2013; due to a substantial reduction in export coal prices, together with lower exports sales. The Stanwell rebate for 2009 and '010 is expected to be in the range of 160 to $180 million at an extreme exchange rate of the 0.8.</p>
          <p>We have locked-in hedge losses of $85 million to be recognized in this financial year. And recognizing the majority of the Stanwell rebate payment and the hedges losses will occur in the first half of this financial year.</p>
          <p>We are clearly implementing aggressive cost reduction programs, particularly at Curragh mine, as we expect some significant cost reductions in the short to medium-term. And subject to satisfactory market conditions we'll be seeking Board approval to extend the Curragh mine to eight to 8.5 million tons of metallurgical exports. This approval is targeted for the end of calendar year 2009.</p>
          <p>I'll now pass on to Rob Scott from the Insurance Division.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Stewart. I'll start with the financials on page 40. We achieved revenue growth of 4.3% across broking and underwriting businesses per year. Underwriting earnings were below expectations due primarily to adverse weather events in Australia. The net earned loss ratio increased well above average levels at 72.9%. Investment income was also below expectations given the fall in interest rates.</p>
          <p>In broking, we achieved nearly 9% earnings growth or 11% growth in constant currencies. We increased the profit margin to 27.9% EBIT for the year, primarily affected by loss ratios was $103 million or 23.7% down on an EBITDA basis. Note that the 2008 figures include a prior year adjustment of $10 million, relating to a non-reinsurance recovery adjustment in Lumley New Zealand.</p>
          <p>Moving to page 41. From the perspective of the property insurer 2009 financial year was very challenging in Australia given the weather-related claims. Weather-related claims for the industry are almost 10 times to 15-year average claims cost. The frequency events meant that more of the losses are retained by insurers. This clearly affected the result. We are now 18 months into the turnaround of Lumley New Zealand and pleasingly our strategy is starting to generate positive returns. We achieved the $32 million turnaround in earnings this year.</p>
          <p>During the year, we embarked on a similar restructuring process within Lumley Australia. We finished the team with a new management &#x2013; we finished the year with a new management team in place and having completed detailed portfolio reviews. We also completed the consolidation of our Australian underwriting licenses, which will result in a greater capital and operating efficiency.</p>
          <p>In our broking businesses, we achieved good organic growth and we also improved earnings and margin. We completed five bolt-on acquisitions of insurance broking businesses through the year.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the outlook on page 42, rate increases are being achieved on renewal in many classes, particularly commercial motor and higher hazard property classes. We would expect to see further upward pressure on commercial rates as a flow-on effect of higher reinsurance costs, low industry reserves and the high loss ratios.</p>
          <p>Underwriting earnings are expected to improve subject to more normal weather conditions in Australia. The transformation of our Lumley business is continuous and with the taming in the Lumley Australia pursuing very similar strategies to those sort of things successful on our New Zealand businesses.</p>
          <p>Our broking business will continue to focus on expansion and effectiveness of distribution, whilst improving business processes. We also anticipate further bolt-on acquisitions in insurance broking space.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand over to Keith Gordon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob. I'll start with the summary of the Industrial and Safety Divisions performance on slide 44. Operating revenues for the full year $1.3 billion was 1.1% lower than last year, due to softer market conditions sales fell up in the second half of the year following a very strong sales performance in the first half.</p>
          <p>As a result of the lower sales activity and increased competitiveness in the market, earnings before interest and tax reduced by 12.3% to $114 million for the full year. The effect of the slowdown was partially offset by corrective expense management initiatives. Those included labor and discretionary expense management. The rationalization of the branch network enclosed of seven small underperforming locations and the continued focus on containing supplier cost increases. Return on capital reduced 14.1% mainly due to the lower EBIT result.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 45, the 2009 result was a solid sales performance considering the impact of the economic slowdown across the division's customer base in the second half. Strong results were achieved by Bullivants as well as businesses with the high exposure to the resources sector in Western Australia including Blackwoods and Protector Alsafe. However, the impact of the economic slowdown was most evident in Victoria and New Zealand.</p>
          <p>Despite the challenging conditions, operational performance was very strong. Customer service and delivery performance further improved and the business continue to invest in increasing organizational and sales force effectiveness.</p>
          <p>Turning to the outlook for the division. Market conditions are expected to remain challenging with the continued margin pressure and lower market demand, especially for manufacturing and smaller customers. However, infrastructure-based activity is expected to provide some growth opportunities.</p>
          <p>The division will continue to focus on further increasing its competitiveness. This includes strategies to further improve the value proposition and delivery performance to increase the share spends from customers, as well as to further penetrate selective growth sectors.</p>
          <p>Those initiatives coupled with strong expense and capital management and improved organizational effectiveness will help to mitigate full impact to the downturn and position the Industrial and Safety division strongly for the recovery.</p>
          <p>Moving to the Chemicals and Fertilizers division on slide 46, CSBP's earnings performance in 2009 was significantly below that of last year. We've previously reported on the impact of Varanus Island, but this was compounded by a rapid decline in commodity prices during the year, and a delayed start to the winter cropping season in Western Australia. This contributed to the lower fertilizer sales noticeable on this slide.</p>
          <p>EBIT for the year was $52 million and return on capital declined from 13% to 4.3%, pleasingly despite difficult operating conditions, the higher standards of safety performance was maintained in the division.</p>
          <p>Slide 47, turning to highlights, ammonium nitrate sales were up significantly for the year, reflecting the full year's production from new AN facilities at Kwinana, CSBP imported ammonia to keep AN plants operating during the gas outage. The QNP expansion was also successfully commissioned during the year. You can see on the slide, the impact of disrupted gas supplies had on CSBP.</p>
          <p>Full supply under contracted terms were stored in the first week of July 2009. So the gas disruption impact on CSBP for the full financial year of 2009. Fertilizer sales were affected by the delays in purchases by farmers due to economic conditions as well as to the partly the late start of the season in Western Australia. Australian Vinyls experienced a loss for the year due to the impact of the DCS implementation in the first half and then a slowdown in the PVC market in the second half.</p>
          <p>Slide 48, an outlook for CSBP, the expansion to the sodium cyanide manufacturing facility at Kwinana will be commissioned later this year, and this additional production will be use to serve us the Boddington Gold Mine in Western Australia. In the ammonium nitrate market, demand remains strong, unless it continue to be the cash with the more positive outlook now than with the case some months ago.</p>
          <p>Fertilizer sales for this financial year has started positively driven by better rains in July and August, which is promoted application of nitrogen stored in July. And this has returned CSBP's WA businesses to a more normal operating environment from the start of the 2010 financial year. Similarly, we are seeing better trading conditions at Australian Vinyls, and we expect to turnaround the performance of that business this year. Finally, as we've worked through fertilizer inventories which has been at high level since the end of 2008, we expect to release a working capital from CSBP over the course of the 2010 financial year.</p>
          <p>I'll now move to the Energy division on slide 49. EBIT for the year $75 million reflected lower earnings from the LPG business compared to 2009, and a modest increase in earnings from the industrial gas business. LPG production for the year was fairly flat year-on-year. This resulted from an increase in average pipeline content for the year, have been offset by lower plant viability during the Varanus Island incident and lower flow rates in the first half.</p>
          <p>There was a significant improvement in safety performance in the division during the year, which was pleasing to see, as this has been identified by management as an area of major attention.</p>
          <p>Now, on slide 50, looking at the major influencing factors in the Energy division across the &#x2013; the Wesfarmers LPG business was affected by drop in the Saudi contract price. The average contract cost in 2008 financial year was US$748 and this fell US$559 in 2009.</p>
          <p>Further to this, the Varanus Island incident impacted across the division's WA-based businesses with the total impact in the order of $25 million. There is a small increase in EBIT for the industrial gas business as the management team continued to focus on developing its coal production capacity, business improvement and customer engagement programs. However, in the second half, the business did experience a downturn in customer demand.</p>
          <p>The Kwinana based LNG plant was commissioned in September 2008 delay a few months from the scheduled commissioning due to Varanus Island.</p>
          <p>Turning to outlook, the division will start to grow at LNG sales into the heavy duty vehicle market in order to fully load the WA plant. The Coregas will continue to focus on strategies to grow the business and being in a position to capitalize on any improvement in the economy.</p>
          <p>In the Wesfarmers LPG business, the outlook remains dependent on a number of factors including LPG prices, pipeline content and demand from the WA gas market.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand over to Terry Bowen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Keith. I'll cover the result of other businesses whereas the capital employed or capital management for the group. On the slide 52, you can see earnings from associates were considerably lower than last year and this record a loss of $60 million.</p>
          <p>The main contributor of the loss was a $57 million downward revaluation of our Gresham Private Equity investment. This included that $35 million write-down of our last investment in Fund one which was Riviera and that was placed into receivership in May. The remaining downward revaluations relate to adjustments in the carrying value of investments in Fund two.</p>
          <p>Assuming no return is forthcoming on Riviera, Fund one would have returned to the Wesfarmers an overall cash internal rate of return of 27% per annum since its inception. And in regards to the carrying value of Fund two and three, it's worth emphasizing that the quarterly revaluations that we undertake our non-cash in nature and do not necessarily reflect their eventual exit value.</p>
          <p>Moving further down the slide, the group recognized higher interest revenue this year, and that was as a result of the increased levels of cash on deposit, particularly in the second half of the year. We recognized $137 million in non-trading and other significant items and I'll discuss this shortly.</p>
          <p>At the bottom of the table, in other, you can see a loss of $50 million. This again is non-cash in nature. It relates mainly to the self insurance provisions &#x2013; due to increased self insurance provisions due to reduced interest rates and lower discount rates which we flagged in the first half as well as a mark-to-market of a number of small investments held by the group.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 53 and non-trading items and significant items. For the full year, non-trading items amounted to $137 million before tax, and this is up from 79 million that we reported in the first half. Coles recorded some additional property impairments in the second half, which took the full year property impairment to $82 million.</p>
          <p>Partly offsetting this was a $30 million gain associated with the writeback of store exit provisions following the agreement announced in June to transfer 45 supermarkets and eight liquor stores to FoodWorks.</p>
          <p>Kmart reported $70 million in non-trading costs for the year. And this was largely due to a substantial restructure of our supply chain that Guy has alluded to and the associated surplus lease space and redundancy provisions that occurred. Within this amount, we also included in the first half, you'll recall, some one-off costs recognized due to some significant support of this restructuring.</p>
          <p>The Insurance division recorded $15 million in non-trading items and this was associated with some Lumley restructuring and the exit of Centrepoint premier funding arrangements. In addition to these non-trading items, the group result also includes some significant one-off items that we've highlighted. The first of these, as was disclosed in February, relates to the closing out of ineffective interest rate swaps following significant debt repayment in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>The final item relates to some one-off tax benefits that we've got in the year. Included in this is $84 million benefit following an upward review of the tax counting value of leasehold assets in Coles, Kmart, Target and Officeworks, against this is only a tax entry, not a book value revaluation of these assets.</p>
          <p>A further $26 million of tax benefit arose from an amendment to a prior year research and development claim. In total, non-trading and significant costs amount to a net 273 million before tax and 106 million after tax.</p>
          <p>Turning to capital management on slide 54, the group's balance sheet was significantly strengthened during the year, following the equity raising in January and February. Net debt at 30th of June was $4.4 billion, with gearing and liquidity ratios all strong.</p>
          <p>As Richard mentioned, the group announced a full year dividend of $0.60 per share, fully-franked, which is ahead of the guidance provided in February. We will continue with the dividend investment plan, which is highly valued by a number of our shareholders, but no discount will apply to the allocation price and nor will it be underwritten.</p>
          <p>The dilutionary effect of the shares issued under the DIP will however be neutralized for the final dividend, through an arrangement with a broker who will acquire the required number of shares on market as a nominee for the participating shareholders. Following equal value payment in cash, the broker's shares will then be transferred to participants on the 1st of October.</p>
          <p>Turning to the group's debt maturity profile on slide 55, highlights. The low level of repayments that we now have due in relation to F'10 and F'11. And the group continues to be active in looking to diversify both the tenure and nature of our debt profile going forward.</p>
          <p>It's worth noting that, in addition to the $1.7 billion of cash balances at year-end, the group also had around $1.4 billion of unused debt facilities available to it. Following the close-out of a number of ineffective interest rate hedges, the group currently has in place hedges covering 4.6 billion of debt in FY'10. As a result, we expect our all-in interest rate to be in the order of 8.5% for FY'10, although this of course will be dependent on official cash rates during the year and any changes to debt.</p>
          <p>Moving now to cash flow on slide 56. From the graph, it is evident that the cash generation was strong during the year, with a cash realization ratio of 117%. This was achieved through overall good working capital management across the group, as well as reflecting the non-cash nature of a number of the write-downs and provisions, as I've mentioned.</p>
          <p>Within this strong result, CSBP's cash flow was significantly negatively affected by reduced earnings and increased working capital usage from both high fertilizer inventory level at year end, as Keith has alluded to, as well as a reduction in creditors compared to the previous year following the completion of the AN2 expansion and reduced commodity prices as well.</p>
          <p>Working capital management was a highlight for the group, as you can see on slide 57, and reflects the delivery of strategies in Coles, Kmart and Target in particular to drive improvement in this area. This resulted in an inflow of over 300 million collectively across our retail businesses, with underlying improvement substantially stronger once you volume-growth or adjust for new stores.</p>
          <p>As mentioned, the non-retail businesses, particularly CSBP, partially offset the improvements we made in retail, but CSBP is focused very much on improving its working capital in the early part of this year, as well as further improving our focus across the group on working capital management.</p>
          <p>Finally, in regards to capital expenditure, which is on slide 58, total growth expenditure was 1.5 billion, and that was in line with the guidance that we gave in April. We continued to invest in organic growth opportunities across the group, which include rolling out new retail stores, refurbishing existing networks, as well as various other expansion projects, such as the Blackwater Creek diversion in our Resources division.</p>
          <p>Next year we expect the group's capital expenditure to increase to around 1.7 billion to 1.9 billion as Coles begins to ramp up its renewal program, other retail businesses continue to roll out and refurbish their stores and the Resources division complete its Blackwater Creek diversion.</p>
          <p>While this is our best indication at this stage of capital expenditure, the ultimate spend will of course, as usual, continue to depend on the proposals coming forward, meaning our financial hurdles, and, in the case of our retail businesses, will also depend to some extent on the level of property development opportunities that arise during the year that we're focused on.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand back to Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Terry. And just quickly on outlook, I think you've had outlook comments from the divisional heads. But quite clearly the economy is looking in better shape now than it did six months ago, although we still think there is a degree of fragility and we will be prudent in the manner in which we run businesses going forward. And to that extent we think retail trading conditions will be somewhat volatile and difficult to predict. And, as a number of the divisional managing directors said, we will be cycling against periods where there were significant stimulus payments last year.</p>
          <p>We will continue to have a very strong focus on the retail turnaround and executing those turnaround strategies and absolutely focusing on that in the coming year and years. We will obviously have a reduction in resources earnings, for the reasons Stewart pointed out. But we'd expect increase in earnings in many of our other businesses in the forthcoming year. And importantly, as I said earlier, a very strong focus on cash flow, return on capital and the balance sheet strength of the group as we move forward.</p>
          <p>And, with that, we are happy to take any questions anyone has.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And you first question comes from the line of Phillip Kimber from Goldman Sachs JBWere. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day. Richard, just wanted to ask a question on Coles. Particularly wanted to get a sense, the second half we saw margins up 30 basis points, can you provide some more (54.15) commentary around whether that would be the official guide to look to going forward in terms of a margin profile? Could you answer that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll let Ian McLeod answer that, Phil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think over five year program, you'd expect to see margins enhance. I wouldn't be predicting a quarter-on-quarter projection based upon these numbers. The focus is very much on driving the sales, improving service to customers and improving revenues, and profitability follows out of that, as indeed it has in these results. So it's an encouraging start. We'd expect to see it continue, but I wouldn't make a progression based upon what's been stated here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. There wasn't anything unusual in there, like particularly big wastage opportunities that you took in that half that helped the margins <mark type="inaudible" /> (55.09)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think this is &#x2013; the margin number is something which has kind of fallen out of a number of different programs that we've got in place and I've touched on a few of them as I went through the presentation. So we'll continue to make improvements on business efficiency as well as driving the customer offer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can I ask, I think you mentioned in there that the net supermarket numbers will increase by April 2010, notwithstanding the selling of 45 stores, did I read that right in the total stores still opening?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. There will be a net reduction during the course of the year. There's a balance here between the actual store numbers and the space. If you look at the space that's being transferred, the actual meterage and square meterage that's being transferred will have been offset by growth in supermarket numbers since the Wesfarmers acquisition and during the course of the year prior to the final transfer taking place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, yeah. So, there will be a net reduction in stores over the course of the next 12 months of about 32, but there will be a square meterage increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Okay. On regulators did you mention, Stewart, that the coal industry performed <mark type="inaudible" /> in general? Just wondered if you can clarify, is that dollar cost or dollar cost per ton?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll certainly do that, Phil. If you look at our cost increases that Curragh's had over the last 12 months, it's been very much in line with what's happened in the broader coal industry, and at the April Investor Relations Day, I presented a slide that showed Curragh's position in the lowest quartile of Australian hard cake and coal producers. And looking at, I suppose, the year ahead, since the onset of the global financial crisis at the beginning of this year we've implemented an aggressive cost reduction program. That program to date has delivered around about $90 million in cost savings. What we've been doing is clearly reviewing and reducing our contractor numbers, we've adjusted our pre-strip ahead of our dragline operations &#x2013; our high cost truck and shovel operations ahead of the draglines. And it's fair to say, last year in a period of very, very high coal prices, we were chasing and targeting to produce as much coal as we could during that period.</p>
          <p>We've also rationalized what work we do internally with our own employees and what we use in terms of contractors. Over the last six months or so we've seen fuel prices come down around about 36%. We've seen state government royalties, with the resetting of the coal price, it's going to come down around about 65% year-on-year. And we have aggressively approached all our coal &#x2013; all our suppliers and contractors for a major reduction in price of goods and services provided to us. And as we speak, we are out to tender for our long-term ten-year truck and shovel pre-strip operations at Curragh, so we expecting some substantial cost reductions in that area. So to-date we've pulled around about $90 million out of our cost structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And one last one if I could, on whether &#x2013; if we can get any comment on the sales momentum in July and August for the retail businesses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Phil, yeah, they're all different. July I think has probably been the first month where we've seen the lack of stimulus impact, and we've had across the group some very strong numbers and some more subdued numbers in July. But generally I described the environment as solid but not spectacular at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Shaun Cousins from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just a question in regards to Coles. Can we just get a fragmentation (59.22) of the quantum of the provision release, half-on-half in '09 and also how much was released in the second half '08 as well, please? And if you did this as a big contract provision, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Terry. It would be the same, Shaun. So it's &#x2013; we quoted 67 million a year and effectively it's half-on-half. So just divide it by two, it'd be exactly the same number on both halves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, guys, are you still there? I haven't heard anything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I can hear you, Terry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You can? Sorry, I'll say it again. The meat (60.01) contract we've disclosed previously was 67, and that's half &#x2013; so that's effectively spread half-on-half or equally divided between the two halves and it was in place for both periods. So it's the net impact that has no impact on the comparison.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there's no change, okay. All right. We didn't specifically get which you guys had indicated what size square meterage you use without hotels. Can you just tell us what hotels contributed on &#x2013; in full year '09?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We haven't broken that out separately, but the overall hotels business is a marginal position relative to the total comp. So it's not significantly material to strip out separately.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I guess it was stripped out of the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. There seems that seemed to cause as much confusion as it caused clarity, so we're just showing an inclusive number now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can you talk a bit about &#x2013; I know Phil asked about July trading, we understand July trading in Coles has been quite weak on the back of some promotional activities that potentially might not have hit the mark. Could you maybe talk a bit about where you guys are at with that and what sort of changes you've got in place to improve trading in the remainder of the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I certainly wouldn't describe our trading as weak. But I think that it's certainly probably premature to talk about quarter one. And we'll no doubt talk about that in a bit more detail when we meet again in October. We instigated some changes to our promotional program and the way that we communicate to customers. In fresh food that's been particularly well received. We had some early transitional issues in grocery but now they've been resolved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, because we hear in the trade that you guys have lost market share in a meaningful way in July as a result of some of those threes and twos not working and the crater store (61.54) not working.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look at our market share, it's broadly in line, if anything there's been slight improvement in market share. So I think whatever you're hearing in the trade is being overstated from what we see in our numbers during the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just, maybe one for you, Terry, just in regards to your capital position, just given we've got &#x2013; potentially you might have the expansion of Curragh coming through in a few years and then you'll also have a ramp-up in the refurbishment profile. Could you talk a bit about how confident you are of repaying all that debt? Or is it just the assumption that the debt that you've got maturing in fiscal '12, fiscal '11 will actually be rolled?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I said, we've got a very strong balance sheet at the moment. Our aim probably isn't to end up with no debt on our balance sheet but we're very confident that we can certainly roll forward our debt at this stage. Our bank conversations are all good. We've obviously got a number of years. We've got a very good cash position on our balance sheet. At the moment we're generating a good amount of cash, as you can see, coming through the business. So there's &#x2013; from that front there's not a lot keeping me awake at night.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And finally, just in terms of Apache, when do you start receiving insurance proceeds on the back of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of Varanus Island you mean, Shaun?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, please, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Keith Gordon here. I would expect that that will take quite some time to come through. To be honest, some of the claims have been lodged, we're finalizing others. But with these processes, we're not counting on receiving monies from that in the immediate future. And just to clarify, we haven't allowed for that in any of the '09 results, so they don't include any provisions for insurance claims received.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Shaun, we'll let you know when they come through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If and when.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the Craig Woolford from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys. First questions just on Coles, just wanted to understand perhaps in a little bit more detail where the source of margin expansion has come from. I'm interested in the impact of &#x2013; on gross margins and cost of doing business, I guess in particular the background about the increased value message that you are presenting to shoppers. So, has gross margins fallen in the FY '09 year or risen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I wouldn't go into that much detail at this stage, we'll probably talk in a bit more depth when we go into the full investor meeting later on in the year. I think there are a number of different dynamics that are operating within the margins, within our business and we're making improvements in some areas which is affording us the opportunity to invest in others to drive volume and grow customers. So we're pretty encouraged by the overall performance on sales, customer numbers and basket. So I wouldn't go into specifics on the specific dynamics within that, but generally, we are satisfied with the progression and the balance between sales and margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And the other comment that was made, I was intrigued on the outlook statement that the first bullet was that economic conditions remained fragile, for the food and liquor business where do you see that fragility actually hurting the business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that &#x2013; the balance there is looking at &#x2013; I think that the value-conscious consumer is something that's here to stay. We had a situation where the economic position is stronger now than it was six months ago, as Richard mentioned. So from our point of view we think the market will still remain competitive. We'll very much focus on continuing to deliver value to customers. We are seeing trends where commodity areas like rice, pasta, cooking sauces are all showing above average growth and indeed we're seeing that in house brand as well, and the feed the family for under $10 program that we've developed has actually seen good growth in the products that are featured in those recipes.</p>
          <p>So I think generally the consumer is still circumspect. Clearly the benefits that we have in Australia in terms of the economy are stronger than they are elsewhere in the world, but having said that, I think the consumer confidence, whilst it's improved, will still be fragile if we don't see further economic growth into the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So would you see an impact on sales or margins there, I mean, because the industry growth has been quite phenomenal for the last 12 months, so the supermarket market industry would have actually benefited from the economic climate, do you see...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think you've got &#x2013; I mean, obviously we've seen some benefits coming through in overall sales in the dynamic splits. We've also seen people trading down as well. They're looking to stretch their dollar further so the benefit of house brand growth is seen as a result of that. Even things as simple as trade-downs on batteries from high powered batteries to standard ones, they're just little indications that the consumer is looking to ensure that they are wise with their money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You mentioned that the auto-replenishment was going to be slowly rolled out over the latter part of this year. It's now back to the takeover documents, but at the time there was indications that supply chain savings could amount to $485 million, is that still within the realms of possibility?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're looking to improve this sufficiency (67.29) in a number of areas. Again, I'm not going to comment specifically on individual cash elements within each of the cost levers, but now that we've got the change in transition in supply chain that will definitely help in terms of drive out further efficiencies. Part of that will include the rollout of auto-replenishment.</p>
          <p>We don't want to move quickly on that, because if you move too fast then your ability to deliver it effectively first time is going to be severely compromised, in my experience. But we've got some trial stores that are proving to be very successful in implementation and we'll be moving to a broader rollout during the course of the next few months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just lastly a more broad question on FX, foreign currency has obviously moved around a lot, how much of a drag was it on some of the non-food businesses in FY '09? And I guess also how will it feature as an impact in FY '10? Are the hedges already locked in at lower rates than we see today at spot?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Craig, I'll give an overview of this, if John or Launa or Guy or Ian want to jump in they can. I think we've managed the businesses very effectively through &#x2013; the retail businesses very effectively through times when currency was moving rapidly. Some of the businesses have had some hedging in place, but we've also moved on pricing in stores and we've also moved on negotiations with our suppliers to mitigate any impact there. So I think if you look at the results it would indicate that we've ridden out a very volatile period in the A-dollar pretty well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean, which suggests that there is some upside to margins for some of these businesses in FY '10.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I reckon it gets overdone. I reckon it gets a bit overdone on the downside and the upside. But clearly it has an impact. We're in a position where we've got a strong position with our customers; in businesses like Bunnings we're able to move the impact up and down reasonably quickly and I think we've managed it pretty well in Target and Kmart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Emily Van Keefe from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just a couple of questions on coal, you mentioned that you've achieved 90 million of cost savings. I'm just wondering over what period you achieved those cost savings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Emily, since the beginning of this year we've, as I said before -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that in FY '09 or is that...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's basically comparing our cost structure at the beginning of calendar year, so middle of the financial year, to where we are today, we've pulled out around about $90 million of cost. And we've implemented an aggressive cost reduction program, we've brought in external assistance with a major improvement firm, Partners in Progress (70.43), and we're very, very happy with the progress to date. But in terms of moving forward, we've set our sights on significantly higher cost reductions than what's been implemented today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Emily, just to clarify, that's a $90 million per annum savings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not 90 million we've saved between 1 January and now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so you would expect significantly more savings fur the full year '10?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just in terms of some of &#x2013; in terms of your comment on where your position is in cost curve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That hasn't changed, now the currency is it sort of 83, 84 still in the first quartile or is that in A-dollar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's an A-dollar number. At the moment we normally get that reviewed once a year. The next review of the Australian hard cake and coal producers' cost curve comes out in the first quarter post January this year coming up. So, we will &#x2013; that's the next touch point to determine where we're at. But at the moment what we are experiencing through our export operations is similar to other coal producers. So we expect it to remain in the lowest quartile and that's certainly our target going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just finally, in terms of China has been importing a significant amount of coal, significantly more than what they have done in the past. Just wondering if you're exporting any coal into China or if you view those exports as less reliable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly our view is we're not looking to have a dependence on the Chinese market. We've got a great customer base across the world, but particularly in the North Asian market. So, we're not aggressively chasing to place tonnage into China. There's no doubt it is an emerging marketplace at the moment. The last quarter we've seen an annualized rate of exports into China of something like about 35 million tons per annum, compared to 12 months earlier of about five. So they are certainly making a major impact on the market going forward.</p>
          <p>At the moment we're also seeing, I suppose, restocking happening with our traditional customers, particularly in Japan, Korea, Taiwan, where demand all of a sudden has jumped up over the last couple of months and we're starting to see some positive signs in the marketplace. So I think that's the conclusion at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Grant Saligari from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning or good afternoon, guys. Look, I have to say I thought the performance on the retail businesses was quite solid from both a market and capital point of view, so that was well done. But I am a bit disappointed that you're not prepared to talk about the movement in the CAGB integrated margin lines in the Coles business, because that goes to improving competitiveness in that business, and it's relatively easy to make money when the industry is growing at better than 9% per annum. Mate, can you give some sort of indication as to the direction of movement in those lines and how the overall competitiveness of the business is improving or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that, as I said before, the scale of change that's going on in Coles is significant and the number of programs that we've got in place to drive out those changes are multi and varied. So we're looking at improvements in fresh food rotation in the stores, we're looking at improvements in waste management, we're looking at improvements in supply chain efficiency into the stores itself, we're looking at improvements in rostering efficiency rather than just simply cutting costs on wages.</p>
          <p>So there are a number of different cost levers that are being looked at and addressed to drive out improvements in overall cost that we can then look to &#x2013; afford to invest in driving the top line as opposed to just looking at trying to improve profitability through a cost cutting exercise. So it's a balance between the two elements, cost and revenue drivers that's delivering the result that we are seeing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you think you've successfully repositioned the supermarket business in terms of value, so that as we go forward into the next 12 and 18 months you should be able to hold your gross margin line and then start to build some of that operating leverage back again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there is still more work to be done, I think I indicated that in the presentation that we'll still be looking to invest in value. You know this is a company which really had lost its away for some considerable time. It's still very early days in the turnaround and we've still got a lot of work to do. So have we improved our value position? Yes, I think we have and that's been demonstrated both by sales and customer transactions and basket value. But is there more that we need to &#x2013; I certainly believe that we have got more work to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just on the convenience business, what happened with the profit line there, because obviously you've got quite good store sales growth, yet the trading unit was basically flat. Should we assume that basically the offset there was fuel, or what was...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. There is a combination of &#x2013; obviously there is a lot of profitability driven not on a liter basis, but certainly on a volume basis that comes through fuel. There was considerable deflation in fuel year-on-year, but actually the underlying growth in the shop sales was quite strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one on that, maybe just more detail on the significant items on the provisions. Just going back to the first half numbers, and there was a number in the self insurance which was negative $48 million, I was just trying to sort of trace that back to where that's ended up in the full year results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's in the other, Grant. That's &#x2013; there's a self-insurance provision that I mentioned. So it actually declined a little bit from the number that we gave you, and then was offset by, as I said, a number of small write-downs of some partially &#x2013; investments that we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that other has the investment write-downs from the first half, the self insurance, the interest rate swap close-outs and the some offsetting from positives?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well it is broken out on the slide, I think. So in other &#x2013; the key issues in other are the interest rate reduction and the impact that had on our self-insurance provisions, which is the material amount of the 50 and then there is a number of mark-to-market on some directly held investments that we've had small investments where you just adjust, so things like <mark type="inaudible" /> property tax, management fund and things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one more question, I just think, sorry, I need to ask on the Coles business. When you look at the new store formats, are they achieving return on capital and margin hurdles that are better than the Group average at the moment or are you still work in progress on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, as I said, we've got pilots in every state now and we're pleased with the overall customer receptivity to those stores but they are still very much in pilot, so we are continuing to work on improving our understanding of the dynamics of those particular stores in a number of different areas, so that's something we will continue to do. But we will still continue to progress our roll out during quarter this year. We'd anticipate having around 50 on the ground before the end of this financial year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot. That's all for me. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Grant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Greg Dring from Macquarie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon guys. How are you? Ian, can I just start with you, the trade feedback about this July issue, it sounds like a ticketing problem, you couldn't actually ticket. Is that correct? And did it materially adversely affect sales in a couple of key categories and have you fixed it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The ticketing change, as I mentioned before, took place in the early part of July. The &#x2013; to improve communication, which works well on fresh, we had to do some more work to improve visibility on grocery and that's been done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the feedback was that the tickets were too small?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the tickets weren't too small. It was a visibility issue in terms of the information that was on the shelf edge label, but that's been resolved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It just &#x2013; all it needed was to increase the font size.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it's not that we <mark type="inaudible" /> ourselves that first quarter comps were affected by this issue in a couple of months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that there is an overall balance of what we'll talk about on the first quarter comps when we get to the end of the first quarter, we're only halfway through at the moment, Greg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Just on the easy-order, you'd previously told us that maybe three, four, five, six stores are on trial. How many stores are on trial now and how many are you going to roll out and in which quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is about seven at the moment and they are going very well. I imagine that in the next couple of months we'll move that out to around 30 and I think I said that by the end of the financial year we'll have about 100 on, I think we're still on track to achieve that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that going to be fully automated for all categories within the store?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of the fresh categories won't be included but the vast bulk of the volume in grocery and dairy and frozen food, all of those key categories will be covered by the change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just quickly on loyalty, the programs you've been running for the last two blocks of three months. Can you comment on what they've achieved in terms of either identifying customers, improving sales or driving sort of repeat purchases in-store?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The enhanced program that we put in place has actually been very well received by customers that signed up to it. So we've seen increases in their basket size as a result of changes that we've made. So we're quite pleased with the program, in fact we extended that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now Terry, the working capital disclosure was a little confusing. Just at a Group level what was the usage or source of funds for the full year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Whereabouts are you talking &#x2013; I mean on slide 57, Greg, the 141 looks at the movement in inventories, trade and other receivables, prepayments and trade and other payables...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's the number for at the Group level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That's the Group level, if you add up the four A it should tot up to the 141 for those categories. I mean what I've done is give you more disclosure to show you that we are making headway in the retail business, as we said we would.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that the source or are you summing up the <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>141, source or used?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the source.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Just on resources, 90 million cost savings and then there was an additional comment, we are going to reduce royalty payments, for obvious reasons, by up to 65%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Was that correct, did I hear correctly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, obviously the state government royalties come down ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...as the coal price comes down, Greg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes. So I heard correctly, that's your forecast?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just on cost per ton &#x2013; cash cost per ton at the entire Group level, it went up 41% to 60 something dollars, or I think about nine of that was royalties, so what else was actually in there, I mean it can't be lots of little things to get such a significant increase in costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we think the underlying number is closer to 30 than 40, Greg, but if you look at what's included in that, is clearly the Forex losses and the close-outs for last year was 88. The increase in Stanwell rebate that's gone up 58 last year to 170 this year. The increase in the state royalties, which has gone up from 58 last year to 208 this year and that's an increase of 150, and the other item that we'll disclose this time is our purchased coal.</p>
          <p>What we do is we do purchase some coal during the year to smooth out the variations between production and sales and basically we buy that coal and resell it with little or no margin, so that should be netted off against revenue and costs in terms of our overall cost structure, and that purchased coal list is not included in either our production statements or our sales statements, it's just there as a pass through in both costs and revenue.</p>
          <p>And the other thing that's clearly impacted that should be discounted ultimately is the impact of the Dragline 302 accident that we had in December last year, not only the accident itself but obviously the additional costs we had to implement in order to maintain our production in terms of moving costs from dragline, which is our lowest cost of overburn removal to truck and shovel which is about four times the cost of dragline. So there are number of issues that impact on the cost, but looking at the underlying costs, it's gone up by about 30%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What was the purchased coal number? I didn't see. If you did disclose it, I missed it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The purchased coal is &#x2013; the revenue side of it's included on the slide on page 36, Greg. And it's there in the first footnote, includes traded coal of $170 million in 2009 compared to 42 in 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I thought that was the thermal, but that's not the thermal that you're talking about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so then this is basically where you just got to replenish your stockpile with stuff you've sold that you didn't basically dig out of the ground and replace it with. Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, traded coal is &#x2013; it's about 5% of our production is additional &#x2013; but about 5% of our total sales is the number we use for traded coal. And what we do is we buy that coal when &#x2013; it's to match the production side of our business to the shipping side. And when the ships turn up, it may not necessarily (85.13) have the full complement of coal <mark type="inaudible" /> but the site. And we just vary our production and shipping by having access to light coal to blend with our sales volume. So it's about 5% of our total volume, it's not included in our numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fine, thank you. And I'm sorry, just the follow-up question from me &#x2013; no, that's it. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Greg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cheers, Greg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Ben Gilbert from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys. First question, just for John, on the Home Improvement side of things, I just was wondering if you can comment a little bit about mix. Over the over the half-year we've seen the margins that are flat to marginally down, and if we look forward and I suppose we start (85.54) to push instead of some of the cooking and those sort of areas &#x2013; what the expectation is going to be there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, in terms of the overall mix, given the growth we had through the retail side of the business and the fact that volumes went backwards a little on trade, our core ratio that we disclosed around our cash and credit, credit being our proxy for the trade volumes, has improved towards the retail side. So sitting around the 82, 83 mark to 17, 18 rather than 80-20, the trade side of the business is very cyclical, so if we get a strong uplift in housing construction, we would expect that ratio to go back the other way and sit around that more long-term average of 80-20.</p>
          <p>Inside the business, we had good growth across all of our categories. And in some areas we were able to improve the overall mix from a margin perspective because of that &#x2013; because of some things we were doing inside trading terms and inside, what we were presenting in terms of the offer for customers. In other areas we went much harder on price to chase our new position and establish things.</p>
          <p>So we've never commented and provided disclosure inside our category mix in terms of gross margins. I'm not going to start that now. But we are pleased to have growth in all categories. We are pleased that we had a lift in our net margin that was driven by good performance on costs, good performance on operational efficiencies and good management at a merchandizing level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So when we start to look forward from here to the 12-18 months, two years time and I suppose some of the newer categories you're pushing into, they look to be sort of some lower category and a lower margin on the bulk. Should &#x2013; do you expect to see further I suppose the margins start to come down or will leverage offset that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We expect to be able to sell a mix of products that keeps margins where they are sitting at around about the moment. Net margins grew a little bit and we were pleased with that. If we can work very hard on our cost structure, we can pass more value through to customers and that is our aim.</p>
          <p>So when we model gross margins for the long term, we actually model gross margins going down. But that doesn't mean we're modeling net margins going down because we work very hard to reduce costs. And we work hard to push that value through both to our bottom line and through to our customers in the form of lower prices. And that's something that sits as a core of our operating principles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just on the Officeworks side of things, I know Richard commented on characterizing. So you guys have always said that the Officeworks <mark type="inaudible" /> so the SME side of things has always been a pretty good proxy for the economy in terms of when they come in, start spending again. Can you comment in terms of how you've seen trade in there over the past couple of months, looking into the ship?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not sure we've said it's a great proxy for the economy. Clearly, the small business sector is one that is very exposed to sentiment and very exposed to sharp shifts in spend. What we've seen in the last little while is a pleasing return to some confidence. And we're seeing better results in the direct business segment, which is pleasing us.</p>
          <p>That's come about not just because of confidence. I think we're doing some very good things in there after having to disrupt our sales in one sense to actually reset the strategy and have one business offer. And we had to also get rid of some very unproductive discounting and very unproductive selling techniques.</p>
          <p>And Mark Ward and the team have done a very good job there. And we expect to see some modest growth in the BusinessDirect sector as we go forward with a combination of what we're doing and a combination of a lift in SME confidence. But I would caution there that it is a very volatile and very exposed segment and if things tweak the other way you can expect that they will cut back spend very sharply.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />. And thanks. And just one more &#x2013; few more questions on Coles, and Ian, if I could. Can you just give us a sort of a little bit of commentary just in terms around category performance? I know you've sort of given some numbers or guidance previous that are fresh and private label.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we're seeing good growth in private label as I intimated previously. That goes back to the fact that the consumer is becoming more value conscious. The areas that relate to in-home dining really, are performing above average.</p>
          <p>So things like rice and pasta and cooking sauce as I mentioned before, we've seen growth in those particular areas. We're starting to see some signs of improvement in the fresh food categories as well, particularly on fruit and veg.</p>
          <p>So across the organization we're seeing steady improvements coming through. And I think that's reflected in the basket growth that we are getting and the improvement in customer transactions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And also just in terms of the extent of the price investment, I know last year you sort of quantified and said you didn't invest around 100 million in price over the period. Can you give us I suppose a better feel for this the extent to which you're investing in price at the moment and I suppose the extent to which you feel you're going to have to do that more so going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's quite &#x2013; I mean you got to look at &#x2013; it's different in different categories. And I think that we've just got to focus on making sure that we improve overall value. I have not put a number on it. Again you got a gross and net number in terms of transactional differences between individual parts of our business. But I guess a good indication of the level of investment is indicative in the inflation numbers, which have actually &#x2013; we've actually had a slower rate of inflation this quarter that we had the previous one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you expect the inflation to continue to ease as we get towards the end of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that it's been &#x2013; in our numbers it's been anywhere between two and 3% during the course of last year. I wouldn't expect any fundamental shift away from where we've been getting it currently.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just one final question. In terms of the market growth, if you look at the real growth we have had across the market over the past, I suppose, 12 months or so that's been alluded to, give us a feel in terms of what sort of growth rates you guys are looking at going forward. I just heard you say macros <mark type="inaudible" /> (92.08) may be starting to edge out a little bit more again and population growth slowing, those sorts of things?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean I wouldn't again comment specifically on growth forecast. But we would expect the business to continue to perform at a progressive growth trend. I think that what we've got to do is recognize that quarter-on-quarter and half-on-half, there will be variation. And we're still very much focused on driving the turnaround, then it's across a five year plan.</p>
          <p>So I think that's our focus. The early results are encouraging during the course of this particular year compared to where we were the previous year. But there is still a significant amount of work to be done in the organization in order to bring about sustainable change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's everything. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from David Cooke from RBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, all. A couple of quick questions if I may. What were your food sales like in Coles? I suppose the other way of asking the question is when you look at sales growing ahead of your food sales during the half or because of the reinvestment that you had after (93.24) the growth in the food section (93.25) that's been <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again, we don't break out the overall growth in each of those individual areas but I'm pleased to sort of say we're seeing growth both in food and indeed in liquor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because you started your &#x2013; you've probably got further ahead in your restructuring of the liquor side catch (93.45) the food side, so I'm trying to see whether the the sense (93.46) that you've got there is a big <mark type="inaudible" /> incentive (93.48) that we should be seeing over the next six to 12 months in the supermarket side of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I am not sure that that's the case. I mean clearly there is a number of factors that need to be improved in food but actually liquor needs to have some fairly significant change as well. There's been investment in price to drive further value both in food and liquor and it's getting encouraging results in both categories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ian, you talked about improving your basket sizes and your foot traffic, can you give us an indication as to how much has improved <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again we've seen sort of progress in each of them. It's something which is encouraging. I think that our total numbers will indicate that we've seen a growth quarter-on-quarter across the year. And that's the real number to focus on. But I think the reason we try to give indication on that is that it's a combination of factors that are heading in the right direction that's driving that and not just any particular one aspect to it. But I won't be breaking it down into individual areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would it be true to say then if you're attracting more customers into your stores, that that's probably a better growth profile that you are getting market side or is it the fact that your stalwart Coles customers are actually getting &#x2013; actually buying more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a combination of both. I think that the &#x2013; when we look to the overall plan of improvement for Coles and how we might drive change, we fully recognize that there is a strong fresh food opportunity. And we had a number of customers coming through our doors already but we probably weren't giving them the complete offer to encourage them to buy from us and that's what we've been working on trying to improve. And that's been beneficial in terms of growing the basket size.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I look at the margin improvement that you've got today, to what extent have you been able to capture the low hanging fruit, and to what extent is the growth profile or the improvement in Coles' profile over the next 12 months going to be increasingly more difficult?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it hasn't felt that easy in the first 12 months, to be perfectly honest. But the next 12 months are obviously going to be challenging as a step on in expectation. The first couple of years are about building a solid foundation and that's what we continue to do.</p>
          <p>If there have been opportunities to capture low hanging fruit as you describe it, we've endeavored to take it. But it's a multifaceted change program we're developing and getting consistent change in improvements will take time. But we're very much focused on it. It's an encouraging start. But we've certainly got a lot more work to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a question for Stewart on the resources side. Stewart, the increase in your expectations of Curragh sales for FY '10, is that all contracted or is some of that going to be sold on spot? Is that increase a matter of being (96.42) sold on spot?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's all contracted with our existing customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So now your production expectation fully match your contracted volume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that &#x2013; sort of within 100 or couple of 100,000 tons, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, I think that just reflects in many ways a view now that customer will take a bit more of what they committed to than they might have three or six &#x2013; we might have thought they would three or six months ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it &#x2013; would I be correct in saying, the previous guidance was probably towards the low end of contracted range, the new guidance is probably towards the upper end of contracted range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't read that into it at all. Basically, we are still taking a pretty conservative view of the market place going forward. It's early days in terms of the recovery, and I think our numbers should reflect that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we've done &#x2013; what we were pleased with &#x2013; and Stewart said this I think in April, what we were pleased with was the level of commitments we did get from our customers at a time when markets were really disruptive and steel production was down. And that was because they value Curragh as a supplier &#x2013; they have a very high value on Curragh as a supplier. And I think that that puts the business in good shape.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you sell any volume on spot?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not per se. The only time we've sold into the spot market was the last quarter in the last financial year, particularly as a result of what was happening in the PCI market where we were struggling to place all our production into that market. We had to sell some coal into the spot market and divert some PCI into the export thermal coal market as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now would you look to sell spot this year if pricing continues to improve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, our philosophy is very much to look after our existing customer base. We have got great customers and 85% of those are in the North Asia, South Asia market place. And we see our obligations to them first. If there is excess capacity above that then clearly other options are available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from David Errington from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Dave. How are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, thanks. Gresham, when are you going to write the other 122 off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I suspect we won't have to. But only time will tell. What &#x2013; there's a couple of things on the Gresham Private Equity. On Fund 1, as you say &#x2013; as Terry mentioned has been a really terrific investment. We did account for Fund 1 differently. We are counting Funds 2 and 3 differently to Fund 1 where they are mark to market each quarter. Fund 1, we kept that the lower of costs to realizable value.</p>
          <p>And so you'll get some movement as the Fund &#x2013; quarterly as the Fund looks at current carrying value at any particular time and that reflects pay-in multiples and current trading additions and whatever. So we've got a mix of investments in Fund 2. Some of those are looking very good. Some of those are being challenged in the current economic environment. But I'm still confident that ultimately, investment in that will be a good investment for our shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I've heard that &#x2013; I've been hearing, I don't know if it's true or not, but I'm hearing that Barminco, Witchery and Noel Leeming are going on on flats (100.19), I don't know about the others, but...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me tell you that all of those businesses &#x2013; you're completely wrong. Witchery is performing exceptionally well, Barminco is on track, and Noel Leeming, I mean, Noel Leeming's been part of the New Zealand economy and that economy has been difficult but in recent times Noel Leeming's been going well as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, when &#x2013; I mean, you know what I'm going to ask you, I mean, you're a top ten or twenty company &#x2013; diversified company, focused now on retail, coal assets, got a range of other assets, why are you doing discretion private equity fund cuts? I mean, why bother? I mean, you've got 60 million here, you've got 122 million, I mean the 60 million loss is your share of the equity, I mean, that <mark type="inaudible" /> (100.12) has probably lost four times that if you look at the debt that has to be written off and the non-equity value of your part or the equity value your partner. Why do that? (101:21)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, David, if you'd been given a chance to invest $100 million and got 27% internal rate of return on it &#x2013; annualized internal rate of return on that investment, would you do it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I might do it directly but I wouldn't do it via Wesfarmers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, why wouldn't we do it for our shareholders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because we don't &#x2013; shareholders don't invest in Wesfarmers for you to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They invest in Wesfarmers to make a decent return on their investment and -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you're not a private equity fund now, you're a public listed company now with a large retail business et cetera, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a degree of influence in these funds. We actually think the exposure to the whole private equity thing and these businesses is good for us. We second employees into Gresham. Terry and I and now Tim Bult sit on investment committee. And it gives us a window into other businesses. So we think there is other benefits but ultimately the reason we do it is because we think we'll make a decent financial return and we've had the capacity to do it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I suppose we'll agree to disagree.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The bottom line is that if I was an investor, I would certainly want my Managing Director focusing on improving Coles rather than investing in Barminco, but anyway, I'll move on.</p>
          <p>Insurance, I've never seen the core ratio of Wesfarmers insurance business being above 100%. And now I do &#x2013; what's happening in the insurance underwriting business &#x2013; I mean I know it's tough but Wesfarmers always used to pride itself, no matter how tough the market was, you'd always have a core in the very low 90s. But now you're well above 100, I mean, that to me is a situation that is very alarming.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll let Rob answer it. It's certainly not a performance that any of us is happy with, but I think the factors that impacted that business this year clearly indicate why it's happened.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, David, Rob here. You're right that since 2004 since the collapse of HIH and the introduction of APRA regulation and so forth in Australia, Australian insurers have enjoyed very strong combined operating ratios as a result of that. That period also coincided with a period of fairly benign weather.</p>
          <p>If you go back a bit longer than that, you go back to '99, 2000 you'll see that our ratios were up at that level as were Lumley's and indeed the rest of the markets were quite a bit higher. And what we're finding as I said earlier, the weather related events over the last 12 months have essentially resulted in 10 times the level of claims that we have experienced over the last 15 year average.</p>
          <p>So when a factor like that happens when you have the bush fires coinciding with significant weather events particularly along the East Coast of Australia, as an insurer, it's pretty hard to hide from that. And I think you'll find other Australian property insurers, short-tail insurers are being exposed in very similar ways.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's one-off, Rob, it's not &#x2013; you haven't increased the risk of your writings have you? Or it's purely just one-off weather events?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No that's &#x2013; the weather events are a very key part of it. I did mention &#x2013; I have mentioned over the last year that we believe that the two Lumley businesses can perform better than they had done. That is not the key driver of performance this year. The key driver is weather-related events. We've signaled a strong improvement in performance in our New Zealand business and we're working on very similar strategies to improve performance in Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, David, just as part of that, you will have seen recently we exited builders warranty insurance in New South Wales and that's part of that sort of operational review that Rob has talked about which has been really extensive across the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Launa must be saying, gee whiz, why isn't anyone asking me questions, ask a bit <mark type="inaudible" /> for Target and Kmart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>She's happy, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm fine, David. You don't have to ask anything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Launa, what's your view towards the upcoming year, particularly the cycle post stimulus? What are you going to be doing for the business going forward? Because this result would have to be an all-time record, fantastic outcome, but how do you face 2010 having to stand up and compare against this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look David I think it is going to be a challenging one. And we're playing it okay in the sense that we're going according to plan at the moment in the beginning of the new financial year. But we do recognize that December is going to be quite a tough month due to the fact that there was a big stimulus program last year. The only thing I can say is that really applies to all retailers and the stimulus package went out to everyone and of course as well for this March, April period.</p>
          <p>The thing that we did well is we were able to respond to it, particularly in March and April, because we did a lot of analysis on what had happened in December and then went in and bought product accordingly. We're still really managing our inventory levels very tightly and keeping a strong focus on our costs. But also recognizing that some of our categories are performing well and we're going to continue to make sure that we're well-stocked of those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you, but you &#x2013; I mean it's going to be pretty hard coming up against this. Have you got any idea what the stimulus gave you, or are you just not prepared to say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do have an idea and I will be quite honest and say we did benefit from it. And that's what we're going to have to work out as to how we sum up those figures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, finally, when I look at this result, I see some good, some average and some below average. And there's some below average here that basically you've got to question what the future is for them being part of the Wesfarmers business mix. I won't name those but you could probably work out that there's been some pretty ordinary performance here. Why &#x2013; are you going to &#x2013; why persist with some businesses?</p>
          <p>And I suppose my question is the concern that I've got it is that you've become so big, so diverse now, so many people are focused on Coles. I mean the questions today, probably 70%, are on Coles. Hardly any questions are on the non-retail business which gives an indication of the investor interest. In my experience with companies that get little interest in them, those businesses are the ones that really do deteriorate. How are you going to ensure that those businesses don't deteriorate and continue to detract from what could be an important turnaround?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, David, we're certainly not happy with the performance of some of the businesses last year. We understand the factors that led to that, but you can't be happy with the outcomes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of those factors were within your control, some were without your control, but there's some that were within your control.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what I'm concerned about. And Wesfarmers management used to be all over it, and then when you start getting things that sneak through, it just means that there's probably been a bit of lack of focus. And that's where I'm hard on aggression, is when you get these issues coming out, it just shows that management can't be in 100 places at one time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. See, that's where I will disagree with you. I think if you look &#x2013; firstly, I reckon, the diversified nature of the Group for the last 12 months has been a real benefit. We've got cash flows coming in from even the businesses that didn't perform as well as we may have liked to generate cash. And in the environment we've been in that's really good.</p>
          <p>If you also look at what we've done in some of the non-retail businesses in the last couple of years, we significantly increased production capacity at CSBP and we continue to do that. We've commenced the Blackwater Creek Diversion at Curragh and as Stewart said, we're looking at how we can increase production not only at Curragh but also at Bengalla. The ongoing improvement growth in industrial and safety division continues. The insurance business has continued to acquire small businesses, and we've commenced LNG production at &#x2013; in the energy division.</p>
          <p>So we're doing a lot in each these businesses. And because of the Wesfarmers model we actually can focus on them. So I don't try and run these businesses, we have very good reporting systems and processes in the Group. We have very good governance processes in the Group.</p>
          <p>We have excellent executives running these businesses. And I'm quite satisfied that in fact we'll get as good or better outcome from these businesses within Wesfarmers as we would outside the Group because of that business model.</p>
          <p>And I think a really good example is the insurance division. Because the insurance division is in the Wesfarmers Group, Rob has had the capacity this year to effect the sort of changes that will make a meaningful long-term difference to insurers, whereas if he was a separately listed company, he'd have everyone on his back about short-term earnings outcomes. And so I think, I'm a strong supporter of the business model and we'll continue to support each of the businesses in the Group. We will be after decent returns on capital from all of them, and we'll be allocating new capital where we'll get the best returns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Richard Barwick from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Couple of questions on Coles for starters. Just thinking, looking across the slides here, there is lots of data out there about investment in stores and basically I guess putting more money into the business. I can see clearly there's some scope for working capital improvements. But can you talk a little bit &#x2013; or, Ian, perhaps talk a little bit about actual cost-reduction possibilities from here? For example, are there any further potential to reduce head count in head office or is that as far as it's going to go?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the head count has been fairly significantly reduced already in head office. We're always looking at each of the cost lines that we have to see how we might improve, and some of those will be how can we get more efficiencies in terms of people costs. The reality is we're still adding value in terms of jobs, as we develop more stores and expand existing ones.</p>
          <p>You obviously look at each of the individual cost lines, whether it's supply chain, whether it's wasted mark-downs in stores or rostering in stores as well. But it's &#x2013; it's about driving efficiency in order to improve ratios and improve the revenue line as much as looking for cost-reduction opportunities. But where there are opportunities, we're identifying them and we'll put programs in place to take them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Margin expansion from here will be more a leverage issue rather than actual elimination of costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it'll be a combination of both if I'm honest. I think that there are ways in which we can improve our efficiency and reduce our costs. We can't just do it just by simply taking money out, otherwise the business will go back to the way that it was. This business needs re-generation, and it needs that level of focus. And we need to make sure that our managers have got the effective tools and investment to do that job. That's why we've invested quite heavily in equipment where it's required.</p>
          <p>But actually there should be efficiency that comes out the back of that. If you're going to put in self-scanning it helps the customer, actually helps the cost line as well, as an example. So, you're looking at a pre-granular level of detail and you will see those improvements come through over time. But as I said before, there are a myriad of challenges that we face. We still face some now, but it's an encouraging short-term early performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And thinking about some of the actions of Woolworths in terms of their driving loyalty through their everyday rewards card, frequent flyers, et cetera, et cetera. Are we going to see something from you guys re fly-bys?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, loyalty schemes, where they're run by retailers, are an element in the marketing mix. They're not a primary determinant of store choice in my experience. I mean value and convenience are significantly higher. So we were looking to see how loyalty plays out in relation to developing our overall marketing initiatives and programs to customers and we've got one or two trials in place at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our general view on it is, and experience is that customers do tend to prefer in-loyalty schemes some form of cash reward as opposed to payments in-kind. And I think the docket program that was developed on fuel is a very good example of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question for Launa, just thinking currency &#x2013; I know, Richard, you said before you felt like the impact was a little bit overstated, perhaps upside and downside. So I'd just be interested to get a view there on how the average currency for this current financial year FY '10 will compare to FY '09, presumably you've got hedging through to the end of the year or very close to it by now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do take currency. We take currency as we go along right the way through, as we did last financial year. Where we're sitting at the moment for the first half of this financial year, it will be at a dollar rate less than it was for the last financial year. But also understanding that the forward cover even for the back half of the financial year we've just had was less than it was for the previous year as well. So it's just something we have to manage and &#x2013; but we do take a forward cover because we really do strongly believe that we're in the game of retailing and not in the game of speculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Richard and/or Terry, just thinking about dividends, I mean, it was a nice surprise to see the $1.10 today rather than the $1.00. How should we be thinking about this fairly wordy dividend policy that you gave earlier in the year. Are you thinking more payout ratio or are you thinking growth year-on-year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're actually thinking in the way the words to describe it, Richard. Yeah, we will look at what our cash balances are, what capital expenditure requirements are, how we're feeling about the business, level of franking credits, et cetera. The reason it is higher is because we had stronger cash generation than we thought. And I think the outlook is better than when we revised the dividend policy, but obviously we're still being cautious.</p>
          <p>We do understand that shareholders would like stable and if possible growing dividends, and that's what we will endeavor to achieve, but. And we do have some volatility in some of our businesses. We know that it's beneficial to pass franking credits onto shareholders as quickly as we can, but our number one priority will be our balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But presumably you wouldn't have moved to the extra $0.10 this year unless you were pretty confident you could surpass that next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not going to comment on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Michael Burn from Souls Funds Management (117:25). Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Richard. My question requires an observation, I refer you to some research earlier this last week by the CFB Resources, it must be (117.36) a guy by the name of Paul McTaggart. And it relates to Felix Resources and you've got a nice table in there showing what this entity is paying for Felix Resources. And to summarize it for you, they're paying $3.2 billion of enterprise value for an operation barely a quarter of the size of your coal business. And the other observation I'd make, if I look at...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd probably take 12, if someone wants to start with it, Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Now, the problem I have is that I as an investor in Wesfarmers see analysts tell me, broking houses tell me, your business is sometimes worth 2 billion, sometimes worth 3 billion, and now I see a transaction which is telling me it could be worth 12 billion. So I guess, if I also then go and look at Wesfarmers as a company and I had to strip out the coal business, I've got EBIT in the non-coal business growing at around about 10 &#x2013; 8 to 10% a year. And I think it's pretty defensive, recurring kind of EBIT that (118.33).</p>
          <p>Put the coal business in there and I've got to contend with earnings some years going up 30%, some years the EBIT's falling 20%, like we got next year. And I guess that gets to the heart of, to state the obvious, things like what you list as appropriate pay for that earnings stream, the cost of capital and hence the value of the business. So I think this question has been asked in a round about way before.</p>
          <p>But I'm thinking specifically with &#x2013; in relation to coal. I get the sense that coal assets somehow have now mysteriously garnered a significant uplift in value in the last six months. And I'll also wager that fast-forward 12-18 months, a lot of this value would have been proven to be very transient I think. How much &#x2013; and here's the question, I think you know where the question is going &#x2013; I mean, how much impetus is there, how much in the imperative do you feel, that the Board feel, to feed the ducks while they're quacking, as it were?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on any of our businesses, Michael, we always have a view that if someone comes up and says they're prepared to pay a price which on an after-tax basis is more than we think the business is worth, then we'll have a conversation with them. And that has happened in the past, it happened with our rural division and it happened with the rail joint venture we had. But that's &#x2013; but it doesn't happen that often. And I quite deliberately said after tax because for a number of our businesses selling them would create a significant capital gains tax issue which is a big value leakage...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...to our shareholders. So I guess the comfort I can give you is, we don't have a closed mind to this thing &#x2013; to these sort of things. But the division you're talking about specifically, I think if you step back and look at the resources sector for the next 10 to 20 years, having highly efficient low-cost open-cut coal mines, with the position Australia is in with the growing economies of India and China and other Asian economies, I think they're going to be pretty good assets to own. So, like any of our businesses, if someone wants to acquire them they'll have to pay a price that we think is attractive to do it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'm assuming spinning them off also has capital gains tax implications.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Spinning off has other implications.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Both for shareholders and for the Group that we'd have to take into account.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. I guess I'm just trying to vent my &#x2013; express some frustration at the fact that I see a business here &#x2013; and not immaterial in the context of a 30, 33% <mark type="inaudible" /> enterprise value of the overall Group, valuation going from a couple of billion dollars to $10 billion. It's quite difficult to &#x2013; it becomes quite unworkable sometimes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it does move our share price around a bit, but over time it's been a fabulous investment for Wesfarmers' shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks for your thoughts, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>And there are no further questions at this time so I'll turn the conference back to Mr. Goyder. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you all, I know it's a busy time for you at the moment in reporting season. If you've got any follow-up questions come through Tanya and we look forward to catching up with you in the near future. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>