<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1136801" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Interim 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-02-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>10138</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Michael Luscombe, Chief Executive Officer and Group Managing Director</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Tom Pockett, Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="2">Michael Luscombe</participant>
      <participant id="3">Shaun Cousins</participant>
      <participant id="4">Thomas Pockett</participant>
      <participant id="5">Tom Pockett</participant>
      <participant id="6">Craig Woolford</participant>
      <participant id="7">Michael Peet</participant>
      <participant id="8">Julie Coates</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="10">Phillip Kimber</participant>
      <participant id="11">Grant Saligari</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. Just get to the right page here. In the Woolworths tradition, we'll simply go through this reasonably quickly and devote the quality time to Q&amp;A. So first of all obviously we're very proud of the business, particularly the team of 185,000 Aussies and New Zealanders delivering another strong result with EBIT up 20% and profit after-tax up 28%, and EPS growth at just under 26%. More particularly, we're very happy because it was achieved during a time of uncertainty, higher interest rates, higher petrol prices and obviously global uncertainty around financial markets.</p>
          <p>Also achieved in a time when we were under a very intense change program, accelerated refurbishment, accelerated delivery of many programs. We opened 108 new stores across all brands for the half and for the second half, we're going to continue that acceleration and we'll have a further 81 outlets opened by the end of the year.</p>
          <p>So quickly on some of the key initiatives that we're working on, obviously we're going to continue to invest in price, range, merchandise and quality across all of our brands. Our "Everyday Rewards" program which is replacing fuel dockets with a card is well underway. We've launched it in our pilot in central west of New South Wales sometime back and it was a fantastic success. We've started the roll out, we've gone to South Australia, we'll take a break for Easter and then we'll continue after Easter with the rest of the nation.</p>
          <p>To date, there's a quarter of a million cards that have been issued in use so we're very, very happy with that and the feedback from the customers have been that this just makes so much sense for them and we're delighted with the customer acceptance of it.</p>
          <p>Clearly, BIG W has been one of our great success stories. The repositioning of the brand, the repositioning of the range, the customer acceptance of all the changes that we put in place have been one of the great case studies internally for our business and certainly one that we're going to take forward and use in revitalizing our consumer electronics business.</p>
          <p>We're going to continue to invest in our supply chain, so we've got new DCs planned for Melbourne and Sydney that will open this calendar year for liquor. We have another one planned for Queensland in liquor. We also have got plans for a new distribution center in BIG W, a national one and also a new one for Dick Smith business and of course, we've also got a plan to build some new DCs in New Zealand. On top of that as part of our overall systems capability we'll be investing into new data centers, state-of-the-art data centers in the coming year.</p>
          <p>We're going to leverage what we've learned from supermarkets across our business. We've already started in delivering those systems into our liquor business, into the New Zealand business, which is well underway and we're altering them all, customizing them for the BIG W business as part our Quicksilver project. We have got an acceleration, obviously, in store refurbishments and for the total group, we'll refurbish some 255 stores this year which compares to 103 for the same time 12 months ago.</p>
          <p>Now CapEx to support that has gone from 1.3 billion to 1.8 billion and as a percent of sales for last couple of years we have been running at about 2.9, 3.1, this now goes to about 4% of sales. The development of our financial services capability, prior to Christmas, we launched and put it in place, implemented our financial switch, some 11% of all credit card transactions in Australia go through a Woolworth's outlet.</p>
          <p>And during Christmas we put through, or during the early stage we put through nearly $8 billion worth of transactions through our switch, 92% of those were completed in under one second and over 99% of those were completed in less than two seconds and we had no downtime, which was the first Christmas that we had that speed and that time and the investment in the state of our technology has been well worthwhile and obviously creates a platform for other transactions that we currently have out there in the marketplace. Later in the year we're obviously going to launch our credit card in the first half of the next financial year and we presently also have 518 ATMs in the marketplace and they're also doing reasonably well.</p>
          <p>Our global sourcing effort is continuing to expand, so just after the Chinese New Year we officially opened our second sourcing office in Shanghai and this coming year we anticipate that the volumes put through those offices will triple on the previous year, so we're certainly ramping that up.</p>
          <p>In all of our businesses, we recognize through our strategic plans opportunities for new products for new channels, private label and obviously our property plans for the next five years are extremely strong. Adjacencies and new business opportunities obviously are going to assist with us, so we've just opened three <mark type="inaudible" /> optometry, now four, now four optometry offers in Queensland to supplement the ones that we already have opened in South Australia and once again they met with great customer acceptance.</p>
          <p>And lastly, I would say that we really recognize that the consumer electronics business is one where we don't occupy a leading position in the marketplace and I'm used to do exactly that, so we're going through right now the, exactly the same process that we went through with BIG W and prior to that our liquor business so the model that we've used for understanding what our customers want from a particular business and how to actually address that is the same platform that we're using and the same methodology for consumer electronics.</p>
          <p>Okay, sales, we already know, was $24 billion unassisted by major acquisitions. In fact, you have to go back to 2004 where we achieved 6.4 to have a clean year without major acquisitions. EBIT up 20% and growing faster than sales. The margin 5.73 and this time we've actually stripped out the hotels to give you a sense of how the rest of our business is going. Obviously hotels have a fairly strong EBIT margin and you can see that this year hotels excluded 5.36, so you can see the effect of hotels have had on our final margin for a number of years.</p>
          <p>The profit after-tax up 28.1% to $891 million, earnings per share up 25.9, so $0.74, quite a leap on the previous year. In fact, when you look at that particular growth it's our best that we've had for some time. CODB, we achieved 19 basis points reduction if you take out the effect of petrol and the hotels, we've achieved better than that, but even allowing for that, we're down nearly 150 basis points over the last five half years.</p>
          <p>Gross margin was up 35 basis points particularly on the back of our private label. Shrinkage improvement, change in sales mix particularly for likes of roll back and our new store formats are having marked effect on the mix that we're achieving in the 2010c stores as well as in the BIG W stores, we're having a major mix change.</p>
          <p>And I think the important thing like EBIT we've tried to strip out the effect of the 80 plus percent hotel gross margin to give you a view of how our business is going excluding the hotels. And you can see that we've had from 2006 as private label ramped up, the DCs enabled us to move away from direct to store delivery etcetera etcetera and order stocker really became an effective tool in managing inventory and improving our shrinkage.</p>
          <p>You can see that we have made improvements but it's important to just recognize that the hotels have obviously had a significant impact on our overall gross margin but nonetheless we have had some reasonable and steady growth over the last three years.</p>
          <p>The sales summary, we'll take as read, and the EBIT summary I'll go through in a little bit more detail with each of the businesses. This is the Australian supermarkets that you have in front of you, just a few comments. Comp sales, obviously, up on the previous year particularly when you take into account that the inflation was 4%, 4.5 in 7 and in '08, it was 2%. And interesting also to note that overnight the UN released their world food price inflation numbers that show that overall food inflation was 40% for the last year across the globe.</p>
          <p>It was near to 80% in developing nations. And really was on the back, according to them on the backlog obviously the move of certain commodities into alternative uses such as bio-fuels, but increased demand for food from developed countries and emerging developed countries at the expense of other service, definitely a worldwide gap between supply and demand for food which is somewhat troubling for many developing countries going forward.</p>
          <p>So you had the BIG reduced by 20 basis points, which is in line with the targeted reduction. We have invested once again in further Rollbacks and also in harmonizing our prices across the nations, so in response to consumer voice about different prices for grocery and dairy freezer and general merchandise in stores, we have now reached a point after a five year journey of moving from some 40 or 50 price bps down to one for each state.</p>
          <p>So, you know, if you are in Brisbane, you get the same price in Mossman, North of Cairns for our product and that we think is a goal that we have long strived for and we have finally achieved it. There are obviously a small number of stores like Weeper and Goven and Darwin and Broom where we have a small loading for freight and in Darwin, there is a small loading for certain products for freight, but we have achieved something that we really wanted to do for a long time and that is for non-fresh products have a consistent price across the state.</p>
          <p>We also invested in some key products, so home brand bread was one way we announced and then followed through with a substantial investment in lowering the price of that basic commodity. Despite all that, we managed to improve our gross margin through the various mechanisms that we've talked about in the past and all of them have contributed very much to supporting both an improved margin but at the same time delivering much better for the customer. Our view is independently verified, that we've absorbed round about 25% of the cost increases that were presented to us in the past year.</p>
          <p>We opened 19 new supermarkets in the first half, and got another 12 to open in the second half. So those of you that haven't been to one of our stores, here's a vision of one that we finished earlier on. You can see the new natural. You know no longer the stack, yellows and reds and greens. You can see new treatment for purchase. You can see that the start lines are very evident for even those of less than average height, they are able to see the whole of the fresh foods and of course further down the store we have made some substantial changes to the way that we lay the store out and we're very pleased with the return on investment that we're getting back in terms of sales and margin mix improvement.</p>
          <p>Liquor has been yet again standout business for us, great sales across all of them. Dan Murphy would be the standout, but we are also very happy with our BWS business. 13 new Dan Murphy's in the first half. We also had 25 new BWSs, 13 more Dans in the second half and another 21 BWSs. And we now have identified and have a stake, again, for 150 Dan Murphy's by 2013. And we got well over 1000 outlets by now.</p>
          <p>Petrol, challenging year, you know, as process went up, the average fuel went down by about 3%, so volume was a challenge. Our EBIT margin was constant at 1.6%, so we actually took a lower margin on fuel to keep the volume going. We had improved as a result of attracting people with our very competitive fuel offer. Our sales of non-fuel items went up very, very strongly and obviously they carry a reasonable margin and it helped subsidize the bit of hurt that we took on fuel. The EBIT equates to $1.88 per liter, so for those that accused Woolworths of price ganging in petrol in the last half, if $1.08 per liter is ganging then we are obviously guilty.</p>
          <p>We opened 12 new canopies during the half and we've got 8 to open in the second half, so we've well and truly passed the 500 mark. There is picture of our card, as I said, quarter of a million now in use and I think we're getting something like 10,000 a day signing up, is that right, Rich? At the moment? Yes, 10,000 a day, so everyone just says volume broaden into this year again. And there's couple of side benefits. How many kilometers of paper did we save? That was some ridiculous amount, we've go to moon and back couple of times with shortening the dockets by-product that we didn't believe or we didn't understand that we'd had.</p>
          <p>Now New Zealand, in fact Thomas would given you a couple of halves just to give you a benchmark on a half with a industrial dispute, one that's not so, but you can say that we're pretty much back to where we should be.</p>
          <p>Sales were up 6.8 and comp up 7.7, we've obviously closed the couple of smaller stores. Inflation was 2.7, that's our internal inflation, which was well below the official mark as it was within Woolies. Prior half was somewhat less than that.</p>
          <p>We've continued to invest in the New Zealand marketplace to become very, very competitive and was -- we can ever be happier that we really won that game. We've made significant gains in the past 12 months, in particular the last six months. And the integration on this business and the various initiatives are well on track. The petrol offer that we have with Shell and with Gull is working very well for us.</p>
          <p>We've now finished our work on the right layout for New Zealand's stores, which is obviously slightly different than Australian stores in the merchandising and ranging. Select and home brand and we've general merchandise offer from Australia is also being very well accepted, and in fact in the case of some products, too well accepted, we've struggled to get enough ships to bring stock across.</p>
          <p>The integration of the various system, the merchandising, point of sale, finance, etcetera, are all on track, either delivered in the case of finance or being rolled out in the case of point of sale. Merchandising is near enough to complete as well.</p>
          <p>The property product line is something that we've been promising for some time, and we're happy to say that concluded negotiations, we have 14 new sights, and we a number of other properties currently under negotiation. And we've also started refurbishments in earnest, five in this half, another five in the next half, and we hope to accelerate that over the next couple of years as we have in Australia. About three stores to open in the next half in New Zealand.</p>
          <p>Delighted with the result from BIG W, I think, the team has to be congratulated. Double-digit growth for both sales and earnings. Sales up 13% and EBIT up 20.1% was a tremendous state. More importantly as we've repositioned the business, one of the dangers would be that we might lose our everyday price position. We've worked very hard to make sure we've maintained the gap between ourselves and our competitors on everyday wanted items, and that's a substantial gap. But more importantly our market researchers said that whilst we're now promised to be able to deliver an ability for our customer to get big for less. I haven't lost sight of the fact that we actually still own the price position, so we've got the best of both worlds in the new way for BIG W.</p>
          <p>Our gross margins have improved by 109 basis points not only on the back of mix and also some buying opportunities that come through overseas buying directly and also currency's being somewhat favorable for us.</p>
          <p>Costs are up a bit, but we've actually deliberately spent that in many areas of service and obviously improving our stores. We've got a way to go, yet, but we're very, very happy that we're on the right path.</p>
          <p>In the next couple weeks, we're going to open our very lightest BIG W at Rouse Hill and we invite everybody to come out, and I'm sure Jeff will have the opportunity to take those who are interested around with Greg to show our very latest BIG W. Whilst [indiscernible ] was a great step in the future, I think, you're going to find Rouse Hill has just turned up for those supermarkets. So I'm absolutely delighted with this store that is being put together there and I'm sure that those in the audience when they have a look at it will recognize that it's a world class offering.</p>
          <p>Consumer electronics, probably competitive market. Our sales were up 10%, comps up 4.5, EBIT up 5.9. I think we are honest in saying that we believe that we've got a lot of up side in this business and we're determined to actually do that. As I mentioned earlier we're underway with the strategic review and we're not going to stop, in the meantime we'll continue to open stores, so that we got the footprint there, 24 in the first half and 21 in the second half, more importantly more at the large format stores. The cost of doing business is up largely on analysis on the cost of the store openings and our inventory has been flat.</p>
          <p>In India we now have 13 stores open. I think there's another three to open by the end of March and quite a few more to open by the end of the financial year. Our relationship is as stated there. The store sales are $46 million. Our operating roster is $2.3 million, which was basically where we want it to be, and we've now established our operating DCs in India to support this store roll-out.</p>
          <p>To give you some vision of what we have, that's one of the Croma stores in India. So you can say that it's very much targeted to the middle-class and the upper middle-class, a very classy offering. And internally, you can say that we're utilizing the very best in terms of merchandising techniques from around the world. In fact, there are a number of things that we're doing here in India that where we've been trying new merchandising techniques. We think they are so good, we are going to retrofit them, back into the Australian business.</p>
          <p>For Hotels, challenging year; sales up 8.5%, profit obviously has done a little better than that, up 10%. Our CODB was down really meritorious, 113 basis points. Gross margins were down, obviously we bought some stores that have a different mix of business, particularly some that have allowed the portion of the gaming against their title sales.</p>
          <p>We are very confident having intelligence to how the market is going, generally that we have done substantially better than the market in those states that have had smoking bans implemented in the last 12 to 18 months. We've acquired nine properties, so we're now up to 271, and we continue to be on the marketplace. We could be -- the hotel market has softened a bit, so we think that there might be a few hotels come on the marketplace in the not-too-distant future. However, we still remain cautious about the long-term effects of the smoking bans.</p>
          <p>I'm now going to hand over to Tom, who take you through some of the less interesting parts, and then I'll come back to the interesting bit at the end. Thanks, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark. As you can see, we've had a very strong result from the operations in Woolies, and that's reflected in the strength of our balance sheet, and the strength of our cash flow, as well.</p>
          <p>Our dividend per share is up 25.7%. That's pretty much now in line with EPS growth, which is up 25.9%, so that's a good outcome to payers, about 16%.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet has strengthened. Inventory is down, our net investment in working capital, which is a negative number has increased. Our fixed assets have really increased just in line with CapEx and depreciation, but probably the key line is the net repayable debt, which is down $1 million, which reflects repayment of debt through the period, but also increased cash levels. There was some impact in relation to the timing of our creditor payments which I'll cover in the cash flow.</p>
          <p>In relation to capital management as everyone here knows we manage our balance sheet to minimize our cost of funds and to maintain our credit ratings. Woolworth's board had a good discussion about capital management and whilst we will continue to say that we are going to undertake capital management during 2008, it'll probably being towards the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>We still have the warehouse, which goes back to quadruple in April, and there is quite a significant amount of volatility both in the equity and debt markets. So the Board just considered get prudent to -- just remain, there is no real pressure on us to do capital management in this half, but clearly we're in a good position to do it during this year.</p>
          <p>In relation to franking credits, we've had about 830 odd million, so clearly that will be distributed on any capital management we do. I think one of the key things also is we've got a very strong financial position, we don't have to go back to the debt markets for anything significant until 2011. All our international borrowings fixed in terms of exposures to currency and interest rates. And we only have a small domestic borrowing about 300 million to renew in September. So, we're in a very, very good position given the volatility in the overseas debt markets.</p>
          <p>Cash flow very strong. Cash flow from operations up almost 39%, some benefit from creditor payments, so help by the underlying cash flow was at least inline with earnings growth and probably well ahead of earning growth. That gave us free cash of about $1.1 billion and free cash flow as percentage of net about 128%, so again, a very strong result in the question of cash.</p>
          <p>Inventory, we're down about 0.6 days. Targets about a day, we still increasing our ramp up of our indent increase. We increased our overseas procurement activity, so that will have some impact on that going forward, but we're still targeting a day.</p>
          <p>Return on equity just under 15%, and probably more importantly the return on funds employed, as we said in 2006 when we -- which was the year we did the bulk of the acquisitions, the return on -- the key measure on the funds employed is the increasing nature of the funds employed and that's clearly gone from 12% to 18%, so that's all heading in the right direction which is very good.</p>
          <p>Our full year report card, we say this every -- we go through this every six months, sales will grow in the upper single-digits and it's 8.6%, EBIT will outperform sales growth driven by cost savings and that's 20% growth and EPS will outperform EBIT growth and we got 25.9%. So, a very strong six months. Michael?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tom. One thing I neglected to mention earlier, credit card issuing partner will be announced today. In fact, probably announced right at the moment and we're delighted to have HSBC as our partner in our credit card. A major international bank that has great expertise in both credit card, back up hospital, so in the customer analytics, that obviously is a key part in having a credit offering.</p>
          <p>Our sales in this quarter to date have very much continued the momentum that we had in the first half, so we're very confident to continue our maintenance of the 8 to 10% growth for the full year. Our earnings we expect that it will continue to grow faster than sales and net profit after tax for FY'08 is expected to grow in the range of 19 to 23%. And we state this very carefully because we will continue to invest in a number of strategic initiatives and I mentioned a few -- in the second slide today, where we'll be ramping up expenditure on the roll-out of the credit card, Petro Card et cetera, et cetera, et cetera, and a few other things that are not publicly available at the moment. So, we are definitely investing in growth for the next period of years and it's important that we spend that money now because establishing that base for growth going forward is going to be key to Woolworth's long-term success.</p>
          <p>Now excluded from this guidance is an expected profit of $35 million on the sale of certain properties. We fully anticipate that these will be completed, the major one probably in the next week so. However, not having that confirmed at this meeting would be irresponsible to include that in the guidance. However, if that does go through then our guidance would go up to 21 to 25% for the year on the basis that those sales of properties are completed.</p>
          <p>Reminded that the financial year is a 53-week year this year and our statements are made on a 53-week basis and of course, subject to the present conditions that we have in business and competition and the general economic environment remain really much the same as we're experiencing at the moment.</p>
          <p>So, with that more than happy to hand over for questions for myself and Tom and any other of the team here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, just quickly on your additional spending in these new ranges. You have mentioned that there's going to be an additional 50 million in CapEx. Can we use that as a basis -- or can I just pose the question this way, in terms of the increased operating expense you're going to be incurring for these new projects in the second half, how does it compare to that CapEx spend? Is it a small fraction or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, it's significant and material but it's not a number that we're going to release. The CapEx has gone from 1.3 to 1.8, so there's a significant number there. But the training required at store level for roll-out of things like petrol card and credit cards and so remarketing, et cetera, et cetera, if I just take those two projects across a thousand odd stores -- actually it's a lot more because we actually have to do petrol stations as well. It's a considerable expense but it's one that is obviously an investment in making sure the programs are well and truly successful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just in terms of consumer electronics, you mentioned you want to be a leader in the market, obviously over the longer term. The majority of the market is serviced through sort of the bulky goods end, so clearly you're going to be driving useful growth through the Powerhouse and the like; is it likely that, A, that it's going to be the case and, B, that there could be a potential second format in that space?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It'd be fair to say that the larger format was -- the medium-size format has been the backbone and strength of our business. The growth opportunity clearly is in the larger formats, and one part of our strategy that wouldn't be hard for anyone to guess would be we're going to accelerate our large format roll-out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of capital management, it just sounded as though -- from what Tom was saying, that the decision or the ability to acquire Warehouse Group is not mutually exclusive with the capital management program in the second half. Is that the way to interpret that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think that's right. Because how we financed the acquisition is they're two separate financing decisions. However, it is a big acquisition, so I think the Board thought, given there's no real pressure on us at the moment. We've got capability and we'll just wait and see what happens over the next six months. And given the market turmoil and [ph, soft audio] it's a good position to be . Mindful of the fact that we still have an appeal to sit through, and then mindful of the fact that we may not be the only one interested in buying it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just finally, thanks very much for the additional disclosure in the notes in relation to the hotels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mike. Shaun Cousins, JPMorgan. Just in regards to Food and Liquor, can you just talk about how long you can sustain gross margin expansion where you have talked, about given the cost of bread and milk, sausages, low and you still have some of these, you've still been able to grow gross margins by some 39 basis points including petrol; but how long can we anticipate this to be a driver of EBIT margin expansion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well both of those, both that cost pool and gross margin pool. I don't see that in the immediate future that we can't continue to improve. We're now in a position with our fresh foods where we're rolling out order stocker and we're already seeing some good improvements in our shrinkage rates, and because we've got better control of the amount of stock, at the appropriate place at the appropriate time for the customer. We certainly believe that our global sourcing will continue to grow. We certainly believe that our private label will continue to grow. We're probably nearing the last little pieces of any major direct to store conversion. We still have some milk that goes direct to store because it makes sense at the moment. We still have bread that goes direct to store and we're in the process of obviously transitioning beer as we open the new DCs.</p>
          <p>So that probably will be in list of the pool, but in terms of our ability to get more efficient, we've got a number of initiatives like self-scanning and others that will help us become more efficient going forward as well as all over, a management system that also will help us make sure we've got the right amount of people at the right time according to the customer needs. So, we think that there's plenty of opportunity for us to become a much smarter company, and where we are smart, and that actually creates a pool of value, then we're going to determine then each year how much we'll put back into driving the volume by in comparison to our competitors, take our margin down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thinking about the refurbs, the 2010s, et cetera, I mean how long do you get a, I mean I'm sure you're not going to give us the actual sales up, but how long will you give us, I'm sorry, how long will you get a sales uplift from these new stores? Is it, you opened, kind of Rouse Hill been opened and you get the use benefit or does that sort of prolong for two year or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For refurbs it's typically, you get the big bang in the first year, but you also get a reasonable bang in the second year. In the case of new stores, quite often it's the second, third year where they really get into their stride. So, Dan Murphy's typically in their second year, go like the Caltex. In the first year they do really well. Some of them might bigger than other stores that opened in Western Australia. You can open the door and you will do close to $2 million in the first week. But that doesn't happen every day, but you can be surprised as we were in Western Australia. But you do get continuous flow-on, and I think you get a synergy effect, too, because you actually -- by doing this quickly, you actually end up with the majority of your fleet, but basically the same format, the same layout and there's a whole host of synergy benefits in the backend by not having to do different planograms and do one-offs for a whole host of stores. One of our big opportunities in New Zealand is that we presently got, I don't know -- how many types of fixtures we got there about 10 or 11...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Counting the rest, its probably about 14.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>14 different types of fixtures. Now you can imagine doing shelf planning or map doing your planograms, I mean it's just impossible. So getting through and standardizing shelving has an enormous benefit, because we know we did that more or less some years back and that made a hell of a difference to our ability to actually manage the sales and profitability of each square meter of shelf.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On New Zealand, how long do you think we'll see gross margin compression in that business, and when will effectively they net cost-out from the CODB line start the result in EBIT margin expense? Because you did actually have your margins go down, first half of '08 and second half of '07, and there's not a lot of seasonality in those businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are actually yet to get the big bulk of the CODB, because we're yet to build our new DCs. We're yet to put -- we are rolling out Autostocker there, so we know from our experience in Australia, getting the right amount of stock at the right time actually not only helps your margin, but it helps your cost tremendously, as well, because you're not double-handling. Our front-ends, the efficiency of the front-end with our new front point-of-sale and our back office, which incidentally, we developed for the New Zealand marketplace, a new version we're now retrofitting back in to the Australian marketplace, which is a new generation. All of those in the ensuing years will mean that we'll have a stream of cost efficiencies that will generate another pool, because we're not going to finish anything in New Zealand until we attain market leadership in that marketplace. That's our goal, and that's where we're heading.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's market share leadership?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Market share leadership, yes, that's where we're heading.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And finally just in terms of consumer electronics, you want to get bigger into that business. That operates a return on funds employed at around 15%, it's up on -- at least in first half. But it's up on last year. I look at your BIG W business, which you are investing in, it's generating return on fund deployed at 40 -- around 42%, supermarkets a little higher than that. What's the reasoning to decide to grow in a business that while it has higher earnings growth, you're generating a lower return on funds employed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess the alternative is that we sell it or just let it die financially and we've determined that we believe that we can run that business a lot better than we have and we believe that we just -- well we know that our customers and consumers have given us a really good indication on where we can improve as they did in BIG W and that's the path that we're going to take.</p>
          <p>Obviously, as we move through the year a few more details of that will be released, but that's probably a little bit too premature to sort of let the cat out of the bag at the moment. But we're certainly are of the view that we're going to change the way that we go there. I think it's an important category to be in because if you think about the electronics that were in our life 10 or 20 years ago in comparison to now, and try and anticipate where they'll be in 20 or 30 years, it's a category I think we need to be in. But we need to be in as a winner and we're in the field at the moment, I would much rather be leading the field than in the field.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you need to have this business managed quite separately from the rest of the Group in that similar to the way you have Dan Murphy's is almost a separate business in that it does require a different skill set that what you have in supermarkets or BIG W in terms of incentivized selling and the like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All of our businesses are actually managed separately. Greg Foran runs BIG W, Naum Onikul runs the Supermarket Group, Tony Leon is under the auspices of Steve Greentree that runs Dan Murphy's and the consumer electronics business is [ph &#x2013; Alvin Ng is listed as head of this group on company site] Ed Sholorf with his own head office and its own slightly unique culture. What we need to do is to turbo charge the business. Hi, there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Michael. Following on from a capital employed question, I'm interested as to why capital employed actually fell for all the divisions except for Australian supermarkets. Looking at the capital employed on the slide all the numbers went down. Is there an explanation for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I need to sale DC the last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. The 20 million of transition costs that you wore in this first half...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Given that you're now are going to be looking at putting new DCs across the other business units, into liquor et cetera, and those transition costs is it -- would it be wrong for us to assume that those transition costs are going to fade away in the second half and in the full year '09?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They will -- they would be perhaps the same of a little less for the second half, but whenever you open a new DC there's transition costs. So when we open the liquors DCs we've currently got a ragbag of facilities at the moment that will need to transition during the year, so there will be transition costs. When we open the third distribution center for BIG W, there'll be transition cost, when we build a new DC for Dick Smith to support our growth, there'll be transition costs. So the reason we put it out there is just to be open, to say that we haven't capitalized what is rightly OpEx and we just want to be transparent to say, included in our cost of doing business is the cost of change and it will vary from time to time. So rightly or wrongly we think it's the honest thing to do, just put it out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Woolworth's is about the only company that I've ever covered that takes the hit to its P&amp;L on everything, whether it be the renovations, whether it be the transition costs, et cetera, et cetera. You really have to pull it out you guys to find out what it actually is. You don't come clean and you don't tell us what the profit could have been or anything like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's all about building for the future, it's one thing to actually put something in place and then expect the future generation to pay for it. I think this generation has to be a part of the foundation costs for the future leaders of the business. Roger did it for me. I will do exactly the same for whoever comes after me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty much from where I can see the most important thing for all of us in the next two years is to make sure that you get you ramp acceleration of your renovations, I suppose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Where it looks as though you're going to be pretty well renovating all stores over two year period almost, that's pretty quick...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably three, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But that being normal it'd be about seven or eight years wouldn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For supermarkets would be seven to eight, for BIG Ws in the past it's probably been 12 to 15. So we had a big backlog to catch up with BIG W, because we obviously went from 80 to 140 stores pretty quickly. But what we didn't do for the last maybe eight or so years was to ramp up the number we did each year. We're still doing three or four or maybe seven, and really what we needed to be doing is close to doing maybe up to 20.</p>
          <p>Traditional wisdom says that you do a major refurb in discount department stores once every ten years, but for the really busy ones you need to go back and do a paint and paper, probably every three to five years, like rearing a mall, you just can't sort of go back there once every ten years, you've got to go back and spruce it up.</p>
          <p>Supermarkets, likewise, average is seven, but some of them you've got to go back every three years and because they just take such a beating. When you look at the customer counts and the number of trolleys that bump into walls and things like that, you've just got to go back and do it. But on average it's probably about six to seven years in supermarkets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give us some numbers just to give us a bit of comfort, because it is a very aggressive rollout. Can you give us some -- just a bit of an indication as to how successful the 2010c series is, once you put that in? Like what is the sort of uplift that you can get?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I've already had friends from elsewhere running the tape ruler over the business, over the stores. The sales uplift is measurable against the pilot stores, the non-refurbished stores at similar, so that's not in a little blip. We can actually say that what's being done. But more importantly, we do notice some mix change and we do notice the margin improves. So, we know that we -- there's certain categories in the longer period, because we're giving them more prominence and changed the way we're merchandising and we actually sell a lot more, we're actually increase the range for others, we've actually tightened the range. And in fresh, we've also noticed that -- particularly some of the range changes that we've had, improved our margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And finally, the [indiscernible ] ask Tom, if he could elaborate a bit on that cash flow. I mean it was a whopping cash flow, on top of last year, I think, first half '07 was a whopper. Can you explain this timing thing a bit more, Tom?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we closed off on the 30th and we did a check run on the 31st.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How does that mean? How does that affect the cash flow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It just means we hadn't paid the cash out of the bank at the end of the year. So it just means we just generated more cash.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how much by did you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well it's probably a couple hundred million dollars, so, yes. It's a bit hard to look at one item because you've got to adjust for the whole day. But I mean the cash flow is particularly strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This payment system is pretty much automated, so it needs someone to go in and -- important that we pay our bills on time, but we're not in the habit of paying them ahead of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And when the check &#x2013; when goes the other way, it just remind process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Greg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Couple of things. I want to ask you that you're thinking about the refurbs in super. So, what are you thinking, you're thinking you're going to drive more foot traffic or you think you're going to share a basket and keep that significant customer base that you have in these stores, I'm talking about the 2010cs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're seeing a bit of both, to be honest. We are actually seeing an increase in the group in terms of customer traffic. But also we are selling a bit more -- there are certain categories where we actually have decided to do something with, and we're actually selling additional products because of those categories, in addition to what we would normally have sold to those customers. So it's a bit of both, to be honest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you've got those browse categories at the front of sale. Is that making a big difference to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, the what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The browsing categories. The trade talks about these browsing categories that you put at the front of the store?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, is that a significant development in terms of it's helping with share of basket and obviously a richer sales mix?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's important that what we've done with certain categories is to bring them all together, to give them a slightly different treatment in terms of share. More importantly, giving people room to have a look and be out of the traffic. One of our key learnings was that you don't want to put browsing categories in with high volume because people get, actually feel embarrassed they're holding traffic up. So they tend not -- tend to take the time that we want them to take to make a purchase. So there is some subtleties, there that we've worked on that have helped us, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you explain how roll back improves your gross profit margin, because you're obviously selling a lower price with a lower gross profit dollar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It works the same way as private label. It's not a primary brand, it's a secondary or tertiary brand that has usually a much higher gross profit, starting point than the market leader for the product. Which is usually -- market leader is usually higher when we promoted and we help to subsidize that promotion price. So any time you can move a product into a rollback or private label you actually lift your overall margin into that category. So it's a pretty simple mathematical model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just on New Zealand, there's some chat about reorganization going on there? Is that important to the refurbishing of the -- within the New Zealand supermarket group, there is chat that there's some reorganization going on in your business in PL, and I'm wondering if it's connected with your format choices that you've made and how it links into the three brands?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've actually done some personnel changes and really demonstrating our business and probably aligning it to the way that we've run the Australian business in terms of the structure. Also we've got some really good young people that we wanted to further their careers. So a couple of the Kiwis that come across to Australia for import jobs, we've sent a couple Australians over to New Zealand for their development. But, more importantly, we've actually streamlined their operational side of the business to pretty much line up with the way we do it in Australia. And we would have done that irrespective of what else we might have been doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the three brands stay for the time being?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the time being, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the DC, you're building a new Auckland one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you building a new Auckland DC?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There probably will be, yes. It's sort of bursting at the stems now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Michael, Craig Woolford from Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Craig, how are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, thanks. Can I just explore a few things on the gross margin just to touch on a question earlier about the sustainability of gross margin expansion? Firstly on shrinkage, where do you feel your shrinkage rates are compared with world's best practice?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I know that in fresh we're not as good as Tesco; we've made marked improvements. So, if I just give you a bit of a flavor, when I was in operations in projects, we probably used to average 12 to 15%. It would vary during the year, during the summer when we harvest soft fruits. We're now in the single digits. But I do know that because the UK guys pretty much wreck everything and the customer has to buy it whether they want it or not, a bit of a surprise when you get home. They actually enjoy very low shrinkage rates. So, we've still got big improvement to be made. As we really look at the ranges in many of our fresh fruit departments, bakery is a good one, there are a lot of products that really were there because it made us feel good but they didn't actually deliver sales and margin. So, we've really cropped the range and replaced them with products that do sell and sell for full price. So, it's a bit like playing the Harbor Ridge, you can never say, we'll fix that. Of course on top of that there's the issue of theft, and we've worked long and hard to put AIS across our business. We also have source tagging happening, and of course our stores are very well equipped with state-of-the-art digital in-house cameras. So, if someone does something, we usually have a beautiful glossy of their face and what they were taking, so it helps the police a lot. And that has meant that we probably moved a few of non-paying customers to other people. And of course, we're working with vendors that have the wholly preferable things; preferable products where people typically take them out of the packet to make the packets -- I don't know if you've tried to open a packet of razors blades, you almost need an oxy torch to get it open to get your blades out. But in the past they've just ripped them open and whip them in because the source tag is typically somewhere in the packet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then also obviously direct sourcing is a big driver of growth of both the food and the non-food business, can you give a rough guidance to where what percentage of your sales now are coming from direct sourcing in China?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I wouldn't like to do that other to say that we had a successful first full year last year, but we anticipate, in fact we've got orders now confirmed from our business that will triple what we achieved in our first year. So, yeah we're comfortable. I think we just need to be mindful of the fact that world is moving, so China may not always be the best place to source products and we're very mindful of the fact that there are some other regions of the world that becoming very competitive with quality as well as price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then on the private labels as a source of gross margin expansion, obviously you've talked about absorbing some of -- a lot of the cost pressures on particular value items, do you think private label will be a source of margin expansion over the next 12 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, probably in the next five to ten years. Yes, I have to congratulate our team. We gave them one chance that is put products on the shelf that people are going to buy and come back and buy again. Tell them I want you to focus on getting me 500 by a certain day or I don't want us to focus on having x percent of our sales in provolone, just put a product on the shelf that won't be deleted and it won't be deleted because it's one, two or three in a category and it's delivering a reasonable margin. Not all of them deliver a reasonable, the basic commodities, it's tough to make a really good margin in the base commodities, but in all the other products we can make a reasonable margin and deliver the consumer a much better, a value product and the guys and girls have delivered. Other than the few rotations in and out of the flavors of products, we haven't had to delete any products that I can think of, which is an amazing effort.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just lastly on the operating, or the cost of doing business. Can you highlight any cost specials you've started seeing on either transport or labor and the reason I asked that you had 6.8% comp stores sales growth in food and liquor, I would have thought that you would have given some additional operating leverage to -- might give above -- more than 20 basis point cost diverting business reduction?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, obviously we re-invested as well in the cost lines. So in areas of service and a number of other initiatives that we had in the supermarket business are actually carried in that cost line by the supermarket business, in particular the OpEx relating to the refurbishment program. It's carried by the supermarket, it's not carried at the center. Sorry, I just -- first other question again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm interested in the operating leverage and natural operating leverages staying in that business and do they vary in the other cost pressure maybe on transport or labor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of labor we're obviously have long-term enterprise agreements in place. In Western Australia and Northern Queensland we've had to go a bit above that because they have been -- it's hard to get enough people in those markets, so you've got to actually go with the market. In terms of transport we're rolling out our new model. So we'll announce our biggest contract for the city base in the next couple of days. And that is one of our new models where we change the asset earning model, where we own the trailers, where we do the planning of routes and loads etcetera. And we change the revenue model for the 3PL to one that actually rewards both us and them for productivity and we've been trailing that elsewhere with good success. So this is our biggest contract and also very pleased to say -- say that the provider will have a brand new fleet with Euro 5 diesel. So from the sustainability point of view, it will be the greenest fleet in the country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Michael...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, you had your hand up...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Finally got the microphone. Interested in your comments on consumer electronics and I think, I understand your rationale long-term. But I don't think you told the same about the hotels business and of increasing CapEx half a billion and in turn, 60 or so gains for the hotels business. So can you comment on your future aspirations in that market? Because it's one of the -- the reasons where we don't see your return on funds employ. And in that context, I suppose half a billion increase in CapEx and no increase in guidance, can you just add some color on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Pertaining the first one, the hotels, part of being on border claim for liquor and we don't have 150 Dan Murphy sights without having 270 hotels, number one. So the return that we get on hotels is actually spread across number of businesses and of course the larger of the businesses there are greater synergies back in the board of the businesses in terms of buying, etcetera, etcetera, etcetera. So taking, what I am saying is not the way we look at it so we will continue to invest in hotels, the right hotels that give us the opportunity to put a Dan Murphy on. And, obviously from a hotel perspective where we believe we can substantially improve the business by refurbishing the hotel and the Mathieson Group are really adept at doing that. So, the second question was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the first question first, I guess...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the CapEx and guidance, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the first question declining asset process in the hotel business then, I mean is just a big there opportunity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is, yes, there are number that -- when it was boom time that people were lining up to buy and all of a sudden they financed to buy fell away and so they are coming back on the market at a much reduced price, so we are well positioned for the right hotels to be the acquirers of those hotels. In terms of guidance, we think it's appropriate that given that there is still a little bit of uncertainty up there around what might happen in the broader world, we don't see food inflation, or cost versus the food inflation, dramatically decreasing. In fact the messages and signals we are getting from our vendors are that they will follow up last years round and the year before round of cost increases for the similar round for this year. We also believe that, from several sources, perhaps we haven't heard all of the potential write downs from international finance houses around subprime, so there might be a little bit more to come. What that might actually do in terms of the flow through to the rest of our business I guess time will tell. So, we are comfortable in giving the nine into twenty-three or the twenty-one to twenty-five if you include the property transactions. If you call this conservative then we are conservative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you are effectively saying it doesn't imply anything about these incremental returns on the capital you are spending.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure the point of the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You are spending another half a billion dollars...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And effectively you are saying you are not getting any incremental profit from it so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we will in the future. I mean any refurbishment we do, any needs to meet our internal guidelines of general right of return, etc., all of those are well above the average cost of capital, in fact, multiple layers off. None of the refurbishes, we are doing none of the new stores we're opening don't get past the property committee unless they actually achieve that. Every year we go back and we review for the past five years every single one that we've actually put on and our strike rate at the moment is that we get around about 90% achieved better than their business case on the projections in terms of return and for the other 10% sometimes there's substantially higher than more than 10% higher than what they projected, that's some good luck. Some have had partway through the five years a new store opened up that wasn't part of the plan when we opened it against it may be one of ours for instance. But generally speaking the guys are really, really good on their investment proposal, so yes we're spending that money now but we'll get the return in years to come. As the result, we go this half was the result of investment that we've made in the past as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Michael Peet from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a question about there's a bit of a view out there that's rollout and cannibalization, something that you might face or be facing. Can you just talk about how you look at that in 15 to 25 stores per annum, what's your view on that as an issue for Woolworth's?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Every new store that we sign up for we do a very stringent analysis of the immediate marketplace, all the existing businesses, all the proposed businesses that are either merged or not, and that gives us confidence that when we build something that we're not going to be surprised and I guess that the previous conversation I had backs up the fact that we do our homework before we sign a deal. Are we going to reach a point where we run out of space? I don't know. I guess people have been asking us that for ten years and yet the property committee we have every four weeks we seem to be always finding more and more sights. So when I look ahead a year, two year, three year, and four, I already know that the numbers of stores that we need, we've actually got them signed, sealed, delivered and locked away. So if we get anymore in the mean time then that'll be a bonus for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you just answered this previous question, but thinking about the payback period on these refurbishments with the 530 odd million, am I right to think of sort of three to four year payback? Is that about what you'd be expecting from these?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We haven't really talked about payback period, but they all made our hurdles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good try anyways. Slide 11 and slide nine, you've got the cost of doing business and then the GP margin with the back out of hotels, just to check that includes petrol obviously still, doesn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It does.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What sort of impact if you back that out would that have had?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Petrol has BA margin and BA cost and not much EBIT so it would change it again. It would take it down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't disclose the gross margin...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It would take the GP margin back up though wouldn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, if you took petrol out it would go up a little bit, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Yes, that's all I have. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If there are no more questions from the floor we'll go to the phone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have another two I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a phone question. It's from Mr. Phillip Kimber from Goldman Sachs. Mr. Kimber, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Hi, Mike, just a question on your guidance and the fact that the growth is going to be lower in percentage terms in the second half. Now you clearly talked about investment. Can I ask how much OpEx is involved in the accelerated store roll-out program? Is that a significant component of that investment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a component of it, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But not a significant component?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a bit -- half a dozen initiatives that are going on in the second half, so all of which have an impact. The CapEx, the additional CapEx not only has a bit of additional appreciation it also has a bit of additional funding cost. And the first half was distorted also because we received the warehouse special dividend in the first and that won't come through in the second. So it's a combination of all factors but I don't think we'd want to go through each individual item.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And then maybe can I ask when you talk, I think you words were a significant investment in pricing range. It's obviously something you've been consistently doing, you are relating to that, but are you stepping that up in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, Phil, we're having trouble hearing the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the commentary around investment in pross and so forth...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there weren't too significant, I'm just wondering if you're indicating a step up in the second half or just you're continued focus on investments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There've been a number of decisions that we've completed just recently that obviously will have you know because they weren't there in the first half, will have a financial effect in the second half, yes. So if that's accelerated, yes that's the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just a housekeeping one, on the depreciation, it's growing about 6% I think, on this half-on-half, about 7% in the supermarket business. CapEx is going north of a billion for three years. I mean what side should we expect depreciation to start significantly growing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it will significantly grow, I think it will probably kick-up a couple of percentage points but nothing dramatic actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's all I had, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Phil. One more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Grant Saligari from CommSec.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Grant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, I've got an echo hear that, I don't know if you can hear me clearly. The question that concerns your expansion into related ranges, product ranges in supermarkets. And I think it was at the last result that we talked a little bit about the supermarket refurbishment program and how that would enable you to move into some related product categories. I wonder whether there's anything you can say about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not publicly. But we're certainly working on a number of things that should appear over the next 12 to 18 months. But there's opportunities there for us, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So we're really not seeing any of that, or much of that at this stage, anything in the light of refurbishments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are being more extensions of range in certain categories and some new ways of selling products. So if we just take rotisserie chickens where we used to sell a 100% out of the Bay Marie (69.00) where we've moved across to having them bagged in the aisle, the majority of chickens are now sold there rather than in the Bay Marie. If you look at fish, we've put a lot of work into a really quality range of packaged, frozen and chilled fish. And that's been a really good growth opportunity for us on the back of investment and specific refrigeration to merchandise them at store level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, a couple of examples that I'd decide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Within product expansion generally, is there any update you can give on some of financial services initiatives that have been undertaken?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I didn't quite catch that correctly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there any update on financial services initiatives that you could elaborate on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we're announcing today that our issuing partner is HSBC, which we're delighted with. The credit card will be launched in the second half of this calendar year of the financial switch, which would put in place, as well, and surely underway in performing absolutely to expectations, which is perfect, which is what you need from a switch. And of course, what goes on for what may come after the credit card launch, so that's probably where I need to draw a stumps on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just turning to the cost side of the equation, we saw some wage figures come out earlier in the month, and as you showed quite a substantial spike in wage growth in the retail sector, generally. I just wondered whether you're experiencing sort of similar wage pressures, we're looking at something like 5% in the aggregate numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. Look, we obviously have in place long-term in prose agreements for the bulk of our team. However, in Western Australia, particularly in the northern stores, and in the northern half of Queensland, there is strong competition from the mines for people, and we've had to change our strategy a little bit there to make sure that we have an appropriate quality people in numbers to operate our stores. But other than that, we're not feeling any pressure at the moment. But, you know, in the non-wage area, in the salaried area, of course, for good quality people, you're always competing by domestically and internationally for the best people. And I don't see any change in that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. First of all, congratulations on the repositioning of BIG W, I think it's noticeable in the advertising and the product range...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The repositioning of that business, that's very well done. I guess, either in sort of turn from that to the consumer electronics business, which I've asked you about previously, and comments there about repositioning that business. Can you elaborate at all on where you think the weaknesses are in the product, or price, or whatever positioning there, and how you might address that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, quite frankly, what we don't have here is a broken business, when you look at the performance over the last three years JB certainly had a blinder this half. When you strip out, as much as you can from the Harvey Norman numbers, I don't know the profit number in terms of the sales, there wasn't a great deal of difference between our sales, and then...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the data we get from the agency that measures market share in the key categories, like flat screens, and computers, and internet, etcetera, etcetera, we're actually growing share. So, this is not a broken business. However, we do realize that a big part of our store's actually taken up by products that are becoming less and less mainstream. There'll always be a demand for it and we'll always carry them, but we'll devote less space to those and more space to the categories that are growing in terms of delivering sales and margin growth for us going forward. So, that's probably as far as I want to go. But we've got a big job ahead of us, the team's up for it and I'm very confident that in due course we'll be able to talk about a business in a consumer electronics in the same way that I'm very proud to talk about BIG W, not to say that I'm not proud of the team at consumer electronics, but we just need to recognize that it's time for us to when positioning ourselves for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well thanks and well done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Thank you. Are we all done?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Once again, thanks very much for your time today and thanks for the questions. We appreciate it, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>