<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1367880" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-20</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9844</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Don Voelte, Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Lawrie Tremaine, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">John Hirjee</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">David Hurd</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Mark Greenwood</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Gordon Ramsay</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Peter Klinger</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Adrian Wood</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Sandra McCullagh</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Paul Garvey</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Stuart Baker</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Jason Mabee</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by and welcome to the Woodside Full Year Results Briefing. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. There will be a presentation followed by a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> I would like to advise that this conference is being recorded today, Monday, the 21st of February 2011.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand the conference over to your first speaker today, Mr. Don Voelte. Thank you, sir. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve. Good morning, folks. Welcome to our 2010 full year results briefing and thank you for your continuing interest in Woodside. I have with me here this morning Lawrie Tremaine, our CFO; and Mike Lynn, our VP Investor Relations, and a bunch of other managers here sitting right next door. So, let's get started and go to slide two.</p>
          <p>And I am referring to the slide that we put on to the platform this morning. On slide two, this is our normal disclaimer. And another reminder that we report in U.S. dollars. So, any dollars that are in the presentation are U.S. dollars, unless we specifically otherwise note.</p>
          <p>Slide three. Here you can see our financial headlines. We are clearly pleased to have recorded another record reported net profit in 2010. And we're pleased to have declared the highest annual dividend payment to this point in Woodside history. Now, this company, I believe, is really running well. Our people are getting phenomenal results from our existing assets. And as you can see with the return on capital figure on this slide, we're making great progress on adding to our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Also, I want you to note the very healthy gearing numbers that we have here that comes with a lot of effort.</p>
          <p>On to slide four. And this just highlights how well our production folks have been running our assets. What's more, I'd like to think that low staff turnover number demonstrates just how loyal our people are. Now, there's one number on this slide I'm not happy with, and that's our safety performance based on total recordable case frequency. If you turn to the next slide, we can look at that in more detail, that's slide five.</p>
          <p>While the severity of injuries suffered by our people and our contractors continues to fall, we should be doing better in this area. Safety will continue to come before everything else here at Woodside.</p>
          <p>On to slide six. Now, this slide makes me really proud. For all the activity we have in our sector, people are reluctant to leave Woodside. Our turnover is half the level it was four years ago. We have a great bunch of employees. Now, we've made enormous strides in increasing the number of indigenous people in our workforce. Note the graph on the left shows both our direct employees and those indigenous people working for our contractors. We directly employ 53 indigenous people and, with another 50 in our training programs, that number will increase substantially next year. Our people are our competitive edge.</p>
          <p>Slide seven. We see no slowing down of LNG demand. The world has produced about 210 million tons of LNG in 2010. The cross hatching at the top of this graph represents the range of forecast demand from a number of industry sources. Now, demand in 2025 is forecast to range somewhere between 390 million tons and 460 million tons. And this is an increase of about 85 to &#x2013; about the range of 85% to 120% from our current levels.</p>
          <p>From 2011, this year, going out towards 2016, 2017, the supply of LNG appears to be tightening, and this is very supportive for LNG prices. Beyond 2017, the market is banking on projects getting up, which we currently rank as only possible developments. Put simply, if you have any spare LNG over the next five to 15 years, you'll easily find a willing buyer. And those buyers are keen to ensure that they have Australian LNG in their portfolios.</p>
          <p>On to slide eight. This shows that there was three main LNG markets with different pricing arrangements. The Asia-Pacific market, which we have circled in red, has the largest demand, the highest linkage of oil prices, and it's right on our doorstep. Consequently, it's our key market.</p>
          <p>Going on to the next slide, slide nine reinforces that view. Here you can see that the circled Asia-Pacific countries represent, as a region, the largest markets with the biggest forecast growth.</p>
          <p>Now with that, I'm going to turn it over to Lawrie to go through our financial results in more depth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Don, and good morning to everyone. I'm going to overview our full year results beginning with production on slide 11.</p>
          <p>Production for 2010 was 72.7 million barrels of oil equivalent. After adjusting for Otway, which was divested in March of 2010, the year's production was 6% lower than 2009. The record North West Shelf LNG production, which was up 8% year-on-year, went some way towards offsetting the natural fuel decline experienced at our producing assets. Don will expand on the North West Shelf production performance in more detail later.</p>
          <p>In November 2010, we provided production guidance for 2011 of 63 to 66 million barrels of oil equivalent for our foundation business and 5 to 9 million barrels of oil equivalent for Pluto. Whilst our outlook remains within this range, cyclone activity and heavy rainfall in the northwest over the past six weeks or so has negatively impacted production, and there is another two months of the cyclone season still to come.</p>
          <p>Now to slide 12. Revenue for 2010 was $4.2 billion, equating to approximately $59 per barrel of oil equivalent of sales volume. Revenue increased 20% year-on-year, which is marginally lower than the 29% increase in the oil price over the same period.</p>
          <p>Slide 13. As most of our costs are incurred in Australian dollars, we have opted to reflect lifting costs in both Australian and U.S. dollars. In 2010, Australian dollar oil lifting costs increased $9 million to $230 million. This increase was due to higher maintenance costs at both the Laminaria-Corallina and Vincent assets. On a per-unit basis, lifting costs increased $2.52 per barrel mainly due to lower production as a result of oil field natural decline.</p>
          <p>Australian dollar gas lifting costs were $10 million lower in 2010, compared to 2009. A modest increase in maintenance costs at the Karratha Gas Plant was more than offset by lower costs due to the sale of the Otway facility. Unit gas lifting costs were essentially flat year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Turning now to operating cash flow on slide 14. The 2010 result of $2.1 billion was $621 million, or 42% higher year-on-year. Much of the increase is attributed to increased revenue from higher selling prices and a decrease in working capital, partially offset by an increase in royalty and excise payments.</p>
          <p>On slide 15, 2010 was a record profit year for Woodside in U.S. dollars terms. The waterfall chart shows that sales price was the major driver of the 7% higher reported profit. The higher cost of sales reported was predominantly due to higher royalty and excise costs associated, again, with the higher sales prices. The variance in other income is due to the gains on sale of our Otway, Sierra Leone and Liberia interests in 2010.</p>
          <p>In 2009, we reported over $700 million in unrealized foreign exchange gains on our U.S. dollar loans. The absence of these gains in 2010, along with the 2010 impairment of our Neptune asset and higher exploration and evaluation expenses are the main drivers of increased other expenses.</p>
          <p>Finally, the adoption of the U.S. dollar functional currency resulted in once off adjustments to deferred tax liabilities, positively impacting income tax and negatively impacting Petroleum Resource Rent Tax, compared to 2009.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 16. Our 2010 underlying profit was $1.4 billion, compared with $1.1 billion in 2009. In 2010, we had net significant items of $157 million. These were mentioned in my commentary on the reported profit result, however, to recap they included; the gains on sale of Woodside's interests in Otway, Sierra Leone and Liberia; a positive once off adjustment to deferred tax liabilities resulting from the change to the U.S. dollar functional currency; offset by the impairment of Neptune asset, and the write down of tax losses.</p>
          <p>For 2009, we have treated $494 million of after tax unrealized foreign exchange gains as a significant item. This is appropriate as following the change to U.S. dollar functional currency, we will no longer report foreign currency gains or losses on U.S. loans.</p>
          <p>Next to slide 17. Woodside has declared a fully-franked final dividend of $0.55 per share, taking the 2010 full year dividend to U.S. $1.05 per share. The dividend reinvestment plan will again be offered and will be fully underwritten for the final dividend.</p>
          <p>On to slide 18. Investment expenditure for 2010 was $3.93 billion. This amount is consistent with the forecast provided in late November. As expected, the Pluto project continues to dominate spending through 2010 and 2011.</p>
          <p>We have updated the 2011 investment spend guidance from $3.2 billion communicated in November 2010 to the current $3.45 billion. This change is largely due to the strengthening Australian dollar. An Australian/US exchange rate of $0.86 was used in November 2010 and $0.93 for this latest estimate.</p>
          <p>Finally, on slide 19, with proceeds from the sale of Otway and from the retail tranche of the equity raising in early 2010, Woodside is in a strong financial position. At the end of 2010, net debt was slightly below $4 billion and gearing was 26%. The company had cash of $1 billion and committed, but undrawn debt facilities were $1.7 billion, leaving us well funded into 2011.</p>
          <p>Late in 2010, we refinanced the $1.1 billion Asia Syndicated loan, extending the maturity from 2012 to 2015. Our maturities now are well-balanced over the next four years, and the refinancing task is manageable. We remain well-positioned to fund our continuing LNG growth.</p>
          <p>Thanks for listening. I will now pass the presentation back to Don to discuss the outlook for Woodside's operations and major projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lawrie. Now, on to some commentary of our operations performance in 2010 and updates on our major activities.</p>
          <p>On slide 21, to the operational headlines. We have seen improved reliability and availability across our assets. North West Shelf is breaking records left, right and center, and we're doing a lot of work to maintain production levels on our oil assets. International production contributed 4.5 million barrels of oil equivalent to Woodside's 2010 production.</p>
          <p>Slide 22. Our growth LNG projects are in good shape. Pluto foundation is 95% complete and we're targeting start up in August. Pluto expansion is maturing on schedule. The Sunrise JV has unanimously selected a development concept and complied with all treaty obligations.</p>
          <p>And Browse is tracking beautifully, rolling from basis of design into front and engineering design in keeping with the timetable set by the state and federal governments.</p>
          <p>On the next two slides, we'll measure our asset wealth.</p>
          <p>Slide 23, our proved reserve replacement remains strong at 148%, up from last year. And our proved plus probable reserves also increased from last year. And as you can see, our reserve to production ratios, or R/P ratios as we call them, are at the top of the industry at 18 for proved and 24 for proved plus probable reserves, respectively.</p>
          <p>To the next slide, slide number 24. That shows you we stack up well against our industry peers in reserve replacement. So, with that, let's move on to our company assets beginning with our existing producing fields, and then moving into our projects.</p>
          <p>Slide 25. With our oil projects, Vincent had a really solid year in spite of the constraints caused by ongoing repairs to the gas compression system. We increased production through infill wells that targeted unswept areas of the reservoir. And we also turned on the subsea pumps that further increased and optimized our production rates.</p>
          <p>Now, the FPSO has been shut down since the start of the year to complete repairs to the gas compression system. Compressor B will be back online in March with Compressor A due to be re-commissioned later on this year. Now, reinstatement of gas compression will restore 5,000 to 10,000 barrels a day of the incremental production.</p>
          <p>This year, we'll complete two further infill wells, which will help us manage the reservoir's ultimate recovery and will stabilize any field decline over the course of the year. A third well is planned and maybe drilled at the end of year or early 2012.</p>
          <p>Now we've completed a 4D seismic survey of the Vincent area and this data is now being analyzed. It's expected that this will identify further infill drilling activities to be undertaken over the next two to five years.</p>
          <p>Moving over to Enfield. 2010 production levels were boosted with the two new wells during the third quarter that came on stream third quarter of 2010. We call them the Main West, and the Horst, well, which added additional barrels of production and targeted unswept volumes within the reservoir.</p>
          <p>Now, over the Christmas and New-year period, we shot Enfield's fifth 4D seismic monitor. Past campaigns have been really successful in identifying infill drilling and side track opportunities and we hold out similar hopes for this campaign. The seismic work will help identify drilling and production opportunities for 2012 to 2014.</p>
          <p>We'll discuss Cimatti on the next slide, but its success confirms our expectations. We believe there are further drilling opportunities for oil in the Greater Enfield Area close to our existing facilities.</p>
          <p>Slide 26. One of the largest opportunities we have on the book is Laverda. Discovered in 2000, it's located fairly close to Stybarrow, Enfield and Vincent right there in the middle. During 2010, we re-shot detailed seismic over the region and completed a comprehensive development review.</p>
          <p>The seismic strongly supported a more detailed appraisal campaign, which we then started with top holes being drilled last December. We plan to complete the appraisal wells during second quarter this year and this data will be vital in taking Laverda to FID. At the same time, we have identified exploration targets adjacent to the Laverda structure and we will be drilling the Opel well as part of this campaign.</p>
          <p>The size of Laverda could be sufficient to support a standalone development or the oil could be used as a tie back to other facilities located in the region, which is certainly our preference. It supports Woodside's ability to maintain its oil production over the next five to 10 years.</p>
          <p>And you can see Cimatti on the map. We drilled the exploration target in 2010 and identified 15 meter gross oil column. We sidetracked the well to test the boundaries of the structure, and these positive results confirmed our desire to develop discovery over the coming years.</p>
          <p>Now, Cimatti is most likely going to be a subsea tie back to Enfield and we'll be looking to take FID, as I said, during 2011, and then secure long lead time items and drilling slots hopefully to come on production in 2013.</p>
          <p>Cimmati's success also increased our desire to drill other nearby prospects like Cagiva and Mineralli. We are confident that this region has many, many, many millions of barrels yet to be discovered and procured.</p>
          <p>Slide 27. I can't forget our outside operated field in the area, Stybarrow, which is operated by BHP. We had a number of challenges in 2010 with natural field decline and a number of planned and unplanned shutdowns.</p>
          <p>Stybarrow North helped out. It was drilled in the later of the year and successfully tied back through the subsea system. It's on production now. We expect Stybarrow North to help stabilize field decline and we're targeting equal or higher production in 2011, this year, than occurred last year, in 2010.</p>
          <p>Now as we look forward, BHP has planned an extensive 4D seismic survey and this is aimed at identifying infill opportunities in much the same way we're doing at Vincent and have already done previously at Enfield.</p>
          <p>And the team on board at North, the Northern Endeavour, continued to deliver safe and reliable production throughout last year. Northern Endeavour remains one of our most reliable facilities at over 98% reliability.</p>
          <p>Now, I would tell you, we're continuing to examine a range of alternatives for Laminaria-Corallina, including potential divestment of the asset. As part of this work, we have underway a field optimization study specifically targeting options to access the unswept portions of the reservoir and maintain production levels over the next five years.</p>
          <p>Slide 28. We're still on Australian oil, our North West Shelf oil field, what an amazing story about this that continues to boggle our mind. Based on our initial estimate, these fields should have been exhausted many, many years ago. But after more than 400 million barrels of production, the fields just keep producing for us, so much so that we're really developing the project.</p>
          <p>The redevelopment project was 86% complete at the end of December, with the FPSO Okha to replace our Cossack Pioneer FPSO. In short order, we plan to shut-in the Cossack Pioneer, do our work, bring Okha on production late in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Now, on to slide number 29. Finally, oil field at Neptune, which is operated by BHP in the Gulf of Mexico, efforts to lower bottom hole pressure helped substantially increase production rates in the second half. And we have four potential additional development wells to contemplate. Likewise, the optimization work at our Power Play field helped improve the performance of that field.</p>
          <p>On the Gulf of Mexico exploration front, the drilling moratorium has been lifted, but so far no new exploration drilling permits have been granted. That hasn't stopped us from continuing to develop our prospect inventory. We have a robust inventory of over 20 prospects and are preparing to resume drilling later in 2011 as the new regulations are put in place.</p>
          <p>Now we expect the first well that we'll participate in will be our Innsbruck prospect. As you know, our drilling operations were suspended above the targeted sections in 2010. We look forward to getting back into that well and resume drilling later on this year.</p>
          <p>Okay. Now, we'll switch gear. Let's go to slide 30, which takes us to the North West Shelf Project. The next set of slides will show North West Shelf just keeps getting better. So, let's run over to slide 31 here.</p>
          <p>Our North West Shelf production was the best year on record. As you can see, our LNG production performance following startup of Train 5 has steadily increased, with 2010 volumes eclipsing the strong 2009 performance.</p>
          <p>Records for LNG and LPG underpin our overall record year. They weren't the only records in 2010. We also had record length of time without trips of 85 days versus the previous record of 64 days, record daily production in July of nearly 800,000 barrels of oil equivalent and we include our oil field, and a record quarter production in the fourth quarter, all resulting in a record number of cargoes delivered this last year, 261 cargoes for the year.</p>
          <p>Next slide, number 32. You can see the actual revenue by product, and the average oil price over the last five years. As you can see, the oil price for 2010 was actually lower than the peak of 2008. Nevertheless, in 2010, we achieved record revenue for LNG, condensate and LPG.</p>
          <p>Now, after 26 years of operating the North West Shelf, we're still setting records in this fantastic project. Combine this production performance with the current price environment, and the results speak for themselves. Let's talk about the physical facilities at North West Shelf.</p>
          <p>Next slide, 33. 2010 North West Shelf production was 16.5 million tons per annum against our current stated long-term capacity of 16.3 million tons. As you can see via the second bullet, we're well on the way to meet our target of 97.5% reliability by 2013. Our second half performance for 2010 was an exceptional 96.8% across all trains. Trains 1 to 3 achieved 97.6% reliability in 2010 and Trains 4 and 5 continued to improve.</p>
          <p>Now getting back to capacity, as I stated, last year we produced 16.5 million tons per annum, or in other words, more production than our stated capacity. Before we go forward, let's go back for a second here. The original design, as you can see on the chart, was a collective 14.7 million tons per annum. Now, with the early Trains 1 to 3 undergoing significant debottlenecking over time of just under 20%, we were able to increase our stated long-term capacity to 16.3 million tons per annum with the additions of Trains 4 and 5.</p>
          <p>Now that we are debottlenecking these two trains, we have a revised long-term capacity target of some 17.4 million tons per annum. But before we get all the way there, we have set the next plant milestone at 17.1 million tons per annum, as an intermediate step, because our folks clearly know how to get to this level. And we know so, because the last half of last year we ran at that level.</p>
          <p>Go to the next slide. On slide 34, the Western Australia domestic gas market is growing as resource projects are competing for energy supply. The North West Shelf participants are continuing to actively contract new gas contracts. We're open for business. Woodside is competing to supply this increased demand.</p>
          <p>Woodside recognizes that a significant opportunity exists relating to the expiry of our legacy contracts and entering into new contacts that reflect current market prices. The market is indicating better than average prices for domestic gas, prices that net back comparable to what we get for our LNG. And Woodside continues to build projects to ensure security of supply well into the next decade.</p>
          <p>Slide 35. We have an update on our North Rankin redevelopment project. This project is designed to access low pressure reserves to meet increasing demands for North West Shelf gas. The project was 63% complete at the end of December. It's on budget and on schedule for completion in 2013.</p>
          <p>Over to slide 36. In 2010, we selected a development concept for our phased Greater Western Flank project and this year we're progressing front end engineering and design studies, or FEED as we call it.</p>
          <p>This development will access around 3 trillion cubic feet, or 3 Tcf, of recoverable gas reserves and 100 million barrels of condensate from 14 individual fields. Now, this will maintain future gas supply well into the next decade. Despite these two projects securing supply for the near future, this is not enough to satisfy our growth ambitions. We're getting back into the exploration biz in the North West Shelf and a key focus area for us going forward.</p>
          <p>On slide 37, the Seraph prospect is located underneath the Angel Field, and is planned for drilling in the second half this year. The well will test the northern end of a very large anticlinal feature called the Madeleine Trend. This trend has focused oil and gas into the Angel field, the Cossack and Wanaea oil fields.</p>
          <p>The targets in Seraph are the North Rankin Beds and Brigadier Formation. The prospect has significant volumetric potential, with follow-up prospects along the Madeline Trend, including under the Cossack and Wanaea oil fields. Now, these hydrocarbons were produced right into the Angel Platform.</p>
          <p>Slide number 38. The Tidepole East prospect is a prominent horst block with strong amplitude support. The feature is a low-risk incremental gas opportunity that could be commercialized as part of the Greater Western Flank project.</p>
          <p>The targets are intra-Triassic Mungaroo Formation sands, underlying the existing Tidepole field. Now, targets at these stratigraphic levels have been successful elsewhere in Woodside's portfolio, especially in WA-404 and WA-434. The North West Shelf Rankin Trend offers the opportunity to further exploit this play concept. Well, North West Shelf. Let's go onto Pluto.</p>
          <p>On slide 39, from discovery to production, Pluto is a global success story. 25 years' experience of exploring, developing, producing, and supplying gas counts for a lot. This know-how and can-do approach at Woodside has been leveraged for Pluto. Production will start up later this year, and there's tremendous upside for growth.</p>
          <p>I'd like to take a minute or two here on page 40 to explain to make sure that everybody is on board. We previously talked about Pluto's 4.3 million ton per annum train. This diagram shows what we mean by 4.3 million tons per annum. This is a long -term average quantity that we expect to load out from the Pluto gas plant and onto LNG ships, in other words, onto ships 4.3 tons per annum.</p>
          <p>To arrive at this 4.3 million tons, we have looked at the anticipated capacity of the LNG train, composition of gas from the Pluto reservoir and ambient temperatures. This determines the amount that can be introduced into storage at any given moment. In any given year, planned and unplanned events will interrupt production. These include unplanned trips and shutdowns or what we call, the reliability of the train.</p>
          <p>Now, planned maintenance is necessary to ensure integrity and maintain long-term production. External factors, such as cyclone events can impact production predominantly by closing the port, causing a ramp back up in production due to tank tops. Finally, some LNG boils off in storage, which reduces the amount loaded on to LNG ships.</p>
          <p>So, 4.3 million tons per annum is our initial long-term average capacity that we expect to load out from Pluto, taking all of these factors into consideration. The actual amount will vary from year to year, largely due to the planned LNG maintenance cycle. The reason we go through this explanation, we think there are folks out there, and there is spreadsheets that use 4.3 million tons as the starting point to these calculations, not the result.</p>
          <p>Further and importantly &#x2013; I'm going to say it's really important &#x2013; it's our intention after ramping up the plant that we target an additional 0.3 million tons per annum debottlenecking, just like we have achieved at the North West Shelf, therefore, moving capacity to 4.6 million tons per annum. So, get the plant started up, smooth it out, and then start debottlenecking.</p>
          <p>Let's move on to slide number 41. Now, we continue to target ready for startup production in August. And I'm happy to report that since our November update at our Pluto foundation project, we've been able to hold schedule on productivity issues via our mitigation plans. Now, further, we have good news on the flare towers and a couple of local western Australian contractors really &#x2013; has done a great job for us. They've got the replacement flare towers off our critical path for us.</p>
          <p>On the other side of the equation, not so good news for us is the horrific weather it seems everybody in Australia has been experiencing these last few months. For Karratha, we have experienced cyclone and low pressure rain events unlike anything we've seen over the past decade. We've lost around three weeks of construction time from the storms over the last three months.</p>
          <p>In fact, Phil tells me, it's still raining this morning at the site and we're in tie-down mode for the next cyclone that's going to come by called Carlos. Now, let me just tell you, it may be hard for us to recover this time at this late date in the project, but we're going to give it our best go.</p>
          <p>Our road to production is one shared by many hundreds of people across Woodside, from exploration to installation, construction to commissioning, and managing our relations with communities and governments. This team effort will result in a world-class production facility, supported by positive commercial arrangements in pricing and delivery.</p>
          <p>Slide 42. Notwithstanding the CapEx increase and schedule we announced last November, the foundation project continues to be underpinned by very attractive economics. Following FID, our 2P reserves have grown by 25% and significant economic upside exists given the debottlenecking potential mentioned earlier. Increasing capacity by 300,000 tons through debottlenecking and optimization boosts NPV by just about 20% due to the relatively low expected incremental capital cost.</p>
          <p>Slide 43. We started our Pluto journey in 2005 with our discovery, and we took a final investment decision in 2007. At the time, some called our Pluto project ambitious. They were right. Since that time, we've been delivering on that commitment to our shareholders, our investors, our customers, our contractors and suppliers, and our communities. We're very proud of Pluto. It's setting the standard for business at Woodside.</p>
          <p>Slide 44. As you know, the Pluto site can accommodate an additional four trains from our foundation project, Train 1. The foundation project has prepared the way for the next phase of expansion with installed capacity, that being the riser platform, trunkline, site preparation, storage and loading facilities.</p>
          <p>And also, the support infrastructure required is also in place. Now, this is really important stuff. This includes construction accommodation, contractor support facilities, logistics, warehousing, and construction laydown areas.</p>
          <p>And, of course, brownfield expansion requires significantly less people to construct. Now, we're talking about that more in a couple of slides. Pluto has always been a good opportunity, but the uniqueness is even more apparent now. Where else in Australia or in the world could we have the potential to bring on four trains sequentially starting end of 2014, with one year stagger to 2017? That's what's construction-wise possible. Compared to any greenfield construction, this is significant lower cost, de-risked, and quicker to production.</p>
          <p>Now, clearly we want to proceed with our own equity train from nearby Pluto waters, but we also want to bring in Other Resource Owners' gas, and we see an integrated development as an excellent opportunity to realize synergies in construction and to build efficiency.</p>
          <p>I'll show you more here on slide 45. The foundation project has installed capacity for expansion, and this schematic shows key elements of that capacity. I want you to note that Train 2 will be accommodated at site very easily with pretty much everything required already in place, except the train and some utilities. Therefore, the next step in expansion is pretty straightforward for us.</p>
          <p>Now, Woodside's experience is a competitive advantage in this aspect. And I'll talk a little bit more about that in a minute.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, on page 46, looking forward to the challenges of resourcing the LNG projects in Australia, Pluto expansion has a significant advantage. The site is already prepared for three trains. This eliminates the huge earthworks and site preparation required on greenfield sites. Support infrastructure is often forgotten, but is critical, and I've mentioned that earlier. Also, Woodside is well-established in Karratha, as well as our contractors, and the Karratha town and community are a great support platform for us.</p>
          <p>Now, there simply is just less to build. The foundation project has installed capacity in storage and loading, tanks, power generation, utility equipment, and their networks. This opportunity comes with a high level of certainty with most issues discovered and managed and systems of work established in the foundation project.</p>
          <p>So, how we're doing with the gas? Page 47. Here we see the 13 wells drilled for Pluto expansion with seven discoveries. We remain excited about our outboard success at Alaric in our Claudius hub and we plan more wells in 2012. Further, we have now shot 3D seismic over our Ragnar hub and I'm happy to report we see multiple prospects as you can see from the number of wells that we planned this year and next. But we view these outposts as future volumes for trains in addition to Pluto Trains 1 and 2.</p>
          <p>What I want to get back to is the goal we have of developing an organic Train 2 from our nearby Pluto or Inner hub and our Central hubs. Between these two hubs, we've drilled 10 wells with six discoveries.</p>
          <p>Now, over on page 48. I want to just say, remembering of course, that all discoveries add tremendous value to the foundation project as backfill, this sets a value hurdle for us to economically provide a hurdle for the expansion project.</p>
          <p>So where are we? Instead of trying to show you schematically as we've seemed to have caused as much confusion last August as not, we're going to try words this time.</p>
          <p>Since the last update in November, we discovered Remy, so we continue to build on the economic case for expansion versus backfill. This year, we plan to drill an additional seven wells in the Pluto Inner and Central hubs. Importantly, we're counting on success in the Martin WA-404-P, and the Xeres WA-34-L prospects to give us the assurance to order LLI's sometime in the middle of this year.</p>
          <p>Now, success with Kelt and/or Hennessy or any of the other wells would give us either substitution or a good cushion. The second half of the year will be largely appraisal drilling to narrow uncertainty, thus getting us in front of the Board for expansion sanctioning. Now, an FID needs a total package: economics, gas, permits, customers, et cetera.</p>
          <p>And by the way, late in the year after we purchased Hess' 50% interest in WA-404, we started, I'm just saying, we just initiated the journey of booking reserves just for backfill to Pluto Train 1 until we get to an FID for expansion.</p>
          <p>Now, with a few of the obvious sands in a couple of the wells, we started the process. I say obvious, because when we drill exploration wells, we don't stop and flow test and do all the other intricate analysis. Therefore, a more robust booking will take place as we include all the discoveries and complete a thorough appraisal and evaluation program overall to sands.</p>
          <p>Let's go over to slide 49, the drilling sequence. We're currently drilling our final commitment well in 404-P. We see significant opportunity in continuing our focus in the Pluto Inner and Central hubs beyond our commitments. We have an active exploration expansion program planned to support future volume build. And we're also excited about testing the Ragnar hub prospects, as well as the additional drilling in the Claudius hub.</p>
          <p>Over on page 50. Here's the location of 404 gas discoveries and potential targets that are shown here. And the next two slides show you our two targets that we'll drill next, Martin and Kelt.</p>
          <p>The Martin well has dual exploration and appraisal objectives. The prospect is located close to the Remy-1 discovery and displays a strong amplitude response, similar to that associated with Remy-1 gas. Now, multiple intra-Triassic zones are being targeted by the well.</p>
          <p>In addition, we'll be going through a stratigraphic interval that was gas bearing in Noblige. So, we'll design a core program to assist us in development planning. So, we're already into the appraisal. Martin-1 is currently drilling right above the exploration targets with progress delayed by cyclones, in fact, another coming through as we speak.</p>
          <p>We hope to have an answer in the next &#x2013; I was going to say, a few days or maybe in the next week or two. Now, Martin is the final commitment well in WA-404-P.</p>
          <p>Over to slide 52. I think I'll just leave that there for you to read, because I'm trying to save enough time for Q&amp;A. So, let's go to 53, we'll drill Kelt and we will report if it's successful or not.</p>
          <p>Back to the Pluto expansion plans on page 53. Our other resource owners' gas, we need to update you with, or ORO, as we call it.</p>
          <p>Now, let me remind you to a comment a few slides ago. While we do want to develop our own organic exploration expansion train, we do not see bringing in other resource owners' gas as either &#x2013; an either/or proposition. Discussions or could you say negotiations are ongoing and we definitely see a good value proposition in the making. And if we didn't see it in the making, we wouldn't be continuing the effort, but we are.</p>
          <p>Slide number 54, a simple summary slide for Pluto and Pluto expansion. Exploration and ORO expansion are still on. We do see the pathway in reaching our goal of an organic expansion train from our close-in Pluto Inner and Central hubs. And we see future organic expansion potential from the Claudius and Ragnar hubs. And finally, we do see value in processing other people's gas.</p>
          <p>Now, let me move over to Sunrise. On 55, let me assure you, Sunrise is driving forward. We had an independent certification of the resource volumes, 5.13 trillion cubic feet of dry gas and 226 million barrels of condensate. This is a project that is blessed with liquids. In fact, I sometimes think of it as a condensate project with LNG.</p>
          <p>Now, we had a unanimous development concept selection by the joint venture of floating LNG. Floating LNG was chosen because it has the lowest capital cost, lowest operating cost, lowest environmental footprint and is the most commercially advantageous development for both resource owners that being Timor-Leste and Australia, as well as the joint venture. One other note, it also costs $5 billion less than the Timor-Leste LNG option.</p>
          <p>Now, we've sent the three comprehensive concept evaluation reports. We've presented those to regulators, and the Sunrise Commission in Dilli in September, all this done in strict accordance with the international treaties, which provide a very clear approvals pathway.</p>
          <p>As such, in selecting floating LNG, Woodside and its joint venture participants have fulfilled all of our obligations under international treaties and applicable laws. We think it's an important milestone.</p>
          <p>Page 56. Why floating LNG? The answer is simple. It delivers the best value. Let me explain this. Timor-Leste received $13 billion for its 18.1% share of the resources that includes an upward adjustment of approximately $6 billion due to revenue sharing agreed under the 2007 CMATS treaty. Australia received $19 billion for its 81.9% share of the resources.</p>
          <p>Sunrise floating LNG has robust project economics. It has to. We're required to develop the field to the best commercial advantage consistent with oil field practice.</p>
          <p>We're also committed, along with the joint venture, to a significant social investment in Timor-Leste. We believe we can set a new benchmark in that area. Sunrise also provides one last opportunity for the people of Timor-Leste to commercialize a known resource, especially in the light of recent regional exploration results, which we understand includes nine straight dry exploration wells.</p>
          <p>Finally, slide 57 on Sunrise. I'm particularly proud of this. When we started in &#x2013; when I started in 2004, it was one of my first calls to shut it down because of a lack of fiscal and regulatory certainty. Three years later in 2007, the treaties were ratified, and the time was right, we were able to reenergize Sunrise and begin the journey again. And what a journey it's been, from rigorous technical and commercial evaluation to a unanimous joint venture selection, an exciting development concept that generates robust returns for all the stakeholders. So, we are where we are with Sunrise.</p>
          <p>Let's go to Browse, next slide. We'll finish up with Browse. On page 58, Browse is really shaping up to be a major driver in LNG growth for Woodside. With our almost 50% share, it will mean more for Woodside in equity terms than the North West Shelf project, in fact, a multiple.</p>
          <p>Our Board approved the project proceeding into front end engineering and design, or FEED as we call it, last week. We have FEED contracts in place for all major pieces of infrastructure. About 400 Woodside staff and contractors are now working on Browse, including 50 mobilized to FEED contractors' worldwide offices.</p>
          <p>Now this is the largest international mobilization in Woodside's history. We have the right people in place and we are right on track for a final investment decision in 2012.</p>
          <p>Page 59. Our basis of design for Browse, or BOD, was completed on time and to budget. The FEED entry decision has been supported by comprehensive joint venture and internal assurance review &#x2013; let me repeat that; comprehensive joint venture and internal assurance reviews.</p>
          <p>Now, the Independent Project Analysis, or IPA as they are referred to, a leading and recognized project assessment group reviewed Browse and found that we are in good shape to progress to FEED. In its findings, IPA said that Browse had a sound basis of design and that the work we have done has placed us on a similar footing to mega projects that have a good outcome.</p>
          <p>The joint venture, all of them &#x2013; let me repeat, all of our joint venture has approved 2011 funding of AUD779 million. Now, that's $130 million more than the Federal Government's requirement under its retention lease conditions. So, we are continuing to meet all obligations and conditions under the retention leases.</p>
          <p>Now, on page 60, our plan is to develop Browse with tension leg platforms, or dry tree units as we call them, at Calliance and Brecknock first, followed by the Torosa dry tree unit and Calliance subsea developments.</p>
          <p>Calliance and Brecknock will give us all the gas supply that we need to produce 12 million tons per annum LNG. Now, we have a dual FEED contracting strategy for the dry tree units and downstream projects to give us some competitive tension going into the engineering, procurement and construction phase, or as we call it EPC.</p>
          <p>The contractors selected for the dry tree units are Aker Solutions and MODEC. We know they are very well suited to handle the dry tree units FEED. The dry tree unit contractors will provide us with designs for two units at Calliance and Brecknock, with an option for a third dry tree unit at Torosa.</p>
          <p>Now, moving up slope, the central processing FEED contract has been awarded to Fluor Australia with a major McDermott sub-contract. The Central Process Facility, or CFP, is akin to our North Rankin B platform size and will comprise two bridge linked platforms. Now, this is located in fairly shallow waters in approximately 100 meters.</p>
          <p>As you can see, this is a very large pipeline and flow contract &#x2013; flow line project, and the contract award is imminent, in fact, maybe today or maybe tomorrow.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 61, the onshore processing facilities are now very well defined. The dual FEED contracts have been awarded and work is underway in London and Yokohama. The first consortium is Kellog Brown and Root, and they've partnered with Leighton Contractors and John Holland. The other consortium is Chiyoda, which has partnered with Saipem and CB&amp;I. Now, these are two highly credentialed consortiums. We believe this is a great outcome for our joint venture.</p>
          <p>We've settled on 3 by 4 million tons per annum design for the onshore foundation development, producing a total of 12 million tons per annum of LNG, using technology very similar to North West Shelf. There remains room to expand to 25 million tons per annum or nearly 50% bigger than the North West Shelf, as we find more gas through our Woodside substantial acreage position in the Browse basin.</p>
          <p>Now, Woodside is the number one acreage holder in the Browse basin. Let me just say, we've got some slides here. I'm not going to go through them in detail, but we are excited about drilling &#x2013; well, understanding Torosa even better, we think there's more gas there, but Argus and Omar are two explorations, both having approximately 4 Tcf opportunity sets with them. So, I'll skip over those and you can read them and ask any questions on those and move over to page number 63.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, we have a busy year and we've got everything ramped up, but everything in front of us is achievable. The Indigenous Land Use Agreement, or ILUA as we refer to it, is progressing well and we're now drafting documents with Traditional Owners, who continue to support the project and are actively involved in site activities. We would like to get this concluded in the near term. Let me repeat, we'd really like to get the ILUA done in the near term.</p>
          <p>Now, the state is managing land access at James Price Point. They've released a Strategic Assessment Report for public comment last year.</p>
          <p>The environmental reports of the Strategic Assessment support the case for James Price Point as the location for the Browse LNG Precinct. And we expect to close out our environmental approvals in time for the final investment decision. Now, I think full credit should be given to the WA Government for taking the initiative to aggregate projects at a single location, which takes just 0.006% of the Kimberley land area. Now, that's about the size of an A4 piece of paper in the Melbourne Cricket Ground.</p>
          <p>Woodside is very excited to have the opportunity to be the foundation proponent at the site, leading the way again. We have agreements with two customers that we expect to progress to sales contracts by mid-2012, and might I add, we have enough interest in Browse to sell the gas many times over.</p>
          <p>Slide 64, is a picture there of our James Price Point site, by the way. Browse, we believe, is a major project for Woodside. It's a company-making event. We have awarded FEED contracts and secured world-class engineering capability to deliver the next project phase. The joint venture has approved 2011 funding from the joint venture to keep Browse on track for FID mid-2012. Now, the JVPs are now receiving BOD assurance, and their respective managements are considering their decision on FEED.</p>
          <p>The next two slides give you a flavor of our basin potential. Again, I'll skip slides 65 and 66. By the way, the text of what I'm saying here will be loaded on the platform here in a few minutes and you can read my comments on those two wells.</p>
          <p>It takes me over to slide 67, the last slide. Finally, the summary. This time around I think it's really all about four major things, the North West Shelf is running like a top, the anticipated startup of our Pluto foundation project, the reality of our Pluto expansion, and the phenomenal progress of Browse. Yes, Browse is just a bit of a year away from some major decisions.</p>
          <p>Now, I also need to include because of all the hard work, the folks at the oil facility, and the options at Sunrise have also factored in.</p>
          <p>Let me make a comment on two other things here that I'm sure on your minds. This morning we released a ASX on the Shell Directors, nominated directors. As you know, 10% of Shell's holdings were sold down last year. And we have a governance of pro rata directors for the type of investment that they have in us.</p>
          <p>The Board, led by our very able Chairman, Michael Chaney, has worked with Shell to reduce their nominated directors to two from three. And at the Annual General Meeting, two gentlemen will be retiring, and the very able Andrew Jamieson &#x2013; Dr. Andrew Jamieson, who I consider an LNG expert, will stay on. We expect Shell to nominate a further number two nominee in sometime in the near future.</p>
          <p>Also my succession, let me tell you. The Board's nominating committee is Michael Chaney, and the NEDs, the Non-Executive Directors, are on it. And I'll tell you &#x2013; I can tell from the confidence in Michael's voice when he talks to me about it, I think they got a good candidate list. Now, I know they've been out &#x2013; the Chairman, and the selected members of the nomination committee interviewing the external candidates, and they'll compare those to internal candidates. I'm sure they'll come up with the right choice.</p>
          <p>I've completely left it open. My most important thing at this time, is focusing on transitioning and to make sure it is seamless and make sure that all the proper contacts are made, et cetera, et cetera. Therefore, because it's kind of timeless, sometime this year, later on this year, I don't know if this is my last results and road show for Woodside or if it's not. If not great, I'll get to talk to you again in August.</p>
          <p>If it is my last, all I can say is, the seven plus years has been a hell of a ride for me. This is a great country, Australia, a great company in Woodside. I have great friends, neighbors and co-workers. I know that now &#x2013; I now know more of what my future path is for me and my family. It's a good one. They're based in the U.S., but I'm going to get stay involved in businesses in Australia and I'll be a very frequent visitor over here.</p>
          <p>I guess that's good news for some and maybe bad for others, but I certainly am excited about it. I said the other day, I think I got more friends in Australia than I do back in the States. But one thing for sure, the rest of my life I will be closely watching Woodside's fortunes, and the fine folks that work here. And for you, shareholders, I've done my best.</p>
          <p>When I came, we had three small trains at the North West Shelf, a couple of oil facilities and a share price that was kind of stuck under $15. Market capital was well under $10 billion and every year reaching $1 billion in profit. Now, since then we've never had a year under $1 billion in profit. And with Pluto, I expect a new plateau will be reached by my successor. But in the end, it's all about people. And as far as I'm concerned, Woodsiders are the very best.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much. And we'll go on to Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> First question will come from John Hirjee from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, all. A couple of questions, if I may. Firstly, in terms of the oil lifting costs, you mentioned the impact on 2010 was more one-off. Should we expect, therefore, going forward, that the oil lifting costs should reduce to some sort of plateau? And would you give us some guide into what potential costs should be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, John; it's Lawrie. The oil lifting costs are, to a large extent, driven by the oil field decline. And so we're saying that across, in particular, Stybarrow and Laminaria-Corallina. In the case of Vincent and Enfield, we've done pretty well in &#x2013; through Enfield drilling and keeping production up a little bit higher in rate and time. And we also said that BHP will be doing some work at Stybarrow through their 4D seismic in the coming year.</p>
          <p>With respect to costs, we did note at Vincent and at Laminaria, there were some once-off maintenance costs. That's true. We don't typically provide guidance on lifting costs, and I don't want to do that from this morning. But what I will say is that the cost increase that we experienced, and there was $9 million of cost increases in the oil asset, has been planned and well controlled. So, this doesn't come as a surprise to us.</p>
          <p>And in the context of $80 oil, we're not particularly concerned by the trend as it stands today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks, Lawrie. My second question is directed more at Don. Pluto third party discussions, Don; I mean, can you give us some guide as to how you think the timetable of getting a result there? You said it was not mutually exclusive to your own exploration efforts with an expansion plan there. So, what is it that you're still waiting on to conclude those negotiations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first off, they're still going on and we think there is good value in there for us. They are mutually exclusive from the expansion train. We have identified different plots of ground to make sure that everybody's happy.</p>
          <p>We're looking at one case with one proponent for two trains. And they desire the bottom plateau, which would move our train somewhere else. We have a couple other ideas on our train. So, it's not &#x2013; it's not, like I said, waiting for one for the other.</p>
          <p>Being in a very intricate negotiations, there are issues around the engineering, the delivery, the timing, and also, for the companies of the first proponent, they'll be eliminating some of their other options obviously and doing some comparisons.</p>
          <p>We're looking for some solutions to some engineering issues and we've had multiple &#x2013; we're talking very large teams involved in each other's offices to resolve some of these plus customer issues as to delivery, specifications, et cetera. So, these things do take time. We're working though, let me just say, across the Board with very competent companies with different proponents. The one in particular, that we've probably gone the furthest with are LNG savvy. They understand it. They understand the marketplace, et cetera. So, I would just say that we're comfortable.</p>
          <p>We haven't put a specific deadline. We did hope that we would get to a point at the end of last year when we would say is this real or not. We passed that. We think it's real. And we're just basically working now into what you might call more detail and getting to a point where hopefully we put an offer out there that's negotiated, that they can accept.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Don, do you think it's largely technical, the discussions, or are the commercial negotiations complete or still outstanding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, a lot of the commercial discussions would be by the proponents to do what their part of the business of the molecules. They want to market their own molecules, which is perfect. I would say that it's heavily weighted right now in the engineering and technical design issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you, Don, and best wishes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will come from David Hurd of Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Don. I would just like to follow up a bit on John's question there; just the commercial approach that you're taking to other resource owners' involvement in trains. Are you looking at a tolling model or are you looking to trade your onshore facilities for upstream gas, and therefore, participate into the upstream? Can you give us some idea as to what your preferences are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, depends with the different proponents, some want tolling, some don't, some want to put their equity investment in and have us operate, construct, operate, and some want a combination of both.</p>
          <p>Let me just say that we are clearly in this to make money. We're not doing this to try to capture gas to keep it away from other people. I think we've already proven that. In other words, we want a viable economic outcome for our efforts and something that's worthy, compared to our own exploration advantage, and that's what we work towards. It could possibly be an upstream interest or might not, depending on what petrol rates are.</p>
          <p>I see it three things or four things. Number one is, there should be a payment for the right to use our facilities. There should be a check for pro-rata infrastructure cost of our Pluto Foundation project for what share they're using. There should be a construction fee for the value of our people building the plant. And also, we demand that we operate the plants inside our fenceline, and they'll be an operating tolling.</p>
          <p>That could be with their equity in the investment, or their &#x2013; basically I don't see us getting into a situation where we build large-scale plants, in other words, one-plus trains, with our equity for other people to put gas through. I would see that their investment had to be the majority of the capital investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, that's helpful. I guess also the highlighting the amount of pre-investment that you've made in the Foundation project. Are you able to give us anymore guidance as to how much incremental CapEx there is for a second train? It looks from the schematic that it should be quite capital efficient, but where do you really see the cost as a proportion of a greenfield project?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the biggest issue &#x2013; you're right, there's a not a lot onshore left to do besides some utilities, and the train. Costs of trains have gone up, by the way, for everybody. The biggest issue is the offshore &#x2013; or where is the gas coming from into the pipeline, flow lines they should say, the tension leg platforms or things like that. So, that's why we're really focusing on our nearby Pluto platform to reduce that cost, et cetera.</p>
          <p>Let me just throw in an idea out there that's in the back of our minds here at Woodside. There should be great synergies with the North West Shelf. We see future oilage over there. Pluto will be specifically and only available to provide that. There is not room for any other LNG components on the peninsula, and we're already seeing great cooperation on things like tug pins and we build a joint laboratory with North West Shelf.</p>
          <p>So, when we take a look at the oilage over there in the future, we have to balance that into 20-year capital build. So, we've got lots of great options and we think we've really built an option set that you can be &#x2013; I think, the rumors in the market &#x2013; I'd say, the rumors up and down the street of how hard it is to build LNG plants is now becoming a fact for people up and down the street.</p>
          <p>We think Pluto, being a brownfield now, we're getting an awful lot of attraction with people that have gas out in the area or have big exploration tracks out there. I think we've built and are five to six years ahead of people and we've got, like we said, four plus there and we'll be very careful what we put there.</p>
          <p>But we still have the opportunity to utilize our oilage in the future over at North West Shelf. And maybe others that don't have gas, maybe we'll be able to attract them with the gas that we'll bring in to our plant. And I think you can see where we're going with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Don.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will come from Mark Greenwood from Citi. Please, go ahead Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day. Just a question about the Pluto reserves and resource position. I see the reserves have grown by 700 or 800 Bcf, and the resources also &#x2013; there's a resource quoted there of another 316 Bcf. So, in total, an extra Tcf, I guess, of resource plus reserve, compared to what we saw last time. I'm trying to reconcile that with the chart you put up last time, which showed the reserve build for Pluto two where it looked like you had closer to 3 Tcf. Can you help me understand the difference in those two numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let's just do it a little bit different way than proved plus probable contingent resource. Let's use P90, P50, P10, that's what we use when we analyze the field. It's not how we report it. Right now, I think we're very clear to say that we've got about excess to our needs on a P90 basis somewhere &#x2013; I think, it's about 300.3 Tcf.</p>
          <p>If you use a P50 number, which is our planning, and what our most probable outcome for the reserves at Pluto, I think we're at 1.7 Tcf excess to our needs of what we would call our contracted and committed volumes for the first 20 years at Pluto.</p>
          <p>Now, what does that mean? That means not only the two Kansai and Tokyo gas contracts, but the sliver of production that's above the 3.75 contracts up to 4.3 million tons. So, that's 1.7 at a P50, and you're right, it's 3.1 Tcf on a P10. Part of our efforts will be, as we start producing Pluto, we'll be able &#x2013; that's a pretty big gap, if you think about it. That's 2.8 Tcf on a base, so that's like a 50% spread. That's pretty wide spread.</p>
          <p>Our reservoir engineers are very conservative. They want to see some production at Pluto. I would suspect that after we get a period of production, that P10, P90 range will narrow quite a bit. And my suspicion is, we'll have more gas there than the 0.3 that right now we're trying to be pretty comfortable with as protection against our contracts. So, bottom line is, yeah, we think that the Pluto and Xena reservoir probably has more to give than what we've taken into contract terms.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just in the presentation, I think you said, I forget what the exact words were, maybe you were counting on success in the next couple of wells in order to get to an FID decision by the end of the year. Could you just expand on that a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, what we said is that just take a look at our Martin well, and if you take a look at the slide number 50, you see Martin sitting down there with one, two, three, four, five discoveries right around it. So, we're pretty certain we're going to find gas there. The question is the cumulation types, the quality of the sands and just adding the other thing. Our expectation is, if it's going to be a good well. We will be disappointed if it's not. So, we're kind of planning on that in our heads that we've got that in that southern region. And the great thing about that as you can see on slide 50 is, that's all really close by, in other words, all these discoveries are clustered.</p>
          <p>If I noted that we're not as confident on Kelt even though we like the prospect, it really is pretty rank exploration up in the area. But Martin, we feel pretty good about. It's like, I do have a show of confidence there.</p>
          <p>Our Xeres well, we know a lot about our Pluto license block and we think this is a good opportunity that we'll be drilling. So, both of those, how we said it was &#x2013; was that we're counting on the success to really solidify everything that we have. If not, we have other opportunities and we'll use substitution form, but right now we're feeling pretty comfortable with both of those opportunities, but you never know. That's the great thing about our business, you just never know. But we're there, and thinking that we got a pretty good slate of opportunities. Like I said, if you take a look at that drawing again that showed Martin on page 50, we've got a lot of opportunities there to fall back on, but we like Martin, we like Xeres quite a bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on Xeres &#x2013; sorry, when did that prospect come up, and why haven't you drilled that one sooner?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've had it for quite a while, mainly because we had our drilling rig out in 404 and it's 120 kilometers away, you don't want to go back and forth. We'll pick it up on the way. So, I think it's on the drilling sequence there, I believe, for some time in April. We didn't &#x2013; we saw the cyclones out there. And I'll tell you, we just have been slaughtered with our rigs having to move off-location.</p>
          <p>So all of this might slide a little bit more, because we're not out of cyclone season. We've already had four cyclones that have put our people in harm's way. And I think this is the fifth one coming. So, safety above all else, we get our people out of there. And we move our FPSOs, disconnect them, and then we move them out of way. Same with our drilling rigs. Our drilling rigs are actually the first to have to go, because they're slow movers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Don.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will come from Gordon Ramsay of UBS. Please go ahead, Gordon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Don, I just want to jump to Browse. Looks like some very positive commentary today on the Browse project. Just want to confirm the timing of the FID decision by your joint venture partners. It looks like Woodside's been the first to commit to FID, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As is normal in our business, everybody wants to make sure the operator goes first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, is there a deadline for the other partners to commit to FID as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's kind of a funny thing, Gordon. They've approved the budget, and they're signing the AFEs, and they're paying the bills. So, frankly, we don't have a deadline on it. They're kind of in FID already. They've signed &#x2013; like I said, we've awarded the contract. They've signed off on the AFEs with the exception of one. I think the pipeline is still outstanding with one partner, but they're all coming along. I would also say, I've been looking at the negative, quote, comments about Browse from people that we saw last year.</p>
          <p>I will tell you, the technical assurance review at the basis of design conclusion, we were getting raves for the technical work done on Browse from our joint venture partners. In fact, one of the partners quietly told us that he was envious of our technical people and he's envious of the work that we had got done. They were all very happy with the ITA results. Let me just say this, they all have a process. We know BP, and I'll just mention them because they are the most vocal about it. We know they're in their process that they use, which has four dates, and we know they're well through it for fee.</p>
          <p>The other companies what you were hearing is, is that they're going to follow their retention lease, which actually puts them into FID anyway. But we hope they all do a formal FID approval. We think that's a good, strong supporting statement, but you're not seeing anything now of people not signing the contracts. Like I said, they gave us more money for budget than the government asked to get to this FID decision.</p>
          <p>So, they have their processes. They have their rights, but I think the rest of the venture's moving on and nobody is either selling their interest, from what I can see, and nobody seems to be stopping. There doesn't seem to be a spirit of any un-cooperation or non-cooperation among the joint venture. When we sit in joint venture meetings, it's amazingly progressive. So, I think we're feeling pretty good right now. They have to go through their own process, but operator always goes first on these decisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just also with respect to Browse, there was a Federal Court decision recently. Can you comment on that, and what it might mean for the decision-making process with the Kimberley Land Council?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'm &#x2013; gee, it was interesting. I was running over to Sydney for another reason on another activity I have. And Saturday morning, I ran into Wayne Bergmann, who's the head of the KLC at the Qantas Lounge in Perth actually, waiting to get on a plane. He was going back home from Melbourne, I was going over to Sydney, and we talked a lot about that decision.</p>
          <p>And I would say &#x2013; and I don't think I'm talking out of confidence here. He has made some public statements. And let me just say, he reiterated those public statements that they're feeling very strong right now. They feel like that was a good ruling, a fair ruling. They hold no ill harm or respect for Joe Roe, and frankly, we're into drafting of the agreement now with the state.</p>
          <p>And what Wayne was talking about was &#x2013; actually we were talking about signing ceremonies and all that kind of stuff. That doesn't say, there's not a lot of water to go under the bridge. We think that their momentum now to sign, even though there's an appeal outstanding. We feel that they have told us they feel very strong right now to go ahead and get an ILUA of land use. I want to get an ILUA. I want to do this without a process. I want it to be a voluntary act on all parties. That would make me feel &#x2013; and I say me, that's Woodside &#x2013; that's Woodside's intent and that's what we want to get done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will come from Peter Klinger of The West Australian. Please go ahead, Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Don. I was hoping you would be able to expand a bit on how your marketing talks with Browse Gas are going. You're saying in one of your slides today that you've got agreements with two customers. I was just wondering if you can just quantify that a bit or expand on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as you know, we have one customer that we've publicly stated we have a KTA with and we're advancing that KTA. The other &#x2013; first, and I don't think we want to say we have an agreement. We have basically &#x2013; let me see, how I said. Yeah, we do have agreements with two customers. So, there is some type of a progress-to-sales type discussion going on. We're getting an awful lot; I mean, an awful lot of interest for Browse.</p>
          <p>The Japanese new minister of MITI was down with a lot of Japanese CEOs, and we had an awful lot of discussions. I had a lot of people coming over to me from our customers saying, we think Browse is real now. We're worried that some other countries might be trying to get the majority control of Browse, and we don't want it to go away. Woodside has been really good with the Japanese companies; we'd like to have interest in it. So we hear that from a lot of different countries from the governments. The companies are backing it up.</p>
          <p>One other thing that's happening in the marketplace, and it's kind of an interesting thing for us, there is lot of people buying 2014, 2015, 2016 volumes, pre-buying volumes right now. We think it might be an indication of how tight things might be out in that area. And we think people are buying protection for some of their projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So can you suggest how much of your equity in Browse might be tied with those two customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, let me just say that you would expect a couple of &#x2013; first off, this 12 million tons, we own somewhere between 46%, 50%, somewhere in that area, so you just take a quick cut of 5.5 million to 6 million tons. That's what we &#x2013; we anticipate equity selling LNG out of Browse, that every partner will take their own piece of it. That's an anticipation, that is not an agreement yet, but we anticipate that.</p>
          <p>So we'll sell up to 5.5 million tons, or thereabouts. We would expect in that to have a couple foundation partners, as we call it, 2 million, 2.5 million tons each, and then we'll probably have some side businesses for what you might call boutique sales. So, I would say probably look at two major customers and maybe one other one on the side that is a boutique-type situation.</p>
          <p>I wish I had my &#x2013; Reinhardt Matison's here today. I understand that he is home extremely sick and he's unable to be here. So, I'm a little bit winging that one on my own without getting some head nods from him.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will come from Adrian Wood of Macquarie. Please go ahead, Adrian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, a couple of questions. First of all, can we just confirm &#x2013; I think just kind of in another question you basically said that the discoveries from WA-404-P have been booked as 2P reserves, is that correct or I misunderstood that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think what we said was, we're just initiating the booking of a couple of the wells, and we've just picked a few of the sands and it's backfill. So, the economics have to be good enough to backfill our Train 1, because you cannot book reserves, pass contingent resources till you have an FID on those reserves or you have a place for them to go that is solidified. So, 404 is just considered, at this point in time, as backfill to Train 1. That has a different mechanism for our reservoir engineers to put on the books versus if we were using expansion train with full compression, everything else that we do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So, the 20% reserve increase from Pluto then is coming from the Pluto and Xena reservoir themselves, rather than from any exploration last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the second question -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The 20% for those reservoirs, as we specified, 404 has its own set of discoveries that are pre-appraisal at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay. All right. And then the second question, and I guess this is targeted more for Lawrie. Just trying to look through some of the carrying values for the exploration and evaluation assets to try and back out what you may have paid Hess for the 50% stake in WA-404. I notice that on Note 12A in the Annual Report, you're talking about additions to the carrying values of exploration and evaluation assets at $701 million. That seems awfully close to the $360 million that you capitalized in the &#x2013; of the exploration you capitalized in the $340 million of the evaluation that you capitalized during the year. That would point to a very, very low acquisition price for, indeed, just a normal acquisition price for the Hess acquisition of 404. Am I looking at it the wrong way, or is there something that I'm missing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I don't want to comment on a transaction, which is obviously confidential, but I can tell you're looking in the right place. So, the amount that was paid was booked to exploration costs for the year. But bear in mind that the contract of sale includes a &#x2013; some milestone payments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So, it would appear that basically the entire transaction is almost &#x2013; almost the entire transaction is in milestone payments rather than upfront cash. Can you tell us that much?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, [Laughter] I can't tell you that much, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Thanks very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please from Sandra McCullagh from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead, Sandra.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Don, you said you lost three weeks in production to catching up for Pluto. Does that mean we could be delayed past August for the start-up of Pluto?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have August as a target. What we said was, some of the issues that we talked about in November, productivity, some of the critical piping &#x2013; final piping mechanical hookup and also, the flare towers, were causing us issues. We cautioned people that our target was condition-precedent, I guess you'd say, on industrial relations issues and on weather.</p>
          <p>I guess we're really feeling good about what we can control up there. The flare towers is really good &#x2013; I was up there a week ago and I don't know what kind of flare tower Phil's building, but it's big. I'll tell you, it's going to handle anything we've got up there. But the foundations are pretty well poured now, and the fabrication at Fremantle Fabricators is going very well, and we're well ahead of schedule, I understand, from where our critical path is.</p>
          <p>Productivity, we've done some things, like putting night shifts on and a few other things, to do welding at night versus rigging in the day. That's all gone well. What concerned us, and what bothered to us is, is that &#x2013; I mean, it is just &#x2013; I've not ever &#x2013; our people up there just can't &#x2013; number one, offshore has been rough as hell, and the port's been shut down several times, but it's been raining cats and dogs up there. It's kind of like other places around, but with Queensland getting all the notoriety, which unfortunate for the people over there, was rightfully placed over there, the Northwest has been going through quite a bit of hell, too.</p>
          <p>And bottom line is, we've lost about 20 days of productivity. What we said exactly was we're doing things to mitigate around that, but at this late stage in project, it might be hard to make up any or all of that time. So, we're going to give it our best shot. Phil is a very competitive person, so is his management team, and we'll give it as best crack we can, but we did want to highlight it because it's a fact of life up there. It is raining and raining and raining up there. It's very unusual.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You're talking to a Queenslander, Don, so I know what it's like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I tell you what, the world changes fast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give me some idea of the timeline for increasing the North West Shelf capacities to 17.1 million, 17.4 million tons?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've run at 17.1 for extended period of time, so our plant managers up there, they're very confident in what they're doing and this &#x2013; about two years ago, we finished up the last construction up there, which was frac six, and so the place just runs right now. And there's not a lot of construction activity going on. The biggest issue for us is integrity maintenance, and making sure that these long aged assets now that we're getting are properly maintained.</p>
          <p>So even though we can run for long periods of time at a 17.1 or a 16.9 rate, we do have to take shutdowns to ensure that some of those design niggles that were giving us on Train 4 and 5, like the refrigerant compressor, and the main cryogenic heat exchange, we think we're pretty well past those now. And we're just doing the run mode with maintenance shutdown.</p>
          <p>So we're kind of targeting that 17.1 as our capacity limit at this time, but you have to detract from that if we have a heavy maintenance schedule. We do have some shutdowns planned, but right now our folks think they can get it now. They've got three or four projects that will actually put some cushion to that, and they're well into it. I tell you, I've never seen a more confident group of people in Woodside than the folks up there that want to make sure &#x2013; their model up there is boring production. They want production just to be boring, day in and day out, no issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And 17.4 million tons?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a little harder. That's kind of a stretch goal out there, but the guys are &#x2013; the engineers have kind of set it up. The reason we didn't do it and put that down at this time, is the plant manager kind of wants to take bite-sized pieces, and 17.4, they kind of roll their eyes, and that might take some capital investment, too.</p>
          <p>But let's just &#x2013; hey, look, 17.1 if you think about that versus 14.7 original design, I would tell you that the succession of plant managers we've had up there and one of them's sitting here looking at me right now, they've done a tremendous job up there. I'm really proud of our operators at North West Shelf. They're really good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with Pluto 2, Pluto expansion, can you comment on the delays there, and the impact that might have with timing in Gorgon, and the impact of that on cost and resourcing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We're delaying Pluto 2. I guess, it's &#x2013; with the greenfield we've always kind of said 2014 was kind of our target. It is at the end of 2014 at this time, to &#x2013; with LOIs if we can get them at the mid-this year. I can't remember what we first said. I suspect we might have started this a couple of years ago, but we haven't had to move the schedule back very much, because with the construction, I think the brownfield fact, and what we learned in construction and modules, and this we've been able to actually even compress the time even more.</p>
          <p>So, maybe two or three quarters versus two years ago, something like that, but I don't even think it's been that much. So, we've been able to still keep schedule pretty well for the end of 2014 over the time period because of what we've learned.</p>
          <p>As to Gorgon and Wheatstone and other projects, Gorgon is certainly something we're keeping our eyes wide open on. I promised myself today I wouldn't talk about any of our competitors, because they're also our joint ventures. But &#x2013; let me just put it this way, whatever is happening at those projects, we've got a really close eye on it. We have a lot of contractor scuttlebutt, but frankly, we will stay out of their way at the peak needs of certain skill sets. We think we can get our 2014 train if we &#x2013; if things go our way. We still think it fits before the main special skill sets are needed at Gorgon, we still think we're okay. It'll be tight, but we'll be okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Don.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will come from Paul Garvey with Financial Review. Please go ahead, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, Don. There wasn't much fat in BHP's CapEx forecast last week for LNG. And just wondering if you're concerned about what that says about BHP's thoughts on Browse going ahead the next five years. And also, if you see any ways Woodside can help BHP find a home for its gas without much CapEx spend winding up going their way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't think they need much CapEx right now. They certainly approved their portion. Now, their portion is only 8.375% or thereabouts, maybe 9%. So, at the end of the day for a company as huge as BHP, this is probably just chump change. But at the end of the day, they've been completely funding everything up to this point. And even if you take a look at their overall, over a four or five year construction period, this isn't a real stretch for them at all for their cash generation that they have.</p>
          <p>They just have really small interest in LNG around the world for some of their projects, and so you probably just don't see it as much. We certainly didn't see any negative comments out of BHP about Browse project or anything else. We didn't see them out of Shell or anybody else. So, we think we've kind of hit a good tune at this point. And we'll just see what happens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about the other gas that BHP sits on around WA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think BHP has done really well at Macedon and Pyrenees, and we are joint venture partners at Stybarrow. But as to any developments of BHP properties, hey, you got to ask their company. They'll tell you what they're doing and I have no special insight.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can you quickly expand it along what your business interests in Australia might be in the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, this is kind of Woodside thing. I'll just say that I've fallen in love with this country, as well as my family has, and I do have family issues back home. I don't want to make a meal out of this, but yesterday, I rescinded my resignation based on my fellow directors at West Australian Newspapers. And bottom line is, I'll continue on with that. I've got a few other things that I'm thinking about. I've been offered a few things. I've been offered some directorships in other companies in the ASX Top 20.</p>
          <p>And let me just say one thing, I will never ever join a board or work in any capacity as anything that has anything competitive with Woodside. So, the bottom line is I'll do &#x2013; I'll be completely away from Woodside, but I want nothing but success for this company and my fine friends out here. I really plan to become friends with my employees, and there won't be any business activity within.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will come from Stuart Baker of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, Stuart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Getting late to place these questions, but just a question, Don, regarding the Browse and the onshore development as it's currently envisaged. Quite a lot of infrastructure there required really, marine terminals, jetties, et cetera. Does the joint venture intend to carry the infrastructure costs to launch this project in its entirety? Or is there a piece of business to be done to perhaps get some of the others, which are independently developing in the Browse to come here?</p>
          <p>It's pretty obvious that Shell are going to do their floating thing and Inpex go to Darwin. But if this project gets built in the Kimberley, then clearly, there's a piece of land there and infrastructure that could sensibly be used by others. So, is there a negotiation to happen around that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, how we're planning to handle that, it's a very good question, Stuart. The total track, we think, can handle about 50 million tons of LNG. Half of that track has been given to the Browse JV as proponents, plus we have additional exploration opportunity. We only plan to use 12 million tons of that 25 million tons at this time.</p>
          <p>You are correct that my construction managers and my Browse team think that the three trains are pretty vanilla. Nothing's vanilla in Australia, but if you can say vanilla, they're vanilla. The big trick there is the marine, to make sure the proper environmental footprint, make sure that we minimize dredging the breakwater, and all that has to be just as well. But that's kind of the biggest issue.</p>
          <p>We would expect that other companies and proponents coming in, if they utilize our facilities, will have a proportional cost, backing cost to pick up their share of the portion. We don't see it as having to be a major issue. The state has been phenomenal in that respect that they're saying everything is coming to this place, and they're handling an awful lot of the issues.</p>
          <p>So let me just say that it's something that we're very cognizant of. We're not giving a freebie for everybody. But I think it will be not too long of a time when other proponents who are moving their gas to other places will see this has a great synergistic value with us and we would encourage other companies to come visit us and work with us at Browse at the James Price Point. We think it's going to be a winner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Don, and all the best in your future endeavors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Stuart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our final questions from the telephone will be from Jason Mabee of RBS. Please go ahead, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Don. I'll keep it brief. I just wanted to ask in terms of Shell, I just wondered is Woodside taking a proactive approach at possibly trying to bring in a new strategic partner or is it a case of just letting Shell deal with it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I want to reject some of the media statements that we don't have a good relationship with Shell. The Chairman and I are working very constructively and professionally with them. I can't go too far on this. It's early days, but I'll just say that I would hope that we're not surprised with the other 24%, maybe we were surprised the first time around. But I would say are we proactive? I think we're doing the right things right now and I really, really just can't go any further than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then maybe just lastly, dividend policy, I guess a big jump in cash flows when Pluto comes along, but then also potentially big CapEx lump on the horizon if everything sort of comes off as planned. Can you just give us some color on where the dividend is heading?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, dividend is always an interesting discussion at the Board level and I would just say I have a huge respect for our Board's sensitivities towards the different type of shareholders we have. We do have a franking credit issue, but the Board spends a tremendous amount of time analyzing this and I think they get it right. They understand that we do have to recognize the past investments of our shareholders and put a return to them, at the same time, balancing the investment for growth in the future.</p>
          <p>By the way, if this is my last time, I'll just say the Board has been phenomenal with myself and our management team, great Board. And I would say, usually the dividend discussions are the ones that I kind of enjoy the most with the Board, because they really get into it, and they analyze all different various angles of it, and I think they always come out, in my opinion at least, with the right answers.</p>
          <p>So I think it'll be a balanced approach to the future, recognizing the shareholders have a right to a good return on their investment, as well as the best, lowest cost capital funding going forward, and using the cash flow in an appropriate way versus debt and equity raisings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>And I guess that's it. So, I'll just say thanks a lot. We've got road shows going on in the East Coast, up Asia-Pacific, North America and also, Europe. We're looking forward to seeing everybody. I don't know how many visits we got, but I think it's a record. So, we appreciate your continuing interest in Woodside. This went long today, an hour and a half, but got a lot going on with the company. Thank you all very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. That does conclude today's conference. We do appreciate your participation and you may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>