<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1249838" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9844</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Don Voelte, Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Mark Chatterji, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Stuart Baker</participant>
      <participant id="4">Mark Greenwood</participant>
      <participant id="5">Matthew Murphy</participant>
      <participant id="6">Matt Chambers</participant>
      <participant id="7">Adrian Wood</participant>
      <participant id="8">Gordon Ramsay</participant>
      <participant id="9">Fayen Wong</participant>
      <participant id="10">John Hirjee</participant>
      <participant id="11">Paul Garvey</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by and welcome to the Woodside half-year results conference call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. [Operator instructions.] Please to advised that this conference is being recorded today, the 19th of August, 2009.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand the conference over to your speaker today, Mr. Don Voelte. Thank you, sir. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. First, I want to convey my appreciation for all of you that are calling in to hear our results and, importantly, our future plans today. I think you'll come away with a very good picture of our accomplishments and our exciting plans to create even more shareholder value in the near term.</p>
          <p>With me today is our CFO, Mark Chatterji; Mike Lynn and Richard O'Loughlin from Investor Relations; and I got Peter Moore here, our Chief of Exploration, aiding in answering questions.</p>
          <p>Slide two is our normal disclaimer notice; nothing changed there. Slide three, I'd like to give you the headlines for the day. First, production of 40.1 million barrels of oil equivalent is, I believe, our second highest half in Woodside history.</p>
          <p>Our profit is a fairly strong $898 million. Our employees did a really good job converting revenue to the bottom line in this weaker commodity-price environment that we're experiencing compared to last year.</p>
          <p>The North West Shelf is right where it want to be, running at capacity, and some persistent design problems that we've had have now been eliminated. Pluto foundation Train number 1's going extremely well, over 70% complete. And we have initiated FEED, that's front-end engineering and design, on Pluto Trains 2 and 3.</p>
          <p>We're moving forward from an industry leading position. We think that these will be Trains 7 and 8 for Woodside out of first nine that get built in Australia. And some other really good news: Confirmation that Pluto Trains 1, Trains 2, Train 3 can all be located on the lower plateau, leaving the upper plateau for at least Train 4 and possibly a Train 5.</p>
          <p>Browse is rapidly progressing, clearly the best six months since we accelerated the development several years ago.</p>
          <p>Seventh, Sunrise. We don't say much about Sunrise, but I'll tell you, several milestones have been achieved this first half of this year and I think many more to come in the second half. This half by far has been the best performance in almost all aspects: production, operations, development, construction. I'd say this current Woodside group of employees have developed into the best group I've ever been associated with in my 34 years.</p>
          <p>From the Chairman of Board to folks turning the valves, I think everyone in the Company is devoted to three things: complete goal alignment, fantastic focus on our strategy, and excellent execution of our tactical plan. Frankly, we're having the time of our lives. It doesn't get much better than this.</p>
          <p>Now, I'm going to turn it over to Mark and he'll give you our half-year results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Don, and good morning, everybody. I'll go to slide number five. For the first half of 2009, Woodside produced 40.1 million barrels of oil equivalent, which was a 10% increase from the comparable first half of 2008. Now the major driver of this increase was North West Shelf, which had contributions from Angel and Train 5, while the Australian business unit put up strong performance despite a shutdown at Vincent.</p>
          <p>We think production in the second half of 2009 is looking good. Vincent production was resumed in mid-June and at the end of the half we were making almost 29,000 barrels of oil per day on a 100% basis. Train 5 is operating at its expected average capacity of 4.4 million tonnes per annum, which takes the entire system up to 16.3 million tonnes per annum, again on a 100% basis.</p>
          <p>Finally, as I'll talk about later, we have several new oil producers on line. Now, as a result of all this, we continue to expect full-year 2009 production to be in our previously announced 81 to 86 million barrels of oil equivalent range.</p>
          <p>Turning to page six, on cost. Production cost for gas fell on both the total and per boe basis as compared to the first half of 2008. This was due to lower OpEx on North West Shelf coupled with final production on North West Shelf and Otway. Per-boe oil production costs were also lower compared to the first half of 2008 primarily driven by lower OpEx at the Northern Endeavor.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide number seven, revenue for the first half of 2009 decreased 21% versus the first half of 2008 with average NYMEX WTI declining to $51.53 from $110.98. Now that fall in commodity prices was partially offset by the fall in the Australian dollar to $0.71 from $0.92. It was also partially offset by the production increase I discussed earlier.</p>
          <p>Slide number eight &#x2013; as you might expect, lower revenue has led to lower profits for the first half of 2009 versus the first half of 2008: however, profit for the first half was also impacted by foreign exchange gain caused primarily by the revaluation of our U.S. dollar debt, ex taking into account the hedge of net investment provided by our U.S. dollar asset.</p>
          <p>Now those of you listening to the call who have been following Woodside for some time will remember that this same accounting impact showed up on our full-year 2008 results; only then, it served to reduce profit as opposed to augment profit. The health warning remains the same: The revaluation is a book effect, not a cash effect. It could just as easily back itself out of the full-year results in the event the Australian dollar declines at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Slide nine, moving onto dividends, the Directors declared an interim 2009 dividend of $0.55 fully franked. The dividend in 2008 reflected an unprecedented increase in the oil price. Woodside is investing heavily in its growth as exemplified by Pluto 1 and we look to provide solid dividends that are consistent with this spending profile. The 2009 interim dividend will be fully underwritten using our dividend reinvestment program. Our intent is to maintain this fully underwritten DRP throughout the Pluto construction phase.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, turning to expenditure, we announced in February that in light of the changes in the marketplace, we were going to tighten our belt. Now the marketplace seems to have gotten better in the interim, but we have stuck to our plan all the same, reducing spending by around a half-billion dollars. And most of these reductions were in capital, which of course is now the major portion of our expenditure profile. Also, as you can see from the update, we expect to spend a bit under $5 billion this year on Pluto, which brings total expenditure on the Pluto 1 project to over $9.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 11, taking a look at funding, you'll see that at the half we had US$1.75 billion of dry powder in the form of our undrawn facilities, on top of which we had almost AUD 800 million of cash on the balance sheet. Keep in mind that we had closed the Asian syndicated loan shortly before we closed the half-year books.</p>
          <p>Our expectation is that these resources will take us through the end of 2009 and into the start of 2010, so we're now turning our attention to the rest of 2010. While we expect our committed spending to be lower in 2010 than it was in 2009, as Don will talk about, we're now moving beyond Pluto 1 into the rest of the LNG growth portfolio. Our funding plan will depend not only on the activity in the rest of this LNG growth portfolio, but also on the scope of any asset sales we might undertake.</p>
          <p>Slide 12. Looking forward, in addition to all the news that Don is going to give you about LNG, we'd like you to keep in mind that we remain a substantial producer of oil and that oil remains an important part of Woodside.</p>
          <p>You can see that we have a number of development wells being planned on our producing fields. Let me highlight two that have already come in. Start with the Northern Endeavour. Last year's subsea maintenance campaign has restored production from the existing wells, but in addition to that we've sidetracked Corallina-2. The team thought that there might be unswept attic oil to go after and we're pleased that this &#x2013; that sidetrack has come in at around 26,000 barrels of oil per day on a 100% basis. We're even more pleased to see several similar structures to go after.</p>
          <p>At Enfield, we drilled an injector and producer pair in the Sliver South block of the field and that well came in at around 20,000 barrels of oil per day on a 100% basis. In addition to Enfield drilling opportunities shown on this slide, we have several near-field prospects across our oil portfolio that are candidates for drilling in 2010.</p>
          <p>And finally on the slide number 13, on exploration &#x2013; 2009 has seen Woodside participate in three discoveries so far: the Martell gas discovery to the north of Pluto and two oil discoveries in the Santos basin in Brazil. We are currently drilling the Venus B well in Sierra Leone. Woodside has a 25% equity interest in this well. The Venus B, in addition to the Rickenbacker prospect in the Gulf of Mexico, both expose Woodside's material oil volume in a success case. And we intend to finish this year by kicking off a new round of Carnarvon Basin exploration, which Don is going to talk about in the next part of the presentation.</p>
          <p>Thanks for listening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark. One quick comment before laying out our future plans. Mark's part of an extremely talented management group here at Woodside; they're really good. A lucky person to have the pleasure of working with this great team. They can handle just anything that gets thrown at them these days.</p>
          <p>Let me go to slide 15. Just a minute to celebrate our North West Shelf &#x2013; 25 years of operating pipeline gas in Western Australia, 20 years of delivering LNG to international customers. This means greater than 4,000 petajoules of pipeline gas has been delivered, more than 2,700 cargoes of LNG and 1,000 cargoes-plus of condensate. And after 25 years, we're fully framed out at North West Shelf: five LNG trains for a total of 16.3 million tonnes annual capacity, three fractionation trains, six stabilizers, two LNG burrs, one condensate jetty, a LPG jetty, two trunk lines, three gas platforms and one FPSO.</p>
          <p>For oil &#x2013; today, this $27 billion project represents Australia largest resource development and accounts more than 40% of all Australia oil and gas, 65% of gas production in Western Australia, and over 1% of the nation's growth domestic product.</p>
          <p>On slide 16, we're just trying to give you an idea that it's more than just LNG that comes out of North West Shelf. It's a total commodity process and we've shown you the last five years' production of LNG, condensate, LPG and pipeline gas.</p>
          <p>Moving over to slide number 17, this is where it gets interesting. I love the headline, "Pluto powers ahead." For Woodside, this is our project that builds on our North West Shelf experience. In fact, in less than five years from now, our plans are to have in place and operating four times the Woodside equity capacity at Pluto as compared to our equity at North West Shelf. More about this in a few minutes.</p>
          <p>So, I'm happy to report that our Pluto greenfield foundation project is 72.5% complete as of today. Further, I am very happy to announce that we're now in FEED for Pluto brownfields Trains 2 and Train 3. For Train 2, we see long-lead-time items mid-next year, FID by the end of next year, and first gas before the end of 2013.</p>
          <p>For Train 3, we just add a year to these events, giving us the third train by the end of 2014. In addition, we have confirmed a Train 4 location in our existing lease area and are setting up for a possible location for a Train 5.</p>
          <p>Now let's take these items in order over the couple of minutes. First, our Pluto greenfield Train 1 project, I'm going to flip through the next 10 slides in pretty rapid progression here to save some time.</p>
          <p>On slide 18, you can see our greenfield site from the water side. Lower left is the jetty construction, condensate tanks to the left, and our two LNG tanks to the right.</p>
          <p>Slide 19, you get the opposing view from the land. You can start at the top and see some of our utilities and flare systems facilities coming along. Train 1's just in front of those facilities; you probably make out the two big turbine packages. Train 2 is where you see some module stores and Train 3 will be where the temporary construction cribs have now located in the near picture. And by the way, you can see our North West Shelf plant in the upper right.</p>
          <p>Slide 20, we thought we'd show you one of our more than 150 already delivered modules being off-loaded from a shipping vessel. Now, this one just happens to be one of our turbine packages.</p>
          <p>Slide 21, we'll take the same turbine package and show you it's on its trek, on its way to its final location, which you can see in the bottom right-hand picture. This module technology we developed now is on &#x2013; we're using on the second time on Train 1 versus North West Shelf Train 5 is really super.</p>
          <p>Slide 22, this is the Pluto jacket up in China getting ready for ocean shipment to the Pluto field. The base of the platform is on the left of the structure as it lies on its side. You can see the four tan mats, which are the ocean-bottom mud mats, and you can see the pile guides very clearly, the long-cylinder pipes at each corner base. I'm happy to announce that the jacket was loaded over the weekend onto its oceangoing transport vessel and it's going to be shipping in the next few days down here to Australia.</p>
          <p>Slide 23, this is the Pluto production deck in our Malaysian fabrication yard. It, too, is nearing completion. You can easily make out the heliport on top. To get an idea of the size, you can see a man in blue and a white hard hat and standing on top of the yellow construction stairwell there in the front of the picture.</p>
          <p>Slide 24, I'm happy to report that both LNG tanks have now topped out with concrete. As you know, these two tanks equal all the storage capacity at North West Shelf. And, significantly, we achieved a successful hydro test at tank number one over the past week. Construction on the condensate tanks is at the right.</p>
          <p>Slide 25, our Pluto trunk line is under construction. We're laying pipe, both outbound from the onshore gas plant site as well as laying pipe inbound from our Pluto platform location. About 45% has been completed; each vessel's making about 1.5 kilometers progress every day and, significantly, the insulation of all the subsea flow lines is now complete.</p>
          <p>Slide 26, this page shows you the milestones we've achieved so far this year and what we expect by year-end. Major items to complete this year: one is to load out, transport and install the Pluto jacket; two, load out, transport and install the Pluto onshore topside; three, set down the main liquefaction modules; and four, kind of a general one &#x2013; generically, we need to continue to what we call break the back of the onshore construction.</p>
          <p>As far as by the end of this year, we plan to be at least 85% complete with the greenfield Train 1 project. Now as far as commissioning is concerned, I'm pleased to announce that yesterday afternoon we moved the first group of five systems over to our commissioning team, who've been awaiting this move. So, they &#x2013; so, we now have commenced commissioning officially. Now, they have a busy year coming up because there's over 1,000 systems to commission.</p>
          <p>Slide 27, the project's maintaining cost and schedule. It should be noted that peak construction, a critical phase for remaining on cost, is anticipated to be completed over the next six months.</p>
          <p>Now, when we took FID in 2007 &#x2013; make that July 2007 &#x2013; we told the market we'd be building the fastest greenfield LNG development in the world. I know people were quite skeptical; after all, much bigger companies than Woodside have sat on bigger gas fields for years.</p>
          <p>Now this was and still is an ambitious and challenging schedule, but we remain on schedule for first gas from the Pluto field in late 2010, first LNG in early 2011, and by mid-2011 we expect to be running at full capacity.</p>
          <p>Slide 28, let me just say one hurdle I wanted to get over before we went on with the future Pluto trains was the reassurance that I could give the Board and our management team that our Pluto greenfield Train 1 management team was grounded, solidly entrenched with the project and well along an inevitable path &#x2013; all that to ensure that Train 1 team would not be distracted by the expansion.</p>
          <p>I now have that assurance that we have achieved that. Therefore, we're now into Train 2 and Train 3 FEED. Since Train 1, Train 2 and Train 3 are sharing the same plateau, we're going forward with FEED for Trains 2 and 3 at the same time.</p>
          <p>Train 2 will be projected 60 to 90% Woodside equity train at a design of 4.3 million tonnes per annum. LLIs are scheduled mid-next year, FID at the end of next year, and first gas at the end of 2013.</p>
          <p>Slide &#x2013; I'm sorry. Train 3 will be projected to be a 75 to 90% Woodside equity train at the same designed capacity. Forecast LLIs mid-2011, FID at the end of 2011, first gas into 2014. Now, one other issue there is we will need a second trunk line with Train 3.</p>
          <p>Now, you can understand what an advantage Woodside has to benefit from, based on our early, industry leading Pluto 1 decision. If I might say so myself, it was a gutsy call, going to pay off big time, I think, for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Slide 29, let me summarize the gas sources for Train 2. Our Train 1 foundation Pluto drilling has come up very positive &#x2013; let me repeat, very positive. We not only have surplus gas for our Train 1 contract needs based on our core 15-year contracts, but we'll also be able to accelerate a good portion of Pluto/Xena tail gas due to very high rate wells that we drilled at Pluto and we will drill at Xena. Now, this is increasing shareholder value to the maximum, as we see it. We also have use of a portion of equity gas, or acquired equity, from recent exploration discovery.</p>
          <p>Also in a few minutes, I'll show you our expectations from our building exploration prospect inventory. And finally, we may or may not include other resource owners' gas. We are very selective because the value proposition has to be a winner for both parties. Again, I'll explain that more in a one minute or two. Now, from the chart on the right, we have tried to graphically show you the acceleration potential of Pluto/Xena tail gas, as well as the stacking effect of the train.</p>
          <p>Slide 30, another very important slide. We want to break down the sourcing of gas versus contract time parameters. In the upper half of the slide, we show you the cumulative volume of gas required for Train 2 and beyond. We show volumes for both a 15-year and a 20-year contract, or contract with option periods. Using the Pluto Train 2 volume requirements of 3.8 Tcf and 5.1 Tcf, respectively, we show a most likely gas supply scenario.</p>
          <p>We expect 0.4 Tcf of tail gas available from excess volume as compared to our true needs of Train 1 at the Pluto/Xena field. In other words, this volume is excess to the 4.85 Tcf committed to Train 1. Further, we expect the equity capacity designated to other resource owners to be approximately 1.5 Tcf.</p>
          <p>In addition, another 0.5 Tcf will come from existing discoveries or other gas secured commercially. Therefore, we need to identify 1.4 to 2.7 Tcf of gas that is profitably accumulated from our 20-plus-wells exploration drilling program coming up.</p>
          <p>The expected range of volumes from our discoveries from this portfolio easily exceed these requirements. Importantly, the tail gas represents a conservative three-year acceleration based on P90 confidence for half of a train. Therefore, in our most likely scenario, the Pluto Train 2 could effectively produced first gas in 2013 and Woodside would not need to get the exploration discoveries developed to supply Train 2 until 2016.</p>
          <p>So, we have to find 1.4 to 2.7 Tcf of gas, not necessarily produce it, to get up and running with Train 2 in 2013. By the way, this tail gas acceleration phenomenon will be available in a domino effect for all future Pluto trains.</p>
          <p>Slide 31, kind of hard without the explanation, but I'll give you a pretty good one here. We'd like to explain the opportunity and the limitation of what we call O-R-O, or "ORO," other resource owner gas economy. Now, I'll go through this slowly. In the top left schematic, you'll see on the right the Pluto onshore gas plant. Adjacent to the left is the Pluto platform with Train 1 Pluto/Xena gas supplied directly to the platform from nearby sea floor manifold of well installations.</p>
          <p>The distant platform, far left, anticipates our collection of our gas from Woodside discoveries located remote to the Pluto platform. Therefore, the cost to bring in this remote gas is the wells, subsea kit, a platform facility, as well as the cost of the new train.</p>
          <p>Now, as shown below and to the right, for other people's gas, if located close enough to the Pluto platform to flow directly, then the cost for ORO is effectively the wells, subsea kit, as well as the cost of the new train.</p>
          <p>If ORO gas is located remote, then the ORO cost is the wells, subsea kit, the distant platform, as well as the new train. So, the economic rent available to Woodside goes something like this. The best gas economically is, of course, Woodside's close-to-Pluto-platform stores. The next best gas we believe is either Woodside's remote gas or ORO's close-to-Pluto-platform stores.</p>
          <p>The most disadvantaged gas is ORO's remote-to-Pluto platform. Also shown here is the fact that if other people want equity in our facilities, they will have to pay us a towing fee or a portion of the infrastructure cost that's already built. So, they get to write big check.</p>
          <p>Now, therefore, we are comfortable to say that there appears to be a strong economic incentive to Woodside with available ORO gas that is either, number one, in close proximity to the Pluto platform or, two, in close proximity to a remote Woodside platform installation where we've found our gas.</p>
          <p>What we're not comfortable with yet is if there's enough economic rent to share with a small, remote ORO source for gas that's found remote to either of our platforms &#x2013; our distant platforms with our gas or with the Pluto platform. And I'll tell you this: we're not pursuing these opportunities at this time.</p>
          <p>Now, moving on to slide 32. I will tell you that our Pluto head start has garnered a lot of industry interest, actually more interest that we at Woodside are interested in. Our Woodside Pluto Train 2 gas potential in 2013 versus next-best industry offer of 2016 is a clear winner. We've had inquiries from numerous companies. We have entered discussions with five companies that we believe have material gas that meets the criteria of Woodside profitability that we just explained.</p>
          <p>Now, two companies are well advanced in due diligence and negotiation. One company is not quite as advanced, but is in due diligence and negotiation. Another company is considering our commercial proposal and, finally, one other company is studying whether to enter a joint study.</p>
          <p>Let me reiterate: not all ORO gas will work through Pluto due to the economics. Only gas that provides Woodside the proper economic outcome for the capacity used will be consummated. I'd rather pass doing the bad deal and wait to cover with our own exploration potential.</p>
          <p>Speaking of exploration, the next set of slides are one I'm really excited to tell you about. Slide 33 is the start of a really exciting Carnarvon drilling program. What Agu [Kantsler] and Peter and our exploration team have compiled in the way of Carnarvon gas exploration prospects is really amazing.</p>
          <p>We've continued to build our acreage position within tieback radius of Pluto. While the acquisition of five new permits has increased the number of prospects in the portfolio, more importantly it's also added new geologic plays and diversity to the portfolio, increasing our probability of finding new gas reserves. Now, we've just &#x2013; we have divided our acreage into six hubs based on location and development scenarios to talk to you about today.</p>
          <p>On slide 34, 3D seismic is key to derisking our present prospect portfolio and, by studying these data in a regional sense, we've been able to identify new geologic plays. Woodside continues to build towards the vision of stitching together complete 3D seismic coverage of the Carnarvon Basin.</p>
          <p>In the past year, we've provided our geologists with 17,000 square kilometers of new 3D seismic. Let me repeat that: 17,000 square kilometers of new 3D seismic data. And by the end of next year, we plan to add another 23,000 square kilometers through a proprietary acquisition, purchase of data from contractors, and acquisition of open-file data. This level of 3D seismic coverage is absolutely unprecedented in Australia.</p>
          <p>Slide 35, Woodside's exploration and support of Pluto now extends over 13 exploration permits, covering almost 40,000 square kilometers. Across our six hubs, we've mapped 39 prospects to drill on 3D data and have at least 35 leads still to be matured. Now, these prospects range in size from 0.5 to 10 Tcf. Hence, you can see we have a large, varied exploration portfolio capable of supporting Pluto expansion.</p>
          <p>Slide 36. This slide shows examples of the variety of geological plays found across the different hubs. Some plays, such as the top Triassic, have been heavily explored in recent years with many discoveries, a number of which are on production today.</p>
          <p>Others, like the carbonate pinnacles, are examples of new plays that have only recently been recognized on new 3D data, but have yet to be drilled. Our portfolio contains good examples of all these plays across the different hubs. Quite a few prospects have potential direct hydrocarbon indicators, as we call them in the industry, DHIs, on the seismic. We're excited about the opportunity to test all of these different plays in an aggressive exploration campaign.</p>
          <p>Slide 37. So, let's go through a summary of each of these hubs. While the focus on the Pluto field has been prog... &#x2013; has been to progress the development for first gas in 2010, there's also a portfolio of exploration opportunities adjacent to and actually just below our field.</p>
          <p>With the focus shifting to Train 2 and Train 3, we have renewed exploration efforts in this area to add additional gas reserves. Two wells we've planned for Q4 this year, with follow up drilling anticipated in 2010.</p>
          <p>Now, the first well, which we choose to call Pelion, we'll drill below the Pluto field to test two possible channel sands reservoirs. Special processing of the seismic data to illuminate gas-bearing reservoirs suggest that these sands should be gas-filled.</p>
          <p>If this prospect is successful, then there are a number of look-alike prospects below both the Pluto and Xena gas fields. The Pyxis prospect lies immediately north of the Pluto field. This slide shows the amplitude map of the target reservoir. This bright seismic amplitude response has been indicative of gas-bearing sands and we're quite confident that Pyxis will be successful.</p>
          <p>Slide 38, over to the Central hub. Woodside made the Martell gas discovery earlier this year with the first of nine commitment wells in WA-404-P permit. Reprocessing of the 3D seismic has improved the data quality and allowed interpretation to be pushed deeper into the geological section. This work is now revealing seismic amplitudes which suggest the presence of gas not only at the top Triassic as in Martell, but also deeper in the intra Triassic section.</p>
          <p>This is an important observation, which enhances the prospectivity of the region, because it suggests local hydrocarbon generation in the area. As an example, the Noblige prospect is shown on this slide and it's located just adjacent to the Martell gas field.</p>
          <p>Slide 39, over to the Cazadores hub. Woodside has three permits on the north edge of the Exmouth Plateau. At the time these blocks were acquired, they were a considerable distance from any proven gas fields; however, with the advances in exploration and recent gas discoveries continuing to be found further north, these blocks are now immediately adjacent to this world-class gas province.</p>
          <p>Woodside has continued to focus geological and geophysical studies on these blocks to derisk the prospect. Earlier this year, we acquired more than 4,500 square kilometers of new 3D seismic. Interpretation of this data is ongoing, but a number of positive features are already emerging. Structural traps are clearly visible and new seismic data are showing geometries that are interpreted to be channel sands which form the reservoir. Hydrocarbon charge is a key risk in the area, but the new data is also showing us features in the seismic that are normally only associated with gas presence.</p>
          <p>Woodside plans to drill an early exploration well in the best prospect, once the Maersk B281 rig arrives in country. Given the large number of very similar prospects, proving gas in this area would significantly increase the potential of these permits and their ability to underpin additional Pluto trains.</p>
          <p>Slide 40, on to our new Claudius hub. We're really excited to have recently been awarded a new permit, WA-434-P, on the western side of the Exmouth Plateau. It was highly contested and the most sought after block in the round. The block just to the south, which Chevron and Shell announced a few days ago, was to Woodside not of as high value and we just did seismic on it.</p>
          <p>The Eendracht gas discovery is just located east of the permit boundary and, even on this coarsely spaced, 2D seismic data, there are number of seismic indications of gas nearby. Geologically, the permit contains Triassic fault structures similar to proven discoveries in the area. Some of the structures are extremely large.</p>
          <p>We have also mapped a number of carbonate reef complexes, many of which have multi-Tcf potential. Although we've just been awarded this block, actually just a week or two ago, we're already out for tender for a large 3D seismic survey and I expect we'll be targeting exploration drilling in 2010 &#x2013; yes, 2010. If this timing reminds you of Pluto, it should.</p>
          <p>Slide 41. And, last, the Ragnar hub. In the first half of this year, Woodside was awarded three additional exploration permits in the Southern Exmouth. There are number of Triassic and shallower Cretaceous played across these permits and multiple prospects have been mapped. Currently, 3D seismic's being acquired and we should have drill-ready prospects for 2010.</p>
          <p>But Woodside's main focus remains on gas. There's also potential that these two eastern permits in this hub may contain oil. Woodside's happy with either outcome, given the proximity of the blocks to our Enfield and Vincent oil facilities.</p>
          <p>Slide 42. So, after looking at this exploration portfolio, why the hell aren't we drilling these great prospects? It's a long story, but I'll give you an idea of our frustration in a short period of time. Going into this year, we had planned to have both deepwater drill rigs, the Atwood Eagle and the new monster Maersk B281, available for the majority of 2009, this year.</p>
          <p>This new-build B281 was scheduled to arrive from the Singapore shipyard in March of this year to drill our foundation Pluto/Xena wells. When it became apparent that B281 was slipping in schedule, we decided the prudent decision was to switch the Atwood Eagle from our exploration prospects to the Pluto drilling to ensure that first gas for Train 1 remained on project schedule. Over time, the B281 has now slipped out to the end of this year; therefore, only one exploration well has been drilled so far, that being in our Martell discovery.</p>
          <p>Now the B281 looks certain for next year, along with the entry of Ocean America. In the meantime, we think maybe we can squeeze possibly one more exploration well after completing the Pluto wells with the Atwood Eagle, probably the Noblige &#x2013; I'm sorry, the Noblige prospect right next to Martell. In addition, we've signed a shallow-water, Songa Mercur semi for two wells in Q4 this year. The first well will be the Pelion located under Pluto field. The second well is presently planned to be Elatus, below the Xena field, but there's several competing opportunities for that slot.</p>
          <p>This is probably more information than you need, but we're very excited with our prospects. We just wanted you to share in our pain of not having a rig. We've tried everything to find a deepwater rig this year, but to no avail.</p>
          <p>Now this slide shows you our forecast 20 exploration wells in the Carnarvon Gas Basin we plan to drill by the end of 2010 and another four prospects in early 2011. We have left the rest of the drill slot flexible, as we know we'll need to mix appraisal with prospects and there's dependency of resource that need to be recognized.</p>
          <p>In summary, late 2009 and 2010 will be exciting times for Woodside's exploration efforts in support of the Pluto expansion.</p>
          <p>Slide 43. More good news. We've spent a few million dollars with an EPC contractor and we've now confirmed that we can fit Trains 1, Train 2 and Train 3 on the lower plateau. The upper plateau will be for Train 4 and possibly a Train 5. We see Train 4 to be 100% Woodside plant. We put a placeholder on Train 5 at this time at 100%.</p>
          <p>Now on slide 44, you can see the layout of Train 4 and possibly Train 5. We will need to add a second jetty and maybe a tank or two and these studies are under way. Making something out of nothing &#x2013; I think this is great news for our shareholders. So we're bullish at Woodside. My 34 years of experience says it isn't a matter of if, it's a matter of &#x2013; a question of when.</p>
          <p>We've created the industry leading position with our Pluto foundation project and now we're going to cash in for our shareholders. Brownfields versus greenfields, incremental economics, improving total economics, improved scale and scope, increasing our industry leading position.</p>
          <p>I think you just have to love it &#x2013; or at least I do &#x2013; when a plan comes together. Our folks are having a lot of fun working Pluto; it's just like a bunch of kids at Christmas.</p>
          <p>Slide 45. So, enough of Pluto; we've told you quite a bit about it, hope to be very transparent. Let's go on with another great project that seems to flying under the radar of everybody, though we know it's knocking over milestones right and left.</p>
          <p>On slide 45 here, we update our Sunrise project. Now, I can't really say a lot because we're in a very delicate period, an evaluation period with our joint venture on theme select at this very time. What I can say is that all four partners, including Woodside, have agreed on resource volumes available to produce LNG.</p>
          <p>As I said, a final evaluation of which concept is under way. I don't want to queer the process the process. I will say that we're very confident the project will produce robust economics. And both governments, Timor Leste and Australia, are now fully engaged. As soon as we select a theme, we'll submit the field development plan for approval. Now, the JV is very aligned and is working to an agreed process whereby the best option will be selected.</p>
          <p>The next two slides, I'll handle together, slides 46 and 47. Like Sunrise, Browse &#x2013; on these two slides, I'll give you an update of the world-scale project which we know to be Browse. Much has been written about the argy-bargy going on with the partner position, but not much has been written about the tremendous progress being made over the last six months. For the Burrup option, we have continued to evaluate it. With common ownership with the North West Shelf Venture, we think that Browse's interests all the information it needs about this option.</p>
          <p>For the Kimberley, the joint venture has created a plan that now provides all the necessary agreements &#x2013; ingredients for a world-class foundation project. But let's go back for a second and pick up the resource progress. Over the last few years, we have extensively drilled the three fields and we now know we have at least a 14 Tcf sales gas LNG project with 370 million barrels of condensate. Importantly, and this is really important to us, we've increased dramatically our confidence in our P90 values.</p>
          <p>So, what are the issues, as Woodside sees them? First, Woodside as operator has intimate and intense, day-to-day management involvement and we think we have naturally arrived at the answer probably just a little ahead of our partners.</p>
          <p>Two of the major issues, as far as Woodside is concerned, are timing and capacity. We all believe the economics of building a 900-kilometer onshore or offshore pipeline and an additional train or two at North West Shelf or Pluto does not stack up economically. In fact, with best Burrup economic option has come down to just a pipeline and backfilling North West Shelf's available haulage in the future.</p>
          <p>So let me repeat: the Burrup option has been reduced to building a long pipeline and offshore facilities and being restricted to backfilling North West Shelf haulage that might be available in 10 to 15 years with a very slow ramp-up of capacity. This versus a typical greenfield development at James Price Point that could have up to 12 million tonnes available in the next six to seven years.</p>
          <p>For Woodside, the economics are compelling. The time value of our approximate 50% ownership of 14-plus Tcf of liquids is critical. At Woodside, we believe the time value of PRRT is also crucial for the Australian taxpayers who own the gas.</p>
          <p>As a reminder to some of our industry friends, none of us own the gas. We discover and operate; the citizens of Australia own the gas. Now, we're told that both governments stayed in Commonwealth repeatedly that the time for Browse is now, not 10 years from now.</p>
          <p>Remember, the Browse venture is not the same mix as six identical equity owners at North West Shelf. Woodside has about three times the equity at Browse compared to the two secondary partners and about six times the equity of the other two small parties. We at Woodside don't think under the "use it or lose it" Commonwealth retention lease policy that a minority 8% partner will be allowed to cause a 10-year delay in getting Browse off the mark.</p>
          <p>Woodside's moving forward and we have great support from both governments. Woodside's ready to finalize the Kimberley concept, initiate BOD, commence FEED, and start early construction in 2011 at James Price Point.</p>
          <p>Slide 48. Let's put it all together now. You can see the tremendous LNG current position and potential of our company. At this time, we have the phenomenal North West Shelf as a base component. Soon, Pluto Train 1 will increase our LNG equity from 2.7 million tonnes at North West Shelf to 6.6 million tonnes annually.</p>
          <p>We're implementing FEED on Pluto Trains 2 and Train 3, projects that could see our equity LNG climb to 9.2 and 12.4 million tonnes per annum by the end of the 2013 and 2014, respectively. You add in Sunrise, which I'm quite bullish on, and Browse, where the governments will ensure timely development, and we have the potential to approach 20 million tonnes per annum equity LNG before the end of next decade.</p>
          <p>And then you add Pluto 4 and maybe Pluto 5 along the way. All this is clearly in the grasp of our company and it's of &#x2013; it's in our grasp now. Woodside has a future production profile second to none of our industry peers.</p>
          <p>Let's not forget, even if we don't find another molecule of gas, which isn't very likely, we'll have enough P2 reserves in our portfolio to replicate 2008 production for the next 22 years. After all the rhetoric about LNG projects in Australia, Woodside's still the only company currently building LNG. We've built or are building six of the seven trains in Australia and we're the only company with multiple Australian potential projects in the future.</p>
          <p>Slide 49. What is important to our shareholders is this slide, which shows the leverage of LNG in the industry to current company capitalizations. By a wide margin, Woodside is best leveraged to our current in the industry and will remain so, with the advantage increasing dramatically in the next few short years.</p>
          <p>Moving over to slide 50, question then becomes, do we have the capacity and capability to carry out these projects concurrently? You bet. We've now developed a Pluto brownfield LNG management team to build Trains 2 and beyond at Pluto. Our Pluto foundation greenfield LNG management team will be ready to move to Browse in 2010 and we have plenty of FPSO subservice project teams to handle Sunrise, as Shell or ConocoPhillips will manage the construction of the Sunrise downstream liquefaction plant.</p>
          <p>Now slides 50 and 51 gives you a small taste of our sustainability. Safety is critically important. We work hard to have a perfect day every day. We don't, but we will not slack in efforts until we do. Same with the environment.</p>
          <p>We have a loyal group of contractors. They've been fantastic to us. They know that Woodside builds, while others just talk. And I will tell you, we do love our employees; they work hard for us, we compensate them well. And I've said enough about our leadership team, probably embarrassingly so.</p>
          <p>Let me also say that I've had the pleasure to work with two great chairmen, Charles Goode and Michael Chaney. Our Board of Directors is collectively a very &#x2013; is a smart group of very, really bright minds. They know everything about our business and we make sure that they do. It's really great for a CEO to be able to work so well with the Board and for everybody on the top to be so completely aligned.</p>
          <p>One last thing: I'm really enjoying my time at Woodside and looking forward to kicking a few more goals.</p>
          <p>So now, finally, on to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Operator Instructions.] And your first question comes from Stuart Baker from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and good afternoon, gentlemen. Just to come back to Pluto and Pluto 1. They're obviously going along pretty well and well advanced. I guess the obvious question is, what is the activity out there that you see as the most critical one that we should look at? What's the one that keeps you awake in the night? Is the moving the platform in the field, the topside, or is it the commissioning phase that comes after, if you like, the snapshot?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this is Don. The thing that keeps me up at night is safety. I worry about our people getting hurt or some action that hurts people. Behind that is the construction. We have a lot of people out there in a small site getting everything put together, but I will tell you this, that I am completely confident in our engineering staff. The way they've worked with our EPC contractor and our contractors, boy, they risk-manage the heck out of this thing.</p>
          <p>I do not worry about the transport of these modules down to. I don't worry about the off-loading them or the trekking them up. Basically, it's just a beehive of activity. It's what you might call multiple tasking at the site, of getting everybody, of making sure that people aren't in the way, that trenches are covered before we need to travel over it, and those type of things.</p>
          <p>So, it's a large, complex project. Greenfields are really hard compared to brownfields. And I'll just say that we've kind of broken the back of the engineering. We've got the modules pretty well finishing up in Thailand. We have finished up in China. We're finishing up in Malaysia. So, it all turns to crawth and putting it all together. This six months, as we said earlier, is where we want to break the back of construction. That's the key. That's the key risk remaining.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks there, and just a second question before I'll pass over to others. Just on the financials, a bit of minutiae here. Just on the royalty and RRT expense combined, particularly the RRT. Obviously that's slumping through time and quite a bit lower this half versus last half and the second half of last year. I just wonder there if you could give us a bit of guidance on what the royalty would look like in the second half, given the fact that it sort of goes between zero and a couple of hundred million half-on-half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And Stuart, just so I'm clear on your question, the &#x2013; your first question was, what's been happening to PRRT and then what's likely to happen over the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, technically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And so, what's been happening to the PRRT, I guess up to date, you kind of go with two basic drivers. First one is, obviously, revenues have come down and so kind of that, that's part of the reduction. The second one is PRRT augmentation has come up and so when you kind of look at those two together, that's the lion's share of explanations for what moved. When you look at the second half and what's going to happen, it gets back I think ultimately to where revenue's going to go, but to the extent revenue continues to fall or stay stable, you'll see PRRT kind of move in line with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Mark Greenwood from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good day. I've got a couple of questions, just around the Pluto 2 and the exploration for Pluto 2. First of all, on slide 30, where you outline I think what you called the most likely scenario for trying to gas supply. The discovered gas there of 0.5 is &#x2013; I think you just mentioned that was discovered and potentially commercially acquired gas. Is that just Martell or is Martell a subset of that 0.5 Tcf?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Martell is not included in that 0.5. I kind of looked for Martell possibly the &#x2013; maybe not the second train, in the second train.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, what &#x2013; could you be a little more, be more specific about what that discovered gas is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I can't right now because we're in negotiation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And when you mentioned that &#x2013; when you outlined the options on slide 31, you mentioned a distant platform versus gas that was close to the existing platform. How far way, what's the sort of maximum distance that you could expect to do a subsea tieback, as opposed to put in a new platform?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it depends on the reservoir, Mark. It depends on the pressure &#x2013; natural pressure of the reservoir, the extended life, et cetera. If it's a big pool, highly pressured, you can move gas quite a ways to the platform and push her in. If your, if your wells are shallower, less pressure and they're going to need compression at some time in the near future, then you're going to need a platform or some type of a facility to handle the compression.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give us sort of rough guide as to what the likely distance is before you then, you put in a platform?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well. If you go, if you go &#x2013; yeah, sure. If you go back to the &#x2013; oh, let's just pick a slide that starts the exploration program up. Yeah, 33, thank you.</p>
          <p>Obviously, gas right around the Pluto platform, we can pick up several kilometers away, tens of kilometers away, directly into the platform. Clearly, 404 will take a platform hub there and I would expect that there will be platform hubs up in Cazadores and over for Claudius. Claudius is the furthest away.</p>
          <p>To give you an idea of the ranges here, I think the Claudius is around 400 kilometers. I think the Central hub they were telling me is about 150 to 200, so these are all well within range for subsea flow lines to tie back to the Pluto Hub. The point we're trying to make is, is that, hey, if people have gas close to the Pluto platform that already exists and they don't have to do anything but drill wells in subsea and subsurface back, there's a huge amount of economic rent to split on that.</p>
          <p>I really don't want to use any capacity because I'm so confident of our exploration program. I just don't want to give up any capacity, unless I get the, kind of the same value as if I had found my own gas located a little bit further away.</p>
          <p>So, people have small dabs of gas quite a ways away and where they got to build their own platform. I don't think there's much use talking about it. It's not going to be part of Pluto probably in the future. So, there is a distance radius and there is kind of a deal. If Woodside builds a platform, let's say in 404 or over in Ragnar hub or in Claudius, other people that has found gas around there can tie to it and their economic rent to split will be better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Yeah, okay. And just one more if I could, just on the revised exploration program that you've outlined in one of the latter slides, I think it's slide 42. I was wondering if you could provide us an update on the exploration budget for 2009? And it looks like quite a significant program in 2010. Do you have a sort of estimate as to what the budget might be for exploration in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I was just going over the budget in 2009. We're staying right very close to what we announced earlier. We'll be just a few 10 million off of our $408 million, I think was our original budget, or 430 I believe it was. 432? Is that right, Mark?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So, the budget was, I think, 405 originally...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Four...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...and so right now it's 408. So, Mark, it's roughly in line with kind of the original budget. The outlook for the full year's roughly in line with the original budget. And then, with regard to 2010, obviously, as with all of our budgets, that's actually what's getting fleshed out over the next couple of months and will be available in November. Like we do every year, we'll show you capital for the next year coming.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, how is it the capital or the exploration budget is similar when you're drilling a hell of a lot of less wells, given that that rig is not available?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for two or three reasons. Number one is, we still have an active drilling program in Brazil. We've drilled two discoveries down there. We have expectation of drilling, of course, in Sierra Leone and in Rickenbacker, but the biggest change has been, we have just loaded up our explorations with the tools they need. And it's paying off big time for us.</p>
          <p>That seismic I was talking about doesn't come free and we've really loaded up on our seismic and kind of shifted the seismic program from 2010 into 2009 and shifting about three &#x2013; probably I think we said six to eight wells we would drill. We're going to probably drill four wells now in Australia, so  we're lacking two to four wells, have probably traded that out with seismic to kind of balance out the budget.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Matthew Murphy from The Age. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, Don. Just a question around LNG. I was interested to ask what your thoughts are in terms of demand for LNG going forward and how you're going and expect to go in regards to marketing that LNG overseas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, let me just say that every project, when you enter into FEED, has to prove up certain things. You've got to get gas contracts, you've got to get permits, environmental permits, you've got to find a location. You've got to figure out how your gas is going to flow. So, like the folks over in Gladstone, they got a whole set of different problems right now they're tackling. We have a set of problems out here, et cetera.</p>
          <p>For Pluto, we've got a great head start. I just always have said that going greenfield's tough. Once you got the greenfield set up, it makes life really quite easy when you can just build brownfields on top of it. So, the point is, we've had &#x2013; I think I mentioned 2,700 cargos Woodside has operated and supplied around the world without incident. Having Australia as a home, having Woodside reputation, we don't expect unloading the gas at a very high, fair price is going to be the major issue here.</p>
          <p>We currently have, as you know, two partners with us in Pluto that have purchased all the gas so far. We've got several others lined up. Selling gas from Pluto or North West Shelf from Woodside, it is different than a newbie that hasn't ever proved themselves before and your sophisticated customers in Japan, Korea, Taiwan and other places, they certainly look for that. So we've got a natural advantage at Woodside. I'm not concerned about that piece of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Don, we saw yesterday the Gorgon project sell 2.25 million tonnes of LNG over 20 years to China. Given that LNG prices are around kind of 300 and projected to go to about $400 a ton, do you find that $50 billion figure a bit unpleasant?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first off, I was interesting that they announced a $50 billion. We've got a $45 billion of PetroChina. But I think what it shows is that there's a huge market out there for big, strong projects. Australia offers that. We predict 380 million tonnes of LNG global requirement by 2020. You're starting to see people starting to gobble that up. I certainly understand some of the issues that some of the other people in Australia have been trying to get a good price for the gas because of the quality of the gas and other things.</p>
          <p>But I'll tell you, Pluto's a great quality gas and we just don't see that to be a major issue. When we talked to the Board about going into FEED, we quickly pretty well &#x2013; that was an issue we talked about. We have risk mitigation plans, but I think that's really not what's on my mind right now. I don't see gas marketing, based on the fact that we got a great gas marketing group &#x2013; we have built customer relationships over the last 20 years. We have not ever, as Woodside, disappointed a customer or any of the set of customers, and I could think, if you just go talk to them directly, they'll tell you that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Don, your deal with PetroChina, the $45 billion deal which you just spoke about, how many tonnes is that supply and over what period and is that finalized?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that &#x2013; no, it's in KTA form, which is the form that we have for &#x2013; initially for, or it's recognized for possibly Browse and on. But it's based on 2 to 3 million tonnes for a 20-year period. And we are continuing to progress that deal and we think it's a great underpinning, which we've offered to our joint-venture partners at Browse to participate in, along with our CPC deal. Again, another 2 to 3 million tonnes for Browse, which we, again, we've offered to our joint venture to share that contract with them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Matt Chambers from The Australian. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Don. I just wanted to check something you said before. Did you say you wouldn't give an indication of how much gas you think there is at Martell-1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. At this time, it is &#x2013; we do have a partner there, and it is confidential based on what that volume and those trends could tell outside our lease block.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And any indications you can give us on what sort of CapEx you'd look at with the second and third trends in Pluto?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That's why we do FEEDs. When we go into FEED, that's where we pin it down. If I gave you a number now, I always get hit by this and I get hurt by it. I give a number that we think is our best expectation now and then we have to give another one when we go to FID. We quit doing that. We said look, we think that the &#x2013; you know, we wouldn't enter FEED if didn't think we had a robust project that gave great economics.</p>
          <p>And I will tell you this: Pluto 1 economics have done nothing but get better since we initiated a FID on that. And bottom line is, when we add these brownfields and build scale and scope and split up the foundation cost, nothing but improved economics for everybody, so that's great news for the shareholders.</p>
          <p>What happens here is &#x2013; the differentiation we will tell you is, is that our pipeline that we're building out to Pluto platform can handle probably two trains. When we go to that third train, we'll probably need to build a second trunk line. But just about everything else is built for multi-train.</p>
          <p>Now, I think a lot of people wondered what the hell we were doing building LNG capacity storage to have as much storage capacity as North West Shelf. What were we doing building huge power plants? What were we doing with a jetty that had huge capability? Why were we building a trunk line that could handle two trains? Why did we build a platform offshore that can virtually handle four to five trains?</p>
          <p>The idea is we've never visioned Pluto as one-train facility. We've always &#x2013; but I think my staff here have always visioned it as a three-train. I've always figured it'd be worth a few more than that. So, we're pretty excited about where we're going. I would say that you would take a brownfield cost. It'll be quite a bit different than greenfield cost. And then you can use some of the industry references. I will say this: there's enough LNG projects getting announced out there. You guys can figure out pretty closely what these costs will be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And just one more, if I could, on Sunrise. What's the East Timor government position at the moment on that? What are they indicating?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, let me just say that we're in a kind of a ticklish period with everybody on this thing. I really like Sunrise, how it's progressing. Our team's done a great job and we got great joint-venture alignment on this thing.</p>
          <p>We are engaged with the Timor Leste government; they're talking both ways with us. When they position themselves, let's just say they position themselves in newspapers, sometimes that's to play locally a little bit more than what it does play with our teams. But we kind of got to understand that we're going to hear a lot in the newspapers, it's going to be a lot noise around it. But at the end of the day, it's a good project that provides a hell of lot of revenue to both countries. And we're playing fair up with both governments. We treat them both the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Adrian Wood from Macquarie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, my question just relates to, back to slide 30. You say there that you're looking for anywhere between 1.4 to 2.7 Tcf of gas for Pluto 2. I just wonder how that requirement for external gas sort of chimes with your &#x2013; the timing of your exploration program and how does that affect your ability to sign a deal?</p>
          <p>Obviously, you've got a &#x2013; you're sitting on a lot of interesting prospects and have an active drilling program coming along. If you find the gas organically, clearly you stated that would be your preferred option. So, does that mean that you can't then sign a deal until you know what you're sitting on? And if that does &#x2013; if that is indeed the case, or let's say the exploration turns out be disappointing, does that mean you have to go back into the market to try and secure more gas in perhaps a tighter market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that's the reason we try to develop Trains 4 and 5 and left them undesignated right now. We are comfortable with the fact because we made a commitment to the state of Australia &#x2013; I'm sorry, state of Western Australia government that in getting our permits for Pluto that we would offer resource owners the ability to come through Pluto, if it was economically viable. I will tell right now that there's some gas that's located so close to Pluto platform that the economic rent split between that company that owns that gas and us is very, very economic, as compared to gas maybe 400 kilometers away that I'll have to find quite a bit more Tcf to make it work.</p>
          <p>Therefore, there are &#x2013; the opportunity set there for the government is to say, wait a second, why aren't we consolidating gas around these particular hubs like we do in the North Sea, like we do in the Gulf of Mexico, et cetera? We're kind of setting up kind of weird thing here in Australia where you can set up haphazard infrastructure, which actually costs the Australian taxpayers at the end of the day less PRRT rent coming back from these things.</p>
          <p>But, if there was shared utilization of gas in collective areas, it would make life easier for everybody and a hell of lot more economic for the government and for the citizens of Australia. Therefore, we live under the rules. We offer it open &#x2013; open for the people, come on our platforms and come through them, but it has to be economic for us, because it is capacity away from us. I would say that we will drill our big prospects next year before we get too far down road, to make sure that if we hit something big or several things big, that we'll lock up what we have.</p>
          <p>If you take a look, what we're projecting right now is basically about 40% of one train &#x2013; well, first off, the first train is fully &#x2013; well, it's 90% Woodside. The second train, our best guess right now, it'll be 60% Woodside. Our best projection for Train 3 is 75% Woodside and then 100% for 4 and 5. Add that mega tonnage up and it makes us &#x2013; I think this little Woodside thing that we didn't even know about five years ago could be a big winner for our shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, okay. So, just to go back to the, sort of the original question, you would happily sign a deal before you know what discoveries you have yourself?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For certain &#x2013; for a few certain properties that we've located, if the split of rent between the owner of that gas and Woodside is acceptable to Woodside, yes, we would sign it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a second question. You talk about the pipeline tolling arrangements on the Pluto 2 project. You've mentioned that the pipeline can handle two gas &#x2013; two &#x2013; enough gas for two trains. What is the capacity of that pipeline? And have you got any sort sense of what those tariffs might be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, yeah, I know what the tariffs look like because we're well into negotiations with a couple of companies, obviously, but &#x2013; and it's commercially confidential. Of course, I can't throw that out here. What I would say is the two &#x2013; the pipeline that we're building is a fairly good match and it's almost evenly matched for two 4.3-million-tonne trains.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And does the Woodside gas get monetized first or will it be equally sent through with third-party gas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if you give somebody capacity and they have gas available at day one, that's all part of the agreement. The intention is, and I don't want to mislead anybody, is day one of Train 2 and day one of Train 3, that these equity splits we have would be indicative of the capacity split between the companies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Gordon Ramsay from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Don, I think you just answered one of my questions. If you look at slide 17, you were talking about equity ranging between 60 and 90% for Pluto Train 2 and 75 to 90% for Train 3. Can we make the assumption that that is an equity split with a other resource owner or could it be an LNG buyer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a good question, Gordon. I think what you should assume is that 90% would be the equity owners of Train 1 that we would carry through in Trains 2 and 3. The remaining split, what you might call, is what would be O-R-O. And the reason we put the range in there is we still have to see people come to the table and get these agreements done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just another question, relating to costs &#x2013; could you give us any idea what it might cost, the day rate, for the Maersk B281?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I again, I'm sure Maersk won't want me to announce that, but I would say, in a way to handle that is, is that the deepwater rigs around the world, we know they're softened in the Gulf of Mexico and they're soft maybe in a few other plays. Nothing like land rigs in the U.S., which is a dime a dozen.</p>
          <p>Deepwater rigs remain in great stress for most of the world. Like I said, we looked for one this year; we couldn't find one. Australia is fully booked out. So, what I guess the question you would ask is, is that, what other services during the recession tended to come off maybe 20, 30% of cost? We haven't seen much cost reduction on the deepwater rigs from the anticipation.</p>
          <p>We did sign up for that B281, by the way, several years back as part of the underpinning. We &#x2013; I think the industry uses figures, when you add all the boats and all the services and everything. For us, we just use kind of the rule of thumb, about a million bucks a day out there, what you might call a full coverage spread. Now, a portion of that is the Maersk contract and the rest of it is all the supply that services the contract &#x2013; or services the rigs, excuse me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And lastly, just on the FEED commitments for Pluto 2 and 3. Can you give us an idea of the total cost for the FEED programs for both those trains?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The combined cost will be somewhere between 100 and 150. And we expect we might get some help with that from some other party.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Fayen Wong from Reuters. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Don. Just few questions here. Have you set up marketing for gas for Pluto 2 and, if so, will these foundation costumers for Train 1 also looking to buy gas from Pluto 2 or Pluto 3?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, it's Mark Chatterji. So, on marketing, just a couple points. One is we're in a reasonably constant dialogue with all of our customers on all of our projects, not specifically aimed at kind of any one of them. Number two, the foundation costumers of Pluto 1 being Tokyo Gas and Kansai Electric, will be involved in Pluto 2 and Pluto 3, and so you have some marketing implications out of that as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And apart from you guys talking about a big half, Chevron is also talking up its potential for third-party gas at Wheatstone project. Could you just offer some comments on how you see the situation and dynamic shifting, considering how you guys are now looking to extend Pluto to a fourth and fifth train?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't look at it as competition. I was quite amused at this article in the AFR over the weekend. Roy and I &#x2013; Roy Krzywosinski over at Chevron and I were at a conference this week and we were sitting together at breakfast and somebody comes running up and shows us this article that we're suppose to hate each other. That's not the case.</p>
          <p>Roy is a good guy and he's got a good company he's running here in Chevron here in Australia. There's plenty of room for everybody. We've built our plan around the fact that Gorgon's going to be there. We've modularized, we've done a lot of things, but &#x2013; you know, this competition thing really isn't there. Yeah, we're competitive on a business basis, as we are in the North Sea, as we are in the Gulf of Mexico, everywhere else in this world. This is industry.</p>
          <p>We can be partners one lease and competitors the next lease. This is kind of a strange business, exploration, producing, but we handle it very well.</p>
          <p>They've announced their plans for Wheatstone. Good luck to them. Building a greenfield on a pristine site and have to build a harbor and everything. They're going to have their own challenges with it.</p>
          <p>I think Roy said that they would have gas avail &#x2013; or opportunity available in 2016. The way I see it is, we'll builds Train 2 and 3 before Gorgon. In fact, our construction guys told me yesterday that we'll be 12 to 18 months in front of Gorgon on people, new requirements and needs. That's assuming Gorgon goes here in the next month or two, which we fully expect. So, we're still very comfortable that we'll build around &#x2013; we've got construction workers that like to go into Karratha at night and everything, so I mean there's all sorts of situations we've already anticipated risk-mitigation of this.</p>
          <p>So, I don't even worry about Wheatstone; that's kind of after Pluto gets done. And bottom line is, it's a kind of a, a long, extended FEED. I think it's a couple of years and that's kind of typical with greenfields, plus and I think they have some issues probably stacking. So, at the end of the day, I don't concern myself with Wheatstone. I worry about other things that are within my control. I spend a lot of time with Browse and I spend a lot of time with Sunrise, as well as Pluto.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And just one last question. Could you just talk a little bit more about the consideration for funding plan in 2010? You've done very well in '09 by tapping the bond markets. So what are your options for 2010? Would you be willing to tap bond market or would you look at XE?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, I'll turn that over to my money man here, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Look, I think on the 2010 funding plan, as we noted in our slide pack, that's all being worked right now as the activity plans and budgets get finalized. As you can see from kind of our activity this year, we do have a focus and a strong preference for debt. As I've always said, you can't rule things out because you can't rule the oil price in or out, but, up 'til now, we've gone with debt. As you can see from the slide, we continue to work on the expansion of our lending capacity on a first and foremost basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thanks. No more questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from John Hirjee from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. A question regarding Pluto again. Now, you've mentioned that you're coming up for a critical phase on Pluto 1 for the cost issue. If I recall, when the Pluto CapEx budget came out, there was nearly $1 billion worth of contingency built into that. How much contingency have you got left?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's a good question. I'm not going to really answer it, except to say we, we're going into the most critical phase of construction at Karratha, where we've put a big productivity contingency in. I will just say this: we still have a lot of contingency in our projection for final cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. But you're coming up to the critical path over the next six months, as you say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. What I would, let me just put it this way: if we started the project with X billions of dollars of contingency in the project, we've taken and given back to the Company, you might say, very little of that contingency at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because we still have a quite a bit of the risk remaining. So that contingency remains with the project unspent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Don.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Uh hm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Paul Garvey from Financial Review [Australian Financial Review]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Don. Just wondering if &#x2013; you've spoken at length today about needing to find a good tariff when talking with these other resource owners. Is the prospect of Wheatstone also looking for third-party gas making it harder, undermining your sales position, your bargaining position there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a big difference in 2013 and 2016.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, no difference, then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sure they're competing, but I'm not. I don't have any privy to what they may be offering. I don't worry about that. I know the proposition we have. I know the winning aspects of our proposition. I know that they've got to make money. I'm talking about the O-R-O and we're putting a very justified position out there to where we both make money. We're supplying people a hell of an opportunity.</p>
          <p>We have fantastic LNG experience. We know how to build the stuff in Australia; by the way, it's not easy. And we basically have a reputation, history in marketing. So, we can give O-R-O an awful lot and we can give them 2013, not 2016. So, the fact is we've built LNG trains versus the competition. We've marketed the stuff, we've got a 20-years history. I mean we've got so much going in our favor. I don't worry about the competition because I know the offer we're making out there. It might be competitive by setting up options for boards to review, but I know we've got the best option out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the China sale we saw overnight, is that an encouraging sign in that, it sort of, what it says about health for demand out of Asia, or is it a worrying sign given you're going to be in the market for more customers down the line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's all good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All good. And Otway, any change in the view on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Change in the view in respect to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Looking at potentially selling out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul, look, as we said on our slide, there's a couple of assets, Otway being one, that's still under review. And so once we have a decision to announce, we're going to announce it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And there are no further questions at this time, so I'll turn the conference back to Mr. Voelte for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I just want to shout out to my son who, in the course of his business, has to listen in to this. It's his birthday today, so I'd like to tell him, Happy birthday, and also, thanks, Kevin, for making Nancy and I grandparents first time. And I'm sure everybody else wanted to hear that.</p>
          <p>But at the end of the day, I appreciate everybody hanging around for an hour and 17 minutes. We had a lot to say today. I want to apologize for the front end, but transparency's pretty good. We've got a lot to say. Thanks a lot. We'll be around to see people here in the next couple of days, couple of weeks over to the U.S., Europe, et cetera. So, we've got our bags packed and we'll be heading out this afternoon. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen that does conclude our conference for today. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>