<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1286057" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-08</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7831</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Mick Davis, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Trevor Reid, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Jason Fairclough</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Tobias Woerner</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Sam Catalano</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Ian Pearce</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Charlie Sartain</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Christopher LaFemina</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep">Peet Nienaber</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep">Santiago Zaldumbide</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Des Kilalea</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Olivia Ker</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep">Peter Freyberg</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Rebecca O'Dwyer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to this presentation of our Preliminary Results for 2009. I would also like to welcome those who are attending via the webcast or by telephone.</p>
          <p>As usual, I am joined by Trevor Reid, Xstrata's CFO and next to him the Chief Executive of each business unit; Santiago Zaldumbide, Executive Director of Xstrata and the Chief Executive of the Xstrata Zinc business; Ian Pearce, Chief Executive of Xstrata Nickel; Charlie Sartain, Chief Executive of Xstrata Copper; Peter Freyberg, Chief Executive of Xstrata Coal; and Peet Nienaber, Chief Executive of our Alloys business. And Thras Moraitis and Benny Levene who make up the balance of the executive team, I can now say are in the audience and I see sitting at the back there, David Rough who is our Senior Independent Director. So we really do have a full complement to talk to you today.</p>
          <p>Against the background of a challenging year, Xstrata's businesses delivered what I think is a robust operating and financial performance with particularly strong second half productions in sales as market conditions improved. Overall, the Group achieved an operating profit of over $7 billion, and net earnings of $2.8 billion, with record production volumes in the number of commodities.</p>
          <p>Real unit cost savings of $0.5 billion realized in 2009, representing 5% of the operating cost base and continuing an unbroken record of eight years of annual sustainable cost reductions. Now these results reflect the rapid and far-reaching actions taken by our commodity business management teams to enable Xstrata to emerge from the downturn in a strengthened competitive position. From late 2008 and into 2009, higher cost operations and production capacity that could not be supported by market demand was suspended or closed. Capital expenditure was slowed down at certain longer greenfield growth projects and capital and operating cost savings initiatives were accelerated across the Group. The robust financial position and the improved output for Xstrata have enabled us to recommence dividends; the final dividend of $0.08 per share.</p>
          <p>While we conserved cash in the early part of the year, our businesses were very careful to preserve the full optionality of our growth pipeline and capital investment in fact increased as market conditions improved. I'm going to provide a brief summary of the operating performance of our commodity businesses this year &#x2013; this last year and then I'll hand over to Trevor, who will take us through the financial performance in more detail.</p>
          <p>Xstrata Coal staged an impressive recovery in the second half following a very difficult first quarter, which was impacted by record rainfall in South Africa and a number of one-off impacts. Productivity gains were recorded by a number of Australian operations including Ravensworth, Oaky North, Mt. Owen and volumes also benefited from the contribution of the Prodeco operations which we acquired at the beginning of the year.</p>
          <p>Over the past few years Xtrata's Coal management team has transformed its portfolio consolidating a range of very small operations into these very large scale complexes, with what I think are world-class operating costs, regional scale and the ability to leverage shared infrastructure in New South Whales, Queensland and in South Africa.</p>
          <p>Now the commissioning of Goedgevonden and the ongoing development of Atcom East are continuing the transformation of the South African division into three major complexes comprising mainly open cut operations to deliver further productivity and cost savings. And Goedgevonden, let me say, that it is on track to commission this year, the full production of 7 million tonnes for 2011, 50% of which is export quality and the operation recently agreed a 17-year contract to supply Eskom at 3.5 million tonnes per annum.</p>
          <p>The successful ramp-up, if we move to Australia, of the Glendell and the Liddell operations in Australia, obviously also benefited our performance in 2009. The Blakefield South longwall operation that will replace Beltana will also be completed this year. Our development of the first extended underground longwall block has commenced at the Newlands Northern Underground extension in Queensland. Major earthworks for the Mangoola greenfield project commenced in December, you'll recall that we delayed that somewhat waiting for 2009 outcome to be more clearer. And the project will deliver 10.5 million tonnes on a run-of-mine basis of a mine life of nearly 20 years.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Xstrata Copper, operating performance was bolstered by a very strong second half and high volumes from Mount Isa in Australia, Collahuasi and Lomas Bayas in Chile, which offset planned lower copper and gold production from Ernest Henry and Alumbrera.</p>
          <p>Both Lomas Bayas and Collahuasi overcame unplanned outages to achieve production records in 2009. And I think this is a particularly impressive performance at Collahuasi, given the catastrophic failure of the main conveyor during the second half and the multiple mill stator insulation failures that it experienced. And I am pleased to say, however, these issues appear to be largely behind us, and production rates in the final quarter bode well, or overwhelmingly so, for an even stronger performance this year.</p>
          <p>Copper C1 cash costs were maintained at around $0.90 per pound despite the planned lower grades at a number of operations. Three brownfield expansions to Copper operations have been approved in the last few months of 2009. Construction on a project to convert Ernest Henry into a major underground operation has now commenced and includes a plant to produce high-grade magnetite.</p>
          <p>An investment to extend the life of the Lomas Bayas mine was also approved during the year and will stay in production at the recently expanded rate of 75,000 tonnes of copper per year until 2020. Around a month ago the shareholders in the Antamina mine approved a $1.3 billion investment to expand the processing capacity by 38% to 130,000 tonnes per day.</p>
          <p>Another three projects in Copper will come to the Xstrata Plc Board for approval in 2010. And these include the brownfield Antapaccay expansion Tintaya; the nearby greenfield Las Bambas project, which will also use Tintaya infrastructure; and an expansion of Collahuasi's processing capacity to 170,000 tonnes per day.</p>
          <p>Xstrata Zinc more than delivered on the promises we made at the start of the year to optimize the Australian operations, increased production and achieved cost savings across its portfolio. Record zinc in concentrate sales were 31% higher than the previous year and zinc metal sales were up by 4%. The Australian operation's performance was especially impressive following a successful restructuring.</p>
          <p>Costs were reduced by 40% at the Mount Isa complex and by 18% at the McArthur River. Production was ramped up from the high grade George Fisher mine and the large scale Black Star operation with a reduced workforce and lower capital spending, substantially improving productivity.</p>
          <p>As you remember we &#x2013; the higher cost Handlebar operation was suspended and is currently operating as a swing producer, sharing resources with Black Star. Recoveries and throughput at the zinc-lead concentrator were maximized at an expanded rate of over 7.4 million tonnes per annum.</p>
          <p>Now prior to acquisition, if you can cross your mind back to 2003, prior to the acquisition of the Mount Isa mines as a company, these zinc operations at Mount Isa and McArthur River were under review and in fact this slates to be closed. Now since that time, Santiago and his team have identified numerous opportunities to progressively expand the mine and the zinc-lead concentrator at an exceptionally low capital cost. And we've spoken about these before as well.</p>
          <p>And as a result, develop new open cut mines and carry out near-mine exploration to extract maximum value from the resource base. And the most recent restructuring is the latest example, I think, of the ongoing optimization of the Australian operations. And Mount Isa itself now represents a large-scale, long life, low cost zinc complex that continues to develop value to the Group. I can almost hear people talk about the world-class asset.</p>
          <p>These initiatives and additional cost savings across the portfolio contributed an overall 25% reduction in C1 cash costs at the mines from $0.58 per pound to $0.44 per pound and on an integrated basis taking into account the benefit of our smelters across our zinc complex C1, overall costs were reduced from $0.508 cents per pound in 2008 to $0.391 cents per pound in 2009.</p>
          <p>Xstrata zinc performance was also boosted by the contribution of the growth projects that have been successfully delivered in recent years including the first full production of the low cost Perseverance mine in Canada and the expansions of the Australian operation.</p>
          <p>What about Nickel? Xstrata Nickel accelerated the transformation of its portfolio amidst a severe deterioration in market conditions. And this included the suspension of the Fraser Mine complex in Sudbury and the Falcondo operation in the Dominican Republic. The early closure of the end-of-life Craig and Thayer-Lindsley mine and a 30% reduction in corporate and operational head-count. And despite these closures mine nickel production rose to record levels and the performance of the downstream facilities was optimized by replacing lower quality Sudbury and third party feed with additional volumes from the Australian operations, the higher-grade Raglan mine and the initial production coming from Nickel Rim South.</p>
          <p>Consequently, consolidated C1 cash costs fell by 33% to an average of $3.80 per pound in 2009 from $5.63 in 2008. And at the end of 2009, Xstrata Nickel was operating at a run rate of less than $3.00 per pound, based on prevailing prices for by-product nickel and exchange rate.</p>
          <p>The commission of Nickel Rim South is progressing well with nameplate capacity already proven and projected production of over 13,000 tonnes of contained nickel and 29,000 tonnes of copper this year, reaching full production next year. This project remains on time, on budget with an exceptional safety and environmental performance record.</p>
          <p>I'll say more about Koniambo project in New Caledonia towards the end of the presentation, but a few remarks here. During 2009, a number of key milestones were reached, including the completion of the industrial site earthworks, significant progress in the dredging program for the port, which we'll complete this year and construction was commenced also on the main wharf.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Xstrata Alloys. We recorded a stronger second half performance as market conditions improved and approximately 85% of total smelting capacity was brought back on-stream after that very considerable scale-back at the end of 2008. Now considerable challenges remain in our prime business, including the strong rand and ongoing inflation and particularly in energy costs in South Africa.</p>
          <p>And now Platinum division, steadier state production was 240,000 PGM ounces was reached at the Mototolo joint venture with Anglo Platinum. And we are targeting a doubling of current production levels from Eland as we moved into an underground operation. The sinking of the Western Decline System at Eland commenced during the year and together with Eastern Decline System will deliver annual production of 300,000 ounces of platinum within a mine life of over 20 years. The platinum business has additional medium to long-term growth potential from its exploration portfolio and with emerging junior VE partners.</p>
          <p>So the developed nature of our business model, I think emphasizes accountability and responsibility at the local level and encourages an entrepreneurial approach to running the &#x2013; our operations. Now, nowhere is this approach more apparent than in the timely and decisive actions taken by every commodity business at every level to ensure that the Group emerged from recession in a strengthened and stronger position.</p>
          <p>I want to commend all of our operation &#x2013; operational management for the timely and innovative responses to conserving cash and cutting costs without impairing safety performance at all, operational integrity all in fact have growth optionality.</p>
          <p>In addition to the range of immediate actions implemented by each commodity business team, Xstrata's Nickel and Zinc commodity businesses for instance accelerated a fundamental restructuring of the operations, which has radically reduced operating costs and improved the competitive position of these businesses for the longer term. At a Group level, a preemptive rights issue in January bolstered Xstrata's financial position. And together with the refinancing of debt to extend our maturity profile has provided the Group with a firm financial footing for the year ahead and a platform for continued delivery of organic growth.</p>
          <p>So with those few remarks, I am going to hand over to Trevor and he'll take you through the financial results and I'll return with a few closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well thank you, Mick, and good morning ladies and gentlemen. Following our usual format comprehensive details on our financial and operating performance are available in the preliminary full year results statement and in the packs, which you received this morning. So I am going to use today's presentation to focus more on the key performance indicators that underpinned our results in 2009.</p>
          <p>As Mick intimated 2009 was truly a year of two halves and perhaps the most striking feature of this year's result is the very strong recovery in the underlying performance of our businesses during the second half. As rising demand for our product and consequent rising commodity prices enabled us to return to a more acceptable level of profitability after the challenging economic conditions we endured at the end of 2008 and into the first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>The revenue EBITDA and operating profit numbers are presented on a pro forma basis to include the full 12 months contribution of the Prodeco operations acquired from Glencore in 2009. And as you are no doubt aware, Glencore has an option to re-acquire these assets, which is exercisable up to the 4th of March and consequently the Prodeco results are reflected in financial income in the statutory account.</p>
          <p>Revenue for the year was $23.5 billion, 16% lower than in 2008 and operating EBITDA of just over $7 billion is 27% lower than the prior period, reflecting lower commodity prices across the board compared to 2008 levels. Lower interest rates and the reduction in debt levels post the rights issue led to a decrease in net finance costs by 47% to $347 million and the effective tax rate for 2009 remained at 25% and I expect the tax rate to remain broadly similar in 2010.</p>
          <p>Attributable profit before exceptionals decreased by 41% to $2.8 billion providing earnings per share before exceptional items of $1.05. Operating EBITDA was significantly impacted by lower average commodity prices for our Alloys, Coal, Copper and Nickel businesses although each one of our businesses mitigated the full impact of lower prices through volume enhancements and real cost savings.</p>
          <p>Chrome prices fell by over 50% as demand for Ferrochrome from stainless steel producers collapsed in late 2008 and remained extremely low in the first half. Lower coal prices also had a significant impact, reducing earnings by over $1.2 billion compared to 2008 when we benefited from record contract pricing for both thermal and coking coals.</p>
          <p>Average LME nickel, copper and zinc prices fell by 30%, 26% and 11% respectively. However, as comprehensively explained in the financial review, which you have with you, the benefits of provisional pricing in a rising market to some extent mitigated these falls in our Copper and Zinc businesses. The standout performance was in the Zinc business where earnings rose year-on-year primarily due to the substantial cost savings and higher volumes achieved through the restructuring of the Australian operations and efficiency gains across the business. In total, these initiatives contributed $300 million to operating EBITDA.</p>
          <p>The acceleration in cash flow generation is clearly evident with two-thirds of the year's operating EBITDA of $4.2 billion generated in the second half. The final quarter was particularly strong in terms of production, volumes and operating performance across the majority of our businesses providing strong momentum into 2010.</p>
          <p>The net impact of lower sales prices on operating profit was $2.7 billion in total with the Coal and Alloys businesses contributing for $2.2 billion or over 80% of that decline. Sales volumes rose compared to the prior period from record production of mine nickel, zinc in concentrate and lead metal, contributing $115 million to operating profits</p>
          <p>Real cost savings of $501 million offset the negative impact of inflationary headwinds, which continue to drag on earnings in 2009. CPI inflation of $301 million represented a 2.9% increase in the operating cost base, while inflationary impacts specific to the mining industry added a further 1.9%.</p>
          <p>CPI inflation persisted in a number of geographies that had a particularly strong impact in two of our major operating regions in 2009, namely Australia and South Africa. The stronger average U.S. dollar against local currencies in our operating countries in the first half, more than offset a progressively weaker U.S. dollar in the later part of the year and added some $216 million to operating profit.</p>
          <p>Now inflation specific to the mining industries calculated using externally verified price indices in each region. Substantially, all of the mining inflation was incurred in the first six months of 2009, as contracted prices from the previous year remained in place.</p>
          <p>Xstrata's Coal operations were particularly impacted due to higher port and rail charges and the lagging impact of higher prices for steel-related spares and consumables, while our energy intensive Alloys business enjoyed significant increases in electricity prices.</p>
          <p>Mining sector inflation eased markedly in the second half and has continued to decline through into early 2010 as the lagged impact of the global downturn flows through to mining input. The acquired Prodeco business recorded a pro forma operating profit of $107 million after fair value depreciation of $52 million.</p>
          <p>A non-cash charge of $328 million in respective share-based provisions was incurred as the Xstrata share price rose sharply during the year and high volatility impacted on the valuation of the potential future liability. Now this charge should be viewed against the write back of $239 million, which we took at the end of 2008.</p>
          <p>As Mick has highlighted, each of our operational teams responded promptly to the downturn, implementing initiatives to reduce costs on a sustainable basis. While cutting unit costs will always be a constant focus for our management, the economic conditions in 2009 allowed us a unique opportunity to execute a fundamental restructuring in a number of areas and achieve a step change in our cost position. In total, 5% of the operating cost base was stripped out during the year, improving our current competitive position and in a number of areas, laying the foundation for further efficiency gains into the future.</p>
          <p>Each of our businesses reduced units cost with the most significant savings coming from the Nickel and Zinc businesses. Xstrata Nickel realized $134 million of real unit cost savings or a cost reduction of 23% compared to 2008 while nominal costs decline by around 20%. Ian and his team have essentially taken a medium-sized high cost Nickel business, downsized and restructured that business through focusing on the key assets and now with the commissioning of nickel Rim South, the expansion of the Australian business, the optimization of the integrated nickel operations in Sudbury and ultimately the commencement of production from Koniambo in 2012. They are transforming Xstrata Nickel into a very substantial low cost business.</p>
          <p>And as the poly-metallic Nickel Rim South mine ramps up over the coming months, unit costs are forecast to drop further. At Xstrata Zinc, Santiago and his team have reduced the real operating cost base of their business for the eighth consecutive year and it is particularly notable that the volume increases in 2009 were achieved on reduced capital expenditure and a smaller work force.</p>
          <p>In total, the Zinc business delivered a $192 million in real unit cost savings reflecting an 11% improvement. Now, despite the cost impact of some $130 million related to lower grades at a number of operations, Xstrata Copper achieved savings of $55 million through productivity improvement and higher production rates at most of its operations relative to 2008. Also through procurement savings, through a revision of all major contracts, reductions in contractor numbers, and improved efficiency in the usage of key consumables.</p>
          <p>At the Coal operations, productivity improvements of the Australian thermal coal operation more than offset increased costs that were incurred earlier in the year. And the initiatives included higher production volumes, the benefit of moving to an owner-operator model at Mount Owen, together with efficiencies at Newlands Northern Underground and Queensland and the restart of operations at the Oaky Creek, coking coal operation.</p>
          <p>At the start of 2009, only the most efficient 20% of Xstrata Alloys ferrochrome smelters were operating, due to very poor market conditions. Lower cost production was prioritized during this period to achieve real unit savings of $13 million in an exceptionally difficult operating environment for the Chrome business.</p>
          <p>Now, during the course of 2009, I announced a number of exceptional non-cash impairments to the carrying value of assets. Under IFRS, impairments are assessed on a cash generating unit basis, and there is no ability to reallocate surpluses between assets. So, consequently while the value of Xstrata's assets continues to exceed book value by some $35 billion at a Group level, impairments have had to be recognized at a number of operations.</p>
          <p>Xstrata Nickel's restructuring included the closure or suspension of a number of operations and the deferral of two projects. The impact of these restructurings on exploration potential and life-of-mine plans prompted a full assessment of the ongoing fair value of the assets. And this assessment coupled with the impact of the weaker U.S. dollar against the stronger Australian dollar, which increased the carrying value of Xstrata Nickel's Australian operations by over $0.5 billion at the end of 2009, gave rise to an impairment charge of $1.9 billion after tax and this was the impairment which was announced in December.</p>
          <p>At that time, we also announced that the copper and zinc metallurgical plants at Kidd Creek in Ontario would be closed permanently from June and this gave rise to an impairment charge to those assets of $194 million. And the ongoing challenging market conditions for custom smelting operations, which continue to suffer from low treatment charges and low asset prices, resulted also in an impairment charge of $141 million post tax in respect of the Altonorte copper smelter in Chile.</p>
          <p>You'll recall that at the half-year, we recorded an impairment charge of $241 million in respect to the Group's investment in London and a further $36 million charge was recognized relating to Xstrata's shares of London's own exceptional charges incurred during the year.</p>
          <p>Restructuring enclosure costs of a $116 million included charges in respect of the closure of Xstrata Nickel operations at Sudbury, the Kidd Creek metallurgical site and restructuring costs at Xstrata Alloy.</p>
          <p>The investment by African Rainbow Minerals in our South African Coal business is accounted for as a debt instrument under IFRS and non-cash movements in the fair value of these liabilities gave rise to a gain of $350 million in 2009. I must stress that that is a non-cash item.</p>
          <p>In October the Group entered into a sale agreement to dispose of our 70% interest in the El Morro copper-gold project in Chile and here a gain of $144 million after tax has been recognized in the 2009 accounts as the transaction is expected to close in the first half of 2010. The tax benefit in relation to these exceptional items was in total over $300 million and the total exceptional items charge on a pre-tax basis was $2.4 billion.</p>
          <p>Xstrata's operations generated $5.3 billion of cash in the year of which $3.7 billion was generated in the second half. Tax paid decreased substantially compared to 2008 predominately due to lower earnings. Sustaining capital expenditure of $1.3 billion reflected a reduction of $300 million compared to 2008 as each of our businesses implemented capital conservation initiatives. Expansionary capital was also scaled back to $2.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Our focus particularly in the early part of the year was to optimize cash through reducing or deferring capital spending at certain longer-term projects while ensuring that we retain our full suite of organic growth options. As market conditions improved, we stepped up capital spending somewhat from the tight constraints imposed earlier in the year to complete or commission a number of projects, which added volumes and earnings during 2009.</p>
          <p>The net result is that more than $0.5 billion of cash flow was generated after capital expenditure. And I can say as I stand here now that this is certainly an outcome that I would have been more than happy to accept when I addressed you a year ago.</p>
          <p>On the 29th of January, we announced a fully underwritten two-for-one rights issue which was successfully completed on the 17th of March, with over 99% of shareholders taking up their rights.</p>
          <p>The rights issue raised net proceeds of $3.7 billion after costs and the net acquisition cost of $2 billion for the Prodeco coal operation. This rights issue has enabled us to significantly de-leverage our balance sheet, decreasing net debt to $12.3 billion from $16 billion at the end of 2008 with a commensurate reduction in gearing from 40% to 26% at the year-end.</p>
          <p>With no material debt maturities until mid-2011, our existing bank debt facilities provide a strong liquidity buffer. And at December 2009 we had $6.3 billion of headroom on our bank facility. The Group remains comfortably within its covenants at year-end. And our covenant is a three times gross debt/EBITDA and will be at two times at the year-end. And the average maturity debt on outstanding debt facility is currently greater than five years. And this combined with our modest gearing and strong operational cash flows, places us in a sound financial position to fund our future capital expenditure plans.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned, capital expenditure during 2009 was prioritized to focus on the delivery of near-term, high return growth projects, which included the Goedgevonden coal open-pit in South Africa, the Nickel Rim South project in Sudbury, both of which were completed during the year.</p>
          <p>Total CapEx in 2009 was in line with guidance at $3.6 billion and a further 200 &#x2013; some $200 million was spent at Prodeco, as those operations continue to ramp-up to 17 million tonnes per annum of production.</p>
          <p>Expansionary capital was decreased by 31% to $2.4 billion compared to 3.5 in the prior period. The Nickel business went just over $1 billion on expansionary CapEx. Expenditure at the Koniambo Nickel project in New Caledonia was optimized and spending reduced to just under $700 million in the period and the balance of the expenditure was mostly spent on commissioning Nickel Rim South.</p>
          <p>Xstrata Coal's Mangoola project commenced major earthworks in December and the Atcom East project in South Africa was approved during the year at a capital cost of just over $400 million. Feasibility studies continue into the massive Wandoan project in Queensland, which has reserves of $1 billion &#x2013; 1 billion tonnes of coal.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditure at Xstrata Copper enabled the completion of several feasibility studies at brownfield and greenfield projects resulting in Board approval in the fourth quarter of a further expansion of Lomas Bayas and an underground extension at Ernest Henry Mine in Queensland. Both projects have now commenced construction.</p>
          <p>Xstrata Zinc has initiated several feasibility studies including the construction of an Albion pressure leaching plant to upgrade bulk concentrates from McArthur River and projects to expand George Fisher and the Black Star mine in Queensland and this follows an 80% increase in reserves at George Fisher over the last four years.</p>
          <p>The Bracemac-McLeod project in Canada has also been advanced to the feasibility study stage and an extensive exploration and delineation program at the Pallas Green project in Ireland is planned for 2010. Now, lastly at Xstrata Alloys, our highly experienced Platinum management team continues to develop the Eland underground operation to replace the current open cut.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned at the Investor Presentations in early December, guidance for 2010 is for expansionary capital expenditure of approximately $4.9 billion with $1.9 billion of sustaining CapEx. Coal, copper and nickel projects each account for just under one-third of the title in growth CapEx.</p>
          <p>Following the improvements in Xstrata's financial position and reflecting our confidence in the outlook for the Group, the Directors have proposed a recommencement of dividend payments with a final dividend of $0.08 per share. This dividend will be paid on the 14th of May to shareholders on the register at 23rd April.</p>
          <p>On that positive note, I will hand you back to Mick for his concluding remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Trevor. And it's quite clear from the exception that Xstrata has pursued a strategy of value creation through growth and asset improvement for its owners. And the strategy focused on growth re-acquisition, operational transformation enhancements to net present value and organic growth for the portfolio.</p>
          <p>In the early days of Xstrata's development, our strategy was of necessity an acquisition-led growth strategy to build a portfolio diversified by commodity and geography with the scale to compete for resources and capital. And the capacity and capabilities to build large scale new operations. An equally important imperative of this acquisition-led phase was to bring a range of organic growth projects and prospective exploration sites into our portfolio to provide each commodity business with an additional stream of options to increase production and lower operating costs.</p>
          <p>Three major transformational acquisitions have been supplemented by the opportunistic and targeted bolt-on additions to optimize our existing businesses and facilitate our entry into new commodities. By way of example, last year we gained our first entry into iron ore by taking an option to acquire majority stake in the owner of the early stage Zanaga iron ore project in the Republic of Congo.</p>
          <p>Last year we also approached Anglo American as a merger of our two companies. Anglo American's rejection of our proposal is, in my view, a lost opportunity to create value for both companies' shareholders.</p>
          <p>The second phase of Xstrata's strategy focused on the transformation of acquired businesses to develop integrated, global commodity businesses with a developed management structure and an owner-operator culture. Operational management within Xstrata has made an enduring mandate &#x2013; have an enduring mandate to enhance the net present value of our operations year-on-year notwithstanding the wasting nature of mining assets and to strive for continuous improvement at our operations.</p>
          <p>Our businesses have constantly risen to this challenge to relentlessly pursue operational excellence and productivity improvements, adding reserves and resources and extending mine lives, improving the health and safety and environmental performance and proactively engaging with a broad range of stakeholders in our business.</p>
          <p>As a result, Xstrata's five integrated global business units position towards to the bottom half of their respective industry cost curves with long mine lives and extensive growth options.</p>
          <p>We have in place a world-class sustainable development framework, which has driven strong improvements in health, safety, environmental performance and community engagement. When I say performance has improved substantially each year with an average 20% annual reduction to injury frequency rates and an overall reduction in total recordable injuries of 73% since 2003, with particular dramatic improvements at acquired operations. And this is obviously very pleasing and an indication of our businesses' success in prioritizing safety at site level and encouraging a strong safety culture.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, I'm never complacent about the scale of the challenge that the industry faces and we in Xstrata particularly face, if we are to achieve our objective of operating without injuries or fatalities.</p>
          <p>During the first two phases of Xstrata's development into a major mining house, our businesses have also developed a strong track record for the successful development of major mines and metallurgical operations.</p>
          <p>Around $9 billion has been spent to deliver 13 major growth projects in the last five years. Our approach to the varying projects have been in line with our overall dissolved management model, which emphasizes accountability at the operational level. Responsibility for each projects rests with the appropriate commodity business management team. So that the team responsible for building the projects is the team that also eventually run the project once it commission.</p>
          <p>We also encourage our operational teams to find innovative ways to manage capital costs and develop the projects more efficiently. For example, Charlie Sartain and his team at Xstrata Copper have formed strategic alliances with third-parties, to ensure availability of appropriate skills and capabilities at a time when we are into a high spend phase.</p>
          <p>Xstrata Concentrated desire concept is being applied across the various projects to achieve engineering and capital cost savings and to minimize long lead delivery times. At Koniambo our best-value-country approach has been adopted, to ensure that procurement of services and equipment is done at the best possible quality for the lowest possible cost. The outcome of this approach has been to use modular construction, which is not commonly seen in the mine industry, using a construction yard in China.</p>
          <p>Through the acquisition of Falconbridge, we gained not only a broad portfolio of growth projects, but also a range of senior executives with extensive experience of developing major projects. Ian Pearce himself has personally overseen the development of two multi-billion dollar projects in challenging locations, and the Xstrata Nickel Senior Management team have some 200 years of direct project development experience between them.</p>
          <p>Opportunistic acquisition and our ongoing focus on NPV enhancement, and operational excellence, will continue to play a very significant role in Xstrata's strategy but this next stage of our growth and transformation is secured &#x2013; is in our hands, and will be developed from the development of projects within our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Many of the brownfield and greenfield projects that have been guided through conceptual and feasibility studies by Xstrata operational management in recent years are now reaching the approval and construction phase. Each of these projects will deliver robust returns with average returns in the mid 20% range and conservative long-term &#x2013; long run prices.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditure obviously will rise accordingly, with expansionary capital expenditure of approximately $14 billion over the next three years. This expenditure will realize the next phase of Xstrata's transformation, both in terms of volume growth, but equally importantly also delivering substantial reductions in the operating cost profile of our businesses.</p>
          <p>At our recent December Investor Seminars, our Coal, Copper and Nickel businesses provided extensive detail on their respective near term and longer-term growth strategies and so going through an exhaustive list again is not functional.</p>
          <p>However in summary, over $8 billion of projects are currently in implementation, including five growth projects that have been approved in the past six months. Construction decisions are expected on a further 10 projects this year. The majority of the projects are low cost, low risk brownfield expansion and if approved, will involve total capital expenditure over $9 billion. The execution of the projects currently in our pipeline will deliver volume growth of more than 50% in copper and coal, while nickel volumes will double.</p>
          <p>Now, let's return to Koniambo. As many of you will know, Koniambo is the largest single project that Xstrata is currently building with an expected capital cost of $3.85 billion and as such it seems appropriate to provide sort of a more extensive update on this project and to set out some key milestones.</p>
          <p>Koniambo will be a first quartile cost operation and produced 60,000 tonnes of nickel in its initial phase with potential to double or even triple production depending on market conditions. The technology used at Koniambo is quite boring. It's low risk and the project does not require high pressure acid leaching and will use conventional power metallurgical smelting technology.</p>
          <p>The project is located in New Caledonia which is not boring and as I mentioned earlier, the project team has looked for innovative ways to build the project, given its remote location and coastal position and the requirement for several substantial pieces of infrastructure including a fourth power plant, metallurgical plant and of course a major mine.</p>
          <p>Now, one of most striking examples of this approach is the decision to construct the metallurgical plant in a modular fashion, assembling major ices of plant in advance in high specification Chinese engineering yards. Together with some other members of the executive committee, I traveled to China a couple weeks ago. And while this trip involved some meetings with a wide range of different companies and officials, we visited this very impressive yard in Qingdao, situated in the South East province of Shandong.</p>
          <p>The high standard of engineering work to my untrained eye, was impressive. The efficiency with which these immense structures are being constructed and I have to say the enthusiasm of our partners to adopt our safety and working standards to enable them to develop getting business further, were quite remarkable. And it was amazing to see the safety performance, which has been quite extemporary following the full adoption by the Chinese contractors of Xstrata's sustainable development policy and standards.</p>
          <p>Now this modular approach has a number of benefits including reduced onsite construction hours, which provides greater certainty of our costs, since much of the assembly is completed before the modules are shipped to the Koniambo Port, where final assembly takes place. And we're reliably assured that senior members of the Nickel team will accompany the modules on the boat. So they can both arrive on time.</p>
          <p>Now going forward, the major project milestones are approaching fast. Industrial site earthworks were substantially complete during 2009 in preparation with the delivery of the modules in the third quarter of this year, 2010. Project engineering, dredging, the construction demand will obviously all be completed in 2010, and the construction of the smelter and power plant will commence during the course of this year.</p>
          <p>The major site works and construction activity will be completed by the end of next year and in 2012, the first ore will reach the furnace, with a ramp-up to full production by 2014, very exciting. So while a number of major challenges remain, I'm very pleased with the project. The progress of this really cornerstone project which remains on budget, on track to commence production in 2012, and which is reaping the benefit I think of a yearlong optimization phase we initiated post the Falconbridge acquisition before the project was approved in October 2007.</p>
          <p>Now although the full implications of the financial crisis and the global recession have not yet fully played out, it is clear that the experiences over the last 18 months, they are going to have a profound and long lasting effect on the world in which we operate.</p>
          <p>In the commodity sector, one of the most significant impacts has been the extent to which the downturn has exacerbated the supply constraints that already existed. Prior to the crisis, our industry was already struggling to maintain or increase production in the face of declining grades, unplanned outages at aging operations and the challenges involved in developing new projects in very complex geographies.</p>
          <p>The mining industry swinging cuts to expenditure on exploration projects and infrastructure in response to the financial crisis, has delayed the onset of new capacity, I'd say, we're at least 18 to 24 months. It means the supply side will fall further behind in its ability to supply even modest increases in future demand. And a lack of credit availability also has forced to many junior miners to suspend or cancel investment in exploration, with forecast expenditure in 2010 to remain subdued at least in 50% of 2008 spending.</p>
          <p>Finally, volatile market conditions and prices for key inputs also meant that many feasibility studies were delayed to incorporate revised assumptions of costs or other variables.</p>
          <p>The robust economic growth and demand for commodities from industrializing nations, I think is likely to continue, with many forecasters anticipating Chinese GDP growth rate around 9% in 2010. Now the inflation poses a risk and a challenge. The recent measures taken by the Chinese authorities to tighten monetary policy and curb inflation, are in my opinion, quite positive and reflect the need to bring planned lending rates to the previously announced target of RMB 7.5 trillion, following a stronger than expected first month in 2010.</p>
          <p>It is clear to me on my visit that the Chinese authorities only see upside risk to GDP growth in 2010. <mark type="inaudible" />  to avoid an overheated economy during this year. Therefore, demand for commodities by China will continue. I expect that increased exports and growth in private investment will help to offset the moderation in the government's stimulus initiatives.</p>
          <p>U.S. consumer remains pivotal to the full recovery in global trade, including China's export industry. And while consumer spending will inevitably rise again, it maybe isn't yet certain when this will begin or indeed what level of consumption Western consumers will adopt in the aftermath of such a severe recession.</p>
          <p>Many of the short and medium-term leading indicators we monitor are showing signs of recovery, including manufacturing output and confidence, notwithstanding the fact that credit expansion in OECD economies remains sluggish.</p>
          <p>But unemployment levels, regulatory reforms in the banking industry, rising national debts, sovereign risk concerns and the imperative to withdraw stimulus packages without dampening economic recovery indicate there are a number of risks that are going to have to be carefully managed on the path to a sustainable OECD recovery.</p>
          <p>The recession also emphasized the pre-eminence of China, Brazil and India as consumers of commodities and in 2009, China represented over 100% of the growth in global consumption in a number of metals including copper and zinc. China and other industrializing nations are taking active steps to rebalance their economies towards domestic consumption-led growth over the next decade.</p>
          <p>Government programs, such as proposed rural land reform, which is currently being piloted in a number of areas in China, and incentives to buy durable goods like cars have continued to facilitate urbanization and industrialization, the two major driving forces that will continue to support demand growth for commodities. The medium term outlook for commodity demand, I think remains very promising.</p>
          <p>Now our businesses rapid and comprehensive response to the downturn in the early part of the year enabled a creditable performance in extremely challenging markets in 2009. We continue to invest in key growth projects during the year in preparation for the economic recovery and to drive substantial volume growth and reductions in operating costs, making the next stage of Xstrata's transformation.</p>
          <p>Our growth projects will progressively reach production during a timeframe in which demand for commodities from industrializing countries seems set to remain robust, augmented by a return to demand both from OECD in due course and ongoing structural constraints of the supply of many commodities.</p>
          <p>Xstrata has been well positioned over the last few years to benefit in this environment. Investments over recent years have delivered a diversified portfolio with scale and the capabilities to develop major new mines. And as we enter into this next phase of Xstrata's transformation, I'm confident that the Group's prospects remain very encouraging. And in due course, Xstrata's shareholders should be able to echo the immortal words of Colonel Hannibal Smith of the A-Team, "I love it when a plan comes together."</p>
          <p>We're now very happy to take questions.</p>
          <p>Have you got a microphone? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Mick, Jason Fairclough, Bank of America &#x2013; Merrill Lynch, I suppose. Two quick questions, if I may. First, could you talk a little bit about the tax review that's going on in Australia and the extent to which you may be more or less impacted vis-&#xE0;-vis your peers? Second question would be on Prodeco. Could you talk a little bit about whether, if Glencore exercises the option with a view to on-selling it, would you look to compete with such an offer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The issue on the tax situation in Australia, I think is clearly of concern to every person, every company in Australia. Uncertainty of fiscal arrangements is not conducive for good and sound investment policies. Our view about taxation and fiscal arrangements is that they need to be predictable and transparent. And that is our approach to this issue as well.</p>
          <p>We obviously clearly with others will seek to engage with government and try to understand what they are trying to achieve. I think elements of retrospectivity will clearly be highly undesirable and the need to maintain predictability and transparency is important. It is open to governments to impose tax regimes as they see fit. At the same time, it is open to companies to decide how they're going to invest. For both sides to make realistic and prudent decisions, we need to understand the basis of that, and that is the framework in which we will have those &#x2013; of those interactions. I don't think that we'll be relatively worse off or better off than other players in Australia. I think this is clearly a matter which we need to invest some time in.</p>
          <p>On the issue of Prodeco, the 4th of March is sort of D-date, I am not going to speculate on what will or will not happen. It really is Glencore's decision and they need to make up their minds as to what they want to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm Tobias Woerner from MF Global. Two questions, if I may. The first one probably more aimed at Trevor, with regard to your net debt-to-EBITDA, when we look into 2010 that should be a relatively sound number. Can you give us some guidance or idea of your thinking with regard to that number? And how much you would like to stretch it in context of CapEx and M&amp;A spend?</p>
          <p>And a second question if I may, a follow-on, is to Mick with regard to the secular theme. It seems to me as if China will want to move to a more consumer driven economy, which means that probably precious metals will take a more interesting angle, will &#x2013; do you &#x2013; would you agree with that, firstly? And secondly, will you want to position your business in line of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Trevor, you want to deal with the issues on debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, look as I've pointed out, I think our gearing ratios are very comfortable at the moment, but I'm also cognizant of the fact that a year ago, having these debt levels was a dangerous thing and we are heading into a period where we are going to start committing to CapEx programs that are going to be relatively inflexible, once we have initiated construction. So I would not want to see our debt levels rising materially at all. I think what we will be doing is restructuring the shape of our debt to access the bond markets to ensure that we keep pushing out the term of our debt in a fashion that is appropriate for a larger capital expend that is going to last over a period of years.</p>
          <p>So no, I don't see us having a huge amount of debt capacity and I think as in the past were we to look at large M&amp;A transactions, we'd look at the appropriate capital structure in the context of those acquisitions and restructure our balance sheet accordingly. But I do think that where we sit now, we're in a comfortable position to contemplate this period of increased capital expenditure and execute it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, I agree with you. Just moving on to your China question, I said clearly, that as the Chinese economy matures, the consumption expenditure will become a great &#x2013; probably a greater role in GDP. But, this is I think a generational change that is going to have to take place. Savings is a deep-seated issue amongst the man in the street in China, a very high savings ratios. The ability to move away from that is going to be a function of the government's capacity to enhance the social welfare net that they put in place, to enhance the pension net that they're putting in place to encourage the rural land reform, which is clearly going to be a very significant effective transfer of wealth from the state to individuals. I think all of those will clearly help drive that.</p>
          <p>I think that one of the other factors that's going to drive it is clearly as the cost of financing increases the need for capital to become more efficient and more effective and that will drive the shape of the country's GDP. So, yes, that will happen. It's going to take time, but it will happen. From our point of view, the movement into durable goods is clearly a positive indication and will impact some of our commodities. We take &#x2013; if you talk about precious metals, we're not specifically a precious metal house and neither will we want to be that, but we look at the industrial aspect of our platinum and we see that has been obviously the long-term benefit of platinum demand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Sam Catalano from Macquarie. Three questions. Just with Xstrata entering the third phase of its transformation as you described, I wonder if you could discuss how you feel about divestments of some of your poorer performing assets or even some of your suspended assets, and specifically if you could touch on copper smelting in light of the recent asset impairments?</p>
          <p>Secondly, just on Nickel costs, obviously a good job has been done bringing those down, but just I wonder how the recent labor agreement will impact that this year. I think, as part of that, there was some resumption of some of your suspended capacity, so how that plays into your cost in the Nickel business. And just finally, with the resumption of dividends how &#x2013; will that also mean the resumption of the progressive dividend policy, if you want to enunciate any policy at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I mean I can't answer your questions specifically on divestments. I mean we constantly look at our portfolio, and I think as the business matures, as Xstrata has, and wanting to look at the portfolio and cutting out the bottom end of the portfolio and increasing the top end is clearly a desirable thing to do. If you can find businesses, which you can sell on to other people who might be more valuable in their hands, and clearly we are open to do that. While it was an operating business, I think the sale of El Morro is a good example of that. It clearly is more valuable in the hands of others than in ours and it made sense for us to do that. Some of the operations we've closed, I think are closed for good reason, because they shouldn't be open. And I think that's probably how they will stay.</p>
          <p>Issues around the competitors on nickel I'm going to hand over to Ian to talk about and maybe Charlie, if you want maybe say a few words on the smelters in Canada that would also be welcome.</p>
          <p>Just before you do that on the dividend approach, I mean this is the time at last you get a dividend. So we've always paid a dividend except for last year. We said we would resume dividend payments as soon as we could. We're doing that. We never were a great dividend yield stock, we're really a growth stock, we'll remain that, but we made a promise, we're living up to that promise and we will continue now to offer this new base to continue the progressive growth of that dividend. Ian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mick. Just on the Nickel's base, particularly it was Sudbury, I think, most importantly is Nickel Rim of course and ramping up of Nickel Rim. I think we're more leveraged to, as you can imagine, prices rather than labor agreements. And so one of the things that we did do when we did the labor agreement was to structurally change the approach we've taken with bonus and reward of the workforce. So one of the things we did is we raised the base for that nickel bonus that gets paid to the workers and at the same time putting a complementary performance based bonus scheme on top of that.</p>
          <p>And, so that is to drive the behavior of the workforce and it's quite encouraging to hear the feedback we already received from the workforce of how they can actually leverage that bonus scheme and how can they help with the performance of the Company. We were able to contain, cost increases in the labor over the first two years, and we only had a minimal increase in the $0.30 or $0.20 per hour. So, I think overall the labor agreement is positive in that we've been able to keep the business running forward and we've been able to change structurally the way we incentivize the workforce.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Sam, in relation to the smelting assets in Canada, the Kidd smelter then the decision to close that was very much related to the lack of profitability of that smelter and the fact that we had significant overcapacity of smelters in that region. So what we are undertaking in Canada is a consolidation of our remaining assets so they're more vertically integrated and we can ensure that we get good freight capture from regional concentrate supplies than we have, bringing that more in balance with the remaining capacity between our mines and smelter and refineries in Canada. And we believe that will make that Canadian copper division more robust division for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris LaFemina from Barclays. Just a couple of questions. One is on the cash cost I think you disclosed C1 cash cost in copper, nickel and zinc. Can you comment on what your cost would be if you include indirect cost and sustaining CapEx in each of those businesses, so, basically a free cash flow breakeven cost in each business?</p>
          <p>And then I'm wondering if you can make any comments or if you have any comments about the Anglo Plat's (sic) [Platinum's] announced rights issue from today and DeBeers' rights issue and how a combination of Xstrata and Anglo may alleviate some balance sheet problems that either one of the companies might have on its own.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to deal with the easy question first and I am not going to comment on the initiatives in the Anglo Group. I will leave them to do that. But in the issue of the all, sort of C3 costs of the various businesses, can I hand over to the team? The team don't want to be handed over to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start with Nickel. Let's say that certainly on a free cash flow breakeven basis, we've seen improvements from 2008 through 2009 and we expect those improvements to continue. I am just looking at 2008 figures, we had 6.91 was our free cash breakeven nickel price and last year it was 5.37, so we see that on an onward downward trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peet. Charlie anything on copper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>CapEx adds about $0.40 a pound to our C1 costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And zinc?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In our case the capital question you have seen were not very relevant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He doesn't like to spend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The only thing I can tell you is our C1 cash cost came down from 1,286 in 2008 to 959 in 2009 and because we are foreseeing some strong additional cost savings, we expect a further strong reduction in our C1 cash costs in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will get back to you with the number on the C3. Is that somebody at the back room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Des Kilalea from RBC. Could you put some flesh on the bones of Zanaga, you are spending 50 million to get 50% plus one on scale because it is a new area for Xstrata and maybe just comment on the infrastructure in the country?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Do you want to pick that up, Trevor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's a very, very early stage project, given the infrastructure requirements which is building a railway line of some $400 million &#x2013; million kilometer &#x2013; start again. Of 400 kilometers across pretty hostile jungle and given the requirement for a port, it's going to have to be quite a big project. The sort of scale of project that would carry that up-front infrastructure cost would be around about a 25 million tonne per annum operation. But I just have to point out this is very, very early stage exploration.</p>
          <p>It's very evident to us that there is a big iron ore system there. This thing was discovered by the BOGM in 1960, work was done on it in the early 70s. We have recruited the team that worked on Ximandu for Rio Tinto, and anecdotally &#x2013; and I put all the caveats of geologists' exuberance at stage in the project &#x2013; they believe that it has all indications of being a very attractive, but early stage iron ore project. We are hoping that by spending the 50 million, we are in a place at least to determine that we have a saleable product, that we have a substantial resource, that we have a large inferred resource around that and that we have orders of magnitude numbers on the infrastructure. And on the basis of that we will decide whether we then commit to the feasibility study, which is what really earns us our 50%. But you know, it's an exciting project but at a very early stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any other questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Olivia Ker from UBS. Firstly, I was wondering if you could maybe comment on the impact of investment funds and financial money on commodity prices during the second half of last year? And then secondly on thermal coal, obviously during 2009 China moved to be a very large net importer of thermal coal, at about 90 million tonnes, three times the amount of normal levels. Can you talk about how sustainable you think that change is over the medium-term? And then just finally, are you able to give us a quick update on the Balaclava Island Port project in Queensland?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the issue of funds and commodities &#x2013; yeah. Commodities have been an asset class for some time. And the behavior of commodity prices leading up to financial prices of 2008 during the price and thereafter, is a great example of the impact they have, because on the margins, clearly these prices responded with sentiment. The people who run this money should be very familiar to many of you and you know that we are all human beings and therefore sentiment drives a lot of these investment decisions. And therefore we have high volatility.</p>
          <p>The frustration that we have I guess as a Company is that we, we don't feel that we have at the moment sufficient information as to the extent of the influence. And so our feel is the same as everybody else's. And it's a sort of new area of endeavor, I think that we want to pick up to really try and understand this.</p>
          <p>But I think really it drives volatility. It doesn't drive ultimate direction. At the end of the day, prices of commodities will follow simple economics of demand and supply. And we just have to accept great volatility. There is no doubt at the back end of the last year, there was strong positive sentiment, which contributed to the strength in prices. And during the early part of this year, there is some relatively negative sentiments, which has taken some of the gloss off those prices. At the end of the day, it's not the funds which are going to be decisive in where the investment trends go and ultimately the price commodities is, it's going to be essentially supply and demand. But it's an area that we'd like to understand better, we don't understand as well as we would like to.</p>
          <p>On the issue of coal, I think Peter is in a good position to respond.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, Olivia, just to answer the question on Chinese demand. We've seen since around 2002 year-on-year, demand for imported thermal coal increasing into China. And other than a slight hesitation, 2008/2009 in terms of their growth, what we have seen is a resumption now of their growth. Sales continue to be very positive, thermal coal going in there. And even this year we understand significant quantities have been booked. It's hard to do long-term forward projections. We need to understand better Chinese thermal growth itself in terms of their own production, but the trend is pretty well established now.</p>
          <p>As far as Balaclava Island is concerned, it's a very important option for us in terms of our Wandoan development, but at the same time we are participating in Wiggins Island development as well. So we've got two ports that we're looking at in terms of capable, that will be capable of carrying tonnage from the Wandoan project, once we get that going.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any other questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Rebecca O'Dwyer from Investec, you mentioned your ferrochrome smelters were running at about 85% of capacity at the end of the year. I was wondering whether there had been any improvement in that this year and secondly whether you could put some color on your outlook for the ferrochrome industry given the significant challenges that it's facing at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peet <mark type="inaudible" /> will deal with that soon, it's just in general terms, the lead indicators which support the industries for ferrochrome ultimately is going to find its way through suggest that the ferrochrome price should be going up. It clearly is not going up enough at the moment to address the issues that you are talking about which is relation to the very strong rand and the rising energy process in South Africa. So, yeah, Peet and his teams have challenge but Peet maybe you just want to talk about first of all the extent of your capacity utilization and then maybe your views on where the market is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we are back at full production and the mere fact that the last two quarters the price is just above a dollar per pound and the spot market is still there and the orders coming through more regularly indicate that the stainless steel market at least have been to its bottom and it is growing.</p>
          <p>Yes, we've got tremendous challenges and I think that this may be a subject on its own. But I think suffice to say that in anticipation of the energy crisis that will come we embarked on <mark type="inaudible" /> and the Premus technology where our power consumption out of LOEs roughly half that of the industry but the mere fact that more than 50% of the ferrochrome comes from South Africa, it will be some time before the rest of the world will really challenge the output, and the &#x2013; output in South Africa due to the cost of the rise et cetera will have an umbrella effect supporting the producers in South Africa. So, the name of game for us is to just stay ahead of the pack.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any other questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Christ LaFemina from Barclays again. Just wanted to ask a question about consolidation in general. Do you believe that being larger and more diversified results in a lower cost of capital, even at this point? In other words, if Xstrata is twice as big than it is today, does that mean your cost of capital gets lower or is there a point where you sort of hit critical mass in terms of when you can get a lower capital cost?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is an interesting theoretical debate if we can have. I think that the evidence to date suggests that the larger, more diversified are the lower your cost of capital is. I mean I think I found empirical evidence indicates that that's true and that certainly is a thesis that has driven our approach to building the Company. I'm quite sure at some point in time you could grow the company to a level where because of the external constraints on your Anti Trust Issues and things like that and your ability to manage across the systems, might well impact your ability to deliver value. But I think that we in Xstrata are not there. I am not sure whether any other companies in the mining sector hardly at this stage, and I think that's sort of a theoretical proposition. All I can say is that empirical evidence suggests that the consolidation has benefited various companies which got bigger and more diversified <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As a follow-up to that. Would you consider M&amp;A activity in sectors that you have &#x2013; already have high exposure, for example, copper and coal to be less desirable than M&amp;A in other segments that might &#x2013; in another words if you went on the board to watch copper, so you'd be maybe 60% or 70% copper would that be something that'd be undesirable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I have to say that at the end of day you go where you could find the value and that's why we've always said that we are opportunists when it comes to acquisition. So, we have a sort of rally clear idea of what is a value proposition for us and when the opportunities present themselves if they &#x2013; or even if the universe of the possible and in essence you try and grab them and that does mean that at times you might have more copper, more weighted to copper or more weighted to coal and we've been through this in our history where we have been sort of majorly dominated in coal and we were majorly dominated in copper and now we sort of people say, well you sort of got a copper, coal buyers particularly investments in Nickel that's going to grow disproportionately and that will make a disproportionate contribution.</p>
          <p>I think you have to live with the fact that if you're building a company, you are not going to achieve your balance, and is 70% in copper undesirable, if you could make a big copper acquisition, per se no, but I mean if you just left it at that well then clearly you live with the risks of a copper <mark type="inaudible" />. So I'm much more driven by, does the opportunity in itself create a possibility we can add value to our shareholders, recognizing that over time the portfolio has to continue to sort of rebalance with them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from Credit Suisse. I just wondered with regards to your comments on Anglo the lost opportunity and Trevor's comments about the balance sheet, does that mean now that after the six months is up, you won't be approaching Anglo management again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I said, I think it is a lost opportunity for both shareholders to create value as a result of their rejection of our proposal. I am not going to comment on what &#x2013; as what's going to happen in the future, because I am not really good in, good in speculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you still think that it would add value for your shareholders, that hasn't changed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I said at the time when we indicated that we were going to pursue the proposal, the combination of Anglo-American and Xstrata was a combination which was a natural combination of the industry and would add value for shareholders. We don't &#x2013; we haven't yet perfected the art of doing these things on our own. Well &#x2013; sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, just a quick follow-up. Actually it's a probably question for Peter. The coking coal was seeing chatter that BHP is asking for quarterly settlements. Do you actually have the flexibility to ask for that from your customers or are you actually committed on volumes against the full year contract?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've never really followed the strict structure of the benchmarking in our coking coal sales and have had straightforward negotiations between us and our customer base. And we'll see where that leads in this new environment. It is situational. There is no doubt that the customer base is a bit concerned about how they will manage their downstream pricing in terms of negotiation, once they try and sell the steel. We will sit with our customers and go forward and see how we can best manage this and find the best value for both of us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Are there no further questions? Well then, thank you very much for your attendance, much appreciated. And as always afterwards, we are available for in formal discussion. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>