<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1309356" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-05-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2568</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Dieter Wemmer, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Spencer Horgan</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Will Morgan</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">James Quin</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Brian Shea</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Stefan Sch&#xFC;rmann</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">William Hawkins</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Andrew Broadfield</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Charles Graham</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Michael Huttner</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Fabrizio Croce</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Jean-Francois Tremblay</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning or good afternoon. I'm Desiree the Chorus Call operator for this conference. Welcome to the Zurich Financial Services Results Reporting for the Three Months March 31, 2010 Analyst and Media Conference Call. Please note that for the duration of the presentation, all participants will be listen-only mode and the conference is being recorded. After a short introduction, there will be an opportunity to ask questions <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> This call must not be recorded for publication or broadcast.</p>
          <p>At this time, I'd like to turn the conference over to Mr. Dieter Wemmer, Chief Financial Officer of Zurich Financial Services. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and good afternoon to everybody on the phone. I welcome you to the Zurich Financial Services Q&amp;A session. I hope you have appreciated the new format with access to the numbers and presentation online at your convenient time.</p>
          <p>We will look forward actually to your feedback, but for now, I'm assuming you have seen the results and I would like to quickly summarize the key parts. Overall, a very strong set of results with our operating business remaining sound with good performance in difficult markets, achieving selected growth in those areas where we have been able to grow profitably.</p>
          <p>The business and economic environment remains challenging, and we will continue to address these challenges. We will maintain our business philosophy of managing our margin in precedence to top line where these conflict.</p>
          <p>The capital base and solvency remain strong and we will continue to manage our business aiming to deliver consistent high-quality earnings with growth. This keeps us in a strong position to be able to react quickly to any market conditions which may arise.</p>
          <p>And now I'm turning to the question-and-answer session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>The first question is from Horgan Spencer (sic) [Spencer Horgan] , Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, there. It's the other way around actually. Spencer Horgan from Deutsche Bank. Can you ask three quick ones probably? The first two are on the rate change monitor. Firstly, in the U.S. commercial business, the rate change has sort of become flat. Is that kind of the end of the end of the strengthening cycle we have seen specifically in the U.S commercial market? Secondly, on the rate change with the personal lines business in Germany, which is showing plus four, could you give us rough feeling at least of how that would split between motor and non-motor business? And then lastly with Farmers, I see your intention to reduce the quota share further given the surplus ratio within the exchanges, is it feasible that that quota share goes down to sort of zero over time, and can you give us a feeling for how much risk-based capital that would free up or how much risk-based capital is currently consumed by the quota share? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. Spencer; that is very good list of questions so let me see whether I got them all right, otherwise you need to correct me. The rate change in the U.S. did slow down, but I think that that continues a bit what we have already seen in the fourth quarter 2009. Still we think we can push through more rate increases. The first quarter both from a line of business mix more gravitating towards property business and the property business in the U.S. is seeing more pressure on rates, as you all know that this is quite often happening after a hurricane-free year on one hand. On the other hand there was one specialty. The modeling agencies have changed their risk models for Californian earthquake, and we are strong participants in one of this earthquake cover programs and there they recalculated rates down by minus 20%, which had as a single special risk niche actually quite some impact on our overall U.S. rate change. If I exclude this, actually all lines together were still positive.</p>
          <p>And in Germany, it's mainly coming from motors, the rate increase. It is less, actually it was 5.2% motor standalone, and less driven through premium increases, but it is very much driven by exposure reduction with higher deductibles and other reductions in coverage.</p>
          <p>So that was this question, and then coming to the Farmers quota share, well, theoretically it could go down to 0% because we don't need to keep it or have it. I think the low point of the quota share was so far 5%; that was back in somewhere in 2007-2008 before we then increased it to 15 and then further upwards. I did not now calculate the whole RBC linked to it. But the 10 percentage point decrease, which we are planning to execute on end of this quarter, will over time release 500, $600 million from the required RBC. It is still a bit higher than it was before the 21st Century acquisition, because the acquisition obviously increased the overall premium volume of the Farmers Exchanges, therefore 25% of the whole portfolio is more than it was before the acquisition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Will Morgan, Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. I have a couple of questions, please. The first one is, you mentioned during your recorded presentation that the underlying loss ratio that you show on slide seven, while it is fairly similar year-on-year, there have been, you said, the impacts in 2010 of kind of other residual weather losses. Do you have in mind a kind of number what that might be? I mean, when you think about it, what is the kind of improvement that you are really seeing underlying in that business.</p>
          <p>The second question I have is related to your sovereign exposure that you gave on slide 15. It's really just a slight technical question. If we were take the kind of percentages you show, this 20 billion number at the top for the -- kind of key markets that you're concerned by and maybe times it by -- and then effectively remove maybe 80% of the Global Life exposure. I mean, is that too simplistic? I was wondered whether or not there were some specific countries where more is the shareholders than others.</p>
          <p>And the final question I had, and I just wanted to double-check, but you said that you would release about 5 to $600 million of capital from reducing the quota share in Farmers. If I remember correctly, at the time of the acquisition of the Personal Auto Group, I think it was --you were saying that you needed almost over a $1 billion in order to fund the taking on of the higher quota share at the time. And yet you were only kind of releasing only 500, 600 million. I may have got something wrong. I just wanted to double-check. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, that's a good list of questions. So let me start with the underlying loss ratio. Yes, if you look at the slide number, it's even to the decimal point the same as a year ago. We have not exactly calculated how many additional losses we had based on icy roads in the U.K. or in other parts of the Europe or how many roofs collapsed in our commercial business in the eastern part of the U.S. due to the snow. And therefore we have not given the precise number of it. We are only highlighting that this is additional conservatism in our way to present our underlying loss ratio because I think I have seen some of the competitors who count each $500 bump on an icy street as part of the weather-related losses. And we are not going to this detail because I think that is a false position and it is only showing you that we are not overstating or understating our underlying loss ratio.</p>
          <p>On the sovereign bonds, there's the split between the policyholder and shareholder, that is a question which is I cannot answer with one number because that is indeed differently between each of the countries. If we just focus on the countries which are called the BRIIC countries with two "i's," I think they are mainly held in the country where matching the local liabilities. I think when we just look at what exposure do we have outside the BRIIC countries liabilities, that is $2.8 billion which is being held by markets outside. So maybe this helps you additionally a bit better to understand this number.</p>
          <p>And the last point was RBC on the quota share, you are absolutely right, our capital increase exercise last year allocated, I think if I remember correctly, $850 million of RBC to the quota share. And when I said or roughly 600 million are linked to the relief, the exchanges are now bigger than they were a year ago. So to go back to the old level, you would have to decrease the quota share not to 25%, maybe to 22%. And if you calculate this properly then you find your missing piece of the RBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That's very clear. Just going back to your point on my second question, when you're saying, say 2.8 billion is what you said was &#x2013; it's actually assets in the BRIICs countries not backing liabilities, is that....?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the other way around: government bonds of the weaker countries being covering liabilities in countries which are not affected by the current crisis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. Okay. Very good, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from James Quin, Citigroup. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Yes, a couple of questions please. The first one just on the investment income in the P&amp;C business, down 7% in Q1 2010 versus Q4 2009. I was wondering if there is any specific behind that. Or is it effectively just reinvestment of maturing bonds at lower rates? And effectively, should we be thinking of Q1 of effectively the sort of return you would normally expect or do you think that there might be further downside to investment income estimates there?</p>
          <p>The second one is just on the expense ratio around 27%, I mean again this is sort of Q1 2010 versus Q4 last year. It's pretty consistent. I mean to what extent do you see this as a sort of bottom of the cycle number and reflecting I guess the reduction in the top line that you had, or do you think that actually there are some specific issues which are effectively causing that to be higher than you would expect? And the third very quick question, Farmers Re, I'm just wondering why the results were so strong in Q1. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Starting with investment income there was nothing special on the investment income in the first quarter 2010. Your guess is totally right. In the end, reinvestment rates are lower that they were before and also new money is being invested at lower rates. So that is nothing spectacular. Certainly you will see usually in the second quarter some uplift from dividend payments in absolute dollars. Even if you have a small portfolio only in relative terms invested in equities or other non-bond investments, you will still see in the second quarter a higher investment income.</p>
          <p>The expense ratio is actually in line with our internal expectations, but it's actually including some special effects, and I would only highlight two effects here. You have all noticed that we have more prior year development in the first quarter than we had in previous first quarter. About $30 million of this prior year development are actually linked to U.S. crop business, which then got to be paid out as profit commission. So it hits the combined ratio twice, once as prior year development and on the other hand as an increased expense ratio. And $30 million would be for full year not a lot, but if you take that first quarter premium, it's only 7 billion, the numbers are very sensitive.</p>
          <p>And talking about the sensitivity of the small base, we have actually $100 million of one-off negative net earned premiums in the first quarter. Also coming out of repayments of premium in particular in the construction business in the U.S. because the underlying project business of our customers was even smaller than they and us expected. And this special effect already makes a little variation also to the expense ratio and will certainly smooth out over the year. Therefore, I think the expense ratio from our perspective, in particular, if I look at the absolute expense dollars we are spending, it's very much on track.</p>
          <p>Farmers Re, we have seen great reduction in particular in the motor combined ratio. Farmers Re has pushed through rates and also we had a low &#x2013; almost eventless quarter on special events, so therefore also, the Farmers Re result does not only contain the quota share, which benefits from the general combined ratio development of the exchanges, but also it has the special adverse development cover for motor comprehensive. And that was &#x2013; had also a very low loss ratio. So that is the main driver for the Farmers Re result, plus the fact that investment income of the quota share is building up over time and you have with the increase of the percentage of the quota share to grow into the new level, and investment income in absolute dollars is catching up quarter over quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for that. Perhaps if I could come back very quickly on investment income, do you feel that if reinvestment rates were to stabilize around this level, that we're seeing something close to the sort of the plateau of the absolute level investment income or do you feel there is still perhaps a bit of room for the absolute level of investment income to shrink a bit more just as higher coupon bonds have rolled over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, James, we can probably stabilize the investment income as we are looking at the moment also to increase some credit risk taking in particular for our U.S. portfolios where we are still fairly low, so that we actually see also some additional plus in generating new investment income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thank you. I hope you buy some great bonds. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Brian Shea, Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I just had one question and essentially partially already been answered by the last question that was raised by James. I was also going to ask about the investment income in non-life, just tracking that from a slightly different angle. If I look at how your stock of invested assets in non-life have been moving, they actually been holding up really well over the past year or so.</p>
          <p>And I am just wondering given the very slow premium growth, to your credit you guys have been disciplined with writing business, does that mean that we should expect the stock of invested assets the stagnate over the next couple of years? Certainly the way I model it, that's kind of what's happening, but I am wondering if the mechanics of that mix make sense to you as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that makes sense to us, but it really depends how our top line will develop over the next years. So I agree with you that when the top line is shrinking and also the invested assets will shrink over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Is there &#x2013; may be related to that, is there any sign of life beyond the pricing conditions you've talked about for Q1? You could see a resumption growth even this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we have actually cleared the plans to grow, and I think that it's already working in some area. It is not yet working overall. I think what is clearly working very well is our global corporate business, where we have new business growth and still getting rate increases. I think we are entering obviously a new phase of uncertainty, strong balance sheet and flight to quality will be again, as I read all the European news, the renewed issue, and I think with our very strong balance sheet I think we will have a &#x2013; we will benefit from this very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Stefan Sch&#xFC;rmann, Bank Vontobel. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I have two questions from me. First one is on duration gap, can you maybe just update us what you did in the first quarter in the Life and Non-Life units in terms of duration between assets and liabilities. And the second one more in detail on the 21st Century, I see that the agency business was still decreasing in terms of gross written premiums in the first quarter against Q4 2009. Do you see sort of a bottoming out there? What should we expect going forward? And the last one maybe as well on commutations, did you have any substantial commutations in central or the other front of operations in Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a long list of questions, Stefan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the 21st Century. I think I can answer this very easily. You will see that this premium will vanish completely because we are renewing also agency business under the brand name Foremost, and we have already announced this two quarters ago that we will not show this separately because as soon as it is in the general book of Foremost, we will not be able to identify the single qualities any more, and therefore it is just not visible. So we will clearly use 21st Century as the direct brand only and not repeat any distribution confusion around the brand names. So Foremost is for the independent agents, 21st Century is for the direct business and Farmers for our own private agents.</p>
          <p>So the duration gap actually it did not movement in the first quarter. We are still keeping it fairly small. We had special activities in the fourth quarter 2009 to close duration gaps further. So therefore there is no additional need at the moment to do this. We might consider lengthening of some of the portfolios for commercial liability now, but that has not yet happened in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the last question special commutations there were some smaller commutations in the Center portfolio in the first quarter 2010 but not to the materiality level as we had it two years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yeah. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from William Hawkins, KBW. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you very much. Dieter, first of all, back of the slide 12b, on 21st Century, when you look the direct premiums, how comfortable are you that we're now seeing a trend increase in those figures rather than just bumping along somewhere in the mid 400s? And you said that this is the beginning of a trend increase, can you just remind us of whether there's been any particular changes of underwriting strategy or any particular marketing efforts or pricing efforts or what have you.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, briefly, in your formal presentation in your said $20 million of one-offs in the Life division and I'm sorry if I missed it somewhere, could you briefly tell me what those one-offs were?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me start with the 21st Century new business. I think we are actually quite optimistic that this is establishing a trend. The new business volume in the month of March standalone was the highest in 18 months, and that's based on an average spend of marketing dollars, so we did not have a special campaign in marketing that would <mark type="audio gap" /> it.</p>
          <p>I think what is probably less visible for most of you is &#x2013; we call it 21st Century, but some of the legal entities locally in the U.S. still have the AIP in their name, because going through a name change procedure in the U.S. is quite a long legal procedure and customers still were a bit shy of buying the policies because this name on the policy itself. So when we have clearly completed that part of the integration, I think we have removed probably a very important hurdle to go to continue and to start growing the new business model.</p>
          <p>The 20 million one-offs was a mixture of various smaller positions. I think there was one pension curtailment gain and that was I think the biggest number. All the others were very small and scattered around the global.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Dieter, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Andrew Broadfield, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Dieter. Two questions, if I may. One, I wonder when you might be able to give us bit more of an update on how you're looking at the capital position now, what you can consider to be &#x2013; you're well capitalized, you've certainly stressed that you want to maintain what you consider to be a level where you have to start to making some decisions, or is it not a level, it's more timing, you'll consider at the yearend or what have you? Just some thoughts about the capital and what you intend, how you intend to think about it.</p>
          <p>And the second question is on this impact of the consequences of the recession of last year on top line, but also I think on claims and experience especially on workers compensation in the U.S., just how you see that working its way through this year. Have we seen all those repayments of over premium payments last year already done or is there more to come? And is that beginning to infiltrate into Europe as well into the commercial lines in Europe? And how do you see the claims impact, which tends to I think dip going into recession and then sort of bounce back out the other side as we come through it? Just what you're seeing and how you're looking at that as well, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much. Well, Andrew, first thing I have to say, we look at the capital position with great comfort. It's a very strong position. I think you have seen that statutory solvency did increased to 212%, and we have for convenience we have now also started to pro rata last year's dividends to subtract it already so that it is really like-on-like. This year end capital position and sustained with it on our economic solvency. Well, our general feelings and view have not changed. We want to run our economic solvency ratio between the 100 and 120% in mid-term.</p>
          <p>However, we think it is mainly a timing position when we go back to this. There is too much uncertainty in the market and when we were all quite positive, we have also heard from U.S. customers that they feel their revenues and businesses picking up, and then you saw last week or last days development in your financial markets, in particular in Europe. So you have really to conclude that we are still living in times of high volatility, and it is not yet the timing to go back to a capital position which is more I think for a more quiet development.</p>
          <p>The recessionary impact on the top line are continuing, in particular our first quarter commercial premium in the U.S. did still suffer from it because we are not seeing any pick up in our construction business. We have increased our market share over the last 12 months, but a bigger market share on a very small and low business volume, as the construction companies have not seen any increase in really in business.</p>
          <p>The recessionary impact is now also a bit swapping over to Europe. I am actually not surprised about it because in Europe you have less of this automatic adjustments in annual premiums of the customer, but when the customers are renewing you see the drop of revenues. And, therefore, Europe's revenues are probably a bit later in reflecting actually the core economic crisis of the year 2008 and '09. That is mainly the top line impact, so we have to wait here until we see the positive. Actually talking to our corporate customers, we are getting a bit more optimistic than we were when we presented our full year results.</p>
          <p>Now talking about the claims side, last year it was -- the picture in the U.S. a positive impact because we saw almost 4% decrease in claims frequency on workers comp, and one of the explanations is that people are really tried to go to work because they are frightened to lose their job.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, we see this year some increases in the severity of workers comp claims, but that is mainly evolving from medical inflation and probably the normal development of medical inflation less driven by recessionary impact.</p>
          <p>In Europe, I think the only point which I would probably link to recession impact is the accelerated claims farming activity in the UK. That is an old activity in the UK, but this sharp acceleration of the claims farming I think that was clearly triggered by the poor general economy, where all these service providers were just hungry for business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So -- just quickly on the claims servicing, what are you pricing in or expecting or are you indeed expecting a pick-up in frequencies, as hopefully there is some recovery in the economy? Is that something you put into your pricing right now or is it something you think doesn't really happen or how do you look at that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the pick-up in the economy is not priced in. I think we are pricing based on the latest experience, and in particular, we are always pricing for the most recent interest rate environment, which is probably for the long tail lines, a much more important driver of pricing than other elements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Charles Graham, ING. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I've got really, I guess two questions, one is to return to the general insurance businesses in Europe and to try to understand it a little bit more about the causes of the deterioration of the performance in the U.K., with the movement in the combined ratio up to 99.4%. You've mentioned personal motor and there was also the element of weather-related claims there as well.</p>
          <p>And also what action are you taking there, because it seems to be that we see deterioration after a period where you've been raising rates already quite significantly? And also within your &#x2013; can you just comment on the Rest of Europe segment, where the combined ratio went out to 107%? It seems to have had quite a negative impact.</p>
          <p>And then one other question, you give the risk weighted capital figure of 29 billion as a requirement; I assume that's net of diversification benefits. Can you give me a feel for what the undiversified capital requirement would be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let's start with the European results, U.K. personal lines overall is affected by the claims farming, as I have mentioned. So, yes, we increased in the first quarter the rates by 14% on average, but that affects, of course, only the policies which we renewed during the quarter, so there's still some months to go before have really turned around your whole portfolio on the higher rate. Plus, you are fully right; the winter in the U.K. has created additional losses for homeowners as well as some increased frequency for the motor business, which is all included in this first quarter number.</p>
          <p>Rest of Europe is driven by three countries; that is Russia, where I think we are, probably I should have mentioned this already on Andrew's question, because here we see the change in economy quite a lot and we see a sharp impact of the economic environment, with lower <mark type="inaudible" /> volumes therefore increasing expenses for running operation and also an increase in attritional losses in this environment, which we try to match with higher rates, but that is really a more inflationary environment.</p>
          <p>And in Turkey, which you see our big contributor to Rest of Europe, we had some large losses, which is nothing spectacular, only in a very small unit. It looks &#x2013; it deteriorates the ratios quite a lot.</p>
          <p>You are fully right on the RBC, the 29 billion, it's a fully diversified number and the diversification effect I think is 45% around, if you calculate from the higher to the lower number. So to calculate it backwards you have to do it on your spreadsheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question is from Michael Huttner, JPMorgan. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. Thanks a lot. Most of my questions been answered, but I had one follow-up and one on Chile. The follow-up just to make sure I understand: of the 247 million prior year development, only 217 actually benefits the P&amp;L. Thirty is immediately offset through profit commissions. And the other question is, can you explain where the Chile loss is? I was trying to look for it. I couldn't see it in your various details by country loss ratios. I mean, if I tried it I could find maybe 40 million in Latin America, 50 million in international; it's 200 million not 90; and the global corporate at 92% is so good, I couldn't think that there was any Chile in there, but maybe you could explain? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me start with the Chilean losses. So I think the 200 are broken down into 37, 38 and 125. So let's look in which boxes is which of the three numbers. The 37 million is the Global Corporate. The 38 million is with International business and 125 is under Global General Insurance because that is our in-house reinsurance division.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's not in Latin America then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Latin America has 38, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, of course, 38.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That number should add up 37 plus 38 plus 125 should work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely. Yes. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So your question on the prior year development was specifically what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. You explained the 30 million.....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is correct. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct. Okay. And then a follow-up, I'm not sure if I missed this.</p>
          <p>Effectively you're saying you are only &#x2013; what I see is, I have to see there is very strong solvency. You are very happy to stay there and there is no -- it would take a lot to make you decide that you'd be happier with a lower number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I did not say this. I said we are happy to return back to our old range of operating our solvency, but to do so I think we would expect that the macroeconomic environment is getting in a more stable situation, and we don't see this for the time being.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you very much, and I must say the results are really smooth, and it's amazing. I couldn't think of any other questions, but thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Fabrizio Croce, Kepler. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and good afternoon to all of you. Very &#x2013; two very simply actually. The first one is about Deepwater Horizon. Here the question is as we are seeing other competitor coming and spanning from zero to 800 million claims, do you also expect some claims arising from this tragedy? And the question is even if you would now say, okay, it's difficult liabilities and we have to discuss with lawyers and litigations, do you have a maximum limit which you could forecast for this claim? And how big is this maximum amount actually in terms of claim?</p>
          <p>The second one is about real estate. First of all, given that the investment rates are coming down, are there projects to invest deeper and stronger in real estate? And a second question is in terms of the SST discussion about the duration of real estate. What are the progress there or what will be your position within SST in terms of length of or the ideal duration for real estate of what will you actually apply into your SST model?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Deepwater Horizon is indeed a tragedy which will cost several billion, our people are talking about that it will be <mark type="inaudible" /> billion overall to clean it up. Fortunately, as far as we can see it at the moment, because there are several of our customers potentially involved in the loss, and then we add up all the policy maximums that could potentially involve customers and we end up with $20 million.</p>
          <p>So that is &#x2013; but that will be then one of the potential large losses being recorded in the second quarter; that is obviously not included in our first quarter numbers. We are very much &#x2013; as it comes to real estate, we are not seeing at the moment that we will go for expanding our real estate portfolio. And as it comes to the SST discussion, we are actually not in any conflict here with the FinMark] proposal. We feel actually quite fine with what FinMark has proposed for the SST and we are using it also in our internal model to calculate SST. I know that some of our Swiss competitors are having big fights about this duration of the real estate. But we have &#x2013; I think that from our perspective the FinMark position has some logic in it and we are happy to apply it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So zero year duration actually?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Jean-Francois Tremblay, RBS. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have two questions. First of all, I want to get back to the answer to you referred to Brian Shea regarding the outlook for invested assets in light of &#x2013; the lack of momentum in written premiums. You made it sound as if we could be forecasting almost negative premium growth going forward.</p>
          <p>I'm sure that doesn't fully reflect your view of the business over the medium to long term. So it would be interesting if you could elaborate, how you see the business evolving as we go through this economic cycle, which has almost result in a very difficult economic growth following the decline we're seeing. That's point number one.</p>
          <p>And then point number two, in response to Brian's question you highlighted that you could have set the potential decline in investment days by taking a bit more risks through your investment strategy, especially in the U.S. So could you elaborate on the hybrid Investments you would consider, how low or other risk or if you would be going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yeah, and maybe I was a bit conservative on our top line assumption. I think, first of all I think you have to see that we have an excellent top line growth in the Life business as well as on Farmers. These are two important segments of the group which are producing a very healthy and actually an excellent top line growth. And that really supports also our bottom line development, as I think we have less volatility out of this revenues. On the general insurance business, as I said already at the full year results, with economic outlook for Europe and the U.S. it will take some time because the insurance volumes are returning and even if you want to be very optimistic for all major markets the total market volume outlook is a small negative in the Western Hemisphere.</p>
          <p>If you go to Asia and to Latin America that is different, and also Latin American business did also grow 6% in local currency. And the reason for this is that insurance premiums are affected always a bit later than the macro economic development. So that means when 2008 was the start of the shrinking of the economy you will see that this is then affecting about 15 months delay the insurance volumes; that is what is happening for the whole market. So for ourselves, as I said, I think in particular in the large commercial business we are doing a lot to grow our business, our new business volumes are up, and we are also optimistic that the large companies will recover faster in the economic environment, and therefore we will also see coming some of the exposure growth, additional revenues.</p>
          <p>In the personnel lines market in Europe, where we had in two markets, the U.K. and Italy, really a threat to the profitability of the business. I think to follow clearly the principle and philosophy of our company, we clearly put correcting the profit margin over the top line number because out of top line we can only pay salaries when we make the profit, and also we can only pay a dividend when we made a profit. And that is clearly our focus, therefore we are not now suggesting that we will grow the top line in the next quarter too fast, but clearly as a company and from our strategy it is clearly our focus and our objective to continue to grow the top line. And I think if you go back over longer periods, we have actually grown substantially the top line in our general insurance business, and in particular we have grown the net earned premium, which is [indiscernible} revenues out of it substantially, but we will not do it based on what profitability we can achieve in the market. And with that you will see that we will also find new areas of growth over the next quarters and we will report about it when the numbers are confirming it that we are doing it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can you comment on investments and your appetite for risk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is just the percentage of corporate bonds and the overall portfolio we are not going down the risk curve and going for higher risk classes, we are &#x2013; we had last year a period where we did de-risk and did go for lower shares in corporate bonds and we are now going back and take more credit risk in this respect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you remind us your target allocation for corporate bonds?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we, specifically for this U.S. portfolio, I don't know it by heart, but I think we are happy to deliver it later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Gentlemen, that was the last question. I would now like to turn the conference back over to you Mr. Wemmer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then I can only thank you for listening in and hope to get feedback from you also on the format. It seemed to me that you are all very well prepared with your questions and had more time to go through the slides than in the past. So I take this as a very positive aspect of the new format. So thank you very much and have a nice day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference is now over. Thank you for choosing the Chorus Call facility and thank you for participating in the conference. You may now disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>