<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1326026" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-08-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2568</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Malcolm Gilbert, Head of Investor Relations &amp; Rating Agencies</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Martin Senn, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Dieter Wemmer, Chief Financial Officer and Regional Chairman of Europe and Africa</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Fabrizio Croce</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">James Quin</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Michael Huttner</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Andrew Ritchie</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep">Mario Greco</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to Zurich's Half Year 2010 results presentation. I know it's a busy day for many people. We aim to get this finished by 10:45 in order for to you to go to any other meetings and any companies that you wish to follow.</p>
          <p>So moving onto Slide Two, I just refer you to the disclaimer slide. On the agenda, we have presentations from CEO, Martin Senn and CFO, Dieter Wemmer. And then we'll move on to Q&amp; A and as I say, we'll aim to get that all wrapped up by 10:45.</p>
          <p>So with that, I hand over to Martin Senn. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Malcolm, and good morning, ladies and gentlemen. It's a pleasure to be with you here today.</p>
          <p>And I am also very pleased to present the half year of 2010 results for Zurich Financial Services. Our core businesses delivered a robust operating performance in a very challenging economic environment. General insurance posted a solid performance in the first half, protect the margins despite top line pressures due to weak demand.</p>
          <p>Global Life continues to produce top line and bottom line growth. Farmers delivered another set of high-quality results with cost discipline continuing to generate strong operating margins, while 21st Century which was acquired last year, strongly contributed to fee income.</p>
          <p>At our Investors Day in June, I announced that we aspire to be the insurance company, as measured by our customers, shareholders and employees. And this step change in our ambition reflects our confidence that we can build on a very solid base to achieve even better performance. I also outlined the process we would undertake to scrutinize our businesses, in particular, general insurance and develop detailed strategies to help us achieve our aspirations. And that work continuous and we will update you in much more detail at our next Investor Day, which is scheduled for December the 2nd, later on this year.</p>
          <p>In the meantime, our core businesses continue to perform well. In general insurance, the economic realities in most of our markets mean we have seen some further top-line reduction as we have continued to focus on writing profitable business, leveraging our geographical diversification and strict underwriting standards. The greatest pressure is in new business. Across our existing portfolio, we are seeing strong retention right and positive underlying trends as our ongoing rate increases the feed-through.</p>
          <p>In particular, the trends in the underlying loss ratio are very encouraging at this stage of the cycle. Global Life new business value continued to grow strongly in local currencies following two years of double-digit growth. And this was driven by both top-line and margin, as we continued to execute our successful distribution and proposition-oriented strategy. Global Life also benefited, naturally, from the recovery in global financial markets.</p>
          <p>And Farmers continued to perform very well, with continuing strong operating margins and aided by fully leveraging the 21st Century acquisition, strong growth in fee income. This acquisition is performing well &#x2013; I should say very well, with efficient integration, strong trends in recovering volume and good profitability The multi-channel distribution strategy in the U.S. personal lines business is developing well.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet position remains exceptionally strong. Holding a high level of capital clearly effects return on equity, but we believe this is the prudent course in these times of continued economic uncertainty.</p>
          <p>Let me summarize. Our first half results underscore our continued focus on profit margin operating efficiency and risk management. Despite the impact of the challenging economic environment, we have continued to achieve a solid operating performance in our general insurance business, generated strong gross in Global Life and Farmers successfully integrated a strategic acquisition.</p>
          <p>Finally, we have taken a number of steps to de-risk our non-core businesses and reduce their effects on the group. Thank you very much and I will now turn over to Dieter Wemmer. He will take you through the financial results in more detail. Thank you. Enjoy the presentation, Dieter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much, Martin.</p>
          <p>So then let's go into the details. So I think Martin introduced this actually very carefully with that we finish exactly in time at quarter to 11. He moved the meeting to the Insurance Mile instead of using our development center. That way, it's a little bit shorter this morning for the next meeting.</p>
          <p>Okay, good morning, ladies and gentlemen. The operating performance for the half year 2010 is the result in the end of a continuing story of previous quarter's strong performance in the core businesses, impacted by the Chilean earthquake in the first quarter. In the non-core business, we continue to de-risk the portfolio, we implemented dynamic hedging in the first quarter on our run-off Life portfolio and we took a banking provision in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>The core businesses are actually performing well. If we calculate the business operating after-tax ROE, our key measurement for these businesses only, it is 15.3% and this is already including a charge or reduction of 1.2% caused by the Chilean earthquake.</p>
          <p>So let's now look in more detail on our core business, starting with general insurance. The effect of the earned rate increases is continue to compensate for lost investment yield. The decrease is actually, as I said, mainly attributable to both to the Chilean earthquake and also higher occurrence of weather related losses globally actually in the whole six months. So our technical pricing, we continue to target consistent levels of profitability and we have also not changed our profitability targets.</p>
          <p>Global Life delivered a strong half year result, increasing 12% above prior year. The result benefited from our continued focus on expense discipline and our move to protection business, but also, we have to say the recovery of the financial market helped. Farmers, again, a strong first half 17% increase in operating profit mainly driven by higher fees coming from the acquisition Martin has already mentioned. So it's the 21st Century integration, but also really continued cost discipline.</p>
          <p>Farmers Re contributed strongly year-over-year, also having been affected heavily actually in particular in May by weather-related events. Overall, this reflects the improved result of the exchanges, as I have always to remember you, which we manage but do not own.</p>
          <p>As the operating business charges increased, reflecting more normalized run rate compare to prior year, where last year we benefited from a one-off buyback of our own hybrid debt. Non-core businesses result of half year includes the increase in the banking loan provision of 330 million as we have already previously announced.</p>
          <p>So now let's turn to the individual business segment, Slide Eight for the audience on the floor. General insurance delivered a solid operating performance based on the group's strategy to protect profitability. As a result of our margin focus and still lower economic activity in many markets, as displayed in low levels of new car sales or depressed construction activity, for example, gross written premium have reduced 4% in local currency.</p>
          <p>Looking at the success of our individual business divisions, global corporate achieved average rate increases of 2% and increased customer retention, although top-line decreased by 2% in local currency. In the U.S., the division's continued focus on profitable customer relationships led to an increase in retention, but new business levels remains depressed. At the same time, our expansion in Asia and Middle East, as well as higher new business in Europe largely compensated for this.</p>
          <p>North America commercial insured customer exposure was mostly flat, with a TWP decline of 2% in the second quart, although retention rates have improved 3%. This means in the second quarter, we have seen a significant improvement over the experience in top-line over recent quarters.</p>
          <p>Our focus on risk selection, underwriting execution and our quartiling strategy is integral to determine rate adequacy by individual accounts. So loss of accounts targeted with the highest rate increases would not show up in the rate change monitor, but their absence obviously will improve profitability in the portfolio.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we accepted modest rate reductions on the most profitable accounts. Overall, for North America commercial, this makes a small rate decrease of 1%. As a result of the relative mix shift towards more attractively priced accounts, the overall profitability of the portfolio was maintained.</p>
          <p>Looking at Europe in general, insurance premium reduced by 6% in local currency, even though we have achieved rate increases, particular in the U.K., Italy and Spain. The personal lines business continues to operate in a very competitive market environment, with premium retention levels up but with subdued levels of new business.</p>
          <p>Our commercial lines business retentions are broadly flat. However, premiums were affected by reduced new business volumes and lower economic activity of our customers with the recessionary impact hitting Europe's insurance industry lagging that of the U.S.</p>
          <p>International markets increased 6% in local currency, with underlying growth in Latin America of 8% as well as from rate increases in Australia. For the total general insurance book, reported business operating profit decreased by 337 million or 19% in local currency to $1.4 billion. The main drivers were a higher level of event and weather-related losses, including the $200 million from the Chilean earthquake already booked in Q1 and lower levels of investment income.</p>
          <p>So now let's in more detail at our &#x2013; look at our rate change monitor. As said before, general insurance rates are up by 2%. The average rate increases and let me stress this, comes on top of a similar increase a year ago and therefore compounds the prior year increases. This is a great achievement in the market where many players have continued or continue to focus on only market share and indicates that our margin protection effort through differentiated weight increases are succeeding.</p>
          <p>If you look in to the details, we see the distribution of these rate increases across the different portfolios show actually a pretty similar pattern as the first quarter 2010. Rate increases in North America have continued to moderate in the first half 2010. This should not come as a surprise, as we started our dedicated rate initiatives already in the last quarter 2008.</p>
          <p>And this compounds over the achievements in 2009 and have achieved the key objective to compensate for lower investment income. However, this is in contrast to personal lines, where rate increases have continued to stay high for the last three quarters. At the same time, commercial and corporate lines in Europe saw similar rate increases as in the first quarter. Increases are at a healthy level and should support the profitability of that really attractive part of our business.</p>
          <p>The reason for high level rate increases in European personal lines remains the same. We have seen market-wide deterioration in motor portfolios in certain countries. As already discussed before, the push for additional rate here is one element of the mitigating actions taken to counter these effects. As a result, the highest rate increases were put through in the U.K. and Italy. The loss development in Italy appears to have bottomed out in the first quarter and is continuing to show further signs of improvement, while the U.K. personal lines market remains a challenge. Both markets continue to be management focus areas for 2010.</p>
          <p>With that, let's look at the loss ratio in more detail on Slide 10. Year-over-year, large claims increased by 0.4 percentage points. The major catastrophe of 200 million or 1.5 percentage points was the earthquake in Chile already reported in Q1, and we have not changed the estimate for this claim in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Reserve releases were about 180 million higher, but include about 100 million of the leases which were linked to adjustable premiums returned to U.S. customers, and hence did actually not hit the bottom line. As a result, half year 2010 underlying loss ratio stayed largely flat year-over-year at 66.4%. This shows the improving trend in the bulk of the book, taking into account the worst winter weather in Europe and part of the U.S., as well as the negative effects of personal line motor books in certain European countries, such as the UK and Italy and to a smaller extent, Russia.</p>
          <p>In other words, without these two effects, the underlying loss ratio would have improved nicely. And this is what you would expect. The prior year rate increases taken to offset lower investment income are earning in. Our broad diversification of risk means that we have been able to achieve good results in spite of these exceptional events.</p>
          <p>Let's turn now the expense ratio. The increase in the expense ratio is largely due to lower net earned premiums resulting from lower business volumes, the returned premiums I mentioned, and also reinstatement premiums following the earthquake in Chile paid to our reinsurers. As such, it is a situation we have expected to see, although we continue to work on managing our expenses.</p>
          <p>You can see the other underwriting expense ratio is up one percentage point. In terms of local currency amounts, these expenses remained flat. We continue to focus on expense, an example being the reduction of total head count in general insurance by 4% compared to year ago. In addition, we continued investments in profitable growth, for example, in our global corporate business in Asia and in Middle East, as well as the operational improvements as part of Zurich Way globally.</p>
          <p>The commission ratio increased 0.3 percentage points, driven actually by a change in reinsurance structure and some higher profit-related commissions paid on low 2009 loss ratios in crop insurance in North America commercial, as already reported in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>As we enter the Atlantic hurricane season, let's have a look at our reinsurance program. As you know, officially, the season started June 1, and therefore, I will give you an update on how we protect ourselves for reinsurance. The structure of the program is similar as reported to you a year ago.</p>
          <p>It is worth pointing out that we retain part of the risk through co-participation in several covers, the striped areas in the chart. We have said repeatedly that we want to allocate our capital as much as economically sensible to our primary insurance businesses. Reducing reinsurance cover is a flexible and efficient way to achieve it.</p>
          <p>To do so, we have not increased attachment points of the co-participation rates, but the co-participation rates. As such, we have increased the overall co-participation from below 20% to 36% for the U.S. cover and to 39% for the European cover. In addition, we now co-reinsure 55% of the global aggregate cover. This development is in line with our stance on retention in other areas of our reinsurance strategy, where we have also reduced protection where it makes sense on an economic basis.</p>
          <p>A clarification worth making is around a component of our U.S. cat cover. This year, we have again agreed to risk swap with a major Japanese carrier. We have assumed a risk of $100 million cover for Japanese typhoon. In exchange, we received a corresponding cover for U.S. windstorm.</p>
          <p>So this concludes actually the general insurance part, and now let's move to Global Life in more detail on slide 13.</p>
          <p>In Global Life, the trends seen in the first quarter were largely continued in the second quarter and resulted in a really satisfactory half-year result. Strong growth in single premium business contributed to an increase in gross written premiums, policy fees and deposits, up 12% in local currency and also benefiting net inflows, which reached $3 billion in the first half, a 77% increase over the previous period.</p>
          <p>As the new business margin improved by 1.8 percentage points to 22.8%, the new business value reached $392 million, an increase of 17% in local currency. The new business volumes increased by 8% in local currency terms and reached 1.7 billion. Strong growth in Ireland, being up 57% overall with domestic sales up 30%, driven by long-term saving products, and cross-border sales increasing from 2 million last year to 59 million this year. Growth in the U.K. and Latin America more than compensated for a decline in Spain, posting lower sales of short-term saving products in a highly competitive market.</p>
          <p>The embedded value operating earnings were $0.08 billion, benefiting from the strong new business value, while the expected contribution continues to be depressed by low yield levels. In total, embedded value operating return was 9.5% for the half year. Business operating profit also increased by 12%, both in U.S. dollar and local terms, actually to 720 million. I will discuss the business operating profit in more detail in a minute when looking at our updated profit by source analysis.</p>
          <p>Looking at new business by pillar, the picture is broadly inline with what we have reported in the first quarter. There, we have strong new business value increases in local currency, in bank distribution, IFA/Broker and the corporate life and pension pillar, which were partially offset by the agent pillar.</p>
          <p>The increase in bank distribution was mainly driven by margin improvements in Germany and Spain, as well as higher sales in Italy. The increased in IFA/Broker was driven by substantially higher volume of cross-boarder business from Ireland into Italy. Corporate life and pension benefited from increased pension sales in the U.K. and also again, in Ireland. The drop in Asian pillars is largely driven by the impact of U.S. interest rates depressing the margin for protection business.</p>
          <p>Coming back to the business operating profit of the Life business, we continued to develop the profit by source analysis to provide better insight into our life business operating profit. As shown here on this very busy slide, we have separated the result between the new business and the in-force book.</p>
          <p>In addition, we have shown separately the impact of acquisition deferrals and also any special operating items. Special operating items are material items includes in the result which do not regularly occur. I will focus on the three key margins of expense, risk and investment, along with the impact of the acquisition deferrals. Overall, the Global Life business operating profit of 720 million increased 12%, as I said, mainly driven by the business in force with a lower level of new business cost impacting the profit.</p>
          <p>While this is not a pure cash view, you can see from this slide that Global Life is well positioned to fund its gross new business cost from the in-force business. Looking into the detail of the business in-force, the expense margin has increased 3% in local currency, benefiting from higher fund-based fee due to higher average stock market level compared to a year ago and focused on expense management in all territories.</p>
          <p>So gross margin has improved 1% in local currency as a result of both increased volumes and favorable experience, mainly in Latin America. These uplifts were partially offset by a reduction in Switzerland due to lower volumes of individual protection business.</p>
          <p>The investment margin has improved 12% in local currency, mainly as the result of foreign exchange gains and interest rate movement on spread products. The interest, depreciation, amortization and non-controlling interest line shown an increase primarily due to changes in assumption impacting the amortization rate.</p>
          <p>Moving to the impact of new business, the expense margin and the related impact of deferrals have increased in line with the growth of new business and the effect of product mix being sold that impacts front-end fees, commissions and the proportion of costs that can be deferrals. You'll find actually more details in the appendix regarding this type of analysis.</p>
          <p>Now let's move to our third segment, Farmers. Again, Farmers has produced a high quality set of results which combine growth and profitability. Starting with the management company, the margin on gross earned premiums remained strong at an excellent 7.4%, as we continue to manage our expenses through various initiatives.</p>
          <p>BOP has increased by 8% to 694 million, resulting from a higher top-line at the exchanges driven by the acquired 21st Century business. In the first half 2010, 21st Century added almost 180 million to management fee and over 80 million to operating profit at the management company level, as well as over 1 billion to premiums at the exchanges. I will update you on the transaction in a minute and you can find even more financial information on 21st Century in the appendix.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Farmers Re. Farmers Re's gross written premiums have been affected by changes in the level of participation in the Quota Share treaties in both years. As of June 30, 2009, the participation was increased from 25% to 37.5, while at end of June 2010, the participation was decreased back to 25%, the level prior to the 21st Century acquisition and I think also underlining that we have closed the integration and financing of the 21st Century acquisition.</p>
          <p>The change in participation have caused a transfer of unearned premiums in and out of back in-force, which has impacted gross written premiums accounting-wise. As a result of the underlying growth in earned premiums, a better underwriting result and higher investment income, operating profit at Farmers Re increased by 151 million. Still, after a benign first quarter, the second quarter was very heavy in terms of the catastrophes.</p>
          <p>The Farmers exchanges, which we manage but do not own, have maintained their strong growth track record which started back in 2006. Gross written premium increased by 9%. Excluding the acquisition, the exchange's top line would have reduced by 3% overall in a contracting market largely driven by the auto book, a result of the difficult economic environment in the U.S. and also competitive pressure.</p>
          <p>The headline combined ratio is 98.6%, a 1.2 percentage point improvement over last year. This improvement is driven by favorable loss trends in auto and homeowners as well as rate increases earning through.</p>
          <p>Although the impact of natural catastrophes is similar year-over-year, the second quarter of 2010 was particularly strongly hit with tornados, wind and hail storms in Oklahoma, Colorado and Montana that all happened in May and did cost us almost $400 million on an exchange level. That means 35% of it did hit our Farmers fee account.</p>
          <p>Net surplus increased by an estimated 103 million. As the result of the lower quota share, the surplus ratio decreased to 41.7%, a level which we still consider to be very strong and if I am not mistaken, it is the second highest surplus ratio we have ever showed in the past years.</p>
          <p>So moving on now to Page 17 and more details on 21st Century. The acquisition has been included in Zurich's and the exchange's results now exactly for 12 months. Following a period for 2009 where lapses were bigger than new business, we have seen continuous improvement in 2010 to a point where this gap is almost closed.</p>
          <p>Monthly renewal rates have increased throughout the first six months 2010 and have recovered when compared to 2009. Now they are up to comparable levels to 2008 level. Even more encouraging is that new business numbers continue to increased strongly and are up 42% year-over-year, the highest level in the past 18 months and July confirms this trend of accelerated growth.</p>
          <p>Premiums in the agency auto business continued to reduce, as this book has been folded into Farmers or the exchange's foremost operations so that less and less of this business is written on 21st Century paper.</p>
          <p>I would also like to point out that 21st Century's quarterly combined ratio has continuously improved over the past three years and has now stabilized at 97.5%. This already reflects some of the benefits from the integration, which continues to show rapid progress and is clearly ahead of schedule. To sum up, the acquisition has been very successful. I am pleased to confirm that the whole transaction has been accretive to earnings per share in year one when allowing for the initial restructuring cost in the third quarter 2009.</p>
          <p>If you were to factor in that the deal absorbed effectively less capital than initially planned, as volumes were lower, earnings accretion would even be better. As capital commitment to the transaction reduces with the reduction in the quota share participation, accretion improves further over time.</p>
          <p>Turning to the other operating and non-core businesses. Other operating businesses includes net corporate center expenses, external debt cost, some central foreign exchange adjustments and the result for alternative investments. Absent the 2009 positive one-offs, the half-year result for holding and finance represents a more normalized run rate of interest expense under the current debt structure. The non-core businesses segment result was impacted by a one-off charge in financial market volatility, although, as I said earlier, we took a number of de-risking actions.</p>
          <p> Center's book held at fair value was impacted by volatilities in the market affecting the mismatch of assets and liabilities. Banking activities, consisting of Tunga bank and Zurich Bank in Ireland, includes the previously announced increase in loan provisions of $330 million.</p>
          <p>We have increased the reserving level of our Irish loan now to 50% of the total loan book, of which 75% are specific case reserves and 25% are general IBNR-type reserves. The $1.9 billion loan book in the UK is now reserved at 18%, where two-thirds are specific case reserves and one-third are general provisions. We were in discussions to dispose of this book earlier this year, but have now decided that the economic environment means that managing the one-off ourselves will produce a better financial outcome.</p>
          <p>As the demand for new commercial properties stays low, we decided to move to a more conservative outlook for the underlying valuations of our mortgage portfolio, for example, reducing the land value for not-yet-finished properties materially. Centrally managed businesses showed a significant improvement compared with the financial market-driven loss in half year 2009.</p>
          <p>As we announced in March, we have implemented a dynamic hedge on the Kemper Life variable annuity portfolio and have changed the accounting on that portfolio to fair value. That's over presenting the economic movements in the account. So that is performing exactly as expected. We did not hedge market volatility as such, which will create some movement in the quarterly results, but we expect that this will average out over time.</p>
          <p>Moving to our investments. Net investment income decreased by 5% in dollar terms and 6% in local currency, driven by cash balances yielding lower rates and lower income from debt securities. Net capital gains for P&amp;L were $418 million, despite impairments totaling $763 million. These impairments include the $330 million of loan provision for the banking provision mentioned before, with the balance largely taken on equity driven by the 24-month payment rule. This will require equity securities to be impaired when their fair value has been below the weighted average costs for a period of 24 months.</p>
          <p>Net unrealized gains increased by $2.8 billion driven by gains on debt securities, reflecting lower interest rates, with equity and other investment remaining broadly flat. The large part of the increase in unrealized gains were experienced in the first quarter, with the second quarter adding another 0.7 billion due to lower government bond yields.</p>
          <p>Turning to Page 20 to the development of shareholders' equity. The balance sheet remains very strong. Shareholders' equity at 28.5 billion was a reduction of 800 million from the restated opening balance after deducting of $2.2 billion of dividend payment. The other movements were a net positive of 1.4 billion. Net income attributable to shareholders of 1.6 billion was after an effective tax rate of 23.2%.</p>
          <p>Let me remind you that although this net income is down year-on-year, the prior year includes the restatement we have previously announced. Without the restatement, we would have shown an increase against the $1.3 billion of net income which was actually published 12 months ago. Unrealized gains attributable to shareholders of 1.6 billion were largely, as I mentioned, from bond revaluation due to lower interest straits. They were counteracted by a negative cumulative translation adjustment, this is a number driven by foreign currency movements, and net actuarial losses on pension plans.</p>
          <p>The book value per share has further increased this year to almost CHF208 and this is after having paid the CHF16 dividend and after deducting CHF8 for foreign exchange movements, which reduced our book value.</p>
          <p>Now let's move to the Solvency considerations. Our Solvency I ratio has further increased to 232%. Included in the increase is an adjustment which has been discussed with the Swiss regulator in second quarter. It is in connection with the required capital we hold for financial companies and has benefited the ratio by 10 percentage points.</p>
          <p>Foreign currency movements have positively affected the required Solvency capital and the Solvency I calculation. Seven percentage points of the increase in the quarter relates to this effect and is particularly pronounced in the Life business. In addition, the Solvency I ratio reflects a lower top line in non-life, which reduced the required capital, resulting in a three percentage point increase.</p>
          <p>Moving now to our internal economic Solvency model on the right side of the slide, this has reduced through the quarter and is at 124%, reflecting lower available financial resources, what we call AFR. This decrease resulted from currency &#x2013; foreign currency movements, which had a stronger impact on our AFR than on our RBC figure.</p>
          <p>Interest rate decreases in the second quarter have contributed to the reduction in AFR. In contrast to the Solvency I calculation, falling interest rates affect both sides of the economic balance sheet. For liabilities, this leads to a lower discount effect on our general insurance liabilities as well as a lower value in-force of our Life business, which means lower AFR.</p>
          <p>We continue to accrue for dividends, both in our economic solvency and the Solvency I calculation. The dividend accrual for the 2010 dividend in proportion to the 2009 dividend is, I should stress here, is not an obligation to pay any particular amount. The dividend proposed to the HM will be a decision of the board next February.</p>
          <p>We are very comfortable with the surplus position close to our 110 to 120% target range for economic solvency, as we remain cautious of external factors which we cannot control. As you know, you can expect more volatility from an economic solvency calculation by its nature, whether it be an internal model, Swiss Solvency test or future Solvency II calculations.</p>
          <p>As part of the simplification of our legal entity structure across Europe, we have received all the regulatory and court clearance for our main German general insurance carrier to be transfer to Ireland. This is the last significant general insurance business based in the EU to be transferred to our Irish general insurance carrier under our major program to simplify cash and liquidity management and improve the fungibility of our capital.</p>
          <p>And finally, we are pleased that ISP has recently released the IFRS for Phase II exposure draft. We will performing an impact study similar to the QIS studies on Solvency II and along with the members of the CFO forum, we will assessing the impact of these proposed accounting changes. And with that, I hand over to Malcolm for the Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Dieter. Usual rules, we'll start in the room, then we'll move to the calls. Could I have anybody who'd like to ask a question in the room. Probably two. Could we have &#x2013; each time, could you just wait for the microphone and give your organization, please, so that we all know who is speaking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fabrizio Croce, Kepler. I have just two question.</p>
          <p>The first one is about growth. Growth was actually very weak in the quarter, so minus 14%. And thinking to how well the integration of 21st Century went, and how cheap some assets are currently, would the non-organic growth actually not &#x2013; would it actually not be an option or in the mass?</p>
          <p>The second question is about the bank distribution APE, which decreased some 18%. My question is, is  this stress on the APE related to Spain and therefore, could this trigger a goodwill impairment or is this independent?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start maybe with the first question and Dieter might add to it or just take then second question. Your question on our growth level said that the opportunity to pursue broader and organic growth to accelerate overall growth. This is something we have always considered in the past. We will consider any M&amp;A opportunity as well in the future. I don't want to becomes specific, clearly not and not deviating as well from our principle on giving any guidance.</p>
          <p>But what I should stress is as well that we will not sort of soften on our discipline and how we look at any unorganic opportunities with regards to the hurdles these or any acquisition has to meet. And from that point of view, there is no change in policy as we have pursued it in the past. You're probably reflecting a little bit as well as the temptations, as there are clearly increased opportunities in the marketplace and eventually, these opportunities will continue to increase. But we will not give up on the disciplined approached we have pursued in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I should comment on the bank distribution question. Your assumption is fully right. The reduction in APE is mainly in Spain. But the big however is, we have changed our business mix substantially and when you look at the other KPI in the same line, you will see that actually the new business value generated out of the bank distribution increased 31%. So it's really a smaller volume, but substantially higher profitability and with this new business value, we are clearly ahead of our business plan and that also means we are more away from any goodwill impairment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we will take two more questions from the room before we move to the telephone. Stefan Zeti?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just two questions. One is a detailed one on non-life. I just saw in second quarter that the rest of Europe and Africa was down a quite a bit on top-line and the claims ratio was up, I think 13 points in half year. Could you maybe just give some details, this really happened in geographic terms and maybe why? And the second point on the Swiss solvency test, is there any update you can give us on approval of internal model and the overall discussion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the second part and the Swiss Solvency test. The Swiss Solvency test will become effective beginning of next year. We have been running a pilot now for couple of years, I think since 2006. We are very comfortable with the current proposals and as such, will fully comply and implement the current proposal by the FinMark. As such, there's no further update. We are very comfortable as well with the Solvency ratios, as we have strong Solvency I and a strong internal solvency, i.e. our economic solvency. We also have strong solvency inline with the Swiss Solvency test.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I pick up from here, Stefan, the internal model sign office has not yet progressed further. I think that will be probably getting more towards the end of this year. I think that's more &#x2013; that there are so many models have in &#x2013; to be signed of parallel. Your observation on rest of Europe and Africa, I think I indicated it a bit in my speech and was referring to Russia. That is included in this figure, where we have reduced volume and also have seen increased loss ratio and also South Africa has shown a deterioration in the loss ratio as well as a reduction in volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Any other questions in the room? On the right over here before we move to the telephone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Just one on the investment policy. How long can you stand such a low interest phase and how do you prepare for possible inflation? Second question, the savings you make on centralizing your PC business Ireland in terms of capital and of operating expense, could you put a figure to that and could you tell us how far are your preparations for the centralization of Life businesses across the EU have progressed?</p>
          <p>Are you happy with your share price? I mean, you trade above book, which can't be said for many insurers, but is that enough for you? And finally, you mentioned your price &#x2013; your rate monitoring. Looking at the German commercial market, I find that you are very good at keeping up prices, but price yourself out of many businesses. So how long it will continue to give up business for rates' sake and sort of be marginalized in many projects?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Frohman. Good morning. This is a basket of good questions. So I will start and then I'm sure Dieter will add some additional flavor or salt and pepper to it. First, your question on low interest environment, it's a clear challenge we are facing. Yet we are, as it stands, comfortable in the sense that our investment policy to truly match our assets with liabilities, i.e. be liability-driven and not make any consideration in terms of trying to outsmart the market as we move forward has paid off in the past and I think will continue to pay off in the future.</p>
          <p>Clearly, we are affected in our underlying performance due to lower investment yields. Yet it is our task in terms of how we manage the firm to counteract against that as much as possible. I should also stress that on the liability side, particularly in our Life portfolio, this part of our core strategy to sort of pursue low capital or other commission-based products and therefore, do not take an accumulation of guarantees and liabilities which are difficult to match with assets, particularly in this market environment. We are exposed to low rates, clearly, but with regards to investment policy, we feel pretty comfortable now that the portfolio is managed and we will not deviate from this policy moving forward.</p>
          <p>Inflation, I do not see any inflation as it stands. I think the market rather direct into a scenario where rates are going to remain low. Should we see inflation coming back into the marketplace, that's always something you'll have to deal with and we will deal with as these challenges will then appear.</p>
          <p>Let me jump quickly to your question on the share price. Are we happy with the share price? The market is always right. The market is what dictates the share price and as such, we believe in a reasonable efficient marketplace, yet we want to have a higher share price for Zurich and it's our task to develop a strategy and execute a strategy along the lines to get the maximum share price as possible for our shareholders and obviously do that in a consideration as well to look at the interest of the other stakeholders., i.e. have a balanced risk adjusted approach.</p>
          <p>With regards to price book, on the share price, we feel relatively good, relatively good because we are clearly at the upper end compared to other insurance companies globally. So from that point of view, we are relatively okay, but the sector as such and the sector overall has been suffering quite for some time now with relatively low consideration. I think the reasons for that, there are multiple of reasons. It is the rate environment, the interest rate environment. It is the cycle of the industry we are in. It is the changes in regulation and the uncertainty with that, particularly the uncertainty of the economic cost of regulation, et cetera, et cetera and that is what is affecting this sector as the whole. Overall, on relative terms, we feel comfortable, but we have to work hard and harder to get better multiples in place. I think there, I want to hand over to Dieter on the questions on Ireland and also on the rate monitoring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me address first at on the low yield environment, I think Martin has addressed, he mentioned the life liabilities. On the general insurance side, that is, of course, less of a question but in general insurance, I think it is our obligation to price in the low yield environment in our technical price and the rates we ask from our customers. And insurers who are not yet doing this, they might get more volume at the moment because they are ignoring economic reality, but will pay for it in the future and that is not our business philosophy.</p>
          <p>On the Octopus &#x2013; sorry, on the moving as a business to Life, that is our internal project name. So the general insurance side, we have completed with the transfer now of Germany which is taking place I think formally in the next two weeks. On the Life side, we have not announced a similar program and that is also a much more complicated story and therefore, it's mainly on the general insurance side where we clearly benefiting from this. I could give you a number, but I don't do it.</p>
          <p>So I think that is probably covering &#x2013; okay, well, I think we are never talking about the internal liquidity and the capital needs on a local basis. I think that actually and the benefits will increase with the implementation of Solvency II. The main swath of this project was really to be prepared for Solvency II, because the branch network will get a completely different treatment in the capital requirement as it will stand for the time being. And then you have 16 isolated legal entities of small, medium and large size in the mixture. And that number, we will therefore also finally only know when we have the final Solvency II calculations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so if we move on to question from the telephone, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question from the telephone is from Mr. James Quin, Citigroup. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. I've got three question on the U.S. and global corporate businesses, please.</p>
          <p>The first one is, I just wondered if you could let us know, are there any major reserve releases in the first half numbers? And the second question &#x2013; you don't necessarily need to break it out specifically, but if you can just give us an indication what the current accident year combined ratio would be?</p>
          <p>And second question is just on the margins in the U.S. against technical levels. Obviously, you have a 1% margin decline in the first half, which has slipped a little bit. But I wonder if you could give us a sense of where the business is you are writing today versus what you see at the technical level?</p>
          <p>And the third question, which sort of follows on from that, I wonder if you could split the 1% rate decline between pure price and what do you expect as your changing place there? Thank You.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, the connection was very difficult to understand. What was the specific write-down question on the reserve releases? I couldn't catch the first few words.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, let me try and be a little clearer. I wonder if you could give us a sense of what the accident year combined ratio is for the U.S. corporate business and for global corporate. Obviously the reported numbers look fine, but I suppose there is a suspicion that they are being propped up by a high level of reserve releases.</p>
          <p>And the second question is just around the margins in the U.S., again, at your technical levels. You could give us a sense of where they are in light of the &#x2013; obviously the 1% rate decline doesn't make a big difference. But if you could give us a sense of how much you would see yourself above your technical level?</p>
          <p>And the third question is just around the 1% decline in rate in U.S. corporate. If you could give us a sense of how that's split between pure price and also change in what you have plugged in for claims cost changes? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Indeed, a very detailed question. I think with the write-down of the reserve releases, we have probably to come back to you because that is not even in the normal numbers we prepare for the half year. That is the next level of an analysis. So I can't tell you what Global Corporate in the U.S. has in this reserve releases in the U.S.</p>
          <p>So the margin decline 1% rate is a result of the renewal of all the policies taken in the six months. So it is not a &#x2013; to break it down in to the two factors you have asked for is a very artificial calculation, because in the end, the rate movement is the result of the negotiation on each renewal.</p>
          <p>So we are achieving nice rate increases on the worst quartile of our portfolio, where we have the highest need. Then there is a middle group where renewals are fairly flat. And on the best profitability product or policies, there is, of course, more competition, and we have given away some of the profit margin.</p>
          <p>And all these actions together result in a minus 1% over many different product lines, regions and portfolios. So now to describe this in two numbers, that would be, for me, a bit artificial to break it down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I can just come back with a &#x2013; on a more simplistic level. Do you have any &#x2013; is there any real change in claims costs plugged into the way you're pricing business? And secondly, are there any major releases in either U.S. or Global Corporate in the first half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we are updating for each product line, also in line when we recalculate the required reserves, the claims trends.</p>
          <p>And certainly there is an uplift in certain parts of the worker's comp business in the U.S. I think we talked about it already in the first quarter, and the second quarter has reconfirmed the trend. So in these areas, we see increases. In other, it is probably more flat.</p>
          <p>We don't see an overall sharp increase in the claims environment. I think we are all still benefiting also from the low general inflation and then overall low claims inflation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and on the reserve releases, I know you don't want to give us hard numbers. But is there any &#x2013; in the past, you didn't have any reserve releases in the U.S. business. I was just wondering if that's still the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have some reserve releases in the U.S., also in the global corporate business, also in global corporate in Europe, but it is strongly driven actually by the settlement of larger losses, where booked case reserves were higher than the final settlement amounts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could we take the next question then, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Michael Huttner of JPMorgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fantastic, thank you very much. Just a couple of questions.</p>
          <p>One is in the way you do the 66.4% calculation for the loss ratio, and you show the 332 million figure &#x2013; sorry, the 332 is the second quarter figure. I can't remember the first quarter. It's 247, I think. So you showed a total figure of about 500 million for prior year development. And you say you don't adjust for it, but you do there, as I got it. I mean you included the 100 million, so I got a bit confused there whether you did or didn't adjust or one should or shouldn't. And I just wondered if you could explain that in more detail?</p>
          <p>And then this dynamic hedge thing, how much was the actual benefit in Q2 which appears in this line, other other? I know you said it's in line, but I just wonder if you could give us a profit? Thank you. Yes, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So maybe I have not explained well the 100 million.</p>
          <p>When you take our total reserve release number of 579 for the second quarter, this number includes 100 million of IBNRs which were released because the underlying business, so the premium, was paid back to the customer.</p>
          <p>So it is still included in this line. It has nothing to do with the underlying loss ratio calculation. That is a completely separate one, because that was premium booked last year, reserve attached to this premium booked, and then when you do your premium audit and economic activity of your customer, it's smaller than originally anticipated or projected. So they get just the premium back based on the formula and the contract, and then you don't need to reserve anymore for this premium. That is a simple process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the only reason I asked &#x2013; so I understand. So effectively you are saying the 100 million disappears from both premiums and claims. But okay, that's fine.</p>
          <p>But I still get a little bit confused. Why should it &#x2013; okay, I'll ask offline, because I understand &#x2013; I don't understand why it should appear on slide 16 &#x2013; on slide 10 at all, then, because &#x2013; I'll ask offline, I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because it is a P&amp;L line, and when you release last year's IBNR, it is technically a prior year reserve release.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sorry. Yes, I was stupid. Thanks for explaining that. Thank you. And the hedging?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The hedging &#x2013; the dynamic hedge in the second quarter did still cost us around $50 million, because market volatility widened in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>We are hedging all other Greek letters, but not market volatility as such. And therefore, when volatility is widening, we are booking a loss, how the calculation of all the derivatives are working. So if market volatility comes back to normal, then you get actually this loss back as a profit.</p>
          <p>And we have decided to do so, because we don't see a one-direction movement of market volatility. That is something which has widened which is narrowing, and therefore it is not worthwhile to spend money on hedging it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So if I'd adjusted for that, your profit would have been a bit higher, if the volatility hadn't been changed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But, if  &#x2013; when we would have not done the hedging at all, then we would have shown a quite good loss in the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So can we take another question from the telephone, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. William Morgan with Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Yes, I just have one question relating again to Slide 10.</p>
          <p>If we adjust for the impact of the 100 million that you say we should exclude from the analysis, then I guess that's about 0.7% impact year-on-year, which would suggest that you've had only about a 60 basis points improvement in your underlying loss ratio year-on-year. Two question related to that.</p>
          <p>The first one is, I think you may have mentioned that was another impact there that would have made the underlying look even better. I was just wondering if you remind me what it was, because I missed it?</p>
          <p>The second thing is, do you think this move is really indicative that you are being able to price your business for lower levels of interest rates? Because the size of the move in the underlying loss ratio doesn't appear to be fully offsetting the impact of lower yields from where I sit, but I was just wondering if you could comment on that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think that the underlying loss ratio in all our efforts to increase rates is not affected by what you have just mentioned, because this number did also affect the net earned premium. So when you take it out here the 100 million, you have actually to add back 130 million to the net earned premium to do the whole calculation.</p>
          <p>I think how I would present what really happened is that weather-related losses, which were manyfold during the last six months, or the first six months of the year, actually created a lot of loss frequency, which is not touching catastrophes or the large loss line. So therefore we had really an unusually heavy six months, as I mentioned before. And also, the increased loss loads in personal lines auto, U.K. and Italy actually substantially affected the un-attritional loss ratio.</p>
          <p>So if we are now working on these two areas, and when you would exclude actually Italy personal lines and U.K. personal lines from all the rest and do then the year on year comparison, you would actually see a very nice effect of our rate activity, which is, as we said, compensating for the lost yield.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you think that if we were therefore to kind of index the cumulative effect of all your rate changes over the last year or so, that actually the impact that we would expect to see on the loss ratio is in fact broadly reflective of what is going on underlying, as you've just suggested?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think we are conservatively presenting this attritional loss ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there any more questions from the room before I go back to the telephone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you just wait for the microphone, then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />. There is one question was unanswered about the pricing exercise and the pricing yourself out of the German commercial market. The market believes you're marginal in your position in many accounts, and that is something I hear from a number of industrial insurance buyers. And if one says so, that's not a problem. But if five or six say so, then you might have a problem. I just wondered how you &#x2013; whether you see a problem or you don't?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I missed the question. Should I answer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's when you talk about the commercial market, that is what we call in our nomenclature the Global Corporate business. So in commercial, we have very stable premium income also in Germany, so the small and midsize companies.</p>
          <p>In Global Corporate, we have not renewed some accounts. That is correct. We run the Global Corporate business as a global business. We have our technical price setting. Our Global Corporate management team is being measured what they achieve in volume globally. And exactly our European business has overall had really a very good 2010 year in retention, in new business, and also in profitability.</p>
          <p>And if &#x2013; the German market is traditionally is the most volatile market for large corporates. And if some smaller or other players believes they can write business at these prices, we wish them luck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Malcolm, just to add, Mr. Frommer, this is not a policy which is specific to Germany, but it is rather the Zurich Way and our global approach, and how we underwrite business, particularly in that segment, Global Corporates. And the same is true for the approach we take in the U.S. and in any other country.</p>
          <p>Just want to make sure you understand this is not an isolated policy in the way we price and managed out the cost and segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Can we just &#x2013; I think we take one more from the telephone and one more from the room afterwards, okay? So telephone first, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question from the telephone is from Mr. Andrew Ritchie of Autonomous Research. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, hi, there, just a couple of questions. First of all, on the internal capital model, could you just clarify, does that include the effect of the increased cap retention? But does it reflect the decreased Farmers quota share?</p>
          <p>And I am not sure you answered the question, is there any impact from the change in structure of Germany on the internal capital model. I guess the other question, what exactly was the impact of FX in the quarter on that ratio?</p>
          <p>Sorry. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay. So thanks very much, Andrew, for the questions.</p>
          <p>I can confirm that all effects you have listed are included in the calculation. The transfer of the German business is not impacting the internal model because the internal model is a consolidated calculation for the group, ignoring the legal entity structure completely. And the effect from foreign currency is two to three percentage points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So we'll take one last from the room, I think, and then we'll just about finish on time. This one here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. <mark type="inaudible" />. The first question is about general insurance. You have a new head now and I just was wondering maybe product wise and from the geographical split where he would see some chances maybe missed in the past to grow organically? The second one, I really didn't learn about the restatement, which was fairly high last year, 1 billion, concerning the running profit and maybe you could just could recall me what it was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe before, I would like to actually introduce Mario to take this question. But before he's doing that, regarding the restatement that was linked to the variable annuity book, and the hedge in the U.S. and the impact on that, on a U.S. basis was 700 million, a bit more than US$700 million. So in other words, if you now see that from a half year to half year comparable, we show a decline on the New York level isolated of this hedge, we would have a double digit or other significant increase, half year by half year, on that comparable. So that accounting impact and that restatement somehow created some noise in the comparisons.</p>
          <p>Now you're right, we have a new head for the general insurance business. Mario Greco was introduced already at the Investors Day we had a few weeks ago. I mentioned in my introduction that he is getting his arms around the business and developing or enhancing rather the segment strategy which will present in December. Probably with regards to the growth question on there, he sees priorities and how we go about it. Why don't we let him take the question himself? Thank you, Mario.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Martin. This is a challenging market for GI, so what we are doing today, is we're looking particularly at the profitability side of the business. Then of course, profitability also grows with the size of the business and with the premium, so we are carefully looking and scanning the markets where we are and the opportunities that we have.</p>
          <p>We will present all this by the end of year and beginning of December to analysts and journalists as a thoroughly consistent plan for GI going forward. But I just want to stress the fact that our main focus today is on improving substantially the profitability, the run rate of profits of the business through all actions that we can take in order to achieve it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so can I now hand over to Martin Senn to close the session. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Malcolm, and thank you very much, ladies and gentlemen, for your attention, for your questions and for being with us today here in the room and on the phone. Let me just sum up. Our core business delivered a robust operating performance in a truly challenging economic environment.</p>
          <p>General insurance posted a solid performance in the first half, protecting margins despite weak demand. Global Life continued to product top line and bottom line growth and its proposition and distribution strategy continued to bear fruit, good fruit, I should say. And Farmers delivered another set of high quality results, managing expenses and margin while fully leveraging the 21st Century acquisition. The group's reported business operating profit and net income attributable to shareholders were impacted by the provisions we announced last month related to our non-core banking activities in Ireland and the UK.</p>
          <p>However, if we calculate the business operating profit after tax return on equity for our core businesses only, it would be 15.3% and this despite a 1.2 percentage point reduction for the Chilean earthquake.</p>
          <p>The economic environment remains challenging. We will continue to focus on profit margin, operating efficiency and risk management, and as we review our businesses and develop detailed strategy to help us to achieve our ambition to be the best insurance company. Now we do look forward to sharing those plans with you later in the year, December the 2nd, mark this date and until then, we wish you all the best and again, thank you for being with us.</p>
          <p>Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>