<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1194783" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-11-13</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2568</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Malcolm Gilbert, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James J. Schiro, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Dieter Wemmer, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">James Quinn</participant>
      <participant id="5">James Schiro</participant>
      <participant id="6">Dieter Wemmer</participant>
      <participant id="7">John Amore</participant>
      <participant id="8">Michael Huttner</participant>
      <participant id="9">Brian Shea</participant>
      <participant id="10">Spencer Horgan</participant>
      <participant id="11">Will Morgan</participant>
      <participant id="12">Andrew Broadfield</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. This is the Chorus Call conference operator. Welcome to the Results Reporting for the Nine Months to September 30, 2008 Conference Call.</p>
          <p>As a reminder, all participants are in listen-only mode, and the conference is recorded. This call must not be recorded for publication or broadcast. Analysts will have an opportunity to ask questions directly after the presentation. Media representatives are allowed to listen in only. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Mr. Malcolm Gilbert, Head of Group Investor Relations. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to Zurich's third quarter 2008 results conference, presentations by CEO, James Schiro and CFO, Dieter Wemmer. And I'd like to now to hand over to Jim Schiro to start the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to nine months results announcement, and thank you all for joining us this morning. As you know all to well, these are extraordinary times that are testing the fundamentals of both business models and regulatory regimes.</p>
          <p>In addition to the financial pressures created by the highly volatile markets, this past quarter also brought us one of the largest natural catastrophes in the US history, as well as the tail-end of highly competitive pricing environment in certain Commercial lines.</p>
          <p>While I will not go so far as to say we could have predicted the scope or scale of these market forces, I will say that the strategy and priorities that Zurich has pursued over the past six years, such as our focus on balance sheet strength and operational discipline, we're designed precisely to build resilience in difficult times and capture opportunities in better times.</p>
          <p>A deep and broad commitment to financial discipline governs our approach to core functions, from investment management and underwriting to expense management and accounting procedures. That discipline governs how we assess and assume risks, as well as how we manage our own internal operations.</p>
          <p>A deep and broad commitment to sophisticated capital management ensures that we effectively leverage and protect our capital base. In these times, that means we regularly document that our solvency position stay comfortably above both regulatory and internal thresholds, thereby ensuring the continued strength of our balance sheet and liquidity position.</p>
          <p>And a deep and broad commitment to operational excellence creates a platform from which we can standardize key processes like reserving, claims and distribution. These continual improvements are not simply about capturing economic value, but ultimately they would allow the consistent execution of our strategies across the Group.</p>
          <p>The value of these priorities over the past six years is fully evident in our ability to generate a resilient operating performance across these nine months, business operating profit of 4.2 billion, net income of 2.8 billion and a business operating profit after tax of return of 16.4%, still in excess of mid-term target.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, we also achieved a third quarter profit posting USD 636 million in business operating profit and USD 154 million in net income after tax, despite absorbing $1.1 million of net capital losses and 595 million of hurricane losses during the quarter. These are solid results and stand as a testament to the hard work and accomplishments of Zurich's people during these difficult times.</p>
          <p>But as stated earlier, these strengths are not simply defensive, preparing us against heightened catastrophe activity or historical financial market turmoil. They are also proactive, positioning us to capitalize on market opportunities that emerge. We are already seeing this in the General Insurance arena, where we are very selective about where and how we grow.</p>
          <p>Europe and emerging markets are showing the benefit of targeted organic and acquisition growth as we pursue customer, product and distribution strategies to generate solid profitable growth. But now we are seeing firm evidence of pricing improvements within North America and Corporate markets.</p>
          <p>We are similarly poised to take a disciplined approach to growth in these markets, and, in fact, <mark type="audio gap" /> (5:05-5:26) we are already seeing rates improve due to our pricing actions. Similarly, Farmers is leveraging a broader product base, an expanded geographic presence and increased agent productivity to post market-feeding growth.</p>
          <p>And Global Life continues to execute on a refined distribution and product strategy to deliver impressive APE growth and increasing new business value. In that same proactive spirit, our past successes is capturing the value of The Zurich Way workstreams. It provides us the confidence to expend and expand our economic value targets under the program going forward.</p>
          <p>For the years 2009, 10 and 11, we will target 900 million of economic benefit, or 2.7 billion over that three-year period. But one must recognize the current economic environment that we are in and the global recession that we are looking towards. So we will be taking further steps above and beyond The Zurich Way workstream to cut our expenses by 200 million in 2009.</p>
          <p>Again, we would not be able to take such decisive actions or have much confidence in our ability to execute such actions if we did not have a proven record of operational transformation. It's these skills that will help us in the years ahead. Where this leaves Zurich then, is that in spite of short-term challenges, we remain in a strong competitive position both as it relates to the current economic climate and future market conditions.</p>
          <p>We have a disciplined approach to our investment portfolio, and I'm confident that we will continue to protect our balance sheet. We take a prudent approach to capital management issues. That is critical to ensuring a strong balance sheet, secure liquidity and healthy solvency margins. And we pursue both growth and operational transformation with a systematic approach that maintains discipline while leveraging global capabilities.</p>
          <p>In the end, I'm proud of the 60,000 employees who have put us in such a strong position. And I'm confident in their ability to take us to even greater positions of strength as market conditions improve.</p>
          <p>With that, I would ask Dieter to provide you with additional details on our performance over the past nine months. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jim, and good morning ladies and gentlemen. We are pleased to announce business operating profit of $636 million for the third quarter in a difficult market, contributing to a 16.4% business operating profit after tax ROE year-to-date.</p>
          <p>This has clearly been a quarter affected by some very large items, resulting in a much reduced result for the three months. In particular, the hurricanes and the general asset evaluations have materially affected the quarter's business operating profit, net income and the closing shareholders' equity.</p>
          <p>However, insuring property against storms is a major part of our business, and looking at the nine months results, our losses on major natural catastrophes are lower year-to-date than in 2007 when we had floods and storms in Europe. The real out of pattern effect is from the revaluation losses we have taken on investment. As a result, net income after tax amounted to $154 million in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In accounting terms, there is some complexity in the way different groups of assets are treated. The business operating profit has been affected by mark-to-market of evaluations on investments held for trading, for example hedge funds, and some bonds designated as fair value through profit and loss, cash flow-matching corresponding Life insurance reserves. Net income is, in turn, reduced by impairments and other charges taking through the capital losses line though profit and loss.</p>
          <p>Finally, the shareholders' equity takes additional mark-to-market adjustments on the available for sale assets and all other asset adjustments not taking &#x2013; taken through net income. I would also point out here that we have not changed any classification of assets following the reasons of relaxations given under IAS 39.</p>
          <p>Accounting treatment does not change the risk profile of the Company. In economic terms, these treatments are not relevant. In addition, the economic effect is mitigated by a reduction in value of the insurance liabilities.</p>
          <p>Now looking at the movement in economic solvency and the regulatory solvency. On both measures solvency has reduced, but the position remains strong as I will come to later. The performance of the underlying insurance businesses has been resilient and operating profit was contributed to by all operating segments, which can be seen on our above summary slides, Page Eight.</p>
          <p>The overall core businesses show a 3% reduction in business operating profit. Other businesses suffered from a number of charges including mark-to-market asset adjustments through operating profit and some adverse insurance reserve movements.</p>
          <p>I will now go through the detail by segment of these operating results, starting with the top line on the next slide. As at the half year, we are pleased, not only with the level of growth, but also that we have achieved it in the areas we laid out in our strategic target. The achieved growth in General Insurance continues inline with our strategy, despite challenging markets.</p>
          <p>General Insurance, while growing 7% in dollar terms, has achieved an overall 1% GWP increase in local currency, driven by a 6% growth in Europe General Insurance and a 10% growth in international businesses. The growth is based on many initiatives, both acquisitions and organic.</p>
          <p>In Europe General Insurance, growth for the nine months in local currency was 6%, with Russia, the UK, Italy, Switzerland and Germany contributing the most. Half of this growth was organic.</p>
          <p>Looking at Italy, which I mentioned at the half year, GWP continues to grow at a rate of 12% in a virtually flat market without compromising our underwriting approach. The main driver behind this is the expansion of tied agents as part of Zurich Way initiatives. In addition, there was a 60% growth in the broker channel itself.</p>
          <p>In Russia, Zurich continues to deliver growth of around 40% through last year's acquisition, Zurich Retail. International business delivered a substantial growth of 10% in local currency. South Africa is leading this through inflation of rate increases and new business with Latin America and Japan also contributing.</p>
          <p>We experienced a 5% reduction in our gross written premium for the nine months in our overall North American businesses. This is due to both lower retention levels and continuingly decreasing rates. Although the rate decline has slowed in the third quarter and we see this trend continuing in the fourth quarter, the lower retention is a result of us passing on renewal accounts that customers are not prepared to accept our required rates.</p>
          <p>Turing to Global Life, annual premium equivalent grew by 9% in local currency, which is in line with the half year, despite the challenging financial markets. About one percentage point of that growth was added by our new insurance operations of Banco Sabadell and Caixa Sabadell in Spain. In addition, we still saw continued growth in emerging market and Germany.</p>
          <p>In the UK, successful sales of mutual funds have more than offset the decline in the bond market. We are pleased with the continued growth in our protection business, with Corporate Life protection sales increasing 88% and Individual Life protection sales increasing 11% in local currency. This growth was driven primarily by our Zurich International Solutions and Latin America businesses.</p>
          <p>We are a leader in unit-linked investments and savings products. We are in the process of extending this range to enhance the product choices. In the nine months 2008, sales of unit-linked and individual savings products, including mutual funds, increased by 3% in local currency.</p>
          <p>However, with the current interest rate environment, investment market volatility and the real estate slowdown, the challenges to grow new business remain. Global Life is committed to driving their growth strategy and achieving the mid-term target as outlined earlier this year.</p>
          <p>Farmers Management Services remains on track with a growth in fees of 9%. This is in line with the still good levels of premium growth at Exchanges of 6%. GWP in other businesses has increased at all lines quota-share Reinsurance Treaty where the Farmers Exchanges would increase on September 30, 2008 from five to 25% in order to provide Exchanges with surplus relief when needed. The portfolio transfer of about $1.1 billion has affected GWP, but none of it was earned on September 30.</p>
          <p>Let's move on to look at the General Insurance segment in more detail on Page 10. Across General Insurance, rate declines are slowing, with discrete Q3 rates down just 1% compared to 3% in the second quarter. This results in rates for the nine months down just over 2% overall. Rate reductions appear to have been slowing significantly in the US during the last quarter, both in Global Corporate and North America Commercial. European experience overall remains positive, and substantial rate increases were realized across international businesses for the nine month.</p>
          <p>Starting with our Personal Lines business, which represents 30% of General Insurance premium volume, the combined ratio is below 95%, hence a return of 12. The rate increases of around 2% combined with Zurich Way benefits should offset any deterioration due to claims inflation. With this stable outlook, we will continue to push for growth in these segments.</p>
          <p>Within international businesses, Commercial rates are up by 11% for the discrete quarter, driven by continued double-digit increases in South Africa and smaller positive rate increases across Latin America.</p>
          <p>In Australia, supported by The Zurich Way methodology, we have reacted to unacceptable reductions in rates by successfully focusing on underwriting discipline resulting in rate increases above 10% for the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Europe, our Commercial rates are flat in Europe General Insurance. We have also seen a slowing of rate reductions in Global Corporate in Europe, especially in the UK. Here, the rate of decline for the third quarter is significantly lower with a rate reduction of 3%. Early indications in the fourth quarters are that rates are flattening out.</p>
          <p>For Global Corporate North America and North America Commercial, we have taken decisive action which has resulted in significant slowing of rate reductions. Global Corporate in North America has gone from a 12% reduction at the half year to a 4% reduction in Q3 standalone. In North America Commercial, rate decreases have slowed as well in the third quarter to 3% which is at two percentage points better than in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>The reporting season is revealing the magnitude of the losses in the third quarter that are forcing some companies to recapitalize in an environment where capital is expensive. With additional strain on capital cost by market turmoil, as well as falling interest rates and losses from natural catastrophes in the US, we see a clear need for rates to turn in the fourth quarter in various segments of the market, particularly, in some of the most pressured US segments.</p>
          <p>We have therefore changed our stance from protecting margins to focusing on improving margins, especially in market segments where rates have fallen to unsustainable levels. We will continue to protect and improve our margins, and we are taking immediate proactive rate actions where necessary, building on our relative strengths in these challenging times.</p>
          <p>In summary, the positives from half year are still there, while we are successfully addressing the more challenging areas of our General Insurance portfolio. Indications in October are that rate reductions continue to slow, and we are optimistic that the fourth quarter will be a turning point.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to Slide 11 to dive into our General Insurance results. Business operating profit is down compared to nine months 2007 by 200 million to $2.6 billion. Global Corporate and North America Commercial suffered from catastrophes and large losses. Europe General Insurance, which had a high charge in 2007 from floods and storms, had a strong performance in 2008.</p>
          <p>International business showed a strong recovery from 2007 from action taken in Australia, South Africa and Latin America.</p>
          <p>Although business operating profit is down year-on-year by 7%, the General Insurance business continues show good resilience whilst being faced with continued rate pressure together with high levels of large claims, thus underlining the strength of our well diversified General Insurance portfolio.</p>
          <p>The overall General Insurance combined ratio has deteriorated by 1.8 percentage points to 98.7. This comprises 0.7 percentage point expense ratio increases and 1.1 percentage point of loss ratio increases.</p>
          <p>Firstly, we can explore the expense ratio in more detail on Slide 12. Our expense ratio of 25.3% was 0.7 percentage points higher than at nine months 2007, driven by changes in business mix to a lower loss ratio business, which continues to increase the commission ratio, and through continued investment and strategic initiatives. The increase in the commission ratio of 0.6 percentage points is the result of active portfolio shift to more profitable business, such as the programs business in North America.</p>
          <p>We continue to invest in efficiency and customer focus improvement also in the third quarter, which are Zurich HelpPoint brand positioning highlights. Like all investments from transformation initiatives, these actions have an impact on our expense ratio. We also continue to make progress in our expense management programs in the US and in the UK. In the US, where we have reduced employees by over 6%, we took restructuring charges of $63 million at the half year.</p>
          <p>For the UK program, the overall head count reduction will be 1,100 this year, a reduction of about 15%. We are confident we can realize a reduction in our cost base by 10% in UK. In this context, we took a restructuring charge of $49 million in the third quarter, giving a total for the two actions of $112 million. In addition, the majority of the extra 2009 cost saving program of $200 million, just announced by Jim, will be in General Insurance.</p>
          <p>Now let's have a more detailed look at the loss ratio on Page 13. The loss ratio for General Insurance is up 1.1 percentage points. Catastrophe losses are lower compared to 2007, but this is offset by an increased frequency of weather related claims, both large and attritional.</p>
          <p>In Europe, the poor summer gave rise to many local and relatively immaterial weather events, which were too small to define as a major catastrophe, but were not made up of individual large losses. And therefore, fell into the underlying category.</p>
          <p>The underlying loss ratio has deteriorated by two percentage points compared with nine months last year, which is accumulative result of rate reductions, claims inflations and weather related losses. This has been partially offset by The Zurich Way improvements. Those business divisions most affected are Global Corporate and North America Commercial, where rate pressure has been the greatest.</p>
          <p>Large loss experience was high in the first half of the year, but was much lower in the third quarter except for Europe, which experienced a high level of large losses. The loss ratios in Global Corporate and North America Commercial deteriorated by 13 and five percentage points to 90.1 and 72.7% respectively. The impact came as a result from catastrophes and other large losses. as well as worsening of the underlying loss ratios, reflecting premium rate declines and claims inflation, which were only partially offset by Zurich Way benefits.</p>
          <p>For Global Corporate, we have also seen an increased impact from mid-sized losses. These are claims which fall below the threshold we use for large losses, but still are more significant in cost than standard attritional losses and have an impact on the underlying loss ratios.</p>
          <p>In Europe General Insurance, the loss ratio improved by five percentage points largely due to the absence of large catastrophes compared with 2007, which suffered from the winter storm Kyrill and the UK floods, partially offset by the increased frequency of large losses and weather events in the UK, Ireland and Germany. In international business the loss ratio improved somewhat as a result of lower weather related losses in Australia and a decrease in large losses in Latin America.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a look at the reserve movements. Net reserves are virtually unchanged from a year ago, but net of currency movements reserves are up 3% in the last 12 month. The level of reserving conservatism remains unchanged. Both 2007 and 2008 September reserves include about the same level of charges for natural catastrophes.</p>
          <p>Prior year reserve for leases [sic] (losses) at the nine months were $925 million, leaving our overall reserve strength in line with year end 2007. The prior year movement is the result of many small movements across the global book following the quarterly reserve reviews.</p>
          <p>The overall level of stability in our prior year development reflects the majority of our reserving processes. These processes were established in a systematic way a number of years ago as part of The Zurich Way of reserving.</p>
          <p>In addition, many of the benefits arising from other Zurich Way initiatives in claims and underwriting are only recognized when there is an evidence of the trend in the actuarial process, and they therefore appear as prior year surpluses.</p>
          <p>We continue to monitor inflation very closely. Claims inflation in the nine month results across the General Insurance portfolio continues at about the same 3% annual rate we have experienced over the past few years. This is in line with expectations, and our actuaries see no noticeable change in the current inflation environment.</p>
          <p>Now moving on to the Life results, Page 15. As I mentioned before, the annual premium equivalent growth improvement to 9% was a result of the performance in a number of European and emerging markets. In the UK, sales campaigns for Sterling Individual Savings Accounts, ISAs, were particularly successful offsetting the decline in the market for single premium bonds.</p>
          <p>The new business margin overall remained well in our target range and at the same level as at the half quarter. New business value increased to $511 million, up from 480 million in the same period last year, which translates into a 1% growth in local currency. This was driven by the pension growth in Germany and Zurich International Solutions, partially offset by lower volumes in the US and Ireland and a change in margin mix. Business operating profit of $1.2 billion increased by 12% in dollar terms and 6% in local currency.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, the result in Germany benefited from a 61 million &#x2013; benefited by 61 million from changes to the German supervisory law that determines policyholder participation, which has ongoing benefits. In addition, we booked a one-off adjustment to net income after tax of $357 million.</p>
          <p>Also included in the overall business operating profit for Global Life are benefits starting to emerge from the implementation of our Global Life reinsurance task that we announced as part of the Life strategy update earlier this year.</p>
          <p>The result was adversely affected by the continued weakness of the investment market in the third quarter, particularly in the UK, requiring a further net charge for the acceleration and the amortization of deferred acquisition costs, intangible assets and deferred fees.</p>
          <p>However, the year-to-date business operating profit results benefited from a number of other one-off items. These include the unlocking of debt in the US as already reported at the half year, and Ireland due to revised expense deferrals and improvement in the UK from transactions to reduce exposure to non-core annuities.</p>
          <p>In total, this one-off effect from investment markets, deferred acquisition cost unlocking and improvement in the UK have benefited the business operating profit for the nine months 2008 by about $90 million.</p>
          <p>The underlying business performance is being further facilitated by a central underwriting team recently hired to support the protection business and also continue development of our propositions to meet customer needs in this demanding environment. In the appendix you can find further details on our emerging market position, which is similar to that reported at the half year.</p>
          <p>Now turning to Page 16, we look at our two acquisitions in Spain. Our pillar strategy is progressing as evidenced in this slide, which outlines the banc-assurance acquisitions in Spain. Of the new business volumes total, $21 million resulted from a few weeks inclusion of our newly acquired 50% stake in the insurance operations of Banco Sabadell and Caixa Sabadell in Spain through the fast and effective integration efforts.</p>
          <p>In particular, I'm very pleased at the pace with which we closed the deal with Banco Sabadell allowing us to include two weeks worth of new business in the third quarter. The result of this work has given us an overall market share of 6.5%, and made us the number two composite insurance player in Spain.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the Farmer's result, Slide 17. Looking at the business operating profit at the bottom of the slide, very much in line with the half year. It decreased by 9% to $919 million driven by two factors as already discussed at the half year.</p>
          <p>Firstly, investment income decreased by $71 million, largely as a result of higher dividends and cash transfers to the Group. Secondly, last year included gains of $59 million on the sale of operating properties which were not repeated in '08.</p>
          <p>The gross management result has increased by 7% reflecting the continued good levels of underlying premium growth at Exchanges to which I will come in a minute. I would like to highlight that the margin on gross earned premiums remain resilient at 7.1%. This demonstrates that the profitability to Farmers Management Services of the underlying insurance business in the Exchanges, is largely unaffected by the market development.</p>
          <p>With that, let's move to the performance of the Exchanges on Slide 18. The Farmers Exchanges, which we manage but do not own, have continued their strong track record from 2006 and '07. In the third quarter, they continued the transfer of the small business portfolio from North America Commercial, which added 219 million in premiums.</p>
          <p>The Exchanges delivered a 6% of premium growth in the nine months '08. 3.7 percentage points of this growth came from integrating Bristol West. The Exchanges withstood the challenging and declining market conditions and outperformed industry once more.</p>
          <p>Excluding North America small business transfer and Bristol West premium growth, organic growth was positive at 0.6%, which was very favorable compared with the market. This growth was driven by renewed activity in the East Coast independent agency channel where premiums grew 8%, as a result of additional agency appointments and the introduction of new auto product.</p>
          <p>In addition, we saw a strong performance in the emerging Hispanic and Asian markets where more than 300 new agents have been appointed. The integration of Bristol West has been completed successfully and their product's now sold in all 29 tied agent states. Bristol West premium grew by 180 million or 25% year-over-year, strongly ahead of non-standard competitors.</p>
          <p>The adjusted combined ratio is at 101.4%, almost up 10 percentage points. 7.7 points of that increase are due to higher catastrophe charges year-over-year. The higher catastrophe charges are driven by the hurricanes in the third quarter hitting primarily Texas and Louisiana, with Ike and Gustav incurring about 480 million net losses, and further storms in the Midwest. These were in addition to the second quarter Midwest storms.</p>
          <p>In line with Zurich's HelpPoint philosophy, the Exchanges had 1,500 claims people on the ground to handle 125,000 claims from Hurricane Ike. 96% of these claims had already been closed by early November. The remainder of the combined ratio increase was driven by increasing loss trends in homeowner and auto.</p>
          <p>More importantly, the Exchanges have continued to file rate increases since the beginning of 2007 in response to higher loss trends. In the nine months 2008, the Exchanges led the market taking rate increases of 7.6% in auto and 4.8% in homeowners. They plan to continue filing further rate increases in 2008 at loss trends warrant.</p>
          <p>Going forward, the total market for US personal lines is expected to increase rates, and the Exchanges early rate actions positioned them well to capitalize on competitors' needs to increase rates. The Exchanges target is to continue to outgrow the industry.</p>
          <p>Net surplus decreased as a result of the sharply higher catastrophe losses and the statutory treatment of both the unrealized and realized losses on equity and debt investments and the transfer of the small business book from Zurich North America. Taking account of the increased quota-share to which I referred earlier, the surplus ratio was 35.4%, a level we still consider to be solid and well within the historical range. As I said, this level of the surplus ratio is not expected to have an effect on the Exchanges ability to fund future growth.</p>
          <p>Turning now to look at the performance of our other businesses and corporate functions segment on the next slide. Summer three took a charge of $25 million for our share of the hurricane losses in the Farmers portfolio.</p>
          <p>In 2007 both center and other benefited from a strong economic environment, generating strong investment returns, and high commutation gains, both are sensitive to equity and debt movements.</p>
          <p>In 2008, they were affected by mark-to-market adjustments of approximately $300 million being charged to P&amp;L through operating profit. And in addition, they have experienced much less commutation activity in '08 compared with last year.</p>
          <p>Finally, we strengthen Life and non-Life reserves in a number of areas in the other category. As we see poor investment market performance in the fourth quarter, further negative volatility has to be expected in this segment. If markets remain at current levels, the result in fourth quarter similar to third quarter standalone is well within the range of probable outcome. Improvements in corporate functions are driven by lower headquarter expenses and a higher allocation of these expenses to the businesses.</p>
          <p>Looking now at the performance of our Group investment on Slide 20, given that capital losses are so important in this result reporting, we have added an additional slide, analyzing capital losses and impairments by quarter and asset class.</p>
          <p>Net capital losses through profit and loss were a negative $1.8 billion for the nine months, including losses of 1.4 billion in the third quarter from the turbulent financial markets. Within this amount impairments, cost of policyholder allocation and hedging added 1.1 billion in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>We already announced losses on the three defaulted financial institutions Sigma, Lehman and Washington Mutual of 615 million for shareholders, which cost 750 million at the gross level. Thereby, further impairment on bonds totaling 150 million and equities added another 180 million.</p>
          <p>Mark-to-market adjustments on trading assets and fair values through profit and loss assets also contribute to the total. These reductions were partially offset by gains on equity hedges. In total for the nine months, the gross 1.8 billion capital losses impacted shareholders after policyholder allocation impacts by 1.1 billion.</p>
          <p>Moving on to another new slide on unrealized losses in shareholders' equity on Page 21. Unrealized losses included in shareholders' equity for the nine months were 5.5 billion, although, as we will see, only 3.5 billion were for shareholders. The increase in the third quarter was 0.8 billion of which unrealized losses on available for sale equities increased by 0.6 billion as a result of stressed markets.</p>
          <p>And losses in value on debt securities increased only modestly by 0.2 billion in aggregate. This was driven by two offsetting items. While lower yields on government bonds increased their market value, higher credit spreads on corporate bonds and some assets-backed securities decreased their market value.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at the summary investment slide. Net investment income increased by 3% in the dollar terms, but is down 3% in local currency. This decrease was largely driven by lower average invested assets, mostly as a result of the transfer of the UK annuities and payment block of about $7 billion to Swiss Re last summer.</p>
          <p>As we just saw, net capital losses through P&amp;L were 1.8 billion of which 1.1 were for shareholders. In the nine months 2008 total net investment return, which includes changes in unrealized losses of 5.5 billion, was a negative 40 basis points a very respectable result in the worst financial market for decades.</p>
          <p>Let me remind you of some key points of Zurich's disciplined investment approach. You can find further details in the appendix as usual. As emphasized, we continue to be very comfortable with the quality of our investments and our asset allocation. Our equity exposure is well controlled and amounts to 3.3% as at the beginning of November taking into account our hedging programs which protect about one-third of our equity exposure.</p>
          <p>Looking at the hedging of our unrealized equity losses in the light of our impairment policy. In the very hypothetical case that all equity prices were frozen as of the depressed October 31, 2008 position, we would expect further impact on equities to reduce net income by less than $350 million in the fourth quarter after policyholder-shareholder split and taxes.</p>
          <p>The credit quality of our debt portfolio remains strong. As requested, we have added in the appendix more disclosure on our high quality and well diversified corporate bond portfolio. These extreme events underscore the benefit of our disciplined investment approach. This approach ensures that Zurich invests in a very diversified portfolio. And though this approach cannot prevent losses completely, the scale of the individual losses remains manageable.</p>
          <p>With that, let me comment on the movement on shareholders' equity, Page 23. Shareholders' equity at $23.9 billion is down 17% on the restated 2007 year end closing number. You can see the net income after tax number, which is also driven by a very pleasing reduction of shareholders' effective tax rate down to 23.5%, an improvement of 0.9 percentage points over year end rate.</p>
          <p>In addition to paying the dividend, we have bought back an additional 421 million worth of shares in the third quarter, bringing the total of our buyback program to $1.45 billion. The $3.5 billion of adverse movement in unrealized investment losses represents the 5.5 billion, which I mentioned in the previous investment pages, net of tax, policyholder and other allocations.</p>
          <p>Translation adjustments, primarily as a result of European currencies weakening against the US dollar since the half year, reduced equity by another $945 million. To put that in context, the overall shareholders' equity in dollars has dropped by 11% in the quarter, whereas the book value per share in Swiss francs was down just 1%.</p>
          <p>With that, let's have a look at our capital position on the next slide. Diverse profile of the Group is largely unchanged apart from a reduction in equity exposure and a higher insurance exposure, which we take on with increased quota-share from Farmers Exchanges.</p>
          <p>Solvency remains at a level comfortable above our internal AA target. Our initial cautious estimate for the opening 2008 solvency position was that we had to buffer over obviously of about $6 billion or about 20%. When we ran the final models, the buffer was bigger at about 26% or $8 billion. This margin was largely maintained until the market turmoil in the third quarter, which used to buffer to $6 billion. We estimate the current buffer at roughly $5 billion.</p>
          <p>Statutory solvency, under Solvency 1 rules has moved from 187% at the year end to 171% in September, and we estimates this ratio to be at 159% at the end of October. This includes the remaining $1 billion of share buyback, which we have not executed yet.</p>
          <p>Our strong balance sheet has been built on prudent capital management. And prudence has to some extent to be measured relative to the economic environment and outlook. In these markets, it is the time for more prudence and not less.</p>
          <p>Considering the market volatility, the Group is not buying back shares as part of the previously announced 2.2 billion share buyback program. It is clear that our shares have recently been at very attractive prices to be bought back. But in the long-term, companies survive and thrive by finding the right balance between prudence and taking advantage of bargain opportunities, particularly during flat situations.</p>
          <p>We will continue to run our capital management on these principles, and look forward to being in a strong position to be able to take advantage of any economic upturns as they arise.</p>
          <p>With that, let's summarize our position. We find ourselves in a strong relative capital position supported by a high quality investment portfolio. The continuing strength of our operating performance is supported by further Zurich Way initiatives and additional expense reduction efforts.</p>
          <p>We have achieved growth and profitability in the areas we target, particularly in Global Life, Farmers and Personal Lines General Insurance. We see an improving General Insurance rating environment. This combination of strong capital in today's market, give us the flexibility and competitive edge to be a market leading insurer.</p>
          <p>And now we are happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Mr. James Quinn, Citigroup. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Yes. I have three questions, please. The first one's on the non-Life business. I was just wondering if you could give us a sense of where you stand in the Commercial lines in terms of the current accident year margins versus what you see as technical price adequacy? Now I presume you're still above technical price adequacy, and, if that's the case, I guess what makes you feel that rates will really go up from current levels, particularly given that your customers are not necessary in a position to pay a great deal more for insurance than they did last year? The second question is just then on the Life BOP result. I wondered if you could give us the sensitivity of the Life BOP result to falling equity markets, i.e. the impact on fees and overall margins there. And also I wonder if you could give us a sensitivity of the Life DAC [deferred amortization costs) on equity products to further equity market reductions? Obviously you've had some DAC positives this year, but if equity markets stayed where they were, what would we see as the potential negative impact of DAC unlocking in Q4 and or indeed in 2009 assuming equity markets stays the same? And I wonder if you could also just give us a quick sense of what the DAC one-off benefit was in Q3? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. James, let me just say, and then I'm going to ask Dieter to deal with the Life DAC questions that you've just asked. And Dieter and I think John Amore is with him could talk about the <mark type="inaudible" />.  Generally &#x2013; well first of all, I want to say that we continue to write business above technical price and where we see that we can't get technical pricing, I think Dieter commented on that in the follow-up, <mark type="inaudible" /> in certain Commercial lines and we're also seeing some improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, can you move closer to the microphone? I'm not sure that everybody can hear you all the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's our microphone here, I'm right on top of it. The other side of that is continuing with those comments. Our submissions are up, particularly in North America and part of that is the result of the dislocation of AIG in several Commercial lines, particularly in the D&amp;O space and in environmental lines. So I think we feel confident if they're assuming, and it's not an assumption we're seeing this slowdown and recession, we may not see premium volumes increase. But we will see the cost of &#x2013; if you take lines like workers' comp where there'll be reduction in workforces, but we will see increases in rate. So I'm going to turn it back to Dieter and John Amore then, to pick the other parts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So James, before I hand over to John for the GI question, let me start with the Life question. I think we would see, in the fourth quarter, roughly a sensitivity out of both items of $50 million. But as you know yourself, that number is changing daily with the market. So if you tell me the stock market level on December 31, I'll give you a precise answer. I think on &#x2013; in the third quarter we have not any additional unlocking effects of DAC DAQ. That was all first and second quarter events and nothing new in the third quarter. I think that was mainly your Life questions, and now I would ask John to comment on our AP/TP ratio for the Commercial business overall and our outlook expectations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks, Dieter and Jim. And, James, thanks for the question. I always like to start to answer this question with reminding everyone that the General Insurance world is a very diverse portfolio by both geography and product. So when we look at the GI world, first thing I want to point is 30% of our premium is personalized premiums in Europe and in our international businesses. In this part for General Insurance, we have continued to see positive single-rate pricing, single-digit price positive movement. And these businesses are businesses that we're growing most dramatically through both organic means and acquisition.</p>
          <p>On the Commercial side, we have &#x2013; the US and UK Corporate and Commercial markets are changing. The pricing environment is changing. We clearly saw that happen in the third quarter. The decline in pricing that had been taking place for the past several years has made a relatively dramatic turn. It cut in half, if you look at the chart 10 and the comments Dieter made earlier, in terms of the progress we have seen in both our North American Commercial and in our Global Corporate business. So this is a very positive change. And market changes never do come in one quarter, they take several quarters to manifest. And that's why we have optimism about the changing of the marketplace in General Insurance and the changing of the pricing environment on our Commercial business. And lastly I &#x2013; Jim was cutting in and out a bit, so let me just reiterate that the AP/TP is still above our target pricing level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So maybe if I could just come back quickly, Dieter, on the Life BOP. Clearly the Q3 number was very, very strong and I think that looks a bit of a surprise given what's happening in equity markets. But I mean again, I'm no &#x2013; no one has a better idea on equity markets than you have, but the &#x2013; in terms of assuming that equity markets would stay where they are now, am I right in thinking that the sort of run-rate then would decline from sort of 450 down to about 400? Is that a reasonable statement? I know I've read profits are a nightmare to forecast, but &#x2013; well you can just give us some sense of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With all the caveats, I think we see a sensitivity of 50 million. What I would like to point out that &#x2013; the policyholder-shareholder split in Germany changed by profit, by source of profit. And our business has strong profit from mortality as well as expenses. And that is the reason why you see a very positive change in our Company from this change in the law. I cannot confirm that this will be the case with all German life companies. I can only speak about Zurich Life in Germany. And that is an ongoing change, which makes about $20 million per quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Okay. So you &#x2013; the 400 isn't a number that sounds unreasonable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as you know, we are very weak on doing forecasts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Michael Huttner, JPMorgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot. I had two questions. One is on the large claims. I'm &#x2013; they seem to be recurring to me, and I know you said your claims are actually adjusted for these things. We've had large claims every quarter now for three quarters this year roughly a run-rate of 500 million. So my question here is where exactly are they? Because listening to the conference call, I wasn't sure if it was Europe or Global Corporate, I just don't know. And the second is when you talk about technical pricing, do you actually include large claims in that? And I'm not being facetious. I just want to understand, that's all. And the third one, is there anything you can do to kind of clear this up because this 500 million of course is a big, big number. The other question &#x2013; and this is something I obviously was not listening very carefully, when you talk about your excellent solvency ratios October, the 159%...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I couldn't understand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sorry. You know you talked about the excellent solvency ratio at Q3 of &#x2013; sorry, at October, of 159%. And here, the two things I hadn't understood. The first one, is this allowing for the extra billion-and-a-bit, the quota-share from Farmers that you're taking on? And other one is does that &#x2013; is this after deducting an extra billion dollars of buyback still to come? Or is it not deducting the billion buybacks yet to come? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So that question I think &#x2013; Jim, if you'll allow, I take the two questions, is this fine?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's start with the technical pricing. Of course, the technical price takes into account large losses and catastrophes. The large claims which were added in the third quarter were more coming from Europe General Insurance. There was not &#x2013; the frequency in Global Corporate and North America Commercial was lower in the third quarter than it was in the previous two quarters. But also I have to say here, large claims we account accessing below $100 million. And we had two flood events in Ireland and UK, which are about $80 million together, or 7 &#x2013; between 70 and $80 million, which are shown under this box, large claims. That was actually a heavy rain and storm as a fallout of Hurricane Gustav which traveled all across Atlantic, and created even floods in Ireland where you would assume they can't have floods. So that is added in this large claim section.</p>
          <p>And the other question, the 159 end of October includes all our business in October, so also other &#x2013; the changes in taking the reinsurance. And what we have done here, so you understood it correctly, Michael, is we have taken out the share buyback in the sense that it is included as capital in the calculation. If we would execute the share buyback, so solvency ratio would be at 151, that is still a very good number, because we include our bond portfolio at market value in our Solvency I ratio. And I know that some companies are using amortized cost or face value for the bond portfolio in the Solvency I ratio. So I think it is a conservative calculation and very strong number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Michael, if I could just add some things  to that. First, as Dieter points out, we have not made any accounting change that was permitted as some others have. So it adds to conservatism in terms of our balance sheet and the accounting. And second, I just want to correct any &#x2013; we have not &#x2013; since the summer, we have not been buying shares back. So once we saw, after our half year result announcement, the financial volatility, our focus continued and accentuated the move towards the balance sheet and capital management. And again, making sure that we were prudent as we were managing in that direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. That's clear. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Mr. Brian Shea, Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I had two questions please, both on the capital position. The five billion of excess capital that you see now and how that relates to the six billion &#x2013; or the eight billion at the end of 2007, could you just split that out into how both the numerator and the denominator have been changing over the course of the year? How much of I guess both have been coming down? If you could just give us some more detail on that I'd appreciate it. And then secondly, there's one capital number you didn't show, which is how S&amp;P looks at you guys. I just wonder how does that look right now? Is that potentially &#x2013; might that potentially become a binding constraint for how you look at your own capitalization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dieter, why don't you go through that calculation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So our RBC, the required risk-base capital, increased only very slightly over the year. Actually, it remains very much flat. Therefore, the reduction is mainly in the available financial resources, and it is a one-to-one translation of our movement in equity. So there is actually not a big surprise in this. Your second question, I think we are not disclosing our S&amp;P ratios and S&amp;P capital calculation. But I can also tell you that we have not heard anything negative from the rating agencies about our third quarter results. And if you actually look at the Solvency I ratios, which I think most of our peers publish also, with end of October numbers, I think that we do quite well and we are probably not the highest rated on this list of companies, which also shows you that that's probably &#x2013; the S&amp;P formula is at the moment not the prime measure to measure the quality of a credit and the rating. Does this help you, Brian, or do you need more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That's fine. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Spencer Horgan, Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Two things, please. Firstly, I hear what you're saying on the share buyback and I guess that's completely logical in this environment. But could you sort of talk maybe in broad terms about the dividend? I think your policy previously has been &#x2013; has talked about it being sort of maybe growing slightly from a stable base. I mean would it be fair to assume that shareholders will not get a dividend that's lower than last year? And the second thing is can you just maybe expand on this extension of Farmers quota-share? I mean what is &#x2013; exactly has happened within Farmers to necessitate it? And how long do you think you need it for? Honestly, what's the &#x2013; I guess as a positive P&amp;L impact from this in a normal environment, perhaps you could you talk about that as well? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. First, we never discuss the dividend, and particularly when you look at the financial volatility that would vary at this point in time. Our focus is on ensuring that we have maintained a strong balance sheet, and that we're prudent from a financial management standpoint and also a capital management standpoint. And that's our main focus. With both of them we were &#x2013; we said that in the past, in good times when the markets were strong, and that was our focus in terms of executing the dividend. The buyback, I think one has to be realistic that markets are in a great deal of turmoil, and financial strength is the real premium. And those companies with strong balance sheets are the one's that will survive and weather the storm that we're going through, but also to be able to execute on opportunities.</p>
          <p>And I'd also like to point out our focus in this market, has to be on our customers, our customers are looking for  &#x2013; and those that are coming to us, particularly as we're seeing in North America, they're looking for companies that are going to be there to provide them the financial security that we need. We are benefiting from the turmoil in the US from AIG, and part of that strength and ability to benefit will come from a strong balance sheet and the ability to write new business in that market. I think as it relates to Farmers in the quota-share I mean, look, this is one of the benefits of that model that we see, and yes the quota-share will have a positive benefit on our operating results going forward. And I don't know, Dieter, if you want to add anything?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe, Spencer, let me add here that this quota-share is changing almost every year. And if you look actually at the bulk contribution of Farmers  E this year compared to last year, there is a &#x2013; 25 million of the reduction is explained by Ike, but the other reduction in profit is actually just coming from the fact that we reduced the percentage. So now we are moving back to a higher percentage, and we use this as a pleasing solvency instrument for the Exchanges over the last ten years. And actually, I think assets still can grow organically very well. It's now time to increase it, and also we take this additional <mark type="inaudible" /> profit then coming from Farmers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Stephan Shurman, Bank Vontobel. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. I have two questions, in fact. The one is Farmers, the surplus ratio. Could you maybe remind me on the target range you do have there? And do you &#x2013; if you feel confident now on this &#x2013; on the 35.4 percentage points, and what sort of potential measures you could take in case of further diverse markets there? And the second question, just a small one, on the investment performance on the hedge funds and real estate portfolios, I didn't find that yet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dieter, do you want to, I mean, comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I'm happy to answer. Well, we disclosed this Farmers surplus ratio since years in this way, but actually internally we manage the Farmer's surplus based on a different KPI and that is the risk-based capital formula as required by the North American Association of Insurance Commissioners, NAIC, formula. And here we are targeting a ratio of 300%, and we are still above this target ratio. That is the way we manage the business. That's &#x2013; I think it's a bit difficult to translate it into this simple premium surplus ratio because it is not a linear relationship between the two ratios.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. William Morgan, Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. I have two questions, please. First question is are you able to give your Solvency I ratio assuming that you do not mark your bonds to market, just to put it in line with, obviously, some of your other competitors, as you mentioned? Second question, just related to...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're having &#x2013; Dieter, I don't know if you can hear it, but we're having difficulty hearing this question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can you hear me more clearly now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sorry. The first question just to repeat is could you possibly give your Solvency I ratio assuming that you do not mark your bonds to market, just to put it in line with your other competitors as you mentioned? The second question just relates to M&amp;A opportunities that you might see in the current environment. I know in the past you've been pretty clear about the areas where you see strategic opportunity and that you would normally look at. But I think if I remember correctly, you mentioned on your last conference call that obviously were extra-special opportunities to come up, you would obviously look at them for the good of your shareholders. Given the financial situation and some of the fallout from that is the opportunity set in terms of areas you might look to do deals expanding? And could you just comment on how you see the landscape at the moment? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me comment on the first piece, on both of these, and I'll let Dieter &#x2013; I don't &#x2013; comment. I mean obviously the solvency ratio would be a lot higher if we were not marking our portfolios market.  I don't have a number in mind, and I don't if Dieter's capable of giving you one. But if you just were to take the impairment's charge or the mark-to-market charge that we take through the &#x2013; this past year on the capital flow sheet. Just even if you just adder that back, you'd have a significant impact on our solvency ratio. So but as it relates to opportunities in the market, clearly there are opportunities in the market. Clearly we will continue to look at opportunities in the market. But though again, I have to come back to the point that we will not jeopardize the balance sheet, the strength of our balance sheet, and do things that are not prudent in this market. And I think it's a matter of watching and looking for those opportunities that presents itself, that are attractive, that serve to enhance shareholder value over the long term, and our goal is to continue to create shareholder value. But we will not jeopardize the buffers that we have in solvency to pursue those kinds of opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>William, it's not a qualified calculation, so I would not print it like this in our annual report. But let me give you some guidance on how to approach it. We have 3.5 billion of unrealized losses in our equity accounts. And if I want to be on the safe side, I make it very simple and say 2.5 billion is linked to debt, so on a rounded basis. So that would be step one in the calculation. And the other step is that the billion dollars makes about eight percentage points in our solvency calculation. So I think with these two information, I think you should come roughly in the right range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Operator, could we now make this next question the last question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question for today is from Mr. Andrew Broadfield, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for letting me having this question. Just a couple of detail clarification actually, one is on the capitalization. The big move from the end of September to, or it seems big to me, end of September to the end of October. Is it fair just to say that, that is simply the equities and the bond spreads, the credit spreads that have driven that? So that's the first question. Or whether there's anything else in there? And the second question's on the quota-share, can you just remind me of two or three things, one, what are the size of the quota-share, did I hear 20, 25%, something like that? How much capital does that consume for you and how much relief was that for Farmers Exchanges, and just &#x2013; I presume it's a 12-month duration contract? And what returns you relate to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Clearly, clearly, the falling markets, September, have had a significant impact here. So the answer to your first question, so your assumptions are correct. I couldn't hear the third question, but I'll let the Dieter ask &#x2013; answer the Farmers question and answer the third question that as well .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Andrew, first I can confirm your assumptions on what moved in October is absolutely correct that it's the credit spread that's mainly on US bond portfolios and that it's the equity markets, which is mainly for us than European, driven by European equity portfolios. So the quota-share, the terms and principal are not changing. We renew it every year at very much the same terms. So it is an arms-length transaction as Farmers Exchanges could do it also with the other reinsurance provider. I think it is probably just only the easier trust to have this floating arrangement with us. It's I guess it makes about 2.5 percentage points in the surplus ratio going forward for the Exchanges. I think that was your question or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's right. Then just on the size of the quota-share, now is it 25% did I hear you say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it moved from 5% to 25%, and the quota-share has a cap exposure because the cap reinsurance is already on the Exchanges. So therefore for us it is a very limited risk transfer, and for this type of personal lines business with cap exposure, I think something of around 20% of the premium is a fair assumption from a first-base capital perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks ever so much. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you all for participating in this call. I really appreciate your questions, active participation and interest, and obviously have remaining questions, of course be pleased to answer them. I think obviously these are some of those typical financial kinds of people who've seen many cases in lifetimes and obviously generations. I continue to be very proud of the 60,000 people that have made it possible as we went through our own turnaround in the last six years and really to focus on or be able to deliver these kinds of results in these market environments.</p>
          <p>It's a commitment that we have financial discipline, prudent capital management, and obviously our desire to continue to enjoy a strong capital position and clearly the high quality of our investment portfolio. We're committed to continuing to drive even deeper our operational transformation. We will balance that against the growth opportunities as we position ourselves to capitalize and create those opportunities for profitable growth, particularly as we see firm signs of markets improving, and we're seeing that, as we mentioned, in General Insurance.</p>
          <p>All told, as we look at the challenges we face right now, Zurich is in a strong competitive position. We &#x2013; I remain confident in the ability for us to generate shareholder value and take advantage of these current market conditions to do just that but obviously not sacrifice our financial discipline, operational excellence and prudent capital management. Those are the things that will enable us to grow and continue to grow profitably in the future.</p>
          <p>So with that, thank you again for joining us for this call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference is now concluded, and you may disconnect your telephones. Thank you for joining and have a pleasant day. Good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>