<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1519582" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-11-15</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2568</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer">Martin Senn</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Pierre Wauthier</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to Zurich Insurance Group's Results Presentation for the First Nine Months of 2012. Our group delivered strong underlying profitability over the period, thanks to our continued focus on pricing discipline and portfolio management. The discreet third quarter results were adversely affected by the previously reported adjustment in our German General Insurance business. I'm disappointed by this, particularly as it masked a strong performance in the rest of the business and we are taking actions to address it.</p>
          <p>We were particularly pleased with the sustained top line growth in our target markets, which include some mature markets notably the United States where we are celebrating 100 years of doing business and our continued success in high potential growth markets in Latin America and Asia. The group's capital position remain strong and well within our AA target range, underpinned by our continued focus on risk management in both our disciplined investment and underwriting strategies. While we have seen some improvement in North America, the economic environment in which we are operating remains challenging, especially in Europe. Nevertheless, we remain focused on executing our strategy and are on-track to deliver on our strategic targets for 2013.</p>
          <p>So let's have a closer look at the numbers. Business operating profit for the first nine months of this year was $3.2 billion, unchanged from the comparable period despite the adjustment of $550 million in our German General Insurance business in the discreet third quarter. Net income attributable to shareholders was $2.7 billion, down 16% due to lower net capital gains compared to the prior year period. Despite the adjustment, General Insurance delivered a gain in business operating profit and has continued to make good progress on delivering its strategic targets through disciplined underwriting and expense management.</p>
          <p>The business has achieved average rate increases of 3.6% and the underlying loss ratio for the nine months improved by 2.8 percentage points to 61.6%. The overall combined ratio improved by 1.2 points to 97.6%. Premium volumes in European markets have been under pressure because of the subdued economic environment there, but this was more than offset by premium growth in North America and the continued expansion in our target markets.</p>
          <p>Global Life continued to show the positive impact of organic growth in U.S., UK and Latin America. Our acquisitions in Latin America and Asia Pacific will further strengthen this growth, though they are not included in new business results for this reporting period. Results were once again adversely affected by the challenging environment in Europe and persisting low interest rates. But gross written premiums, policy fees and insurance deposits increased strongly and the segment continues to shift its product mix through its protection and fee-based business.</p>
          <p>At Farmers, profitability at the management services company rose on the back of an increase in cross earned premiums in the Farmers Exchanges, which are managed, but not owned by Farmers Group, a wholly owned subsidiary of the group. This was offset by weather-related losses and the absence of favorable prior year loss development at Farmers Re. Farmers Management Services' cross earned premium margin was little changed at 7.4%. The total return on group investments for the nine months on a non-annualized basis was 5.3%, a strong result in the current low interest rate environment.</p>
          <p>Shareholders' equity increased by 7% to $34.1 billion and our return on common shareholders' equity was 11%. Our business operating profit after tax return on equity was 10.2%, down from 10.6% in the same period in 2011. These results reflect a strong underlying performance in a challenging economic environment. I would like to thank our 60,000 employees around the world for their hard work and dedication, which has made our success possible. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and good afternoon, ladies and gentleman. As Martin highlighted, the group maintained its strong business operating profit over the first nine months. If we look at the third quarter BOP in some more detail, the underlying profitability continue to be strong, but the group's business operating profits and net income were significantly impacted by the previously announced financial adjustments of $550 million in General Insurance in Germany.</p>
          <p>General Insurance's underlying performance in the third quarter continue to be strong with an underlying loss ratio of 61.6%, but the Germany adjustments, which I will address in more detail on slide eight contributed to the reduction of BOP to $182 million. The Life BOP held fairly steady at $305 million, an improvement compared to the prior year third quarter as the expense and risk margins continue to grow, largely offsetting the impact of the continued low interest rates on our investment margin.</p>
          <p>And in Farmers, the management services company showed strong profit growth, while Farmers Re returned to profitability, benefiting from the benign cat quarter and the underwriting and pricing actions taken by the Farmers Exchanges. The Zurich Santander business continues to perform well and in line with our expectations. The discrete quarter statutory result for Zurich Santander showed continued growth in both top line and net income as I will discuss in more detail on slide 16.</p>
          <p>Turning to net income for the quarter, the impact of the Germany adjustments benefits from gains and derivative positions used for hedging as well as restructuring costs were the main drivers for the decrease of 61% compared to the third quarter of last year. Now, let's look at the business operating profit by segment. General Insurance BOP increased by 5% to $1.8 billion, despite the impact of the financial adjustments in Germany. Excluding this impact, General Insurance delivered a very solid set of results for the first nine months, as the underlying performance of the business continues to improve and benefited also from less severe catastrophes. We continue to see growth in our targeted markets, while maintaining rate increases.</p>
          <p>In Global Life, the business operating profit decreased by 5% in U.S. dollar terms, but improved 1% in local currency to $959 million as improvements in the expense and risks margin and the contribution from Zurich Santander offset the impact of continued lower interest rates. Premiums and APE showed good growth as the Corporate Life &amp; Pensions pillar had good success, notably in Latin America.</p>
          <p>Farmers business operating profit declined by 9%, primarily due to the absence of favorable prior year developments in Farmers Re. Farmers Management Services profit increased as the growth in Farmers Exchanges which we manage, but do not own drove increased fee income. Other operating businesses' loss increased due mostly to the absence of last year's favorable foreign currency movements. Non-core businesses reported a strong result of $118 million. This was driven mainly by the Life business included in the other run-off book. The reported business operating profit after tax return on equity decreased to 10.2% compared to 10.6% in the first nine months of last year.</p>
          <p>With that, let's to move General Insurance. Apart from Germany, which is explained in more detail on the next slide, General Insurance had again a strong underlying performance against the background of the subdued macroeconomic environment and persisting low yields. Gross written premiums increased by 6% in local currency. Our acquisitions in Latin America and Malaysia added about two percentage points. The remaining four points are driven by organic growth from rate increases as well as exposure growth particularly in certain lines in North America and international markets.</p>
          <p>Our General Insurance strategy is continuing to show results. Our stance on pricing, underwriting discipline and portfolio management is unchanged and contributed to the improved underlying loss ratio of 2.8 percentage points. BOP improved by 6% in local currency, benefiting from the improved underlying loss ratio and the absence of major catastrophes, partly offset by the previously announced adjustments in Germany, an additional tax charge in the quarter also in Germany, and the continuing pressure on investment income.</p>
          <p>Let's now take a closer look at Germany GI. As announced on October 17, Germany GI's business operating profit has been impacted by financial adjustments totaling $550 million. We're taking the necessary steps including engaging external experts to validate the remediation actions. We are confident that we have addressed the bulk of the issues and that there are no similar issues of significance elsewhere in General Insurance as I will explain in more detail.</p>
          <p>Of the $550 million adjustment, $426 million are attributable to an increase in claim provisions primarily on long-tail lines of business and hit our loss ratio. The rest is related to our re-assessments of the DAC asset in Germany, impacting our expense ratio. In total, the adjustment impacted the nine-month combined ratio of General Insurance by 2.6 percentage points. You'll find the detailed figures and the impact on the different ratios on the chart on the left.</p>
          <p>Looking at the history for a moment, we identified certain negative developments patterns in Germany back in 2010. Additionally at the time, we were facing operational issues such as low data granularity and old system landscape as well as heavy reliance on manual processes, particularly for IFRS reporting. To address these, we have been implementing a series of management actions. Let me be more specific on some of these.</p>
          <p>We have been in the process of strengthening governance and controls for some time now. The establishment of our Actuarial Center of Excellence and the increasing internal peer reviews helped identify the issues in Germany. Additionally for the past 12 months, we have been moving Germany to a new accounting platform, which handles multiple accounting standards. This is a long process, but the core system will be implemented in early 2013 with further developments during the year.</p>
          <p>In 2011, we began a data improvement project to obtain more granular data and restructure it to get a better understanding of the claims patterns, which has been essentially completed in the third quarter of 2012. Also in 2012, we continued to perform detailed claims reviews in medical malpractice and other long tail lines. We also strengthened senior management with a new CEO, Chief Underwriting Officer and Chief Claims Officer. All these initiatives converged in Q3, leading to the additional financial adjustments required and mentioned before i.e., the claims provision related to prior year reserve developments, stemming from case reserve increases in medical malpractice and IBNR increases, mainly in medical malpractice and architects and engineers over several years.</p>
          <p>To that issue, largely resulted from an incorrect data extraction which has now being fixed. We are confident that we have addressed the bulk of the issues and are conducting further analysis which is expected to be essentially completed by the time we report our year-end results. In addition to that, we conducted a review of General Insurance data quality, the reliance on manual processes, particularly on IFRS accounting, the quality of information flow and control framework, which concluded that among all the large countries, Germany was a unique combination of all these points and therefore, an in isolated case.</p>
          <p>With that, let's go back to General Insurance. We continue to apply rate-tiering strategies and reshape our portfolios in a balanced way to drive profitability. As a result, General Insurance rates increased on average 3.6% in the first nine months of 2012. Let's look at the rate changes of our individual market facing units in more detail.</p>
          <p>Global Corporate with rate increases of 5% for the nine months further improved against the first two quarters, with clearly stronger rate increases in North America, particularly in property, energy, and workers compensation. North America Commercial had a further quarter of strong rate increases, keeping overall rate increase above 4% for the nine months. All major lines of business continued to show rate increases and workers compensation led with a strong increase of over 10%.</p>
          <p>In addition, we saw high rate increases in property, motor and liability. The increases of European Personal Lines of about 3% in the first nine months are mainly due to the continuing rate increases in UK, Germany and Italy Personal Lines, which are driven by the motor books. Rate increases in other lines of business were more moderate, as the pricing is more adequate. Commercial lines in Europe remain stable around 2% for the nine months.</p>
          <p>Now, let's move on to premiums. Global Corporate grew in local currency by 6% for the first nine months. This increase is helped by improved new business with the exposure base increasing in North America, Asia, and the Middle East offset by a reduction in Europe as a result of challenging economic conditions. North America Commercial's growth at 4% for the nine months remains strong.</p>
          <p>The primary drivers are the rising rate environment, successful execution of strategic growth initiatives, such as in real estate, car warranty and program business and the current economic conditions in the U.S., which like in the first half year, also showed through in favorable prior year premiums. Despite the rate increases, we were able to improve customer retention and the amount of new business, thanks to our targeted strategic growth initiatives.</p>
          <p>Turning to Europe, we still face a challenging economic environment in many European countries and we continue to defend our margins with targeted re-underwriting strategies and rate increases. As a result, we see Europe's premiums declining by 2% in local currency for the first nine months. This decline however is more than compensated by our international markets which continued to grow strongly, with gross written premium up by 28% in the first nine months, contributing over 60% of the overall growth.</p>
          <p>This is of course driven by Latin America, both from the Zurich Santander business contributing about $480 million as well as organic growth in Brazil, Mexico, and Argentina particularly, in motor lines. The Asia Pacific region also grew 15% in local currency from our acquisition in Malaysia as well as organic growth in Australia and Japan. The two acquisitions contributed about two thirds of the total $950 million premium growth within international markets.</p>
          <p>Let's move now to the loss ratio. We maintained our underlying loss ratio at the level achieved in the prior quarter and compared to prior year continued to improve it by 2.8 percentage points in the first nine months to 61.6%. This underlying loss ratio includes losses related to the worst U.S. drought in recent history in the amount of about $50 million, which impacted the discrete quarter-by-quarter loss ratio comparison by roughly 1%.</p>
          <p>As the harvest and premiums earning goes on in the fourth quarter, the impact of the drought will also continue to affect our results. The improvement is achieved by virtually all market facing units as re-underwriting, portfolio re-shaping, and rate-tiering actions in the current and prior periods are earning in continuously. The biggest improvements in the underlying loss ratio stem from Global Corporate, where such actions taken in motor, construction and energy lines are showing through. In addition, Zurich Santander also helped to further improve the loss ratio by about 0.5 percentage points.</p>
          <p>Let's continue by looking at the components of the underlying loss ratio. In the second column from the left, you see the year-to-date impact of prior year premiums, which represents the earned element of premiums related to increased exposure on prior year policies, which I have already mentioned in the first two quarters. Moving on to prior year reserve releases, excluding Germany, these amounted to $617 million or 2.9 percentage points of the loss ratio, which is about $300 million lower than last year. Roughly $100 million of the decrease in prior reserve releases was the impact of positive prior year premiums mentioned before.</p>
          <p>The remaining movements from across all of our regions and lines of business are normal for a book of our size. Additionally, the claims provision strengthening for Germany of $426 million contributed two percentage points to the nine months loss ratio and 5.8 points to the discrete Q3 loss ratio of General Insurance.</p>
          <p>Moving on to large losses, in total, these came in at 8.8 percentage points of the loss ratio or 0.3 percentage points below last year. Despite the fact that there were no major catastrophes in the first nine months, there have been some large loss events including the weather events mentioned in the first and second quarters. As you all know, the insurance industry has been hit by Storm Sandy in the fourth quarter. While we are actively assisting our customers on the ground to bring them back to where they belong as fast as possible, it is too early to give any indication on the impact for Zurich. Like with other events or incidents in the past, Zurich is taking a bottom-up approach to assess possible losses and we'll inform the market in due course.</p>
          <p>In summary, the overall reserve adequacy is unchanged. The prior year development is heavily impacted by the financial adjustments in Germany, where actions are being taken, the underlying loss ratio improved by 2.8 percentage points and remained on the low levels achieved in the second quarter. And we see written rate increases overall to exceed our current estimates of loss cost inflation, while re-underwriting actions and previous rate increases are continuing, helping to offset declining investment yields.</p>
          <p>Let's now move to the expense ratio. Our expense ratio for the nine months is at 28.2%, an increase by 1.8 percentage points. The expense ratio is impacted by the financial adjustments in Germany, which contributed 0.6 points for the nine months and 1.7% to the third quarter. Overall commissions as a percentage of net earned premiums are up 1.2 percentage points, the main reasons being the reassessment of deferred acquisition costs in Germany, the Zurich Santander operations, lower ceding commissions, and changes in business mix.</p>
          <p>When discussing the loss ratio and in line with the first two quarters, I mentioned that Zurich Santander's loss ratio was below the average of General Insurance. The flip side to that is that the business also comes with a higher commission structure and with that, an expense ratio above the group average, which contributed about 0.3 percentage points to the increase.</p>
          <p>Tax items are up 0.4 percentage points, driven by the provisions for premium taxes and VAT charged in Germany, following tax rulings which we booked in the third quarter and accounted for 0.3 percentage points in the expense ratio or around $60 million. Other underwriting expenses, which is the element of the expense ratio that we can influence most actively, is up 0.2 percentage points. Main drivers are the accounting charges related to IAS 19 pension costs as well as investments in organic growth initiatives in international markets. Stripping out these items, we continue to benefit from our expense reductions in mature markets.</p>
          <p>Now, let's look at the major drivers of the underwriting and BOP performance by business. As discussed in the previous sections for General Insurance, the underlying loss ratio improved in all market facing units, as re-underwriting, portfolio re-shaping and rate-tiering actions continue to benefit the result. Furthermore, the absence of major catastrophes compared with the first nine months in 2011 was a significant factor. This applies in particular to Global Corporate and international markets and explains a large portion of the improvement in their combined ratio to 90.6% and 97.2% respectively.</p>
          <p>North America Commercial benefited in addition from positive prior year premiums and lower levels of underlying property losses. This and the lower expense ratio due to our ongoing efficiency initiatives were offset by the underwriting loss related to the worst U.S. drought in recent history of around $50 million, adding roughly one percentage point to the nine months combined ratio.</p>
          <p>Europe's combined ratio at 101.7% for the first nine months deteriorated by 4.7 percentage points, with the financial adjustments in Germany contributing 6.2 percentage points. Additionally, as mentioned before, Europe's combined ratio is impacted by the tax charges in Germany by around 0.7 percentage points. Other than that, especially in Europe, we see a continuing underlying improvement of the business.</p>
          <p>With that, let's move on to our Global Life business. The trends in the Global Life segment are consistent with the macroeconomic environment and continue to substantiate our strategy. While economic conditions in Europe continue to be difficult, with low interest rates persisting impacting product demand and margins, we continue to see pockets of growth in the Corporate Life &amp; Pensions market specifically in Switzerland and the UK. We also continued to see strong organic growth in Latin and North America with a net result of this diversification being positive volume growth albeit at a slightly lower overall margin.</p>
          <p>Moving to the slide itself, gross written premiums, policy fees and insurance deposits increased by $1.8 billion to $21.1 billion or by 17% in local currency, benefiting from the Zurich Santander business and higher volumes of single premium business in Corporate Life &amp; Pensions and Private Banking Client Solutions, partly offset by a reduction of single premium retail business in Europe.</p>
          <p>Net inflows to assets under management remain positive both in the third quarter and through the first nine months, at just over $1 billion. The decrease of $524 million compared to last year was driven by net outflows in the UK and Spain. New business margins declined 4.9 percentage points to 21.4%, mainly driven by a reduction of 1.8 percentage points related to the transitional impact of the methodology refinement for corporate protection renewals and a reduction of 2.5 percentage points or seven percentage points for the third quarter, related to the impact from the high volume and lower margin social security transaction in Chile.</p>
          <p>I will talk about the change in new business value, APE new business margin and BOP on the next two slides. New business value in the retail pillars which includes bank distribution, IFA brokers, agents, and international and expatriates, collectively declined by $62 million or 10% in local currency. Geographically, the largest impact to the retail pillars came from continued margin and volume reductions in Germany and Switzerland, as a result of declining interest rates reducing spreads on traditional business.</p>
          <p>We continue to diversify new business away from interest-sensitive products. The agent channel particularly benefited from a strong growth in protection new business margin in North America driven by a combination of growth in the portfolio, price increases and improved utilization of reinsurance. New business margin for the first nine months in the North America agent channel alone was 99%. Within international and expatriates, the single premium business continued to be impacted as our disciplined underwriting standards did not allow us to compete on all product offerings, leading to a decrease of $17 million in new business value.</p>
          <p>Within the Corporate Life &amp; Pensions pillar, the reported new business value declined by $32 million, excluding however, the transitional impact of the refinement in methodology for corporate protection renewals, new business value however grew by 24% in local currency. A sizeable element of the growth in new business value came organically from Latin America where we successfully participated in the biannual social security bid process in Chile, contributing just over $400 million of APE and $19 million to new business value. Other highlights in the pillar were strong growth in savings and protection APE in the UK and corporate protection in Brazil.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to profit by source, in the first nine months, Global Life reported business operating profit declined by 5% in U.S. dollar terms to $959 million, but increased by 1% in local currency. Continued improvement is the expense, risk, and other profit margins offset the decline in the investment margin and a lower net contribution from the impact of acquisition deferrals and special operating items.</p>
          <p>The business in the force expense margin of $1.13 billion increased by $56 million or 11% in local currency as a result of higher fee income generated from high assets under management and higher policy based fees, as we continue to shift from traditional to fee-based business in Europe and a higher unit-linked volumes in APME and the U.S.</p>
          <p>Expenses were flat over the same period in 2011, as higher new business expenses in Latin America, Ireland and the U.S. were partially offset by lower acquisition expenses in the UK and in force expense savings in Spain. The risk margin of $539 million improved $17 million or 9% in local currency, growing in line with our focus on writing protection business and helped by favorable claims experience, particularly in Switzerland, Germany, the UK and the international business sold in the Middle East and Asia.</p>
          <p>The investment margin of $387 million has decreased $169 million or 26% in local currency continuing to be impacted by the low investment yield environment, reducing investment margins across the board, and particularly in the traditional savings business in Germany. In line with our disclosures at the half year results, we added approximately &#x20AC;50 million to the local German statutory Zinszusatzreserve in the discrete quarter, which brought the year-to-date figure to &#x20AC;147 million. This has indirectly contributed to a reduction in the IFRS investment margin of $95 million year-to-date.</p>
          <p>The gross new business strain improved by $65 million to just over $1 billion as increased income from policy based fees particularly in Europe reflected the continued focus on fee income product as part of the Global Life strategy. The increased fee income was however partially offset by higher acquisition expenses in Latin America, Ireland and the U.S. in line with volume growth. Other profit margins improved by $90 million as the inclusion of $130 million from the Zurich Santander insurance businesses before non-controlling interests was partially offset by build out costs in North America and Latin America.</p>
          <p>Special operating items for the third quarter were a negative $17 million, reducing the nine month impact to $39 million. Positive reserve reviews in the UK and modeling changes in North America were more than offset by a Federal Court ruling and VAT settlement charges in Germany as well as IT impairments and a product reclassification in Spain. You can find more details in the appendix regarding the profit by source results by country.</p>
          <p>We are pleased with the progress of the Zurich Santander insurance operations in Latin America. On a statutory basis for the first nine months of the year, we saw an increase in gross written premium and deposits of 8% and an increase in local statutory profit before tax of 20% as well as growth in cash generation as it continues to be able to payout the sizable majority of local statutory profits.</p>
          <p>On the left hand side of the slide, you can see what we have reported in our results for Global Life and General Insurance together. This is the recognition of profits generated since the acquisition dates to the end of June 2012, minus the amortization of the intangibles and IFRS adjustments and the impact of the earn-out interest unwind.</p>
          <p>The core segment BOP increased by $55 million in the quarter to $98 million as the continued finalization of the Zurich Santander accounting treatment resulted in recognizing the performance of certain investment product through investment income, adding up to $12 million. As you would expect with a complex acquisition of this size, we continue to work on embedding the processes required to be able to incorporate the numbers in a timely fashion and we continue to target to catch up the quarter reported in arrears by year-end.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the Farmers segment, Farmers showed a strong performance in the third quarter. The efforts to improve the Farmers Exchanges' combined ratio are showing first results. CAT losses were very benign, and the Fogel class action settlement has become final. Let's look at this in more detail. In the third quarter, the Farmers segment business operating profit increased by 8% to $397 million while it decreased by 9% to $998 million year-to-date due to the losses incurred at Farmers Re in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>Farmers Management Services continues to benefit from the top line growth at the Farmers Exchanges. Its business operating profit increased 5% to $1.1 billion year-to-date. Growth of business operating profit slowed down slightly in the third quarter, mainly due to higher employee benefits, IT expenses and project-related expenses. Farmers Re posted a gain of $42 million in the third quarter. This reduced the loss in business operating profit for the first nine months to $68 million. Farmers Re's combined ratio in the third quarter was 99.3%, bringing it down to 105.2% year-to-date.</p>
          <p>The main driver of the improvement was a favorable CAT experience in the third quarter which amounted to 1.4% compared to 6.7% year-to-date. The third quarter also saw some improvement in the underlying combined ratio when adjusting for prior year developments.</p>
          <p>Let's turn to the Farmers Exchanges. As I already mentioned, the Fogel class action settlement has become final as all appeals were abandoned. The settlement provided for a cash payment of $455 million to the class members who filed claims with any unclaimed amount going to the Farmers Exchanges. This unclaimed amount of $294 million or $191 million after tax was booked as a return of management fees and thus, benefited the Farmers Exchanges' expense and surplus ratio. Year-to-date, the Farmers Exchanges' gross written premiums grew 4.1% to $14.5 billion. This growth is largely driven by the rate actions, which resulted in higher average premiums per policy. Growth of policies in force since year-end 2011 was 0.4% to reach 20.9 million policies.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, policies in-force declined by 0.5% due to the underwriting actions we took in specific areas like in non-standard auto and business insurance sold through the independent agents channel as well as a lower advertising spend in 21st Century Direct. Overall however, retention rates held up well despite the rate increases that we're pushed through. The Farmers Exchanges' third quarter combined ratio improved to 101.2%, bringing the year-to-date combined ratio down to 106.5%. These combined ratios do not include the benefits of the Fogel settlement, which should lower the expense ratio by 6.2 points for the third quarter and 2.1 points for the nine months. Again, favorable CAT experience was the main driver for the improvement in the third quarter combined ratio.</p>
          <p>However, there is also some improvement in the underlying loss ratio showing that the rates and underwriting actions implemented so far are gaining traction. The efforts to improve the profitability of the Farmers Exchanges continue. Filed rate changes in standard auto and home owners increased to 7.9% and 12.2% respectively with a written impact of 5.7% and 6.6%.</p>
          <p>Finally, the Farmers Exchanges' surplus ratio improved to 38.6% as of end September compared to 36.6% as of the end of June. Clearly, this is largely driven by the $191 million post tax benefit from the Fogel settlement. As you would expect, Storm Sandy also affected the Farmers Exchanges and Farmers Re, but it is too early to give any indication of the impact.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at the performance of our group investments. Financial markets in the third quarter saw interest rates overall falling, spreads narrowing and equity markets rising in response to a more supportive policy environment. This in particular had a positive effect on the movements in net unrealized gains of $4.6 billion to reach a total of almost $10 billion for the end of September. As a consequence, total net investment return was 5.3% for the first nine months.</p>
          <p>Net investment income decreased by 7% in dollar terms, but just by 1% on a local currency basis. As in previous periods, this reflects the lower reinvestment yield for debt securities. Net capital gains of $1 billion or lower than in the previous year which benefited from the sale of a stake in New China Life in the second quarter and from significant derivative gains used for economic hedging in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>The current third quarter included some gains realization on our debt and equity portfolios. These realized gains more than offset losses on derivatives. Again, I would like to remind you that the rationale for these derivative positions is strictly to manage risks relative to liabilities. We are satisfied with how our group investments continue to perform, benefiting from our strongly diversified portfolio.</p>
          <p>With that, let's turn to an update of our solvency position. Our capital and solvency position remains strong on all metrics. The internal capital model we use to run our business is Zurich Economic Capital Model, or Z-ECM as we refer to it, increased by seven percentage points over the full-year 2011 to 110% at the half year and is well within our AA target range of 100% to 120%. The SST ratio as filed with FINMA for the half year 2012 decreased by five percentage points to 178%. As we have pointed to in the past, the economic models have different parameters and methodologies which means that they can at times move differently. I would like to take a minute here to highlight the main movements and where the models differ.</p>
          <p>First, the active risk management actions taken in the second quarter to reduce our capital consumption at a greater relative impact on the Z-ECM ratio. This was mainly because the tail risk actions created a larger benefit in the internal model, due to the higher calibration of the model at AA level compared to the SST. Second, the Z-ECM ratio includes the benefit of $700 million of additional eligible debt in 2012. Senior debt does not benefit the SST ratio. Third, the SST includes an uplift for credit migration risk at temporary requirements requested by FINMA while we refine the modeling of this risk.</p>
          <p>Conversely, the downgrade of the peripheral EU states as well as lower yields negatively affected both ratios. These aspects of the capital models can appear to some overly technical. So I would like to just reiterate a few key points. First, we continue to run the business using the Zurich Economic Capital Model, the half year 2012 ratio of 110% is comfortably within our target range. Second, while broadly based on the same principle, capital models can and do at times move in different ways. We expect this to continue especially while FINMAs approval remains provisional and the SST model continues to be refined. The SST ratio continues to remain very strong with available capital, very significantly above the target capital.</p>
          <p>Now, let's turn to shareholders' equity. The balance sheet remains very strong with shareholders' equity increasing 5% to $34 billion, benefiting from just above $800 million increase in unrealized gains, and just under $500 million of net income in the quarter. The increase in shareholders' equity year-to-date has pushed up the average shareholders' equity by $1.2 billion. This combined with a net income declining by around $500 million has resulted in the net income return on common shareholders' equity, reducing from 13.5% a year earlier to 11% for the first nine months of this year. The book value per share has increased by 7% to CHF217.5 compared to year-end 2011.</p>
          <p>In summary, our underlying profitability remains strong. We are taking the necessary steps to address the issues in our German General Insurance business and consider this to be an isolated case. The underlying loss ratio in General Insurance improved significantly over the same period last year, demonstrating the continued focus on profitability.</p>
          <p>The expense and risk margins of the Global Life earnings improved, reflecting the strategic focus on unit-linked and protection business. The Farmers Exchanges' corrective actions to improve their underwriting performance continue and show the first positive impact on the results, benefiting Farmers Re. We were pleased to see the top line premium growth continue, especially in targeted markets with strong growth in the international markets and also select mature markets. We reported a strong capital position with our Z-ECM ratio well within our AA target range. And we remain focused on executing our strategy to deliver our target.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>