<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1537096" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-02-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2568</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer">Martin Senn</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Pierre Wauthier</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to Zurich Insurance Group's results presentation for the 2012 financial year. We are pleased to report solid profitability for the year despite the challenging market environment, the occurrence of Storm Sandy and the disappointing result in our German General Insurance business.</p>
          <p>Our underlying performance was strong with excellent progress in all our core segments. Thanks to our strategic focus on disciplined pricing and portfolio management, we maintained our strong capital base, generated strong cash flows and delivered strong underlying profitability. This gives us the confidence to propose a sustainable and attractive dividend of CHF17 per share. As the dividend payment will be paid from the capital contribution reserve, it is exempt from Swiss withholding tax. We continue to sharpen our focus on insurance while diversifying our business geographically and by product mix, achieving top line growth in target markets and maintaining our position in mature markets.</p>
          <p>In 2012, we further expanded our bank distribution agreements, strengthening alliances in the Middle East, Italy, Spain and Indonesia and continued to progress the integration of our acquired insurance businesses in Latin America and Malaysia.</p>
          <p>In December last year, we announced two further milestones in our strategy to exit non-core businesses. The transfer of Eagle Star's General Insurance portfolio to RiverStone and the return of Zurich Bank's banking license in Ireland.</p>
          <p>We also benefited from a strong performance in our investment portfolio, as our Group investments delivered a total return of 7%, an increase of 1.7 points from 2011. As we reported at our Investor Day in November, we have made solid progress towards delivering on our 2013 targets.</p>
          <p>So let's have a closer look at the numbers. Business operating profit for the year declined 4% to $4.1 billion, while net income after-tax attributable to shareholders was $3.9 billion, up 3% from 2011, reflecting a strong underlying performance in our core businesses and in our investment portfolio, but also losses due to weather-related events and developments in our German General Insurance business.</p>
          <p>In the review of our German General Insurance business, it was determined that a portion of the previously announced financial adjustment was due to material errors in prior years, which requires an accounting restatement. Pierre Wauthier will explain this in greater detail.</p>
          <p>We are pleased that our underlying businesses continue to perform strongly, and make progress towards delivering on our targets. The General Insurance segment delivered a strong underlying performance as gross written premiums rose 7% on a local currency basis on the back of average rate increases of 4%. The underlying loss ratio for General Insurance continued to improve in 2012 and was 61.4% at year-end. Performance was adversely impacted by a continued decline in investment income as well as increases in favorable prior year and the financial adjustments in Germany.</p>
          <p>The segment's combined ratio improved 0.5 percentage points to 98.4%. Global Life maintained profitability with continued growth in gross written premiums, policy fees and insurance deposits. Excluding the recent acquisitions in Latin America and Malaysia, new business value declined by $90 million to $890 million or 5% on a local currency basis, as the slowdown in Europe offset strong growth in Latin America and North America.</p>
          <p>If we include Zurich Santander and Zurich Insurance Malaysia in Asia-Pacific, which generated $195 million of new business in Latin America and Southeast Asia, new business value rose by 11% to $1.1 billion underscoring the growing importance of Global Life's contribution to the Group. The segment continued to diversify the protection and fee-based products, particularly in mature markets and to expand in emerging economies.</p>
          <p>At Farmers, business operating profit in the Management Services company rose 5%, and the margin and gross earned premiums was unchanged at 7.3%, which is above the 7% we expect over the long-term. Our reinsurance operations however had losses, reflecting the second consecutive year of significant weather-related events, and the absence of favorable prior year loss development compared with 2011.</p>
          <p>Finally, our non-core businesses delivered a business operating profit of $128 million, thanks to an increased profit from other run-off businesses. As a result of this solid performance across the Group, we have preserved our excellent capital position, with shareholders' equity increasing by 10% to $34.5 billion. The return on common shareholders' equity for 2012 based on net income attributable to shareholders was a robust 11.8%, while the business operating profit after-tax return on equity was 9.3%.</p>
          <p>Our strong capital position and cash flows gives us the confidence to propose a dividend of CHF17. As this table demonstrates, we have consistently delivered over the years in line with our policy to pay a sustainable, competitive and attractive dividend. We have delivered a strong underlying performance with improved underlying profitability. Our Group continues to generate strong sustainable cash flows. We remain focused on the execution of our strategy. We are growing where we want to grow and we are well capitalized with solvency within our target AA range. We remain committed to delivering sustainable long-term value to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>In closing, I would like to thank all my colleagues around the world whose commitment and dedication has made these results possible. I would also like to thank our customers and shareholders for their continued trust and support. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. As Martin highlighted, we delivered a strong underlying business operating profit in 2012. This is very important to note as the reported results have a lot of moving parts. But the main message is that we're continuing to see the underlying business perform well. There is accelerating top line growth and we generated strong cash flows during the year.</p>
          <p>Before I go into the numbers, you will notice we have restated a portion of the Germany General Insurance adjustments from the third quarter to prior periods. I will give you more details on the next slide and the remarks in my presentation are focused on the reported figures, i.e. after restatement. If we focus now on the fourth quarter BOP overall, the result of $569 million has been negatively impacted by the catastrophe losses and lower favorable prior year developments in General Insurance compared to 2011, with Global Life and Farmers both contributing above last year's fourth quarter results.</p>
          <p>In General Insurance, the fourth quarter underlying performance further improved with an underlying loss ratio at 60.8% for the quarter, a very strong result. But the impact of Storm Sandy, and the fourth quarter Germany reserve strengthening, which I will address in more detail later contributed to a total reduction of BOP of almost $850 million. The full-year performance for General Insurance was down 7% year-on-year and 5% in local currency.</p>
          <p>The Life BOP contributed $380 million, continuing to benefit from the good expense and risk margins and the better investment margins compared to earlier quarters. The full-year performance was down 1% compared to last year, however, up 5% in local currency. And in Farmers, the Management Services company showed healthy profit growth while Farmers Re delivered a profitable quarter despite the losses from Storm Sandy, proving that the underwriting and pricing actions taken by the Farmers Exchanges are starting to take effect.</p>
          <p>For the full-year, Farmers in total was down 5% compared to last year. The slightly higher loss of our other operating businesses is mostly due to less favorable foreign currency movements in 2012, compared to 2011 with the full-year charge increasing by 8%. Non-core businesses performed strongly. The first quarter includes a partial benefit of the announced portfolio transfer of Eagle Star International of $17 million. The remaining benefits of approximately $30 million is expected in 2013. The full-year results of $128 million was driven mainly by the Life businesses included in the other run-off book.</p>
          <p>The Zurich Santander business continues to perform well and in line with our expectations. As planned, the discrete fourth quarter includes the catch-up quarter for Zurich Santander resulting in a contribution for the year of $164 million to Group BOP, and $66 million reported in the fourth quarter representing two quarters. The full-year statutory results for Zurich Santander showed continued growth in both top line and net income as I will discuss in more detail later.</p>
          <p>Turning to net income for the quarter, the strong performance of $983 million reflects the impacts of realized gains that benefited from the strong market valuations, offset by a higher quarterly tax effect relating to the losses from Storm Sandy. The full-year net income of $3.9 billion contributed to the $3 billion increase of shareholders' equity to $34.5 billion during the year.</p>
          <p>The increased equity combined with the reduction in business operating profit has resulted in the business operating profit after-tax return on equity, reducing from 10.2% the year earlier to 9.3% at year-end 2012. We indicated last year that the target of about two points below our strategic 16% ROE target was more realistic, given the low interest rate environment. To provide further clarity about two points in this environment realistically means 13% to 15%. With that overview, let me give you some detail on the periods impacted by the restatement. During the fourth quarter, we determined that a portion of the Germany GI adjustments required restatement to prior periods. On this slide, you see the impact of the accounting restatement for the Group and General Insurance for 2011 and 2012.</p>
          <p>The restatement has two components. The deferred acquisition cost which, as we mentioned in the third quarter, were overstated due to a system error in Germany, and this amounted to $84 million. The remaining portion was on loss reserves, as we determine that improper case-reserving practices had resulted in incorrect amounts being booked. The total of these errors amounted to $264 million in BOP and $194 million in net income.</p>
          <p>In aggregate, they were deemed to be material and needed to be restated in accordance with IFRS accounting standards. The majority of the restatement has impacted the opening shareholders' equity of 2011 by an amount of $187 million. There has been a small restatement of the 2011 P&amp;L, reducing both BOP and net income by under $20 million. In allocating the restatement to prior periods, we are giving a closer view of the underlying performance. We have provided more tables for you in the appendix to show also the impact on the interim periods in 2011 and 2012.</p>
          <p>Let's move now to the General Insurance results. Our General Insurance strategy delivered a strong underlying performance in 2012. We continued our stance on pricing, underwriting discipline, and portfolio management. And we also accelerated top line growth. However, the year was impacted by Storm Sandy and the reserve strengthening in Germany. Gross written premiums increased by 7% in local currency. Our acquisitions in Latin America and Malaysia added about 3 percentage points. The remaining four points are driven by organic growth from rate increases as well as exposure growth particularly in certain lines in North America and also in our international markets.</p>
          <p>But overall, our BOP reduced by 5% in local currency mainly driven by the Germany result and the continuing pressure on the investment income offsetting the benefits from the improved underlying loss ratio. The standalone fourth quarter performance of $21 million was impacted by Storm Sandy reducing BOP by $718 million, and fourth quarter reserve strengthening in Germany of approximately $130 million, partly offset by the continuing improvement in the underlying loss ratio at 60.8% for the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Let's now take a closer look at the specific rates and premium levels. On average, we achieved rate increases of 3.7% in 2012 and we're pleased with the level of rate increases in the various regions.</p>
          <p>Global Corporate achieved strong rate increases of 5% for 2012, particularly in energy and our U.S. books of casualty, workers' compensation and property. Also North America Commercial has strong rate increases of 5% for 2012 with workers' compensation seeing rates up over 10%. The increases of European Personal Lines of about 3% are mainly due to the continuing rate increases in the motor books of UK, Germany and Spain. Commercial Lines rate increases in Europe remained stable at around 2% for 2012.</p>
          <p>Now let's move on to premiums. As already said, overall premium grew by 7% in local currency. The implementation of our customer-focused approach led to certain business transfers between the North American business of Global Corporate and North America Commercial. Global Corporate premium grew in local currency by 9% in 2012 on a comparable basis or 12% as reported, including the business transfers from North America Commercial. The growth was helped by improved new business with the exposure base increasing in North America, Asia and the Middle East.</p>
          <p>North America Commercial's growth was a strong 5% when adjusting for the business transfers I just mentioned. The primary drivers are the rising rate environment, the successful execution of strategic growth initiatives, and the current economic conditions in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Turning to Europe, we still face a challenging economic environment in many European countries, and we continue to defend our margins with targeted re-underwriting strategies and rate increases. As a result in 2012, we saw Europe's premiums declining by 2% in local currency. But this decline is more than compensated by our international markets, which continued to grow significantly with gross written premium up by 34% in 2012 in local currency and contributed more than 60% to GI's total growth. Of course, this is driven by our two acquisitions, which have made up almost two-thirds of our growth in these markets, but also by organic growth in Latin America, especially in our motor books in Brazil and Mexico, as well as in our portfolios in Australia and Japan.</p>
          <p>Let's now move on to the loss ratio. For year-end 2012, we delivered a strong improvement of our underlying loss ratio, which is at 61.4%, 2.9 percentage points better than in 2011. This improvement would be even higher considering that the underlying loss ratio includes the losses related to the worst U.S. drought in recent history, which impacts the loss ratio by 0.7 percentage points and 0.3 percentage points on the combined ratio.</p>
          <p>The improvement was achieved by virtually all our mature market-facing units as re-underwriting, portfolio reshaping, and rate-tiering actions in the current and prior periods continued to deliver. In addition, Zurich Santander also helped to further improve the loss ratio by about 0.8 percentage points.</p>
          <p>Regarding our Germany GI business, we mentioned in the third quarter that we were confident that we had addressed the bulk of the issues. We also mentioned that the review would be ongoing and would essentially be completed by the time we report year-end.</p>
          <p>The analysis in the fourth quarter resulted in an additional increase in claims provision of roughly $60 million for the lines impacted in the third quarter. Additionally, for other lines of businesses, we strengthened our reserve by roughly $70 million incorporating more granular data and normal market development.</p>
          <p>Going forward, this portfolio will revert to a business-as-usual scenario where the risks of adverse development are balanced against the possible benefits of favorable emergence. As it relates to long-tail liability claims in Germany, you should keep in mind that they take approximately 8 years to 12 years on average to settle. They remain uncertain due to the nature of the risks we protect, particularly those relating to legal developments and medical practices going forward. The remaining phase of the review, which was initiated in the second half of 2012 and is not focused on financial items, will be concluded in the next few months.</p>
          <p>We have identified the issues in Germany and are taking appropriate actions to address them. We also remain confident that there are no other material issues of significance elsewhere in General Insurance and Germany remains an isolated case.</p>
          <p>Moving on to prior reserve releases, excluding Germany, these amounted to roughly $950 million or 3.3 percentage points of the loss ratio, which is about $270 million lower than last year. Roughly $100 million of the decrease in prior reserve releases was the impact of positive prior year premiums. The external review on our U.S. asbestos and environmental reserves in the fourth quarter resulted in an increase of prior year reserves of around $100 million. In addition, we experienced releases in the U.S. across various lines of business.</p>
          <p>Major catastrophes includes only the impact of Storm Sandy as communicated in December. Although devastating for our customers, the impact was lower than the significant catastrophe events in 2011. And finally, large losses, in total these came in at 8.6 percentage points of the loss ratio or 0.3 percentage points below last year. As last year, there have been some significant large loss events, including the weather events mentioned in the previous quarters, such as the severe weather in Europe, hailstorms in Germany and Switzerland, and floods in UK and Ireland.</p>
          <p>In the appendix, you will find also an update on our reinsurance program. Overall, we increased retention reflecting our growing property portfolio and the strength of our balance sheet. We have also more coverage in place for sideways and peak risks and we're thus able to reduce capital consumptions in a mostly cost-neutral way.</p>
          <p>Now, let's move to the expense ratio. Our expense ratio increased 1.2 percentage points to 28.1% for the full-year, driven by two key factors. First, overall commissions as a percentage of net earned premiums are up 0.9 percentage points, the main reasons being the Zurich Santander portfolio with a higher commission rate, lower seeding commissions and changes in business mix. And second, tax items are up 0.3 percentage points driven by the provisions for premium taxes and VAT charges in Germany following tax rulings, which we booked in the third quarter and accounted for 0.2 percentage points in the expense ratio or around $60 million.</p>
          <p>Other underwriting expenses, which is the element of the expense ratio that we can influence most actively, were stable. In our mature markets, we continued to achieve benefits from focused expense management and reduced spending in absolute terms. But this progress was masked by higher charges related to pension costs in Europe and the shifting mix of business towards international markets reflecting the investments in organic growth initiatives.</p>
          <p>Now, let's look at the major drivers of the underwriting and BOP performance by business. If you look to the chart on the right, you will see that all our regions report a combined ratio below 100% despite significant one-off impacts. Stripping out the catastrophe impact, the combined ratios of Global Corporate and North America Commercial were around 92% and 95% respectively.</p>
          <p>For North America Commercial, the ratio was achieved despite the higher losses related to the U.S. drought. Europe's combined ratio at 97.4% for 2012 was on a similar level as the previous year despite the third and fourth quarter results in Germany, which contributed 3.5 percentage points after restatement, the third quarter tax charges and the additional IAS 19 pension costs due to lower interest rates.</p>
          <p>For international markets, the improvement in the combined ratio is mainly explained by the absence of major catastrophes compared to last year, but also by an improved underlying loss ratio, particularly in Latin America driven by Zurich Santander.</p>
          <p>So let me summarize our performance in General Insurance. Our underlying loss ratio improved further by 2.9 percentage points, a very strong result. We grew gross written premium by 7% in local currency, despite the subdued macroeconomic environment. We continue to see written rate increases overall to exceed our current estimate of loss cost inflation.</p>
          <p>The prior year development is heavily impacted by the reserve strengthening in Germany in the third and fourth quarter and General Insurance reserves of $55 billion continued to be strong with $0.6 billion of favorable prior year development in 2012 and overall reserve adequacy is unchanged.</p>
          <p>With that, let's move on to our Global Life business. Before going through the numbers, there are three key points that I would like to make. First, the trends in the Global Life segment are consistent with the macroeconomic environment and continue to substantiate our strategy of diversifying geographically and through product mix.</p>
          <p>Second, we have now caught up with the quarter in <mark type="ph" /> arrears (27:30) for the Zurich Santander business in terms of contribution to business operating profit as well as including, for the first time, the market-consistent embedded value and new business value. We have included these numbers where relevant in the presentation. And third, the fourth quarter business operating profit is higher than in previous quarters due in part to the Zurich Santander catch-up, but also due to a significant improvement in the German investment margin following some realization of gains and revised actuarial assumptions.</p>
          <p>Now, let's turn to the numbers. Gross written premium, policy fees and insurance deposits increased by 16% in local currency, benefiting from the Zurich Santander business and higher volumes of single premium business in Corporate Life and Pensions and private banking client solutions reduced by single premium retail business in Europe.</p>
          <p>Net inflows to assets under management remain positive both in the fourth quarter and throughout the full-year at $1.4 billion as net outflows in Europe were more than offset by net inflows in all other regions. APE increased 24% in local currency. Excluding the $737 million contribution from Zurich Santander and Zurich Insurance Malaysia, APE increased by 5% in local currency. This was mainly driven by North America, Latin America and Switzerland supported by some large corporate contracts during the year.</p>
          <p>New business margin decreased by 1.7 percentage points to 22.8%, driven by some offsetting factors. The refinement to corporate protection renewals referred to in previous quarters combined with an impact from the high-volume, lower-margin social security transaction in Chile reduced the margin by over 3 percentage points. On the other hand, we had positive contributions from the acquisitions and underlying improvements in the existing business. New business value including Zurich Santander and Zurich Malaysia increased by 16% in local currency to $1.85 billion, further underscoring the growing importance of the Life business' contribution to the Group.</p>
          <p>Zurich Santander and Zurich Insurance Malaysia contributed $195 million with new business value from ongoing operations amounting to $890 million, a decrease of 5% on the local currency basis.</p>
          <p>Moving on to embedded value. The operating earnings of $1.7 billion represented an operating embedded value return of 11.4%. The return increased 2.8 percentage points over 2011 driven by improved operating variances and expected emergence of value from the in-force. This improvement excludes the contribution from Zurich Santander and Zurich Insurance Malaysia.</p>
          <p>The closing MCEV increased by $3 billion to $18.9 billion. The increase was mainly driven by the improved operating earnings and positive economic variance as well as $1.2 billion for the first-time inclusion of the embedded value for Zurich Santander and Zurich Insurance Malaysia. These increases were partially offset by $0.6 billion of dividends and capital movements as Life business continued to generate and pay out free capital.</p>
          <p>I will talk more about the components of the business operating profit in more detail on the next slide.</p>
          <p>Global Life's full-year business operating profit increased by 5% in local currency to $1.34 billion. This reflects a couple of the key points I pointed out on the previous slide. First, Zurich Santander contributed $105 million to the Global Life business operating profit with $42 million coming in the fourth quarter and representing two quarters.</p>
          <p>Second, as well as the contribution from the Zurich Santander in the fourth quarter, the strong fourth quarter business operating profit of $380 million includes a significant improvement in the German investment margin following some realization of investment gains and revised actuarial assumptions impacting the terminal bonus reserve.</p>
          <p>The business in-force expense margin of $1.4 billion decreased in U.S. dollar terms, but increased by 1% in local currency as higher volume related fee income, particularly in Ireland, the U.S., Spain and the UK was partially offset by higher in-force expenses.</p>
          <p>Expense increases came in the form of IAS19 pension cost in the UK and higher IT cost in Germany, partially offset by expense savings in Switzerland and Spain. The risk margin of $769 million improved by 5% in local currency growing in line with our focus on writing protection business and helped by favorable claims experience particularly in Germany, Latin America and the international business sold in the Middle East and Asia.</p>
          <p>The investment margin of $661 million has decreased by 1% in local currency. The low interest rates continue to pressure the investment margin overall, particularly in North America, APME and Spain, while aforementioned actions in Germany offset some of this pressure. Other profit margins improved by $199 million, as the inclusion of $225 million from Zurich Santander, before non-controlling interests and earn-out interests unwind was partially offset by build-out costs in North America and Latin America.</p>
          <p>The gross new business strain reduced by $107 million to just over $1.4 billion. Increased income from policy-based fees, particularly in the UK, Ireland and Latin America, reflected the continued focus on fee income products. A net decrease in acquisition expenses also contributed to the reduced strain, in line with the reduction in retail volumes, particularly in Germany and the UK. It is worth noting here, that some of this reduction and acquisition expenses is offset in the decrease of the impact of acquisition deferrals.</p>
          <p>Special operating items for the year contributed $18 million, a reduction of $108 million over 2011. Positive reserve reviews in the UK and modeling changes in North America were more than offset by a Federal Court ruling and VAT settlement charges in Germany as well as an IT impairment in Spain.</p>
          <p>You can find more details in the appendix regarding the profit by source results by country.</p>
          <p>In summary then, the Global Life business is delivering on organic growth with improving underlying margins as well as benefiting from the integration of the newly acquired businesses in Latin America and in Malaysia. The expense and risk margins in the business operating profit continued to improve reflecting the focus on fee-based and protection business offsetting the decline in the investment margin.</p>
          <p>The Life business continue to grow and generate healthy free capital and cash supporting the Group's sustainable dividend policy.</p>
          <p>Let's now move to an update on Santander. We continue to be pleased with the progress of the Zurich Santander insurance operations in Latin America. On a statutory basis for the full-year, we saw an increase in gross written premiums of 12%, offset by a decline in lower margin deposits of 5% resulting in an overall growth of 4%, while the local statutory profit before tax grew by 16%. Cash remittance to the center represented $130 million as the business continues to be able to pay out the sizeable majority of the local statutory profits.</p>
          <p>We have now caught up the quarter in the arrears, meaning that the full-year 2012 results combined with a partial quarter in 2011 have been included in the full-year accounts. The result is that the core segment BOP increased by $66 million in the quarter to $164 million as we continued to make adjustments to the accounts to reflect our BOP policy and to the earn-out interest unwind and purchase adjustments.</p>
          <p>In addition to catching up with the quarter in arrears in the IFRS accounts, we have also included Zurich Santander in the MCEV at $820 million for 51%, with $182 million of NBV at 100%.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the Farmers segments. Let me first make a few points about Farmers to put the numbers in perspective. The fourth quarter was the strongest in the year, helped by pension settlement at Farmers Management Services and an improved loss ratio at Farmers Re despite the impact of Storm Sandy. At the Farmers Exchanges, rate and underwriting actions continue. While they start to show the desired impact on combined ratio, new business generation was subdued overall.</p>
          <p>Let's now look at the figures in detail. Farmers business operating profit declined 5% to $1.4 billion for the full-year, but increased 7% to $416 million in the fourth quarter. This reflects a strong result achieved by Farmers Management Services and the losses incurred by Farmers Re in the first half of the year, largely recovered in the second half. Premium growth at Farmers Exchanges continued to drive Farmers Management Services results with its profit increasing by 5% to $1.4 billion.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter business operating profit of $375 million was particularly strong, which also reflects a favorable pension settlement of $19 million. The managed gross earned premium margin remained at a level of 7.3%, which is above the 7% we expect over the long-term. Farmers Re incurred a business operating loss of $26 million over the year driven by its combined ratio of 103.7%, but had a good fourth quarter posting a business operating profit of $42 million as it's combined ratio improved to 99.3%. This combined ratio is virtually at the same level as the previous year's fourth quarter, which was almost catastrophe-free. This shows a marked improvement in the underlying combined ratio. The loss estimate booked for Storm Sandy improved slightly to $36 million from the previously communicated estimate of $40 million.</p>
          <p>Farmers Re participation in the All Lines Quota Share reinsurance treaty was reduced to 18.5% from 20% as of the 31 of December 2012 and the participation in the Auto Physical Damage reinsurance treaty to $925 million from $1 billion as of the 1 of January 2013, but the capital support to the Farmers Exchanges remained unchanged as a global reinsurer took up the difference of 1.5%.</p>
          <p>Even though Farmers Re's capacity commitment to the Farmers Exchanges did not materially change adding a new counterparty provides flexibility and counterparty diversification to the exchanges. Now let's turn to the Farmers Exchanges. The first thing I want to draw your attention to in this slide is that the Farmers Exchanges 2012 figures reflect two settlements, the Fogel class action settlement. This has finally been settled with Farmers Exchanges receiving a fee refund, and in the fourth quarter the anticipated settlement of a Texas State homeowners pricing litigation case with the Farmers Exchanges. These impacts favorably the combined ratio by approximately 1 percentage point. The second point I would like to highlight is that even excluding these settlements the Farmers Exchanges combined ratio improved by one point in 2012 to 105.4% with an acceleration in the fourth quarter to 102.4%, a 1.9 percentage point reduction over the same period in 2011.</p>
          <p>Going back to the Texas case, it was originally filed in 2002 and an initial settlement was reached in 2003. It is now approaching final approval. The settlement has no impact on the Farmers Exchanges surplus as a legal contingency accrual had been set up in previous years, but it does result in $74 million of return premiums charged against current premiums.</p>
          <p>Growth rates and ratios of Farmers Exchanges that I will discuss now are excluding the impact of the settlements. Farmers Exchanges gross written premiums grew 3.9% to $19 billion. This growth was driven by higher average premiums per policy reflecting the significant rate action taken with approved rate of 12% in standard auto and 15% in homeowners. Policies in-force declined 1.3% in the fourth quarter and 0.9% over the year. These reductions predominantly occurred in those business areas where strict underwriting and rate actions were taken. Shaping out non-standard auto for example, policies in-force actually would have increased by 0.7% over the year.</p>
          <p>While the retention held up well for standard auto and homeowners, new business was weak in light of the rate increases push through. Lower marketing spend also negatively impacted new business and 21 Century Direct. But cross-selling efforts generated $289 million of premiums in 2012 compared to $174 million in 2011. While the rate and underwriting actions took a toll on policies in-force and lower new business production, these actions are improving the combined ratio. The full-year combined ratio landed at 105.4% and 102.4% for the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>I have already mentioned that the capital support provided by the two quota share treaties remains unchanged. The year-end Farmers Exchanges surplus ratio at 38.4% remains well within the target range. In summary, Farmers delivered a good result in 2012 in light of another year with above average catastrophe losses. At the Farmers Exchanges rate and underwriting actions showed first positive results.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at the performance of our Group investments. Financial markets throughout the year and also in the fourth quarter were relatively friendly. In the last quarter, equity markets rose further and credit spreads narrowed particularly on peripheral Eurozone sovereign debt. The historically low interest rate levels led to a decline in net investment income by 7% in dollar terms and 2% on a local currency basis driven by lower reinvestment yields for debt securities.</p>
          <p>Net capital gains remain virtually unchanged at $2.2 billion. In 2011, there were gains on sale of part of our stake in New China Life and our derivative positions used for hedging economic risks. In 2012, sales of securities again contributed to our total net capital gains, especially in the fourth quarter as our asset managers rebalanced our portfolios after a prolonged period of improving markets.</p>
          <p>Looking at our results, the market developments in 2012 resulted in increased net unrealized gains of $5.3 billon despite the capital gains realizations I just mentioned. Unrealized gains reached a 10-year high of $10.7 billion. As a result, total net investment return reached 7% in 2012, markedly higher than the strong 5.3% already achieved in 2011, representing a strong out-performance of our assets relative to our liabilities.</p>
          <p>Overall, we're very satisfied with how our Group investment performed and believe that this result is a consequence of both favorable market conditions and a continued commitment to a disciplined investment approach.</p>
          <p>With that let's turn to an update of our shareholders' equity. As Martin already mentioned, we have proposed a dividend of CHF17 which we expect will maintain Zurich's position as one of the top dividend payers in the sector. As with last year, the dividend will be paid out of additional paid-in capital and therefore free of Swiss withholding tax.</p>
          <p>As clearly stated throughout 2012, our dividend policy remains to pay a sustainable and attractive divided. This means our decision is not driven by a specific payout ratio or yield but our intention is to pay a dividend which is sustainable and therefore reflects our confidence in our cash flows and our expectation for future profit growth.</p>
          <p>For 2012, the net cash flows from the businesses amounted to roughly $4 billion as forecasted at our Investor Day in November, providing healthy cash coverage of the dividend. The balance sheet remains very strong with shareholders' equity at $34.5 billion for the full-year and the book value per share increasing by 6% to CHF214.8 compared to year-end 2011 or 8% at a constant FX rate.</p>
          <p>The capital position as of July 1 of 2012, the last reporting date, also remained strong with the Zurich ECM ratio at 110% well within our AA target range and the SST ratio at a 178%. As a reminder, both ratios will be updated for the full-year at the first quarter of 2013 report.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, we are pleased to propose a dividend of CHF17 supported by our performance last year, which I would like to summarize. Our underlying profitability continues to be strong. In General Insurance, our underlying loss ratio improved further to 60.8% in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>In Global Life, new business value grew by 16% in local currency including Zurich Santander and Zurich Insurance Malaysia. And in Farmers, we saw the corrected actions taken by the Exchanges improving the fourth quarter combined ratio of Farmers Re to 99.3%.</p>
          <p>We were pleased to see overall top line growth continuing across the Group and our investment performance was excellent. We continue to have a strong balance sheet with $34.5 billion in equity and $4 billion of cash flows to support our dividend, demonstrating our sustainable commitment to our shareholders. This will provides the evidence that we're progressing on our strategy to deliver our 2013 targets.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>