<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1246412" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2568</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Malcolm Gilbert, Head of Investor Relations &amp; Rating Agencies</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">James J. Schiro, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Dieter Wemmer, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Michael Klien</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="5">Spencer Hogan</participant>
      <participant id="6">Andrew Broadfield</participant>
      <participant id="7">William Hawkins</participant>
      <participant id="8">Fabrizio Croce</participant>
      <participant id="9">Brian Shea</participant>
      <participant id="10">John Amore</participant>
      <participant id="11">James Quinn</participant>
      <participant id="12">Paul Goodhind</participant>
      <participant id="13">Michael Huttner</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. I think we are ready to start now. And welcome to Zurich's Half Year 2009 Results Presentation. Can you please make sure if you are in the room, you have your phones switched off? And I would refer you to the Slide Two, the disclaimer cautionary statement.</p>
          <p>Today we have CEO, James Schiro; CFO, Dieter Wemmer, who will take you through the results and then we will have the Q&amp;A after both presentations. So without further ado, I hand over to Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Malcolm. Welcome to Zurich's half year 2009 results announcement. I am pleased to report an outstanding set of operating results. Amidst some of the most volatile markets anyone has experienced, we are effectively managing our way through this crisis, positioning ourselves to enter the recovery period from a position of strength.</p>
          <p>But as we look at the second quarter results, let me remind you that that recent upturn of the capital markets only brings us to the year-end 2008 levels. It does not bring us back to the pre-crisis financial market valuations or the pre-crisis consumer confidence levels.</p>
          <p>This is an important reality to keep in mind. It underscores why we believe these are such outstanding results. Since the financial crisis began in earnest in the latter half of 2008, all sectors of the global economy have struggled with the business and financial implications of the greatest economic dislocations in a generation. For insurers, those impacts have been most acutely felt through reduced investment earnings, slower economic activity and cautious customer behaviors.</p>
          <p>Over the past several quarters, Zurich too has been impacted with our $185 billion investment portfolio suffering impairments and our tens of millions of customers feeling the effects of the recession, some more acutely than others. But by leveraging the execution culture embodied through the Zurich Way, we are reacted to proactively manage those factors that were within our control, ranging from our risk tolerance and investment exposures to our expense base and product portfolio. As a result, I'm proud to announce our 26th straight quarter of profitability and our third consecutive quarter of increased profitability.</p>
          <p>Net income for the six months was 1.3 billion, of which, close to 900 million was generated in the second quarter alone, nearly 150% increase over the first quarter's earnings. Similarly, business operating profit for the first half was 2.6 billion, 1.5 billion of which was earned in the second quarter, representing a 46% increase over the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Based on the strengths of these results, we continue to meet our mid-term target, generating a 16.6% business operating profit post-tax return. Furthermore, despite the ongoing financial pressure, we increased our shareholder's equity by 14% and strengthened our Solvency 1 ratio to 180%, showing the value of a sophisticated and transparent approach to capital management.</p>
          <p>Our ability to achieve such strong results is rooted in the disciplined approach we take to operational and financial issues and our commitment to control those factors of success that are within our ability to influence.</p>
          <p>On the rates we charge, it means we have systematically gone about making the price of risk more transparent to our customers, refusing to chase volume at the expense of profitability. As a result, we are seeing continued and widespread improvements in rates, from a 1% improvement in the fourth quarter to a 2% in the first quarter, to a 4% in the most recent quarter. These results are a testament to our success and lead the market efforts and directly reflect the disciplined approach we take to putting risks on our book.</p>
          <p>On the products we sell, to which customers. It means our global life business continued to shift its focus towards more protection business, while accelerating growth in its banking distribution and other significant pillars. Both APE and new business values are up in local currencies and with a new business margin holding at a solid 21%.</p>
          <p>And how we invest the revenues on the business generated. It means our strict approach to managing assets relative to liabilities on a risk-adjusted basis, maintained its long-term view on asset allocations, generating a non-annualized 1.6% total investment return.</p>
          <p>Last, on how we manage our operating cost. Controlling what we can influence means that we remain well on target to achieve both our 900 million Zurich Way improvement target and the 400 million expense reductions target, illustrating just how valuable operating efficiency can prove in challenging markets. In fact, despite the defensive nature of some of our tactical responses to the crisis, we continue to capitalize proactively on market opportunities that emerge, positioning us well for when, not if, economic activity returns to pre-crisis levels.</p>
          <p>For example, our integration of AIG's personal auto group is in line with our plans and when done, will propel Farmers into the leading ranks of the direct auto market and solidify its position as the third largest personal lines insurer in America.</p>
          <p>However, we have also been making other investments in long-term sustainable growth, driving the Zurich HelpPoint concept deeper into our proposition development processes, improving our capabilities to deliver on our customers needs and broadening our product range.</p>
          <p>None of these action steps or financial achievements would be possible, however, without the motivation and commitment of 60,000 Zurich employees around the world. It is a testament to their effectiveness that we entered this financial crisis with the fundamentals intact and with the institutional means to respond and adapt the prevailing market conditions. Their immense capabilities are also evident in the series of internal appointments we have announced recently in the U.S., Europe, South Africa and elsewhere, illustrating the depth of our bench strength and the success of our ongoing talent management efforts.</p>
          <p>Needless to say, I'm proud of these results, and the efforts our people undertook to make them possible. I'm also confident in our ability to continually proactively manage our through this financial crisis in a manner that will deliver strong results, while positioning us to enter the recovery period from our position of strength.</p>
          <p>To achieve this, we will continue to pursue operational transformation as we enter the second and third waves of our target operating model initiative. We will continue to exercise a disciplined approach to rates, balancing the needs of our customers with the economics of risk. And we will continue to pursue opportunities for growth, both organic and through acquisitions, if they meet our strict financial and strategic targets.</p>
          <p>There is no question, these are certainly challenging times and Zurich has not been immune from the pressures of this marketplace. But we entered this crisis prepared. And I'm confident that we will exit it even stronger.</p>
          <p>And now to give you a more detailed review of these financial results, I hand it over to our Chief Financial Officer, Dieter Wemmer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>So thank you, Jim, and good morning, ladies and gentlemen. As Jim has said, looking at our overall results and year-on-year comparison does not put our half year 2009 results into the proper context.</p>
          <p>The simple picture which the first slide illustrates is the steady recovery of the operating profit and net income over the last three quarters from the effect of the financial markets. Even in the weakest quarter, we made profit and although the numbers dropped, at no time was integrity of the Group capital or solvency position threatened. This, as we have said before, is not a lucky accident. Our balance approach to the business and to risk management and our diversification of risk has paid off in this stressed situation.</p>
          <p>We don't assume we are at the end of the crisis and continue to manage the risk profile of the Group carefully. However, the improving markets through the second quarter and into July continue to further consolidate the position.</p>
          <p>The other theme I will refer to as we go through the numbers as the resilience of the operating business. In fact, a number of areas are showing signs of improving results from recent quarters independent of financial market volatility. In addition, we are well on track to achieve our 2009 Zurich Way targets and actions have been taken to achieve additional expense reduction of at least $400 million during 2009. So the effect of this is beginning to show through in the expense base of all our operating segments.</p>
          <p>So we are pleased to have announced another solid operating performance with business operating profit for the quarter of $1.5 billion and once again, business operating profit after tax ROE over our 16% mid-term target. The underlying strength of the operating profit can be seen on the next slide.</p>
          <p>The core operating businesses achieved a BOP of just over $2.8 billion, down 19% from half year last year. This is mainly driven by currency effects, accounting for six percentage points, financial market impact, accounting for about two percentage points, as well as lower investment income, particularly in our general insurance segment, which suffers more from falling interest rates at the short end of the interest curve. So non-core business was again where the financial market impact most affected the operating profit.</p>
          <p>I will now go through the detail by segment of the operating results, starting as usually with our top-line on Page Nine. We continue to achieve profitable growth in selected areas of business, but have seen top-line reductions in some areas where levels of insured exposures were down due to the economic environment or where we lost business, when we were not able to achieve the rates necessary to maintain our margins.</p>
          <p>For general insurance, gross-written premium decreased by only 2% in local currency, due to a small increase in the second quarter following a 3% reduction in the first quarter. Global Corporate and International markets achieved local currency growth, while Europe General Insurance is largely flat.</p>
          <p>However, during the second quarter, our top-line in Europe started to be impacted by the economic downturn. For example, this manifested itself in Personal Lines motor in the U.K. and Spain. In North America Commercial, we are continuing to manage for margin in an environment with falling levels of insured customers' exposures.</p>
          <p>Again, the second quarter showed a recovery compared with the first quarter. Gross written premium reduced by 10% for North America Commercial in the six months, with the second quarter being down less than 7% compared to 14% in the first quarter, this in spite of the continuing effects of lower economic activity, mostly in the automotive and construction industry which we talked about in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to Global Life, new business volume grew by 19% in local currency, a good result in the challenging financial markets. The business acquired in Spain in the third quarter 2008 contributed $390 million, representing 20% of our new business in the first six months. This combined with growth in market share helped to offset the general decline in many markets. Additionally, the net policyholder cash flow further increased during the second quarter and now exceeds positive 1.5 billion inflow year-to-date. You can find details on this on Page 43 of the appendix.</p>
          <p>Farmers Management Services saw also growth in fees of 4%. This was driven by premium growth at the exchanges largely supported by the transfer of the small business portfolio from North America Commercial starting a year ago. Farmers Re gross-written premium has increased as the Quota Share reinsurance treaty with the exchanges, as already reported, was increased from five to 25% in September last year and then following to 37.5% from June 30 on.</p>
          <p>Let's move on to look at the general insurance segment in more detail on Slide 10 with the rate change monitor. I am very happy to tell you that overall, our general insurance rates continued the upward trend observed in the last couple of quarters. Year-to-date, average rates are 3% up for the segment, as a result of a discreet quarter improvement of over 4% compared to 2% in the first quarter and 1% in the last quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>These improvements are the direct result of our lead markets initiative, launched late last year. Our approach to rate increase is a differentiated one, responding to individual risk characteristics and is based on underwriting and pricing discipline rather than on volume management.</p>
          <p>This holds true not only for our renewed business reflected in the rate change monitor, but equally so for our new business, where we apply the same pricing methodologies based on technical price. We have observed that's a main focus and the commercial market appears to be on renewal rates, while the approach to new business pricing seems to be a less disciplined in the industry in general.</p>
          <p>Starting with Global Corporate, the overall rates are up by over 5%. As expected, our North American unit is leading the way with 9% increases, but equally encouraging in the U.K. result, where rates are up by 7%. So that's a view of global corporate, it's up 2%, but this is in marketplaces where earlier year's reduction were much less pronounced.</p>
          <p>In North America Commercial, we have achieved higher rate increases compare to earlier quarters, in spite of the continuing pressure from the economic environment. Year-to-date rates are up by 3%, a clear improvement to the 2% in the first quarter. And our European personal lines see overall increase of 2% is driven by the U.K., with Spain and Italy improving on the first quarter performance. In our Commercial business there, the rate increases continue to be around 2%. In international market, the change in commercial line rates is mostly attributable to the Australian unit, where we continue to push for improvement started last year.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to Slide 11, to dive into our General Insurance key performance indicators. General Insurance continues to deliver strong operating results, with the net underwriting results mostly flat in local currency. The business operating profit decreased by 23% year-on-year or 16% in local currency. As I said before, this reduction is driven by the investment income but also by non-technical result. A small amount arises from the effect in yield from reinvested assets and assets invested in the period. Also, we have seen a step change in investment income due to the $1.3 billion repatriation of capital from the U.K. to the group and lower returns from repo activities.</p>
          <p>Expressed in local currency and net of the effect of repos, the investment income explains roughly half of the drop in business operating profit and the non-technical result largely explains the remaining balance. The non-technical result is always driven by non-recurring items, which will always show some volatility. In 2008, we experienced a significant number of positive items whereas in 2009, our experience so far has been less favorable.</p>
          <p>In total, the combined ratio was flat year-on-year at 96.2%, with North America Commercial largely flat and Global Corporate improving significantly, the latter due to much a lower share of large and mid-size losses compared to 2008. In international market, we experienced the opposite with a higher proportional of large losses in Mexico and Australia, the latter due to the bush fires earlier this year.</p>
          <p>Also offsetting the improvement in Global Corporate was Europe General Insurance where we, apart from higher large losses, also experienced a deterioration in our motor portfolio in Italy. As you know, there is a market-wide issue in Italy that is mainly due to a court decision on bodily injury compensation levels, changes in the regulation which impacting rating schemes and the reporting pattern of claims.</p>
          <p>As mentioned in May, we are addressing the situation. We have strengthened the local management team. We are improving our risk selection process and we have started to increase rates, both on April 1 and July 1.</p>
          <p>Moving on, I will now go into more detail around the expense ratio development. The expense ratio is flat year-on-year, at the same time as we continue to invest in operational transformation and profitable growth.</p>
          <p>As you can see from the graph, the increase in the commission ratio is compensated by lower premium tax and improvement in our managed expenses. The commission ratio increased by 0.4 percentage points, mainly as a result of change in business mix.</p>
          <p>Business mix is also the major reason for the 0.2 percentage point reduction in premium taxes. Our other underwriting expenses ratio reduced by 20 basis points and the driver include a total head count reduction in General Insurance by 1,500 people since the beginning of year, equivalent to 4%. Our 2009 expense saving initiative of a General Insurance target around 60% which are starting to show. This is evident when looking at this item, other underwriting expenses, which improved compared to the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Now let's have a more &#x2013; closer look to the loss ratio. The overall half year loss ratio for General Insurance is largely unchanged, as is the underlying loss ratio. This result is very much encouraging, since we expect higher rate levels to continue to come through in the upcoming quarters.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the details, the large losses are around 300 million lower this year. As I mentioned, since it's driven by Global Corporate, where the large loss experience returned to more normal levels, after seeing a higher frequency of large losses in the first six months in 2008.</p>
          <p>North America Commercial also experienced lower large losses. Offsetting this are the prior year reserve releases, which are lower year-on-year. As you know, this component is made up of a large number of movements across all our units. Our reserving policy remains unchanged and the variation of $114 million in first quarter and 281 million in the second quarter is simply a normal variation of the numbers for a large reserve portfolios like ours.</p>
          <p>With that, it's now time to look at our reinsurance program on Slide 14. As you all know, the Atlantic hurricane season officially started on June 1 and therefore, I will give you an update on our reinsurance protection for major catastrophes. The structure is made up by three independent towers of regional catastrophic covers, the U.S., Europe and rest of the world.</p>
          <p>We buy our reinsurance on an economic basis and the primary aim is to protect our balance sheet and solvency. The regions have similar structures and coverage, but the limits vary in accordance to the economic risks for each region.</p>
          <p>As you can see on this slide, Europe has the largest individual cover which represents the fact that our largest CAT exposure is still European windstorm. It is worth pointing out that in the U.S. and European tower, Zurich retains part of the risk to its co-participation. The co-participation varies depending on layer, but on average, Zurich's share is 19% of the U.S. treaty and 15% of the European Tower.</p>
          <p>A final clarification worth making is around a new component of our catastrophe cover. This year, we have agreed to a risk swap with a major Japanese carrier. We have assumed the risk of a $100 million cover for a Japanese typhoon. In exchange, we receive a corresponding cover for U.S. windstorm. The reasons behind the swap are that reinsurance capacity has become scarcer, cover more expensive and reinsurer counterparty risk has increased since last year. Through the diversification benefit achieved by swapping a peak risk for a non-peak risk, this is economically very attractive to both us and our counterparty.</p>
          <p>This concludes the General Insurance part and we can now move to have a look at our Life business. As I mentioned before, new business growth of 19% in local currency reflects the volumes from the businesses acquired last year in Spain. In total, on a like-on-like comparison, the annual premium equivalent volume was flat year-on-year in a difficult market environment.</p>
          <p>By country, we are particularly pleased with the performance in Ireland, where we saw a flight to quality and grew 3% in local currencies in a market that has declined over 40%, ensuring obviously further gains in market share. We also saw growth in Latin America, balancing challenges in emerging markets and Asia.</p>
          <p>The new business margin at 21% overall remained at our target level. We are increasing our focus on protection and long-term savings in response to changing market conditions. Obviously the lower interest rates impacted the profitability of guaranteed savings products in Germany and Switzerland.</p>
          <p>The strength of the Zurich brand allowed us to maintain our premium rates while building market share. This combined with the strong expense control allowed us to keep our profitability high. In addition, Global Life is benefiting from cost reductions in several areas including headcounts and discretionary spending.</p>
          <p>The growth and sustained margin resulted in a new business value of $332 million, up 9% in local currency. This value was driven by volume growth in Spain and Latin America and improved margins in Farmers, U.K., Ireland and Australia. Business operating profit of 641 million decreased by 17% in dollar terms, and only 5% in local currency.</p>
          <p>The half year result was adversely affected by the ongoing weakness in the investment markets, partially compensated by a reduction in U.K. policyholder tax reported already at the first quarter, and by refinement of assumptions and methodology impacting the amortization of intangibles. Overall, the half year result includes a net one-off positive impact of roughly $70 million.</p>
          <p>Now turning to page 16, we see more details on the Global Life new business volumes. Bank distribution continues to be the main growth driver, principally from the acquisitions in Spain. The growth in both Banco Sabadell and Caixa Sabadell continues to exceed our business plan expectations.</p>
          <p>The Corporate Life and Pension pillar increased 43% in local currency terms, driven by strong sales of protection business to international groups and from local protection business sold in Ireland, Latin America and the U.K.</p>
          <p>The IFA/Brokers pillar increased by 1% in local currency, despite tough market conditions. Growth was supported by the U.K., driven from successful pension sales and an increase in our broker relationship managers. For both our Agents and International/Expatriates pillar, many territories continue to be resilient in the economic conditions. However, our Hong Kong business, both domestic and the international expat business were significantly affected by a fall in consumer appetite for unit-linked insurance products.</p>
          <p>Now turning to page 17 and the embedded value results for our Life business. We continue to calculate our embedded value on a market-consistent basis. Because of market disruption in December 2008, we used average volatilities at the year end to measure the cost of financial options and guarantees. As markets have normalized, we have reverted to spot volatilities for the half year.</p>
          <p>In addition, we have replaced the cost of non-market risk based on European embedded value principle standards with the more sophisticated cost of residual non-hedgeable risks, in line with MCEV principles. We have also aligned our calculation of frictional costs, so that it reflects required capital rather than available capital. The impact of these methodological changes is plus $170 million. These changes position us to make the final minor changes to disclosure by the year end to be fully compliant with MCEV principles.</p>
          <p>Embedded value operating profit increased by 8% to $962 million, representing an annualized operating return on embedded value of 13% for the half year. This reflects the continued strength in new business value as well as the effects of the MCEV changes I just referred to. The negative economic variance of $273 million was largely driven by the effect of investment markets, particular in the U.K.</p>
          <p>Now turning to Farmers Management Services. The gross management result has increased by 6%, driven by two factors. Firstly, management fees are up 4%, reflecting the underlying premium growth at the exchanges, to which I will come to in a minute. Secondly, corresponding management expenses are up only 2% driven by our expense initiatives. As a result, the margin on gross &#x2013; on premiums increased by 20 basis points to 7.3%.</p>
          <p>Looking at the business operating profit at the bottom of the slide, it increased by 4% to $643 million. The increased management results was partially offset by lower investment income, largely as a result of higher dividend and cash transfers to the group, which lowered the average investment base.</p>
          <p>With that, let's move to the performance of the Farmers Reinsurance on the next slide, number 19. There are two factors driving the $2 billion increase in the gross written premium of Farmers Re. Firstly, the increase from 5 to 25% in the All Lines Quota Share Reinsurance Treaty in September last year. Secondly, the increase from 25 to 37.5%, which was effective from 30th June, generating a gross written premium portfolio transfer of 700 million.</p>
          <p>This transfer has not affected earned premium or profit in the first half year. This portfolio transfer is only in respect of the 12.5 percentage point uplift on the existing business of the exchanges and not the business bought from AIG, which will be accounted for from third quarter onwards. The loss ratio of 70.1% was 1.8 points better than the first half year last year, despite a higher level of catastrophes from the hailstorms already reported in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the exchange results, the Farmers exchanges, which we manage but do not own, have maintained their strong growth track record, which started back in 2006. They continue the transfer of the small business portfolio from North America Commercial, started in June 2008, which added 300 million in premium.</p>
          <p>Excluding the small business transfer, the exchanges achieved largely a flat top line overall in an overall contracting market. The adjusted combined ratio is 92.1%, 4.9 percentage points better than half year 2008. 1.5 points of this are due to lower catastrophe experience and the balance is driven by price increases, earning through and improving loss trends on the motor book.</p>
          <p>As to our 2008, the exchanges have continued to lead the market in 2009 by taking rate increases of 4% overall. Net surplus increased by $95 million, excluding the effect of the portfolio transfer due to our Quota Share uplift, which would give another $90 million increase, although this will be offset in the third quarter by the effect of the AIG transaction. Until the full effects of the acquisitions are taking into the exchanges books, there will be some volatility around the published surplus ratio.</p>
          <p>Now let me update you on the acquisitions of AIG's Personal Auto Group. As announced, we closed the transaction on July 1, 2009, with slightly updated terms. We reduced the initial Quota Share Reinsurance Treaty to 37.5 instead of 40% and the capital note to 200 million instead of 400 million.</p>
          <p>As you can see, AIG Personal Auto Group wrote over $1.3 billion of premium during the first half of 2009, 80% of which was from the direct channel. The AIG book of business has experienced lower retention and new business, but if you take a look at the underlying performance, the combined ratio continues to improve, due to expense and underwriting actions undertaken.</p>
          <p>Let's now look at the integration status. The integration planning started quickly after the April deal signing, particularly in the areas of finance and shared services. Since the deal closed, detailed business and functional work-streams have commenced. These work-streams are focused towards addressing areas of business and expense synergies as well as strategic planning and execution of cross-selling with Farmers' exclusive agents. While we expect a certain amount of restructuring activities to result in charges primarily in the third and fourth quarter of 2009, this acquisition remains on track to achieve earrings per share accretion in the first 12 months.</p>
          <p>Turning now to look at the performance of other operating and non-core businesses on the next slide. Other operating businesses include the operations previously described as corporate functions, as well as our banking operations. As we reported previously, there was a gain of $52 million in the first quarter on buying back some subordinated debt. This &#x2013; in addition interest charges were lower in 2009 on short-term borrowings.</p>
          <p>On the banking side, increased loan provisions explained the profit reduction of $63 million. The non-core business segment has shown the most volatility from financial markets, with approximately $300 million being charged to P&amp;L through operating profit in the first quarter and the recovery of $243 million largely reversing that position in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Looking at the specific components, in Centre, the spread mismatch suffered in previous quarters reduced in the second quarter and Centre achieved a profit of $57 million for the first six months. In centrally managed business, financial market recoveries in the second quarter were offset by a strengthening of reserves in the U.S. run-off life business.</p>
          <p>Looking now at the performance of our group investments on Slide 24. Net investment income decreased by 14% in dollar terms, but this was a decrease of 4% in local currency, driven by lower dividends on equities and reinvestment at lower interest rates. Net capital losses for P&amp;L were $1.3 billion; of this, the second quarter charge was about 300 million, largely driven by impairments. You can find further details in the appendix on Page 55.</p>
          <p>As a result, net investment returns for P&amp;L was a positive 1.3% in the first six months. Changes in unrealized losses on investments included in equity were another positive of 600 million, so that total investment return, not annualized, amounted to 1.6% for this period, a strong result taking into account that government bonds lost in value due to rate movements. The key principles of Zurich's disciplined investment approach are unchanged and you can find further details in the appendix as usual.</p>
          <p>Our equity exposure is well-controlled and amounted to 2.8% at the end of June, taking into account our hedging programs, which protect about 12% of our equity exposure. As equity markets have recovered in the second quarter, equities have increased in value by about half a billion, but more to that in just a minute.</p>
          <p>Looking at the aging of our unrealized losses on common stocks in light of our impairment policy, in the very hypothetical case that all stock prices were frozen at June 30, 2009 position, we would expect further impact on common stocks to reduce net income by about $150 million in the third quarter 2009, after policyholder-shareholder split in Texas. In light of current market conditions we have referred to back to our proven long-term strategic asset allocation.</p>
          <p>With that, let me comment on our unrealized losses in shareholders equity. Given that unrealized capital gains and losses continued to be an important driver, we have included this slide again this quarter. The half year unrealized gains included in shareholders' equity of $600 million is made up of a second quarter gain of 2 billion, which is &#x2013; more than offsets the losses of the first quarter.</p>
          <p>As you would expect in the market conditions during the second quarter, unrealized gains accrued on both debt and equity securities. Of the total 1.4 billion gains on debt in the second quarter, roughly 1.7 billion were on corporate bonds and another 400 million on asset-backed securities, largely as a result of tightening credit spreads.</p>
          <p>These gains were partially offset by unrealized losses on government bonds of 700 million, driven by higher interest rates on longer maturities particular in U.S. dollars. In addition, a recovering equity market reduced losses by another $500 million on our common stock investments.</p>
          <p>With that, let me comment on the movement on shareholders equity. Shareholders' equity at $25.2 billion is $3.1 billion or 16% up on the 2008 year end number. Net income attributable to shareholders of 1.3 billion was net of an effective tax rate of 24.7%.</p>
          <p>So a $700 million increase in unrealized investment losses in the first quarter was more than reversed in the second quarter, giving rise to a net unrealized gain of 629 million year-to-date, net of tax, policyholder and other allocations. Translation adjustment also reversed between quarters and increased equity by another $889 million for the six months, predominantly driven by sterling recovery. The actuarial losses on pension plans decreased largely from movement in discount rates. These are based on long-dated AA corporate bond yields, which increased.</p>
          <p>The capital movements in the quarter largely matched out with the total issue of shares in the quarter of $1.2 billion and dividends paid of 1.4 billion. Looking at the movement in Swiss Franc, book value per share increased 11% in the six months to 186 francs.</p>
          <p>With that, let's have a look at our capital position on the next slide. Our Solvency 1 ratio has improved by 23 points to 180% in the second quarter. This includes the equity increase of $1.1 billion in April. It also takes in the full 2009 expected effect of the Farmers Quota Share increase to 37% and of the 200 million hybrid issue, although a number of these components were not be booked until the third and fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>As you know, there is much variability in the components of Solvency 1 calculations throughout Europe. We are mark-to-market our bond portfolio, which reduces the ratio by about 13 percentages points. In addition, we calculate our solvency net of general insurance deferred acquisition costs, which accounts for another 24 percentage points.</p>
          <p>Moving on to economic solvency at the bottom part of the slide. Including risk efficiency actions already taken, the six months' profits, capital actions and economic effect in the half year as well as committed items for the second half, our economic solvency level recovered during the first half to 124% on our internal double AA calibration.</p>
          <p>Finally, as in previous quarters, our numbers have no allowance for liquidity premiums allowing, for example, for 100 basis point liquidity premium, would increase the economic solvency by 80 percentage points.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the next slide. As you will have seen, we tendered for the buyback of about 730 million of subordinated debt and subsequently issued &#x20AC;425 million of new subordinated debt. Taken together, this transaction will give us net benefits in profit, capital structure and solvency. The major benefit is to have generated a profit net of expenses and future increases in paid interest charges of over $120 million. The capital gain will be booked in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>So let me summarize. Our strategy of managing our risks, particularly underwriting investment risk in a balanced way, has allowed us to continue to perform at good levels of profitability throughout the crisis. Our operating businesses remain sound with good performances in difficult markets, achieving selected growth in those areas where we wanted to go.</p>
          <p>As financial market volatility recedes, the results of recovering and our BOP after tax ROE is back above target. However, we have not relaxed on the financial market crisis and we continue to manage those things we can control to contain the risk and protect the capital base.</p>
          <p>The capital base and solvency have been considerably strengthened by the actions we have taken and the recovery of the investment market. But keep in mind that the market movements taking over the whole six months period were largely flat. Subsequently, the strong recovery in July has generated a real year-to-date uplift.</p>
          <p>In our core businesses, the General Insurance combined ratio was supported by the increase in rates and the expense savings actions taken. Also, we saw profitable growth due to an increased rating of Farmers' contribution to the Group and good progress in executing the Life strategy.</p>
          <p>Our task is to continue to manage our business, aiming to deliver consistent, high quality earnings and stay focused on exploiting those attractive opportunities for profitable growth which we expect to become available during today's market conditions. So we can now move on to the questions and answers session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so we have quite a lot of people on the line, I think, as well. But we will start with some questions from the room. The normal house rules, would be please wait for the microphone if you are in the room and give your name and your organization? So where are the microphones? Okay. I'm going to reverse this and take the first call from &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; you've got a microphone, the one there at the back, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There was a Board meeting yesterday, can you tell us if a new chairman has &#x2013; a new CEO has been found already? Why is it difficult to find a new CEO? And my third question is, your philosophy was always discipline, you always mentioned that. Can you tell us, how did you put in practice your philosophy in the daily business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So this purpose of this meeting is to discuss the results, not to discuss the Board agenda. There is a separation between governance from the Board and the responsibility for CEO succession is the Board's. As I have commented on in the past, there is a process in place that the Board is following. I am confident that they will come to a conclusion and as soon as we've reached that conclusion, I'm sure they will communicate it to you.</p>
          <p>Let me answer the third question, which I have some control over and that is how one manages the business with discipline. I think the &#x2013; we learned from a very, very difficult crisis in 2001 and 2002 and I think those learnings have served us well in this period of time. And that is really to have financial discipline, operational excellence, have strict measurements, because what gets measured gets done. Centralization of key areas, particularly around finance and risk and investment management, underwriting and claims management in a business like this are key.</p>
          <p>If you look at some of the failures in the financial services industry, they stem from perhaps a much more entrepreneurial attitude to the delegation of some of those functions out to subsidiaries. We have embedded in the culture, through the Zurich Way, holding people responsible and accountable and when they fail to be accountable and responsible, we take appropriate actions. So I think that's part of our culture.</p>
          <p>We prepared ourselves during those very strong years. I am often humorously reminded when people said, we did not have a vision, we were not aggressive, everyone was moving ahead of us. We stayed the course. We've had 26 consecutive periods of profitability. Let's not move side of the fact that some of those periods were during this crisis. When others were reporting losses, we were continuing to report profits. And as we re-shifted our focus, we've had profit &#x2013; increasing profitability during this crisis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Do we take one, this one here please, Stephen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Stephen Schulman from Vontobel. I have two questions. The first one is on the non-life prior year reserve releases. Can you give us some color in order to estimate the future reserve releases? They were down half year on half year, just some feelings and background there? And the second question is on the M&amp;A. Can you maybe give us some update on opportunities currently in the market in terms of geography and segment, if there is anything specific you are currently looking at or you are specifically interested or has changed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, look, those are two very good questions, both of which are on your mind. We do not comment on M&amp;A transactions. So that's part of discipline and how we execute on that discipline from the last question. So if you stay the course on things like that, you don't get yourself into trouble at the end of the day.</p>
          <p>Look, this is a period where there are a lot of things for sale, the question comes between sales price of what the seller expects and what the buyer expects. Extremely important is how is it fit into our strategy and we look at lot of different opportunities in different markets. It has to fit in, meet our hurdle rates, fit into our strategic focus. We have a very tight screen and we are very, very disciplined around this.</p>
          <p>And I think that's the part of the success, as you hear from these results, as Dieter talks about, the success we have achieved in Spain, with the Spanish acquisition. If you go back and look at the others and our ability not to dilute our culture, be able to effectively and rapidly integrate these acquisitions into our business and a key part of the due diligence process is, you look at 21st  Century, for example. We were not just analyzing and evaluating that, we were looking at the same time we were going through there, is how we could rapidly integrate that and hit the ground running. So as soon as we reached an agreement, as Dieter pointed out, the Farmers people were in there focusing on moving forward with the appropriate integration techniques.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So then let me take the second half of the question &#x2013; or the first half of the question, Stephen. Actually when you look at that the first quarter had 114 million prior year and the second quarter, 280. So you see it is not a number which we plan or manage. It is a bottom-up process and I think the two numbers give a good range for quarterly volatility, I know last year, it was much more stable but that was more to our internal surprise that a number is coming out this stable every quarter. And that is actually something which we don't manage. So therefore any forecasting either done by us or by you would be &#x2013; probably be difficult.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll take one more from the room and then we'll go to the phone. Michael, I think &#x2013; the far end of the second line there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. It's Michael Klien from Cheuvreux. I've got two questions. My first question would be on the economic solvency that has improved quite substantially. If I remember correctly in the past year, it has always been targeting a buffer of about 10 to 20%. At the moment now, it is at 124%.</p>
          <p>So my question would be, do you currently feel with your outlook that it's safe to have somewhat of a higher buffer or are you considering managing maybe a little bit more risk on the investment side, for example, at Gen Re on the required capital side? Or are you thinking about maybe reducing your available financial resources, for example, with increasing the dividend versus last year or maybe some other options?</p>
          <p>And my second question is with respect to the non-core business, I know it's very difficult to focus quarter-over-quarter because it's highly geared into the financial markets, but my question is on the centrally managed business. We saw a huge change here, so could you give us a little bit color what has happened in the centrally managed business and how we should be thinking about forecasting this going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let me come back to first and then allow Dieter to comment on both of these topics. We are not setting the dividend today and that's a long way off. I think this will be a long, protracted recovery. I think the focus of having a strong balance sheet is extremely important. It served us well as we've come through &#x2013; the focus of that balance sheet is to protect our shareholders, our policyholders and employees and that's been our main focus. We think that is a key driver.</p>
          <p>So we don't take risks relative to what our solvency looks like. We are very disciplined and focused in how we manage our risk. You heard Dieter talk about the fact that we've gone back to, in light of current market conditions, the normal asset allocation in our investment portfolio that has served us well over this period of time. But we will watch and manage our solvency appropriately as we go through the rest of these very challenging times, which I think recovery will be protracted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, I think certainly the number of the economic solvency is probably still a bit more volatile than we have seen it in the past. And if &#x2013; what I mentioned in my summary was, in the first six months of the year, the financial market actually had roughly zero impact on our overall equity number. Actually, the total market value moved by $100 million, which is in light of &#x2013; close to 200 billion, of course, nothing.</p>
          <p>So the whole market recovery started just in July. It certainly would add at the moment something positive to our solvency numbers, but what can be gained in four weeks unfortunately probably can also be lost in four weeks. So therefore, I think we have still to wait until the whole world is in a more settled and a more predictable stage.</p>
          <p>And as difficult as it is to predict and forecast the economic conditions in the next 18 months, there is probably a similar difficulty in predicting exactly our non-core CMB business, which is very much linked to equity market levels, but also customer behavior in these one-off portfolios in this difficult market environment. And therefore I think we have probably to live with some uncertainty around it, still enjoying that early August, the markets are very nice to ourself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We will take the first call from &#x2013; on the line. Operator, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>From the telephone conference is from Mr. Spencer Hogan from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Three actually quick ones from me. First one is, you talked about the non-technical result and obviously that is a bit volatile quarter-to-quarter, but could you just give us a bit more color on what's driving it up in the second quarter?</p>
          <p>Second question is, if we look at the reinsurance program, you said you bought the three pillars on an economic basis. Is that all a feature of the global aggregate CAT cover or is that more just kind of the results yielding purchase that doesn't actually have that much economic value? And then the third one is just briefly on Italy, I can see the published combined ratio is 111%. Could you tell me, is the accident year combined ratio substantially different? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the CAT cover, we still have the aggregate CAT cover. The CAT cover towers I have presented addressing the big single events, so what happens when this big European windstorm or the big hurricane is hitting our portfolios. This aggregate cover you were referring to is actually more addressing if we are being hit by multiple mid-sized storms and that with higher than usual frequency during the year and therefore, both covers together are completing our overall protection against volatility coming from storms, quakes and other catastrophes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The purchase of that aggregate cap cover, that is purchased for reasons of economics rather than just sort of results, do you think? Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, actually, two years ago when we had the two big floods in the U.K., which were both for our net retention, we &#x2013; I think if I remember correctly, we didn't get a single dollar from our reinsurers on this. We were almost close to draw under this reinsurance of the aggregate cover and now you say, well, the two big floods was a very unusual event, but when you see the summer this year in Europe, so far the events coming out of it were fairly small. But the frequency of this floodings, hail and other, is certainly increasing as we can all notice ourselves. Your &#x2013; referring to your Italian questions, the accident year combined ratio is nine percentage points better than the number you quoted.</p>
          <p>On &#x2013; I think your first question was referring to the non-technical. It's actually not this year hit by the additional expenses. It's more lacking some positive news we had last year and things, for example, was provisions we had on certain premium tax numbers, which were then not being paid or we had some gains out of the sale from unused buildings and this year, it's probably so far a very normal year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we take a second question, please, from the line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Andrew Broadfield from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Just a couple of quick ones, I think. Just on your asset allocation, I think you mentioned about your equity hedging. Can you just remind me what your equity hedging is now and whether that is sort of an integral part of your asset strategy or whether in fact you normally not have the hedging in place and just have a gross position?</p>
          <p>The second question is on the distribution of reserves, just where, I think if we go back to year or two, it was predominantly coming out of Europe and the U.K. I was just wondering whether we are seeing a bit of a shift sort of maybe into the U.S. or somewhere else. That would be helpful to know.</p>
          <p>And just one other quick one, if possible. The 2.5 &#x2013; I think the loan-loss provisions you put through your small banking operation, it seems like quite a big amount given &#x2013; I think it's on the Irish and U.K. portfolio with a reasonable LTV. I just wonder whether you can give us a little bit more information about that provision, whether we can expect anything more or whether this was a bit of a kitchen sinking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I am going to Dieter to comment on that and if you need more on the asset allocation, we can ask Martin Senn to pick up on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll start with the hedging that was 12% of the overall positions we have in equities, so that our net exposure to equities is 2.8% of the investment portfolio. The reserve releases are coming actually from acquired mix, a list of countries. There is a bit from North America, but there is from various European countries and also from, I think actually from Hong Kong and Australia. So it is a broad range of countries and it is not linked to one country and as I said before, it is a large list of pluses and minuses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so no particular trend there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think your last question was referring to our banking operations. You are right, loan-to-market ratio of the book is still at a very good level. However, we have taken here a view that we should have provisions which are in line with industry practice. Even if we are not a specialist in this industry, I think we still understand how these reserves are being calculated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just if I got my numbers right from an earlier conversion, there is a portfolio in Ireland and U.K., which I think there is provisions against, was, what, 2 billion or something and you are holding a 40 or 50 million provision against it? That seems like quite a big number as a percentage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's 2.5%. You are fully right with your number calculations and 2.5% is probably a good industry average number, although we feel that that our book is not industry average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And just on the equity hedging, you intend to keep an equity hedge as part of the practice or is that just a sort of legacy that you will wind down now that you are back at your strategic allocation there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's part of the ongoing strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Operator can we take one more call from the line and then we will come back to the room?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. William Hawkins from KBW. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you very much. My first question, Dieter, could you just clarify little bit more how the risk swap fits into the three towers on Slide 14? I understand it's included but I don't quite see where it comes in, in the first and the third columns.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, slightly more generally, we're starting to hear various non-life companies refer to recession-related claims as explanations of performance. So far, that seems to be more kind of credit and surety-oriented and you don't seem to be making too much reference to that. But I'm just wondering in your P&amp;C book if you got any kind indication of any kind of recession-related issues that may be on the horizon? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's &#x2013; the swap I have referred is at the U.S. tower at the upper-end of the tower. So that is a 100 million cover. We &#x2013; both parties have swapped here protection at the very high end, so where it is &#x2013; actually, the probability that it is being utilized is fairly low but this as an area is where the capacity is most scarce and you have actually in relative terms, you pay the highest prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does it also influence tower three?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it is U.S. hurricane versus Japanese windstorm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll come back offline. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And your other question is, maybe I indicated it in my speech or at least I tried to, saying that we are at the moment not seeing a lot of recessionary impact on claims. So yes, there are all these nice headline stories on fraud and we have also very active fraud units built up in various regions which also added to some the newspaper headlines, but overall, we cannot say that our loss ratio has any significant impact from this market environment. Actually, the inflationary impacts are certainly more than offsetting, or the lower inflation is more than offsetting what is left from additional frauds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll come back to the room for questions. Fabrizio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fabrizio Croce, Kepler. I have just one, it's about your rate change monitor, if I look to this overview I see that only Switzerland is problematic for the time being and in Switzerland, for next year, other companies announced already substantial rate increases, up to 10%. I am right supposing that you will take part to these rate increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly, when the market and also the profitability of the business justifies this, we are always participating in going for higher rates, but we are calculating our rates based on a technical price and that defines our price level we want to see. Additionally, I would not say that Switzerland is in the critical territory. When you look at the combined ratio of Switzerland below 90%, we would be very glad to have this critical level in all other markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Can I just highlight because I think it's an opportunity to focus once again on how we run this business. We focus on a technical price, which is the cost of the risk in a given market. So when we referred earlier to lead the market, we were out in front of many of our competitors in putting in place rate increases.</p>
          <p>Because of the declining returns that we see and other factors that impact our technical price, we have been driving since the fourth quarter of last year price increases. We've been willing to give up business, but the corresponding piece is true as well. We don't just follow a herd mentality in pricing our product, we see ourselves as providing value and making sure that the customer understands the cost of the risk and that's a balance that we strike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So if anybody in the room receives this 10% higher bill, call your nearest Zurich agent to compare.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Any other calls from the room before I put it back to the Operator? Okay. Can we have another question from the line, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Brian Shea from Banc of America-Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. I have two questions, please. First of all, on Life Insurance, I really like the disclosure you guys gave at the Life Analyst Day describing the drivers of business operating profit. Could you &#x2013; can I make a request that you do start providing this as a regular part of disclosure? And can you give us any color on sort of how the composition of the first half was different from the full year disclosure 2008?</p>
          <p>And then my second question is European personal lines, your pricing is doing a lot better. But, Dieter, I think you made a few comments, or maybe it was Jim, about how competition is picking up and we're hearing that from others, that recession is pushing on the top-line and that's creating a fight amongst competitors for a shrinking pie. Could you comment on your customer retention trend? Are you &#x2013; how are you getting your prices up and are there any signs of your volume suffering as a result? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'll ask John to comment on customer retention and what we are seeing, this is John Amore in Europe, and Dieter will talk about the profit disclosures on the Life side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, you'll remember, fully correct, that we are going to add this profit by source analysis to our disclosures and Mario and his team are using it certainly also internally to manage the business. The only however is for managing the business and management results, it has already passed the test. For a full disclosure in our external reporting, it has to go through some formal hurdles and therefore, we will probably only be able to do this with the year-end reporting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Brian, this is John Amore. And relative to our retentions in Europe on the personal lines business, there is two stories. In the U.K., we have seen a drop in our retentions and we have started taking price action there quite a while back, because we felt it was necessary and we have seen a lowering of our normal retention levels. On Continental Europe, retentions have held up fairly well and we've not seen that kind of issue there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Could we have another question please, Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. James Quinn from Citigroup. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Two questions, please. The first one is on the Farmers Re combined ratio, which was 99.7% first half versus 102.3% end of Q1 and the catastrophe impact is about the same for the first half versus Q1. I just wondered if you'd give us a sense of what's driving that, whether there is anything specific behind that?</p>
          <p>And the second question is a question on claims paid. If I look at the first half picture, the current year claims paid have increased by 8%, but the current year incurred has actually fallen by 3%. And if I have to compare the first half of this year versus the first half of 2007, the claims paid have increased by 24% and the current year incurred has increased by 5%, so I mean, it may be that there is all sorts of movements within that and I'm sure there are, but I guess that is quite a big move.</p>
          <p>And I wonder if you could give us a sense of what is happening there, whether it's the fact you are moving to pay claims a lot more quickly or whether you are essentially looking to reflect some of the good recent claims experience in how you book the current year incurred? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, James, I have read your analysis on the Zurich ratio and claims paid, which is, in principle, okay if you have all the underlying data and understand all the volatilities behind it and it is, on a summarized level, very difficult to judge. I can only give you a few examples in early 2008, there was obviously a lot of payout from the previous year cat.</p>
          <p>The same we have early 2009, there was the hurricanes in the U.S. which then created additional paid out, as well as we had in the U.S. coming out of our cop and hail insurance coverages, we had to pay out all in the first two months of 2009, which is a fairly big one-off claim payment which was just focused on this period. Therefore, this analysis of claims paid and reserving levels, that only works actually when you have a portfolio where nothing is changing. If you are looking at a national motor policy portfolio, then this analysis works probably quite well. But it is also true in general, we are trying to pay claims faster as part of our Zurich Way of claims handling.</p>
          <p>So the other question was on Farmers Re result. The driver of the combined ratio improvement is, as I said, half of it is coming, that's the total cat for the half year is being &#x2013; was more heavily in the first quarter and less in the second quarter. Then we are driving through higher rates on the motor business. So that is starting to earn in. Additionally supported that actually motor frequency in our motor portfolio at the Farmers exchanges is showing clear signs of improvement. That is also a bit of a market trend, because also 21st Century shows these improved signs. In the first slide, we have shown about it in the update on the AIG acquisition. So this is driving in the right direction.</p>
          <p>So what type of cats are these? While it is in the end very similar as previous year, only previous year, it was much more dramatic in number and sizes, these floods, hails, tornados, all the local events which we see more frequent now for the last eight, 10 quarters. And the wildfires in California, not to forget.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, the actual catastrophe experience is exactly the same pretty much for the first half of &#x2013; for Q1, so presumably in Q2 the same as Q1 as well . But...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's lower in Q2. When you look at the Farmers exchange slides, it might be easier to see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe we handle this offline, that is probably more technical, going through the line items.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can we have one &#x2013; I think two more questions and then we will finish. So could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Paul Goodhind from Redburn Partners. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, good morning I had two questions. Could you give a bit more flavor, I guess, this is probably for John Amore, this question. On the new business pricing, I think the comment was that there was more competition on new business compared to renewed business. Could you give some geographic flavor for where you see most competition on the new business? And is your new business pricing as adequate as your renewal pricing, or are you also selling at a discount and perhaps you can quantify that discount?</p>
          <p>And secondly, just back to Slide 23 and the centrally managed reserve increases relating to one-off life business, I presume that is disability, is it? Any flavor about what's driving that? Is that a recessionary impact and to what extent are you confident that those reserves are adequate now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, while we get John a microphone, I am going to ask Dieter to deal with the centrally managed businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, as I tried to answer to Michael Klien's question, the results are volatile, as they are driven by financial market movements as well as customer behavior. We increased reserves in the Life one-off book in the U.S. based on our new updated forecast about customer behavior and that is the best view we have at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But can you break down the part between financial markets on the hand and customer behavior on the other?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The customer behavior, we increased reserves 250 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And that's not recession-related, is it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is recession related. I would say, as more people are surrendering.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Paul, this is John Amore. To answer your question about new business, new business is quite competitive and I'd shown, I think in the top-line, having &#x2013; and just not only for us, but almost for every company that's reported so far. And of course, part of that is recession-related and that our customers have less exposure to insure, especially commercial customers.</p>
          <p>However, in general when we price new business, we price it to meet our target of &#x2013; well, for General Insurance, a 25% pre-tax BOP ROE, which converts to the 16% Group level BOP ROE that we're retaining. That can be different at times than from renewal pricing, when we have very attractive markets that we want to &#x2013; where we think the margins are very rich and we want to grow new business. And so we can have differences between new business pricing and renewal business pricing, but it's always at &#x2013; designed to be at our return levels that we're attracting to the Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess the question is, what is that difference? Is it at a discount to renewed pricing and is that discount sort of narrowing or changing in any way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, as I say, the &#x2013; if we are in a portfolio where we think it's very high returns, we can have a difference in new business pricing in order to grow our market. But it's always designed to get &#x2013; meet the minimum return for the company. And it really is &#x2013; we don't see shifts in that taking place at the present time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay. Then we can talk offline to get more detail on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Could we go to the last question now please, Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question from the telephone conference is from Mr. Michael Huttner from JP Morgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I had a question or two. The first is, the assets which are in the non-core, could you explain a little bit how much of these assets are market sensitive? I guess those are in Centre and how much of the banking assets in total and whether they've grown? The impression I get is, you are actually growing your banking operation, but I don't know and I don't see the figures. I would be very grateful for that.</p>
          <p>The other one is in terms of the pricing moving up. I can never quite reconcile the pricing with actual results. I suppose there is lags and maybe if new business was renewed and &#x2013; I am always a bit confused, but I wonder if you can help me and actually say on the underlying loss ratio, which is flat at 66%, when would we expect to see the improvement of 3%? Would it be in the second half already or next year or is it offset by other stuff, just to get an idea, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, I think we see already some part of the 3% in the half year numbers as we had last year in some areas, as you can see from last year's rate monitor, a reduction in rates. So I think we have here various cycles and generations of renewal prices which go &#x2013; which are now in the upswing, but came out of a period of downswing for quite some quarters. So therefore that this curve is then embedded in the numbers is just earning in months by months and I think that the number has not moved against the half year 2008. I think that is a great achievement and I think &#x2013; I hope also differentiates us from some of our competitors.</p>
          <p>Your other question was with respect to the assets in non-core business. I think in non-core business, the assets are all volatile to the market as we are &#x2013; as you'll remember, our visibility book in Centre is booked through a fair value. That means the assets and liabilities are going fully in their changes through P&amp;L. And therefore, we have a full exposure to the financial market there on the Life line of business that is more indirect exposure to the financial market, not driven to the assets on the balance sheet. I think you also had made the statement that we are growing our banking assets, which is not the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you just say how big they are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it got mentioned before, it's roughly 2.2 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>2.2 billion. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. So that concludes the Q&amp;A and I'll just now hand over to Jim Schiro to conclude the session. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Malcolm. I want to thank all of you once again for participating in today's discussion of our half year 2009 results. I hope you walk away understanding why we are feeling so good about these outstanding results and our ability to achieve these results in spite of this global economic recession.</p>
          <p>However, you should also walk away understanding that our focus remains the same. We've currently reaffirmed our strategy. We've made some adjustments to it from a tactical standpoint to allow us to drive through with these results during these difficult times, such as in our rating environment, which we're seeing sustained improvement. We'll see the results of that, as we've just been discussing, as that new business and these new rates flow through in the coming quarters and years.</p>
          <p>Our product portfolio, we continually readjust that to make sure we are providing, as we've discussed in Life, the kinds of products that customers want and you see that in terms of the diversity that we present in terms of where our revenue is coming from in Life.</p>
          <p>Also, our acquisition strategy. I want you to walk away again being assured of our discipline in that area and that we will be effective in terms of looking at those opportunities as they present themselves, but we will also maintain the discipline and rigor we have.</p>
          <p>Our investment portfolio continues to be resilient and also, I would say our expense base is in check. We are very, very mindful of the importance of strong expense controls. I reiterate that in all of the discussions with our employees, because we have to balance our expense management and make sure that we are investing in the future, so that we can leverage the financial strength that I'm certain we will emerge from this recovery period with and be able to capitalize on it. So also, our capital and solvency positions continue to improve. We monitor those weekly, particularly during this crisis period. I feel good about where we are and especially the fact that we are once again exceeding our 16% BOP ROE target.</p>
          <p>So I thank you all again for you patience, participation and assure you that we feel very good and optimistic that the strategy we put in place three years ago is working and is serving us well in these difficult times. Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>